<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>php on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/php/</link>
    <description>Recent content in php on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kata formulation: Find the comments</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/01/kata-formulation-find-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 08:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/01/kata-formulation-find-comments/</guid>
      <description>Little Johnny is inspecting a PHP source code that contains comments. These comments contains words that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand, as it written in another language.
Rules and constraints The source code in the PHP files does not need to be correct.
A comment (a subset of PHP comments) is defined as:
 A line containing C-style comment delimiter, except when it is within a string  // hello C-style is a valid comment echo &amp;quot;//&amp;quot;; is not a comment echo &#39;//&#39;; is not a comment   A line containing Perl-style comment delimiter, except when it is within a string  # hello Perl-style is a valid comment echo &amp;quot;#&amp;quot;; is not a comment echo &#39;#&#39;; is not a comment   There are no multi-line comments  /* .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
