<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming-language on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/programming-language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming-language on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/programming-language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper: Fundamental concepts on programming languages</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/06/paper-fundamental-concepts-on-programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 07:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/06/paper-fundamental-concepts-on-programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>Note: all quotes on this post come from this paper: Strachey, C. Fundamental Concepts in Programming Languages. Published in Higher-Order and Symbolic Computation, 13, 11–49, 2000.
Contents This paper starts slow, from the mathematical and philosophical point of view, until it gets to the basic concepts on the fundamental concepts:
 Assignment command L-Value and R-Value Definitions Names Numerals Conceptual models: an explanation about the relationship between the code, the memory store and the abstract concepts  Later, it gets more in depth to the conceptual constructs, where most of the content is explained and contains:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in July 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post
Clojure made simple I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk Easy made simple
 polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter  Productive pair programming I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about pair programming, using the driver &amp;amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé
Building Automated REST APIs with Python Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about it</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
