<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Redesign | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/redesign/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-12T17:26:13+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redesign as a New TDD Phase]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/13/redesign-as-a-new-tdd-phase/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-13T22:00:45+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/13/redesign-as-a-new-tdd-phase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last TDD workshop (experience report <a href="../../../../2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop">here</a>), a conversation with <a href="http://twitter.com/@garymcleanhall">Gary McLean Hall</a> introduced to me this new concept of &ldquo;Redesign&rdquo; as a TDD phase.</p>

<h2>Concept</h2>

<p>As Gary introduced it to me<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, it is a phase that might appear after refactor.</p>

<p>It is about changing the outside design without changing the expected behavior. I thought this was also included in the refactor phase.</p>

<h2>How I do redesign</h2>

<p>I usually do this &ldquo;changing of the outside design&rdquo; by applying a series of refactors <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> to the production code but not changing the test code; using a bridge / adapter to get to the new API from the old one. Later you can inline the scaffold and use the new API directly.</p>

<p>The same for the test code: when you want to change design in the test code, do not modify production code (a.k.a. model code).</p>

<h2>Other thoughts</h2>

<p>Merriam-Webster defines &ldquo;<a href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/redesign">redesign</a>&rdquo; as</p>

<blockquote><p>to change the design of (something)</p></blockquote>

<p>or</p>

<blockquote><p>to revise in appearance, function, or content</p></blockquote>

<p>an example:</p>

<blockquote><p>The book&rsquo;s cover has been redesigned for the new edition.</p></blockquote>

<p>The Refactoring book (by Martin Fowler) describes &ldquo;refactoring&rdquo; as</p>

<blockquote><p>Refactoring is the process of changing a software system in such a way that it does not alter the external behavior of the code yet improves its internal structure</p></blockquote>

<p>Taken literally, the public API is not internal but external structure, so changing it, should belong to a phase that is not refactor (see definition), nor red (no failing tests), not green (making it pass). Maybe this phase is &ldquo;redesign&rdquo; or we have to take the refactoring phase less literally so it includes redesign. Any thoughts?</p>

<h2>Other references</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve searched for redesign and refactor and <a href="https://practicingruby.com/articles/refactoring-is-not-redesign">this blog post</a> came up. They cite redesign as a way of rewriting</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/80758/1181094">This answer</a> and the <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/80758/1181094">original question</a> in StackOverflow is interesting</p>

<p>Redesign also appears cited in <a href="http://blog.testdouble.com/posts/2014-01-25-the-failures-of-intro-to-tdd.html">this blog post</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Excuse me if you explained it differently and I understand it wrong; you can always open a pull request to fix it <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/blog_source/tree/source/source/_posts">here</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>thanks for the clarifying refactor vs refactoring <a href="http://blog.4mm.co.uk/2012/12/11/pet-peeve-726.html">here</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
