<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>laziness on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/laziness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in laziness on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/laziness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal training: Testing is hard - just do it</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/05/internal-training-testing-is-hard-just-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 23:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/05/internal-training-testing-is-hard-just-do-it/</guid>
      <description>At a client, last week I&amp;rsquo;ve organized an internal training, in the form of a discussion about this article: Testing is hard - just do it
Our thoughts  When a bug is found, prove it exists with a test
 This immediately reduces defect rate: the same regression cannot be introduced again
 fix a bug a second time
 If fixing a bug (having defects in your code) was &amp;lsquo;waste&amp;rsquo;, as defined by lean methodologies, it also is wast fixing it for the following times</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
