<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Deliberate-practice | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/deliberate-practice/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-07T01:32:19+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in May 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-01T00:08:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Being A Developer After 40</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.freecodecamp.com/being-a-developer-after-40-3c5dd112210c">this article</a> by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:</p>

<ul>
<li>Forget The Hype</li>
<li>Choose Your Galaxy Wisely</li>
<li>Learn About Software History</li>
<li>Keep on Learning</li>
<li>Teach</li>
<li>Workplaces Suck</li>
<li>Know Your Worth</li>
<li>Send The Elevator Down</li>
<li>LLVM</li>
</ul>


<p>He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM</p>

<blockquote><p>Take conscious decisions in your life. Be aware of your actions and their effect. Do not blush or be embarrased for changing your opinions. Say “I’m sorry” when required. Listen. Do not be a hotshot. Have integrity and self-respect.</p></blockquote>

<p>Recommends these books:</p>

<ul>
<li>Dealers of Lightning by Michael A. Hiltzik</li>
<li>Revolution in the Valley by Andy Hertzfeld</li>
<li>The Cathedral and the Bazaar by Eric S. Raymond</li>
<li>The Success of Open Source by Steven Weber</li>
<li>The Old New Thing by Raymond Chen</li>
<li>The Mythical Man Month by Frederick P. Brooks Jr.</li>
<li>Peopleware by Tom DeMarco and Tim Lister</li>
<li>The Psychology of Software Programming by Gerald M. Weinberg</li>
<li>Facts and Fallacies of Software Engineering by Robert L. Glass</li>
<li>The Design of Everyday Things by Don Norman</li>
<li>Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly by Bertrand Meyer</li>
<li>Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson</li>
<li>Geekonomics by David Rice</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: adrian-kosmaczewski, career, profession, age, galaxy, long-term, book</p>

<h2>Firing people</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://zachholman.com/talk/firing-people">this article</a> by Zach Holman on firing people at your current work, both from the perspective of the employee (fired), employer, coworker.</p>

<p>Also explains his personal experience of being fired from Github.</p>

<blockquote><p>You’ll know the difference between doing far and away your best work, and doing work that is still good, but just nominally better than what you’ve been doing. Once you catch yourself adjusting to that incremental progression… maybe it’s time to leave, to change things up</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: zach-holman, github, team-management, firing, coworker, employee, employer, job, relationship, next</p>

<h2>10 design principles — for developers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@nirbenita/the-10-design-heuristics-for-developers-1e70a9dc58a7">this article</a> that explains what are the 10 design principles for programmers, as outlined by Jakob Nielsen. The article itself is by Nir Benita</p>

<p>Tags: design-principle, ux, jakob-nielsen, nir-benita, usability, testing, list</p>

<h2>Design Patterns — Coming Full Circle, Part Two</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/swlh/design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two-ced2c69e4724#.x8ud7eeqm">this article</a> that explains how design patterns can be observed and then discovered and shows a list of four patterns dot working with data, by flux.io. Article by Jen Carlile</p>

<p>Tags: design-pattern, data, pattern, flux, flux-io, pattern-catalog, jen-carlile</p>

<h2>Why I’m Ending my Github Streak after 844 Days</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@karan/why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days-80fd014dc8df">this article</a> by Karan Goel on the mechanics of following a pattern, of an activity sliced in small parts (1 problem a day or half an hour) and how this can be counterproductive sometimes.</p>

<p>Discusses ROI of this type of activity at the beginning of your career and later.</p>

<p>Tags: karan-goel, github, streak, python, code, everyday, practice, deliberate-practice, career, career-management</p>

<h2>Good lessons learned from past jobs</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.kartones.net/post/good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs/">this article</a> by Diego &lsquo;Kartones&rsquo; on a synopsis of his work experience, job by job and what he has learned on each job.</p>

<p>Tags: diego-kartones, job, professional-career, career</p>

<h2>Too Much Work In Progress</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://monospacedmonologues.com/post/144137568985/too-much-work-in-progress">this article</a> by Samir Talwar on factors that indicate work in progress.</p>

<p>Tags: wip, work-in-progress, list, samir-talwar</p>

<h2>TestDouble</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.martinfowler.com/bliki/TestDouble.html">this article</a> by Martin Fowler describing the test doubles that Gerard Meszaros describes in xUnit Test Patterns.</p>

<p>Tags: test-double, martin-fowler, gerard-meszaros, stub, fake, mock, dummy, spy, xunit, junit, pattern, test-pattern</p>

<h2>Scaling to 12 Million Concurrent Connections: How MigratoryData Did It</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://mrotaru.wordpress.com/2013/10/10/scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it/">this article</a> by Mihai Rotaru on how MigratoryData scaled to 12 million concurrent connections in a 1U server. They explain what optimizations they did in order to achieve this.</p>

<p>Tags: migratorydata, mihai-rotaru, concurrent-connection, 1u-server, scalability, websocket</p>

<h2>Do what you love</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/do-what-you-love-jorge-diaz">this article</a> by Jorge Diaz on doing what takes you out of your comfort zone, changing careers, and life-work in general.</p>

<p>Cites this <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/scott_dinsmore_how_to_find_work_you_love/transcript?language=en">TED talk: How to find work you love</a></p>

<p>Tags: jorge-diaz, work, life, career, comfort-zone, scott-dinsmore, career-management</p>

<h2>JHipster - The best way to breed a new app</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/olbpetersson/jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app">these slides</a> by Ola Petersson, where he describes the architecture and contents of the jHipster, its pros and cons.</p>

<p>Tags: jhipster, ola petersson, java, code-generation, code-generator, microservice</p>

<h2>How going to coding events helped me get an awesome job</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.freecodecamp.com/networking-at-meet-ups-getting-hired-f0f7c4f4681a">this article</a> by Gwendolyn Faraday on how to kickstart a career in web development, attending events, pairing and networking. That netted her some interviews to start programming for a living.</p>

<p>Tags: networking, gwendolyn-faraday, event, job, learn-to-code</p>

<h2>Maze Generation: Algorithm Recap</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2011/2/7/maze-generation-algorithm-recap">this list</a> of maze-generation algorithms by Jamis Buck. Including:</p>

<ul>
<li>recursive backtracker</li>
<li>Eller’s algorithm</li>
<li>Kruskal’s algorithm</li>
<li>Prim’s algorithm</li>
<li>recursive division algorithm</li>
<li>Aldous-Broder algorithm</li>
<li>Wilson’s algorithm</li>
<li>Hunt-and-Kill algorithm</li>
<li>Growing Tree algorithm</li>
<li>Binary Tree algorithm</li>
<li>Sidewinder algorithm</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: recursive-backtracker,eller-algorithm,kruskal-algorithm,prim-algorithm,recursive-division-algorithm,aldous-broder-algorithm,wilson-algorithm,hunt-and-kill-algorithm,growing-tree-algorithm,binary-tree-algorithm,sidewinder-algorithm, jamis-buck, maze, maze-generation, algorithm, list</p>

<h2>The Poverty of Constraints</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2016/3/19/poverty-of-constraints.html">this article</a> by Jamis Buck on interpreting two Korean proverbs in the world of software:</p>

<ul>
<li>A dutiful son comes from a poor home</li>
<li>A poor house has many children</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: proverb, korea, philosophy, software, constraint, jamis-buck</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in April 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-01T00:08:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.</p>

<p>The four essential components:</p>

<ul>
<li>Motivation</li>
<li>Tailored (practice)</li>
<li>Feedback</li>
<li>Repetion</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career</p>

<h2>10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jooq.org/2016/03/31/10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language/">this list of features</a> that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language. By Lukas Eder</p>

<p>Tags: list, lukas-eder, kotlin, java, comparison, language, jooq</p>

<h2>How we built Uber engineering&rsquo;s highest query per second service using Go</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://eng.uber.com/go-geofence/">this post</a> by Kai Wei on a microservice they&rsquo;ve built using Go.</p>

<p>Explains the reasons for choosing that algorithm for geofencing, the performance they&rsquo;re achieving, and the architecture.</p>

<p>Tags: uber, go, microservice, performance, geofence, geofencing, rps, go-memory-model, kai-wei</p>

<h2>Unwinding Uber&rsquo;s Most Efficient Service</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@buckhx/unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service-406413c5871d">this article</a> by Buck Heroux commenting on the decisions of Uber for building the geofencing microservice (above read).</p>

<p>Explains the different alternatives for algorithms in this problem space and has implemented them in go. Provides a benchmark for comparing those, including a profiling session.</p>

<p>Tags: s2, quadtree, rtree, brute-force, geofence, geofencing, uber, comment, buck-heroux, go, read-on-read, meta-read</p>

<h2>Lawful Hacking and Continuing Vulnerabilities</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/03/lawful_hacking_.html">this article</a> by Bruce Schneier on the stance the FBI is taking in regards to vulnerabilities discovered in Apple&rsquo;s devices.</p>

<p>Tags: bruce-schneier, apple, security, fbi, vulnerability, exploit, law, hacking</p>

<h2>A Side Project Helped Jumpstart My Career — Life Learning</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/life-learning/a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-7cd6f8e9b07f">this article</a> by Dave Gerhardt on how making a side project happen affected his life and his skills.</p>

<p>Some of the reasons for doing it include:</p>

<ul>
<li>It forces you to figure stuff out</li>
<li>The only way to learn is by doing</li>
<li>It gets your brain working on something other than your job</li>
<li>You have to create your own network</li>
<li>You are the CEO</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: long-life-learning, continuous-learning, side-project, dave-gerhardt, drift, professional-development, personal-development, business, career</p>

<h2>Fun Jekyll Tricks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.madebymarket.com/blog/dev/fun-jekyll-tricks.html">this article</a> by Brian Knapp where he explains some tips and tricks of jekyll (in which octopress is based on): speed, deployment, subcategories inside the blog, <em>data, </em>includes.</p>

<p>Tags: brian-knapp, jekyll, octopress, tip-and-trick, improvement, subcategory, meta, automation, deployment</p>

<h2>La ola que llega</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;id=f8a8ee92cc">this bonilista</a> by David Bonilla, where he explains (in Spanish) the &lsquo;contractor&rsquo; phenomenon arriving to Spain, 2-3 years after being in other countries and the effects that this could have both for workers and companies.</p>

<p>Tags: bonilista, david-bonilla, contractor</p>

<h2>10 razones por las que este sábado deberías ir a un code retreat</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://francho.org/2015/11/10/10-razones-para-ir-a-un-coderetreat/">this list</a> of reasons for attending a code retreat, by Francho Joven, who I met in the Global Day Of Code Retreat (GDCR) &lsquo;15 in Zaragoza</p>

<p>Tags: francho-joven, list, zaragoza, code-retreat, gdcr</p>

<h2>Meaningful Work through Passion, not Genius</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIYUMwxKFzo">this talk</a> on the importance of hard work and how it can be mistaken as genious. By Malcolm Gladwell</p>

<p>Tags: malcolm-gladwell, passion, genius, work, time-management, productivity, career, mastery-autonomy-purpose</p>

<h2>How to ask your wife for permission to spend $250,000 on a domain name</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@Stockphoto.com/how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name-c27a3c2852e1">this article</a> by Jon Yau on how they started StockPhoto.com, buying a $250,000 domain name.</p>

<p>Tags: startup, domain, stockphoto, jon-yau</p>

<h2>Sorry, developer bootcamps: I was wrong</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@dillonforrest/sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong-ea37fcc5572c">this article</a> by Dillon Forrest on the topic of developer bootcamps. Explains why developers should not be threatened by recent graduates of these programs and describes how people pursuing these programs usually are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Intelligence</li>
<li>Risk appetite</li>
<li>Resilience</li>
<li>Self-investment</li>
<li>Entrepreneurship</li>
<li>Growth trajectory</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: bootcamp, developer-bootcamp, dev-bootcamp, dillon-forrest, intelligence, risk-appetite, resilience, self-investment, entrepreneurship, growth-trajectory</p>

<h2>The JVM and Java Garbage Collection</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoJr5QQYsl8">this webcast</a> about how the JVM garbage collection works. By Michael W Williams</p>

<p>Tags: michael-williams, oracle, webcast, jvm, garbage-collection, gc,</p>

<h2>Files Are Hard</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://danluu.com/file-consistency/">this article</a> on why software that writes on files is difficult, based on the different filesystems that are below, and the operating system. Written by Dan Luu.</p>

<p>Uses software product to find bugs in filesystems</p>

<p>Tags: filesystem, file, dan-luu, analysis</p>

<h2>Contrata a un fracasado con ilusión inquebrantable</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.contunegocio.es/tecnologia/contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusion-inquebrantable/">this article</a> by Alberto Mena (in Spanish) on what are the qualities that define a good programmer:</p>

<ul>
<li>humility</li>
<li>failure</li>
<li>illusion</li>
<li>hard work</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: alberto-mena, spanish, team-management, success, developer, quality, developer-quality</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t react</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://journal.avdi.org/2016/04/14/dont-react/">this article</a> by Avdi Grimm on how the action vs reaction attitude. Why to prefer the former.</p>

<p>Tags: action, reaction, social-media, avdi-grimm, productivity</p>

<h2>FTP is so 90&rsquo;s. Let&rsquo;s deploy via Git instead!</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://coderwall.com/p/xczkaq/ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead">this guide</a> on how to deploy using git. By Kerrick Long</p>

<p>Tags: kerrick-long, git, deployment, webapp, application, devops</p>

<h2>Job vs Career: 10 Key Differences You Need To Understand</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.officevibe.com/blog/job-vs-career">the infographic and the article</a> by Jacob Shriar on what differentiates a job from a career</p>

<p>Tags: jacob-shriar, infographic, job-vs-career, comparison, job, career</p>

<h2>The Secret To Employee Motivation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.officevibe.com/blog/secret-employee-motivation-infographic">the infographic and the article</a> by Jacob Shriar on what motivates employess: mastery, autonomy and purpose. A direct reference to Dan Pink&rsquo;s &ldquo;The puzzle of motivation&rdquo; TED talk.</p>

<p>Tags: jacob-shriar, motivation, employee, infographic, mastery, autonomy, purpose</p>

<h2>The puzzle of motivation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation">this TED talk</a> by Dan Pink on what motivates us: intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation.</p>

<p>Also about the gap that exists between what science knows and what businesses propose.</p>

<p>Tags: ted, ted-talk, video, dan-pink, mastery, autonomy, purpose</p>

<h2>Applying a ceiling to the bug count</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://techblog.king.com/applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count/">this interview</a>, written by Susanna Berg, on how King has reduced the amount of bugs in their backlog using an agile technique, measuring and setting a limit.</p>

<p>Tags: susanna-berg, king, agile, bug, bug-count, defect, defect-count, per-malmen</p>

<h2>Coming up in 2016: Spring Framework 4.3 &amp; 5.0</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://spring.io/blog/2015/08/03/coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0">this announcement</a> of Spring&rsquo;s new release, 5.0, which will require java 8 and will turn most of the features into the reactive programming paradigm. By Juergen Hoeller.</p>

<p>Tags: juergen-hoeller, spring, reactive-programming, release, announcement</p>

<h2>Why offices are where work goes to die</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://swizec.com/blog/why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die/swizec/6695">this article</a> by Swizec Teller explaining the downsides of working in an office as compared to working remotely.</p>

<p>Tags: swizec-teller, remote, home-office, office, comparison, time-management</p>

<h2>The Myth of the Passionate Developer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@bm2yogi/the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer-76a41d457304">this article</a> by Michael Ibarra on what are the implications of being a passionate developer, how it affects your tasks and what are the factors to a job.</p>

<p>Tags: michael-ibarra, passion, development, job, motivation, myth</p>

<h2>Mossack Fonseca Breach – WordPress Revolution Slider Plugin Possible Cause</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2016/04/mossack-fonseca-breach-vulnerable-slider-revolution/">this article</a> by Mark Maunder, which describes an hypothesis on how the Mossack Fonseca breach could have happened. Also describes and shows how to breach a Wordpress installation with a vulnerable Revolution Slider plugin.</p>

<p>Tags: mark-maunder, security, breach, mossack-fonseca-breach, mossack-fonseca, hypothesis, attack, plugin, revolution-slider, wordpress</p>

<h2>Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator">this TED talk</a> from Tim Urban on how the procrastinator&rsquo;s mind works, exemplified by his own career.</p>

<p>Tags: procrastinator, procrastination, mind, time-management, tim-urban</p>

<h2>PEP 20 &ndash; The Zen of Python</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/">the PEP20</a>, the zen of python, with special attention to this:</p>

<blockquote><p>Explicit is better than implicit.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: pep-20, pep, python, zen</p>

<h2>Why I switched from Octopress 2 to Hugo</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/">this article</a> by Franklin Chen on the change he made on the static site generator (SSG) he used. He considered hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo. Was decided between hakyll and hugo for their speed but, finally, decided to use hugo for their bigger community.</p>

<p>Tags: franklin-chen, comparison, ssg, static-site-generator, hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo, change, speed, statically-typed, dynamically-typed, golang, performance</p>

<h2>Why incremental regeneration in Jekyll 3.0 is such a big deal</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/11/04/jekyll-30-released-incremental-regeneration-rocks/">this article</a> by Tom Johnson on one of the new features that jekyll 3.0 brings: incremental generation. How this can speed up the generation</p>

<p>Tags: tom-johnson, incremental-generation, speed, performance, octopress-2, octopress-3, jekyll-3</p>

<h2>Hugo, S3, Travis CI, oh boy!</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://continuousfailure.com/post/s3_blog/">this guide</a> by Alan Scherger on how to set up a specific stack for developing and deploying a static site blog.</p>

<p>Tags: alan-scherger, static-site-generator, ssg, travis, hugo, s3</p>

<h2>Deploy your blog to github pages automatically using Hugo and Travis</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://rcoedo.com/post/hugo-static-site-generator/">this article</a> by Roman Coedo on how to deploy a hugo blog to github pages, using travis.</p>

<p>Tags: roman-coedo, travis, hugo, github, github-pages, ssg, static-site-generator</p>

<h2>Improve Octopress with Advanced Tweaks &amp; Tips</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.narga.net/improve-octopress-advanced-tweaks-tips/">this list</a> of tips on how to improve the octopress (2) installation. By Nguyễn Đình Quân.</p>

<p>Tags: nguyen-dinh-quan, octopress-2, tip, tweak</p>

<h2>Laboratorios</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2014/11/12/laboratorios/">this article</a> by Ángel Medinilla, about laboratories to use a percentage of company time to investigate, innovate, learn and improve.</p>

<p>Tags: angel-medinilla, team-management, time-management, innovation, strategy, improvement, kaizen, laboratory, craftsmanship, spanish</p>

<h2>What Refactoring is, and what it isn’t</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://swreflections.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isnt.html">this article</a> by Jim Bird, where he splits some practices into refactoring and not refactoring. Draws the line between these two different activities.</p>

<p>Also cites scratch refactoring.</p>

<p>Tags: jim-bird, scratch-refactoring, refactoring, martin-fowler, kent-beck, definition, quote, design</p>

<h2>Pitfalls of Unlimited Vacations</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://haacked.com/archive/2016/02/18/unlimited-vaction-pitfalls/">this article</a> by Phil Haack on the github, travis and netflix policies about unlimited vacations and the effects they have on the employees.</p>

<p>Also about minimum vacation periods, (paternity) paid leave.</p>

<p>Tags: phil-haack, unlimited-vacation, holiday, vacation, team-management, burnout, github, travis, netflix, policy</p>

<h2>Cultura Corporativa</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2011/02/06/cultura-corporativa/">this article</a> by Ángel Medinilla about the corporate culture, and how &ldquo;hanging a highly interchangeable sentence on a wall&rdquo; does not represent it.</p>

<p>Tags: angel-medinilla, corporate culture, spanish</p>

<h2>What It’s Really Like to Learn to Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@sandjar/what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code-53f6d9156a32">this article</a> that explains firsthand how it is to learn programming for a novice student,even with a strong financial background and having completed a university degree. By Sandjar Kozubaev</p>

<p>Tags: sandjar-kozubaev, learning, programming, student, firsthand, coding, story</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in March 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-02T10:58:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@benedictfritz/learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard-40a4cf3104f4">this article</a> by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology</p>

<h2>BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing">this category of posts</a> by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</p>

<p>Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc</p>

<p>Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis</p>

<h2>BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing">this category of posts</a> by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</p>

<p>Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc</p>

<p>Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis</p>

<h2>Tracer Bullets</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TracerBullets">this page</a> about tracer bullets, an analogy from the military warfare to a software project.</p>

<p>Serves the purpose of adjusting the aim of the cannon to better reach the target.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, metaphor, warfare, management</p>

<h2>Cohesion - the cornerstone of software design</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://codurance.com/2016/03/03/cohesion-cornerstone-software-design/">this article</a> by Sandro Mancuso on the topic of cohesion. Describes the 7 types of cohesion, as described in Structured Design<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, from worst to best:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coincidental cohesion</li>
<li>Logical cohesion</li>
<li>Temporal cohesion</li>
<li>Procedural cohesion</li>
<li>Communicational/informational cohesion</li>
<li>Sequential cohesion</li>
<li>Functional cohesion</li>
</ul>


<p>and about Design-Level Cohesion:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coincidental relation (R1)</li>
<li>Conditional relation (R2)</li>
<li>Iterative relation (R3)</li>
<li>Communication relation (R4)</li>
<li>Sequential relation (R5)</li>
<li>Functional (R6)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: cohesion, codurance, edward-yourdon, larry-constantine, list, sandro-mancuso, software-design, design-level-cohesion, smc-cohesion, dlc-cohesion</p>

<h2>Etsy CTO Q&amp;A: We Need Software Engineers, Not Developers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thenewstack.io/etsy-cto-qa-need-software-engineers-not-developers/">this interview</a> with John Allspaw, where they explain the onboarding experience for new hires at Etsy, the DevOps philosophy and the need for engineering skills, more than developer skills. This can be exemplified in the need to know more, defining the boundaries of your job and finding the right tool for the job.</p>

<p>Tags: devops, interview, q-and-a, john-allspaw, etsy, onboarding, hire, team-management, deploy</p>

<h2>Frequency Reduces Difficulty</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/FrequencyReducesDifficulty.html">this article</a> by Martin Fowler on why we should repeat things that are difficult for us:</p>

<ul>
<li>Perfectioning the technique</li>
<li>Internalizing the details</li>
<li>Easing its automation</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: martin-fowler, automation, process, perfection, internalizing, technique, detail, process-theory, agile</p>

<h2>Lambdas are confusing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video where Coman Hamilton from JAXenter interviews Dr. Heinz Kabutz about Java&rsquo;s lambda syntax. Cites the problem with exceptions, generics, method overloading.</p>

<p>Tags: java, lambda, coman-hamilton, jaxenter, heinz-kabutz, problem</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;feature=youtu.be">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;feature=youtu.be</a></p>

<h2>El full-stack developer en 2016</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.developerdepueblo.com/development/full-stack-developer-2016/">this article</a> by Jose Ignacio Andrés about the job descriptions of 2016.</p>

<blockquote><p>El principal valor de un full-stack es poder simplificar el trabajo a los demás miembros del equipo.</p></blockquote>

<p>My translation:</p>

<blockquote><p>The main value of a full-stack developer is to be able to simplify other teammates' work</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: teamwork, teammate, fullstack, simplification, work, team-management, jose andres</p>

<h2>I am a software craftsman</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.dirv.me/i-am-a-software-craftsman/index.html">this article</a> by Daniel Irvine about calling yourself a craftsman or not. He says that if you adhere to their values, you should.</p>

<p>Tags: craftsmanship, label, daniel-irvine, craftsman, group-belonging</p>

<h2>Teaching Programming Languages in a Post-Linnaean Age</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Papers/Published/sk-teach-pl-post-linnaean/paper.pdf">this paper</a> by Shriram Krishnamurthi where he explains the need for books like <a href="http://www.plai.org/">PLAI</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>lack of paradigms in new languages, and its separation (or lack of)</li>
<li>design of languages cheaper and cheaper these days</li>
<li>rigor level in publications</li>
<li>inductive and deductive learning</li>
</ul>


<h2>Notes</h2>

<p><code>post-Linnaean</code> refers to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Linnaeus">Carl Linnaeus</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>He is known as the father of modern taxonomy</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: inductive-learning, deductive-learning, dsl, domain-specific-language, type-soundness, continuation-style, garbage-collection, reactive-programming, scheme, plai, teaching, programming-language, shriram-krishnamurthi</p>

<h2>Lazy Ruby</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://sonnym.github.io/2014/04/05/lazy-ruby/">this article</a> by sonnym about using ruby&rsquo;s lazy (non-strict) features, detailing an example with Fibonacci&rsquo;s sequence.</p>

<p>Tags: laziness, strictness, non-strictness, ruby, fibonacci, comparison</p>

<h2>Jessica Livingston</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://paulgraham.com/jessica.html">this essay</a> by Paul Graham about his co-founder at the Y-combinator: Jessica Livingston. She was considered the Social Radar at YC</p>

<p>The essay also talks about the non-existent separation between working hours and not and about her implication and personality.</p>

<p>Tags: jessica-livingston, paul-graham, y-combinator, feminism, yc, essay</p>

<h2>Four Laws Of Software Economics (Part 1)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@RichMironov/four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1-e162aa0ea9e5">this article</a> by Rich Mironov on why the development team will never be big enough (because of economics, because there are more things to be done than time to do them, so we have to prioritize them) and about the communication problems between the dev team and the client(s).</p>

<p>Also talks about the general personality of clients and devs and task prioritization</p>

<p>Tags: exclusive-or, magical-thinking, tnstaafl, management, agile, team, capacity, death-march, estj, intp, software-economics, product-strategy, law-of-ruthless-prioritization, law, rich-mironov, slack, myers-briggs-type</p>

<h2>You Should Take A Codecation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/you-should-take-a-codecation">this article</a> by Ben Orenstein explaining what is a codecation and what he&rsquo;s done in the two codecations he&rsquo;s taken.</p>

<p>Tags: codecation, ben-orenstein, vacation, holiday, coding, shipping, in-company</p>

<h2>Giving Up on TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://iansommerville.com/systems-software-and-technology/giving-up-on-test-first-development/">this article</a> by Ian Sommerville about the problems he&rsquo;s found while doing TDD, mainly about design, but also about being conservative in the amount of tests you allow yourself to break while refactoring.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, ian-sommerville, refactoring, problem, design-problem, design, giving-up-tdd</p>

<h2>Giving Up on TDD - answer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/03/19/GivingUpOnTDD.html">this article</a> by Robert C. Martin on the common issues for people adopting TDD:</p>

<ul>
<li>The Fragile Test Problem</li>
<li>The Design Problem</li>
<li>The Testable Design Problem</li>
<li>The Magic Bullet Problem</li>
</ul>


<p>This article is an answer to another by Ian Sommerville.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, uncle-bob, robert-martin, adoption, ian-sommerville, fragile-test-problem, giving-up-tdd, design-problem, testable-design-problem, magic-bullet-problem</p>

<h2>Seek out jobs with fast learning cycles</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@sarahtavel/seek-out-jobs-with-fast-learning-cycles-f923c8d8a4be#.7bxx65a4x">this article</a> by Sarah Tavel on learning on the job and how fast these learning cycles can happen at companies at different stages of maturity.</p>

<blockquote><p>So if you’re thinking of changing jobs, or taking your first, my advice: find a place with a fast learning cycle, and a steep learning curve.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: learning, job, hypothesis, sarah-tavel, learning-cycle, maturity-level, learning-process, product-management</p>

<h2>Clean Code Vs. Implementation Patterns</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.xebia.com/clean-code-vs-implementation-patterns/">this comparison</a> of Clean Code vs Implementation Pattern books, by Vincent Partington.</p>

<p>In it, the author explains the differences in style in both books, and how they compare to others.</p>

<p>Tags: clean-code, implementation-patterns, comparison, book-review, book-comparison, vincent-partington</p>

<h2>Stuck in Traffic vlog #103 - New Spammer Techniques</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.peerlyst.com/posts/stuck-in-traffic-vlog-103-new-spammer-techniques-j-wolfgang-goerlich">this vlog entry</a> on machines fighting machines (exemplified with the spam producing and filtering) and how some spammers are trying more direct techniques focusing on higher-value targets, sometimes even handcrafting messages and modifying them every few units.</p>

<p>Tags: wolfgang-goerlich, spam, vlog, spammer, machine-learning</p>

<h2>Becoming A Finisher</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://christopherdbui.com/becoming-a-finisher/">this article</a> by Christopher Bui where he explains that projects that are too ambitious stall your productivity and make you lose your focus.</p>

<p>Tags: christopher-bui, pomodoro, time-management, productivity, motivation, ambition, paul-graham, quote</p>

<h2>Hanging around with red-black tree implementations: the beginnings</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.fraixed.es/post/hanging-around-red-black-trees-implementations/">this article</a> by Ivan Fraixedes where he details the progress of implementing a red-black tree, and also his motivation for doing it.</p>

<p>Tags: ivan-fraixedes, red-black-tree, abstract-data-structure, adt, deliberate-practice, pet-project</p>

<h2>Some Tools for Faster Blogging in Octopress</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://dgmstuart.github.io/blog/2015/03/27/some-tools-for-faster-blogging-in-octopress/">this article</a> for tips and tricks on how to blog faster with octopress. Written by Duncan Stuart.</p>

<p>Tags: duncan-stuart, blog, improvement, meta, octopress, tip-and-trick</p>

<h2>The veil of ignorance</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mrmrs.io/writing/2016/03/23/the-veil-of-ignorance/">this article</a> by Adam Morse on how not being on the top of the skills performance can affect your design and your user experience. Also, references the concept of &ldquo;The Veil of Ignorance&rdquo;, a concept by John Rawls.</p>

<p>Tags: john-rawls, veil-of-ignorance, user-experience, design</p>

<h2>To Smile Again &ndash; Recovering from the paralysis of burnout</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://m.signalvnoise.com/to-smile-again-ae0ba9f2198c">this article</a> by Jamis Buck on his story of burnout, what symptoms had on him and how he got out of it.</p>

<p>Tags: burnout, jamis-buck, psychology, productivity, personal, story, analogy</p>

<h2>Beyond email: could startup Slack change the way you work?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/mar/25/slack-butterfield-emoji-chat-nasa-harvard-silicon-valley">this article</a> on Slack&rsquo;s office culture, with their diversity, policies and values after a high people growth in a short period of time. By Jemima Kiss</p>

<p>Tags: culture, office-culture, slack, jemima-kiss</p>

<h2>Slack: Work This Way</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@iaintait/slack-work-this-way-9221284472dd">this article</a>, a response to my above read, about the office culture at Slack.</p>

<p>Tags: iain-tait, response, slack, office-culture</p>

<h2>BEM 101</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://css-tricks.com/bem-101/">this introduction</a> to a CSS style called Block, Element, Modifier methodology (BEM).</p>

<p>In it,</p>

<blockquote><ul>
<li>a block is a top-level abstraction of a new component</li>
<li>Child items, or elements, can be placed inside and these are denoted by two underscores following the name of the block [&hellip;].
modifiers can manipulate the block so that we can theme or style that particular component without inflicting changes on a completely unrelated module. This is done by appending two hyphens to the name of the block [&hellip;].</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>By Joe Richardson, Robin Rendle et al.</p>

<p>Tags: joe-richardson, robin-rendle, bem, css, css-methodology, introduction, css-architecture, sass</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Structured Design: Fundamentals of a Discipline of Computer Program and Systems Design by Yourdon and Constantine.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
