<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tool on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/tool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tool on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 18:04:28 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building private tools in the open</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2024/08/31/building-private-tools-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 18:04:28 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2024/08/31/building-private-tools-open/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It is very common to develop private tools in private: private git repositories, private servers, private data, private everything.
But what if you want to obtain the benefits of developing in the open while keeping your privacy?
Context and Applicability We have been developing tools like this. It works well, you just have to be careful on what gets committed where.
Alternatives:
 Keep all development hidden (e.g., private repositories, private cloud) Hide the data using git-crypt in the public version Merge the public and private versions into one using submodules  How to Split the tool in two parts: the public part and the private part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</guid>
      <description>Managing projects with GNU Make, Third Edition book about GNU Make, with recipes and going into detail about how to use it
Tags: book, make, gnu-make, project, skeleton, ci, continuous-integration
Id: 028b0e1f-a181-4469-8789-900ce6641d97 Read: Sun, 01 Jul 2024 17:22:52 +0000
Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs a tool to diff pdfs visually
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319
Tags: hackernews, imported, olshansky, testing, test, diff-pdf, pdf, diff, git, e2e-testing, end-to-end-testing, tool
Id: 4fc53bae-d81c-45b4-9f6b-995ec5d4df6a Read: Tue, 02 Jul 2024 07:26:08 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Build a Compiler, by Jack Crenshaw Crenshaw&amp;rsquo;s tutorial on building a compiler
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36054416
Tags: hackernews, imported, synack, compiler, crenshaw, brian-kernighan, rob-pike, programming, programming-language
Id: 3b2e9382-1144-4cfe-bdaf-72b30e8c3712 Read: Sat, 1 Jun 2024 09:14:25 +0000
Scientific glassblower continues century-old campus tradition (2021) the story of a glassblower dedicated to producing specialized hardware for a university
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40549209
Tags: hackernews, imported, dredmorbius, glassblower, university, hardware, profession, glass
Id: e07b0ed2-185b-4cf7-bdbe-a134c555d797 Read: Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:26:29 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2023</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/02/01/self-study-february-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/02/01/self-study-february-2023/</guid>
      <description>CBMC: The C Bounded Model Checker CBMC on GitHub: https://github.com/diffblue/cbmc Some usage examples: https://haslab.github.io/MFES/2122/CBMCexamples-handout.pdf
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34703004
Tags: cbmc, c, c-language, bound-check, sat-solver, tool, static-analysis, checker, imported, hacker-news
Id: bbe38520-a846-11ed-957a-0242ac110002 Read: Wed Feb 8 01:46:40 2023
TESTING BAREMETAL FIRMWARE AT NUBIX Extensive guide on how to test firmware. Lots of tools, good recommendations
Tags: bare-metal, firmware, testing, nubix, reini-urban, tool, crashdump, testing-pyramid, addresssanitizer, valgrind, memcheck, dr-memory, gperftools, cbmc, clang, c-language, c, heap, stack, fuzzing, afl, llvm, asan, ubsan, memory-sanitizer, memsan, san</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2023</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/01/01/self-study-january-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/01/01/self-study-january-2023/</guid>
      <description>Show HN: I built Haystack – your own google for scattered workplace knowledge https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34218724
Tags: tool, index, note, knowledge-base, haystack, privacy, neural-network, imported, hacker-news
Id: 0fb5be84-8b37-11ed-b09f-0242ac110003 Read: Mon Jan 2 15:14:13 2023
Extending Python with Rust Tags: binding, rust, ffi, foreign-function-interface, tool, rumpy, tool
Id: 232ad576-8b37-11ed-bc27-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:20:44 +0000
Why CVE-2022-3602 was not detected by fuzz testing So recently a very hyped memory corruption security vulnerability was discovered in the OpenSSL punycode parser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/12/01/self-study-december-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/12/01/self-study-december-2022/</guid>
      <description>CCache: a fast c/c++ compiler cache Related to 027d6f8a-714e-11ed-869a-0242ac110003
Tags: tool, cache, compilation-cache, optimization, speedup, c, cpp, c++, gcc, clang
Id: f2423a38-714d-11ed-92b4-0242ac110003 Read: Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:58:30 +0000
CATS: OpenAPI fuzzing and test generation tool Tags: cats, tool, openapi, fuzz-testing, test-tool, java, endava, eoin-woods
Id: 08b0cdb0-714f-11ed-a45c-0242ac110003 Read: Thu, 01 Dec 2022 08:06:18 +0000
I&amp;rsquo;ve fuzzed a small part of the GitHub API. Here are my findings. Using CATS to fuzz part of the Github API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/11/01/self-study-november-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/11/01/self-study-november-2022/</guid>
      <description>Doing what you love when the money won’t follow https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33434326
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 509ce49c-c1a4-11ed-afdd-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Nov 2 12:01:16 2022
Ask HN: How to deal with burnout and its consequences? https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33434742
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 52f6012e-c1a4-11ed-b778-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Nov 2 12:38:33 2022
Embedded programming is like web development https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33450575
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 59ea8176-c1a4-11ed-9922-0242ac110004 Read: Thu Nov 3 13:24:05 2022
Ask HN: How to regain focus when you feel overwhelmed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/10/01/self-study-october-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/10/01/self-study-october-2022/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Logging https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33054741
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 02a22390-c1a1-11ed-b61a-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Oct 2 10:42:15 2022
“Rust is safe” is not some kind of absolute guarantee of code safety https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33056077
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 12483f20-c1a4-11ed-84be-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Oct 2 14:20:21 2022
Have lots of AWS accounts Using the physical separation of your AWS accounts as a way to isolate the data and services
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33069547
Tags: aws, aws-account, physical-isolation, isolation, data-isolation, risk-management, imported, hacker-news</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/07/01/self-study-july-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/07/01/self-study-july-2022/</guid>
      <description>Zetk: CLI utilities, fzf-based scripts, C++ lib for managing your Zettelkasten Zettelkasten notes implemented as a library with a set of CLI utils
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31969931
Tags: zettelkasten, software, personal-knowledge, application, tool, cli, fzf, search, wiki, imported, hacker-news
Id: 5017abd4-fb79-11ec-ad8c-0242ac110003 Read: Sun Jul 3 18:38:57 2022
Show HN: C3 – A C alternative that looks like C https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32005678
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: d665c1c0-c1a4-11ed-a153-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Jul 6 19:31:01 2022
Formally Verifying Industry Cryptography https://news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2021</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Perfect Media Server Hacker News discussion on a media server, half open source (?).
Tags: hacker-news, media-server, perfect, tool, software
Id: c37b0f2a-4dc5-11eb-8048-0242ac110002 Read: Sun, 03 Jan 2021 13:15:34 +0000
How your startup can survive technical debt Mentions the paradox of success: you need debt to start quickly, yet too quickly leaves no time to pay debt. Hence your prototype turns into an MVP, and that is your first piecce of technical debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On private but leaked information in a SaaS</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: how to uncorrelate public and private information.
Context Context: there are clients who have sensitive information. Some is just &amp;lsquo;companies being stealth&amp;rsquo; (e.g., don&amp;rsquo;t want to make public until launching), some is just protected by a Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA), some are protected by security clearance. The more sensitive, the greater protection needed. This tool applies to all sensitive information, regardless of where it&amp;rsquo;s stored or how it is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/01/self-study-september-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/01/self-study-september-2019/</guid>
      <description>Profiling Memory Allocations In iOS With Instruments Describes a technique for profiling memory allocations
Tags: memory-management, memory-allocation, tool, technique, ios, matt-eaton
Id: 237dd71a-dc50-11e9-b201-0242ac110003 Read: Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:13:56 +0000
Programming as translation  Converting the real world into digital abstractions requires distillation. And, like literary translators, developers must understand their biases.
 Tags: alvaro-videla, old_sound, analogy, metaphor, quote, umberto-eco
Id: a2c0f458-dc50-11e9-95d7-0242ac110003 Read: Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:17:29 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>How I use reveal.js This author explains how they use reveal.js.
The online editor (slides.com).
The author uses plain html for storing the slides.
Tags: slide, slideshare, reveal-js, reveal, presentation, slide-deck, michael-mccune
Id: 41e287b4-ae15-11e9-9e8a-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 07:16:33 +0000
All your digital life on a single timeline, stored locally Keep your digital life under your control
Tags: backup, local-data, encryption, control
Id: 4d115f64-ae17-11e9-bf0e-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:31:11 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Tooling</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/30/defense-tooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/30/defense-tooling/</guid>
      <description>A quote (on a curriculum vitae) that I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed:
 I am a firm believer in the value of tools, and often spend significant time at the beginning of a project developing tools specific to the needs of the project. This always pays off in the long run. I use tools to:
 Perform tasks not otherwise achievable Automate tedious/repetitive processes Simplify steps in the build/debug cycle Eliminate &amp;ldquo;human error&amp;rdquo; in scanning, translation etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically keeping the intermediate history of your work using git</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: using git to automatically document your development process (special cases only.)
Context When I&amp;rsquo;m spiking a feature, I usually get in the zone (e.g., Csikszentmihalyi&amp;rsquo;s Flow), and I can forget my good engineering practices, searching for that desired answer. After a few of those bouts of coding, you realize you&amp;rsquo;re wandering. You circle around, get lost, get back on track, then get lost again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters  In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding all pending work in progress (WIP) in your workspace</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/find-all-pending-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 06:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/find-all-pending-work/</guid>
      <description>It is a good practice to push your local work at the end of the day. Be it for increasing the bus factor (more people have the code), be it for reducing the lifespan of the branches (less time without integrating) or just enabling visibility (your teammates to see what has been developed). If you&amp;rsquo;re using Continuous Integration (CI) or Continuous Delivery (CD), this is even more often
You can even do it more often: for example before going to lunch, before a meeting, before a demo, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying titles in a Trello Board</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/modifying-titles-in-a-trello-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/modifying-titles-in-a-trello-board/</guid>
      <description>A teammate and I have created a small tool to modify the titles of the trello card in a trello board.
Technical description It works by applying a function to the existing title (because we wanted to remove a prefix from the existing title).
The modification is done, not through the API, but simulating user interaction:
 Click to edit the card Input the new title Save  The full code is available here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert a project from npm to yarn</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/03/convert-a-project-from-npm-to-yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 11:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/03/convert-a-project-from-npm-to-yarn/</guid>
      <description>At a client, we&amp;rsquo;re converting all projects (i.e., sites, services, libraries) from npm to yarn. Mostly for the speed (as it uses the internal cache).
Step by step guide  Install yarn in your local environment * https://yarnpkg.com/lang/en/docs/install/ Run yarn install * This will create a yarn.lock file * Add that file to the repo: git add yarn.lock Modify Dockerfile * Install yarn (in the Dockerfile). Idea: shortcut this execution with yarn --version in case it is installed * Configure the PATH variable (ENV PATH &amp;hellip;) * ADD yarn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>Advice for white men I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cate Huston about how advice affects different people.
 But here are some things to consider:
 Advice on failure is different for people who are judged on performance rather than potential. Advice on saying no is different for people who aren’t appreciated for doing work for the collective… but who are punished if they don’t. Advice on negotiation is different for people who are perceived negatively when they do negotiate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool: Building a local pipeline</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Motivation At a client, one of the projects has a long building process and the tests are mostly slow, so I use a local building pipeline, an example of the Pipes and Filters pattern.
This allows for executing manually only the fast unit tests, then automatically (no user intervention, no time spent) executing the rest of them before pushing. In case the latter fails, it is possible to do git push -f to the pipeline without corrupting the central repository (origin) history, possibly disturbing others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool to Find Duplicate values in Constants</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/tool-to-find-duplicate-values-in-constants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 13:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/tool-to-find-duplicate-values-in-constants/</guid>
      <description>Imagine having this java class:
private static class RepeatedConstants { public static final String A = &amp;#34;A&amp;#34;; public static final String A_1 = A; public static final String A_2 = &amp;#34;A&amp;#34;; public static final Integer _3 = 3; public static final Integer THREE = 3; } I wanted to remove the repeated values in the constants, in an automatic way, because the file was big (&amp;gt; 4000 constants). A way of doing this is basing the differences on the values, directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session: docker</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/16/brown-bag-session-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 18:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/16/brown-bag-session-docker/</guid>
      <description>Today we have done a brown bag session about Docker. One of the team members explained to us the latest news, topics and how tos, including:
 the difference between a container and an image diffing image contents AUFS (Another Union FS) persistent vs non-persistent (volatile) filesystems running CMD and other commands on the instance problems of running with permission = root (or its group) downsides of it how to compare it with a virtual machine  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session: maven</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/06/brown-bag-session-maven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 22:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/06/brown-bag-session-maven/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we did a training about the maven tool. One of the team members explained to us some topics including:
 lifecycles profiles and how to create one  slowTests for integration tests (this client only) downloadJavadoc downloadSources   convention over configuration scopes of the dependencies (test, runtime, compile, provided) tricks about the tool:  order of the dependencies (especially junit, hamcrest)   plugins and how to build one destination folders  target, classes, test-classes, etc    Note: this post was created a posteriori, with the original date</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
