<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cas2k14 | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/cas2k14/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-08T23:26:33+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should We Start the TDD Cycle on Refactor?]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/should-we-start-the-tdd-cycle-on-refactor/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-29T20:30:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/should-we-start-the-tdd-cycle-on-refactor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this lexical scope, TDD by example is referring to this book<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, available <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">on Amazon</a></p>

<h3>The TDD cycle</h3>

<p>Altough <a href="https://twitter.com/KentBeck">Kent Beck</a> in his book Test-Driven Development by example explains in &ldquo;Part I: the money example&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> that one should</p>

<blockquote><p>quickly add a test;</p>

<p>run all the tests and see the new one fail [&hellip;]</p>

<p><cite>Kent Beck </cite></p></blockquote>

<p>Implying that the TDD cycle starts with the red. Later on he explains that the cycle continues with green and refactor and back to red.</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;ve been hearing for a while that there&rsquo;re some useful refactors to be done before introducing new code. Rings in my head but the only example I have is Xavi Gost&rsquo;s &ldquo;La economía del refactoring<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the definition of refactor (found <a href="http://www.refactoring.com/">here</a>):</p>

<blockquote><p>[Refactoring] is a disciplined technique for restructuring an existing body of code, altering its internal structure without changing its external behavior.</p>

<p> <cite>Martin Fowler</cite></p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;ve found some info on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1355101/test-code-refactor-when-should-we-start-a-refactoring">stackoverflow</a> about the subject. The currently <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1355782">accepted answer</a> points out some interesting comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do not refactor on red. Always a good reminder</li>
<li>If you are refactoring for introducing a feature, how much refactor is enough? This is speculative development, possibly taking much time from needed development</li>
</ul>


<p>The last point is the one that interests me the most:</p>

<ul>
<li>Your refactoring might not be where you&rsquo;re going to introduce new production code<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> (spatial caché)</li>
<li>You might end up introducing features after a few hours/days of refactoring, therefore losing focus on the refactor you did and why (local caché)</li>
<li>Given that I&rsquo;ve already &ldquo;cleaned up&rdquo; this, I could also go somewhere else (slippery slope). Heard from <a href="https://twitter.com/xav1uzz">Xavi Gost</a> at the CAS2014 at his talk <a href="http://cas2014.agile-spain.org/sessions/sesion-1h-la-economia-del-refactoring-una-vision-desde-la-gestion-economica-del-proyecto-xavier-gost/">La economía del refactoring</a></li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>No está justificado hacer cambios fuera de la rebanada.</p></blockquote>

<p>Roughly translated to &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not justified to change outside the bread slice&rdquo;, as Xavi was referring to software as sliced bread instead of layers, vertical rather than horizontal</p>

<h3>Should you do it?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Doing it would be a good thing, as long as you know in advance what will be affected by the next feature.</li>
<li>It can allow for less refactoring at the end of the cycle. This is not about duplication but refactoring to patterns. There might be a gain in refactoring to a pattern before introducing another feature. An example might be adding a new strategy when it&rsquo;s currently coded as if-then-else</li>
<li>The last responsible moment might be before or after introducing the feature. You decide.</li>
<li>Work less as there&rsquo;s no need for adding new cases to old structures and then simplifying</li>
</ul>


<h3>Should you not do it?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Foreseeing the future is difficult, therefore you might end with unused development, as it is speculating</li>
<li>Related to the last point, you might end refactoring in the wrong places. There&rsquo;s no current business value to it.</li>
<li>Not useful on first round of a new feature, you can use a lambda transition to the red again. But then, this is not a general pattern, only applicable to a big percent of cases.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>Short answer: it mainly depends on your environment:</p>

<ul>
<li>You: experience, common sense (sadly) &mdash;another post coming&mdash;, benefit/time-wasted ratio</li>
<li>Your project: how tight are deadlines, how critical that code is, the team&rsquo;s pressure</li>
</ul>


<p>Long answer: Yes, as long as:
 1. You realize there is a fine line between fixing code and rewriting code (Egoless programming #4). Don&rsquo;t be a lone enforcer
 2. Strictly follow the boy scout rule but only around your campfire, not outside of it.
 1. You know your domain, pitfalls and team well
 1. You want to test this hypothesis and post an answer</p>

<h3>Sources</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://cas2014.agile-spain.org/sessions/sesion-1h-la-economia-del-refactoring-una-vision-desde-la-gestion-economica-del-proyecto-xavier-gost/">La economía del refactoring</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/xav1uzz">Xavi Gost</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">Test-Driven Development by example</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/KentBeck">Kent Beck</a></li>
<li><a href="http://refactoring.com">Refactoring.com</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/martinfowler">Martin Fowler</a></li>
</ul>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Test-Driven Development by example; Beck, K. (ISBN-13: 078-5342146530)<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>from the book, description of part I, before chapter I<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>That talk is not yet available (AFAIK), but there&rsquo;s a <a href="http://ocana.github.io/articles/Conferencia-Agile-Spain-2014-primer-dia/">post</a> about it (Spanish)<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>The &ldquo;pains&rdquo; you might feel before introducing new features might not be real<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CAS2014 Wrap Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/cas2014-wrap-up/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T19:18:28+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/cas2014-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year&rsquo;s edition of the CAS 2014 has been awesome. There were several tracks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Enterprise Agile</li>
<li>Collaboration, Culture and Teams</li>
<li>Delighting Products</li>
<li>Agile+</li>
<li>Development Practices and Craftsmanship</li>
</ul>


<p>The last one is where I spent most of the time.</p>

<h2>The schedule</h2>

<p> The first day:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a>: talking about Software Craftsmanship</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/fiunchinho">Jose Manuel Armesto</a>: talking about Unit Testing sucks (and it&rsquo;s our fault)</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/rmarpozo">Rubén Martín Pozo</a>: talking about Specification by example - Historia de un equipo que no odia documentar</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/XaV1uzz">Xavi Gost</a>: talking about La economía del refactoring. Una visión desde la gestión económica del proyecto.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/_pedro_torres">Pedro Gustavo Torres</a>: talking about Pair Programming</li>
</ul>


<p> The second day:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/rafadc">Rafael de Castro</a>: talking about Generando tests</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/borillo">Ricardo Borillo</a>: talking about CQRS y los beneficios surgidos de la necesidad.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/cupcicm">Manu Cupcic</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/eidrien">Adrian Perreau de Pinninck</a>: talking about Delivery at Scale.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/jgabardini">Juan Gabardini</a>: talking about Testing en equipos infectados de test. This talk was also prepared by Juan Diego Vasco Moncada but he couldn&rsquo;t come.</li>
</ul>


<h2> Some thoughts</h2>

<p> The conferences were awesome, but I&rsquo;d preferred if most (if not all) were in English so this conference can attract more international speakers</p>

<p> There were 600+ people in the <a href="http://www.cccb.org/">CCCB</a>. That was only possible due to all the volunteers, organizers, caterers and the assistants.</p>

<h2> More info</h2>

<p> You can find more information on the <a href="http://cas2014.agile-spain.org/">official website</a> and on twitter using the hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23cas2k14&amp;src=tyah">#cas2014</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
