<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Craftsman | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/craftsman/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-31T18:11:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in March 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-02T10:58:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@benedictfritz/learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard-40a4cf3104f4">this article</a> by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology</p>

<h2>BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing">this category of posts</a> by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</p>

<p>Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc</p>

<p>Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis</p>

<h2>BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing">this category of posts</a> by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</p>

<p>Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc</p>

<p>Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis</p>

<h2>Tracer Bullets</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TracerBullets">this page</a> about tracer bullets, an analogy from the military warfare to a software project.</p>

<p>Serves the purpose of adjusting the aim of the cannon to better reach the target.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, metaphor, warfare, management</p>

<h2>Cohesion - the cornerstone of software design</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://codurance.com/2016/03/03/cohesion-cornerstone-software-design/">this article</a> by Sandro Mancuso on the topic of cohesion. Describes the 7 types of cohesion, as described in Structured Design<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, from worst to best:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coincidental cohesion</li>
<li>Logical cohesion</li>
<li>Temporal cohesion</li>
<li>Procedural cohesion</li>
<li>Communicational/informational cohesion</li>
<li>Sequential cohesion</li>
<li>Functional cohesion</li>
</ul>


<p>and about Design-Level Cohesion:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coincidental relation (R1)</li>
<li>Conditional relation (R2)</li>
<li>Iterative relation (R3)</li>
<li>Communication relation (R4)</li>
<li>Sequential relation (R5)</li>
<li>Functional (R6)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: cohesion, codurance, edward-yourdon, larry-constantine, list, sandro-mancuso, software-design, design-level-cohesion, smc-cohesion, dlc-cohesion</p>

<h2>Etsy CTO Q&amp;A: We Need Software Engineers, Not Developers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thenewstack.io/etsy-cto-qa-need-software-engineers-not-developers/">this interview</a> with John Allspaw, where they explain the onboarding experience for new hires at Etsy, the DevOps philosophy and the need for engineering skills, more than developer skills. This can be exemplified in the need to know more, defining the boundaries of your job and finding the right tool for the job.</p>

<p>Tags: devops, interview, q-and-a, john-allspaw, etsy, onboarding, hire, team-management, deploy</p>

<h2>Frequency Reduces Difficulty</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/FrequencyReducesDifficulty.html">this article</a> by Martin Fowler on why we should repeat things that are difficult for us:</p>

<ul>
<li>Perfectioning the technique</li>
<li>Internalizing the details</li>
<li>Easing its automation</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: martin-fowler, automation, process, perfection, internalizing, technique, detail, process-theory, agile</p>

<h2>Lambdas are confusing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video where Coman Hamilton from JAXenter interviews Dr. Heinz Kabutz about Java&rsquo;s lambda syntax. Cites the problem with exceptions, generics, method overloading.</p>

<p>Tags: java, lambda, coman-hamilton, jaxenter, heinz-kabutz, problem</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;feature=youtu.be">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;feature=youtu.be</a></p>

<h2>El full-stack developer en 2016</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.developerdepueblo.com/development/full-stack-developer-2016/">this article</a> by Jose Ignacio Andrés about the job descriptions of 2016.</p>

<blockquote><p>El principal valor de un full-stack es poder simplificar el trabajo a los demás miembros del equipo.</p></blockquote>

<p>My translation:</p>

<blockquote><p>The main value of a full-stack developer is to be able to simplify other teammates' work</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: teamwork, teammate, fullstack, simplification, work, team-management, jose andres</p>

<h2>I am a software craftsman</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.dirv.me/i-am-a-software-craftsman/index.html">this article</a> by Daniel Irvine about calling yourself a craftsman or not. He says that if you adhere to their values, you should.</p>

<p>Tags: craftsmanship, label, daniel-irvine, craftsman, group-belonging</p>

<h2>Teaching Programming Languages in a Post-Linnaean Age</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Papers/Published/sk-teach-pl-post-linnaean/paper.pdf">this paper</a> by Shriram Krishnamurthi where he explains the need for books like <a href="http://www.plai.org/">PLAI</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>lack of paradigms in new languages, and its separation (or lack of)</li>
<li>design of languages cheaper and cheaper these days</li>
<li>rigor level in publications</li>
<li>inductive and deductive learning</li>
</ul>


<h2>Notes</h2>

<p><code>post-Linnaean</code> refers to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Linnaeus">Carl Linnaeus</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>He is known as the father of modern taxonomy</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: inductive-learning, deductive-learning, dsl, domain-specific-language, type-soundness, continuation-style, garbage-collection, reactive-programming, scheme, plai, teaching, programming-language, shriram-krishnamurthi</p>

<h2>Lazy Ruby</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://sonnym.github.io/2014/04/05/lazy-ruby/">this article</a> by sonnym about using ruby&rsquo;s lazy (non-strict) features, detailing an example with Fibonacci&rsquo;s sequence.</p>

<p>Tags: laziness, strictness, non-strictness, ruby, fibonacci, comparison</p>

<h2>Jessica Livingston</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://paulgraham.com/jessica.html">this essay</a> by Paul Graham about his co-founder at the Y-combinator: Jessica Livingston. She was considered the Social Radar at YC</p>

<p>The essay also talks about the non-existent separation between working hours and not and about her implication and personality.</p>

<p>Tags: jessica-livingston, paul-graham, y-combinator, feminism, yc, essay</p>

<h2>Four Laws Of Software Economics (Part 1)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@RichMironov/four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1-e162aa0ea9e5">this article</a> by Rich Mironov on why the development team will never be big enough (because of economics, because there are more things to be done than time to do them, so we have to prioritize them) and about the communication problems between the dev team and the client(s).</p>

<p>Also talks about the general personality of clients and devs and task prioritization</p>

<p>Tags: exclusive-or, magical-thinking, tnstaafl, management, agile, team, capacity, death-march, estj, intp, software-economics, product-strategy, law-of-ruthless-prioritization, law, rich-mironov, slack, myers-briggs-type</p>

<h2>You Should Take A Codecation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/you-should-take-a-codecation">this article</a> by Ben Orenstein explaining what is a codecation and what he&rsquo;s done in the two codecations he&rsquo;s taken.</p>

<p>Tags: codecation, ben-orenstein, vacation, holiday, coding, shipping, in-company</p>

<h2>Giving Up on TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://iansommerville.com/systems-software-and-technology/giving-up-on-test-first-development/">this article</a> by Ian Sommerville about the problems he&rsquo;s found while doing TDD, mainly about design, but also about being conservative in the amount of tests you allow yourself to break while refactoring.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, ian-sommerville, refactoring, problem, design-problem, design, giving-up-tdd</p>

<h2>Giving Up on TDD - answer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/03/19/GivingUpOnTDD.html">this article</a> by Robert C. Martin on the common issues for people adopting TDD:</p>

<ul>
<li>The Fragile Test Problem</li>
<li>The Design Problem</li>
<li>The Testable Design Problem</li>
<li>The Magic Bullet Problem</li>
</ul>


<p>This article is an answer to another by Ian Sommerville.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, uncle-bob, robert-martin, adoption, ian-sommerville, fragile-test-problem, giving-up-tdd, design-problem, testable-design-problem, magic-bullet-problem</p>

<h2>Seek out jobs with fast learning cycles</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@sarahtavel/seek-out-jobs-with-fast-learning-cycles-f923c8d8a4be#.7bxx65a4x">this article</a> by Sarah Tavel on learning on the job and how fast these learning cycles can happen at companies at different stages of maturity.</p>

<blockquote><p>So if you’re thinking of changing jobs, or taking your first, my advice: find a place with a fast learning cycle, and a steep learning curve.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: learning, job, hypothesis, sarah-tavel, learning-cycle, maturity-level, learning-process, product-management</p>

<h2>Clean Code Vs. Implementation Patterns</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.xebia.com/clean-code-vs-implementation-patterns/">this comparison</a> of Clean Code vs Implementation Pattern books, by Vincent Partington.</p>

<p>In it, the author explains the differences in style in both books, and how they compare to others.</p>

<p>Tags: clean-code, implementation-patterns, comparison, book-review, book-comparison, vincent-partington</p>

<h2>Stuck in Traffic vlog #103 - New Spammer Techniques</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.peerlyst.com/posts/stuck-in-traffic-vlog-103-new-spammer-techniques-j-wolfgang-goerlich">this vlog entry</a> on machines fighting machines (exemplified with the spam producing and filtering) and how some spammers are trying more direct techniques focusing on higher-value targets, sometimes even handcrafting messages and modifying them every few units.</p>

<p>Tags: wolfgang-goerlich, spam, vlog, spammer, machine-learning</p>

<h2>Becoming A Finisher</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://christopherdbui.com/becoming-a-finisher/">this article</a> by Christopher Bui where he explains that projects that are too ambitious stall your productivity and make you lose your focus.</p>

<p>Tags: christopher-bui, pomodoro, time-management, productivity, motivation, ambition, paul-graham, quote</p>

<h2>Hanging around with red-black tree implementations: the beginnings</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.fraixed.es/post/hanging-around-red-black-trees-implementations/">this article</a> by Ivan Fraixedes where he details the progress of implementing a red-black tree, and also his motivation for doing it.</p>

<p>Tags: ivan-fraixedes, red-black-tree, abstract-data-structure, adt, deliberate-practice, pet-project</p>

<h2>Some Tools for Faster Blogging in Octopress</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://dgmstuart.github.io/blog/2015/03/27/some-tools-for-faster-blogging-in-octopress/">this article</a> for tips and tricks on how to blog faster with octopress. Written by Duncan Stuart.</p>

<p>Tags: duncan-stuart, blog, improvement, meta, octopress, tip-and-trick</p>

<h2>The veil of ignorance</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mrmrs.io/writing/2016/03/23/the-veil-of-ignorance/">this article</a> by Adam Morse on how not being on the top of the skills performance can affect your design and your user experience. Also, references the concept of &ldquo;The Veil of Ignorance&rdquo;, a concept by John Rawls.</p>

<p>Tags: john-rawls, veil-of-ignorance, user-experience, design</p>

<h2>To Smile Again &ndash; Recovering from the paralysis of burnout</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://m.signalvnoise.com/to-smile-again-ae0ba9f2198c">this article</a> by Jamis Buck on his story of burnout, what symptoms had on him and how he got out of it.</p>

<p>Tags: burnout, jamis-buck, psychology, productivity, personal, story, analogy</p>

<h2>Beyond email: could startup Slack change the way you work?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/mar/25/slack-butterfield-emoji-chat-nasa-harvard-silicon-valley">this article</a> on Slack&rsquo;s office culture, with their diversity, policies and values after a high people growth in a short period of time. By Jemima Kiss</p>

<p>Tags: culture, office-culture, slack, jemima-kiss</p>

<h2>Slack: Work This Way</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@iaintait/slack-work-this-way-9221284472dd">this article</a>, a response to my above read, about the office culture at Slack.</p>

<p>Tags: iain-tait, response, slack, office-culture</p>

<h2>BEM 101</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://css-tricks.com/bem-101/">this introduction</a> to a CSS style called Block, Element, Modifier methodology (BEM).</p>

<p>In it,</p>

<blockquote><ul>
<li>a block is a top-level abstraction of a new component</li>
<li>Child items, or elements, can be placed inside and these are denoted by two underscores following the name of the block [&hellip;].
modifiers can manipulate the block so that we can theme or style that particular component without inflicting changes on a completely unrelated module. This is done by appending two hyphens to the name of the block [&hellip;].</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>By Joe Richardson, Robin Rendle et al.</p>

<p>Tags: joe-richardson, robin-rendle, bem, css, css-methodology, introduction, css-architecture, sass</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Structured Design: Fundamentals of a Discipline of Computer Program and Systems Design by Yourdon and Constantine.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polishing Your Tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/22/polishing-your-tools/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-22T08:30:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/22/polishing-your-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The toolsmith</h2>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fred_Brooks">Frederick P Brooks, Jr</a> quoted / explained a theory explained by Mills and Baker<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> around 1971-72:</p>

<blockquote><p>Chapter 3: The Surgical Team</p>

<p>[&hellip;] but the team be organized like a surgical team rather than a hog-butchering team. That is, instead of each member cutting away on the problem, one does the cutting and the others give him[her] every support that will enhance his[her] effectiveness and productivity.</p>

<p>[&hellip;]</p>

<p><quote> Brooks, F. - The Mythical Man-Month, chapter 3: The Surgical Team </quote></p></blockquote>

<p>(Text between square brackets is mine)</p>

<p>The author goes on to explain the job descriptions for the surgeon, copilot, administrator, editor, secretaries, program clerk, toolsmith, tester and the language lawyer.</p>

<p>The one that will be covered in this post is the toolsmith:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>The toolsmith</strong>. File-editing, text-editing, and interactive debugging services are now readily available, so that a team will rarely need its own machine and machine-operating crew. But these services must be available with unquestionably satisfactory response and reliability; and the surgeon must be sole judge of the adequacy of the service available to him. He needs a toolsmith, responsible for ensuring this adequacy of the basic service and for constructing, maintaining, and upgrading special tools &ndash;mostly interactive computer services&ndash; needed by his team. Each team will need its own toolsmith, regardless of the excellence and reliability of any centrally provided service, for his job is to see to the tools needed or wanted by his surgeon, without regard to any other team&rsquo;s needs. The tool-builder will often construct specialized utilities, cataloged procedures, macro libraries.</p>

<p><quote> Brooks, F. - The Mythical Man-Month, chapter 3: The Surgical Team </quote></p></blockquote>

<p>Even though the chapter reads a bit outdated, especially with the part about genders and methodologies (i.e., waterfall), the part about roles is interesting. The surgical team, as the author presents will be composed by 9 &frac12; (nine and a half) as the language lawyer can be shared among two or three teams.</p>

<h2>Day to day practices</h2>

<p>So, one full-time job is to build tools to service the surgeon and the copilot (1:8,5 ratio), or approximately 12% of a full-time position.</p>

<p>These tools can make the surgeon and the copilot more effective, ranging from a single digit percentage to orders of magnitude in other tasks.</p>

<p>As agile teams no longer have a toolsmith and the scrum master is not necessarily a technical expert who can build tools for the whole team, the tasks of creating tools must be taken care by everyone. No one better than yourself can know your needs and tailor solutions for them.</p>

<p>The only downside is you have to invest ~5h (for a full time position) per week into creating and polishing tools for your work: it is a need for achieving more productivity when working.</p>

<p>Nowadays that IDEs are configurable, this time might be invested on learning more advanced features as other shortcuts, refactoring techniques, other design patterns, etc. I like having my own live templates (see <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/creating-and-editing-live-templates.html#d1333587e219">description</a>), especially for tests, as I saw on the <a href="https://skillsmatter.com/courses/503-sandro-mancuso-s-crafting-code-course#programme">Crafting Code workshop</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a></p>

<p></p>

<p>It may also include other activities as setting up your bash alias, cleaning your desk, trying a new UML diagram modeler, etc. Anything that improves the productivity of your main task.</p>

<p>If we consider our experience and knowledge part of our tools (as we are knowledge workers), training could be considered part of polishing our tools. Short, daily or weekly training sessions (even internal) can make a great impact on breadth (not depth) of knowledge among your teammates. This shallow knowledge can open doors for more knowledge to be gained outside of company time, or used to practice and test other methods.</p>

<p>This training is so useful for everyone (&ldquo;when one teaches, two learn&rdquo;) that I recommend my clients to do it. This has helped them cope with changing technologies, knowledge transfer and even some team building.</p>

<h2>Company provided or not?</h2>

<p>Should the company provide for this time to improve? Although I don&rsquo;t know the answer, it would greatly affect the programmers' productivity to do so. I would say, provide this time as long as what is produced is useful. How do you measure useful? This is a subjective opinion, so it depends on each one.</p>

<p>Some companies acknowledge that this is so important as to invest part of their resources (0-2 hours per week) into training.</p>

<p>Either way, should your company provide it for your or not, you are the one in charge of your career (from Mancuso, <a href="https://leanpub.com/socra">Software Craftsmanship</a> - now called <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Software-Craftsman-Professionalism-Pragmatism-Robert/dp/0134052501/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1416521895&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+software+craftsman">The Software Craftsman</a>). If you are not allowed to invest company time for your own benefit, you could use some of your personal time to do so. It is not required, but you will soon enjoy its profits.</p>

<h2>Examples</h2>

<ul>
<li>Every sprint, one of my clients (as of 2015-05) wants to review the work done using some slides and a live demo. The &lsquo;sample&rsquo; slides with the format, layout is useful. Everything that should be replaced (timestamp, contents, etc) is marked with a TODO</li>
<li>Every day, I commit plenty of times to the control version system (i.e., git). I have an alias for commit, diff, status, etc, that saves me some keystrokes on the most common commands</li>
<li>See the post &ldquo;A basic working environment&rdquo;</li>
<li>Deployment, even on local, is automated: a script for getting the latest <code>branch</code>, <code>develop</code> or <code>master</code> code, build the Docker container, start the docker image, notify me the code is ready</li>
<li>Pipeline: I have a pipeline, in local, where I can push and the tests will be executed automatically. If the build fails (usually BDD tests), I can <code>push -f</code> without affecting to the repo history.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<p>Mills, H., &ldquo;Chief programmer teams, principles, and procedures,&rdquo; IBM Federal Systems Division Report FSC 715108, Gaithersburg, Md., 1971.</p>

<p>Baker, F. T., &ldquo;Chief programmer team management of production programming,&rdquo; IBM Sys. J., 11, 1 (1972).</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Original references in &ldquo;The Mythical Man-Month&rdquo; (Notes and References, page 294) point to these:<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
