<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sandro-mancuso on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/sandro-mancuso/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sandro-mancuso on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/sandro-mancuso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian of the Source</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/the-guardian-of-the-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 22:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/the-guardian-of-the-source/</guid>
      <description>Overheard today at the office, while they were discussing the approval of a pull request:
 [Pull request reviewer] - I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, can&amp;rsquo;t approve this: I don&amp;rsquo;t really agree with this design. Isn&amp;rsquo;t there an alternative for this?
[Pull request author] - [redacted], of course you don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;re the guardian of the source
[PR reviewer] - Well, sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m a bit picky about introducing bad code into our codebase.
 This has made me think about Gandalf blocking the path of Balrog Demon, shouting &amp;ldquo;[you shall not pass][you-shall-not-pass-meme]&amp;rdquo; while on top of the bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
