<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>octopress-2 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/octopress-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in octopress-2 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 23:39:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/octopress-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faster site generation with a native Octopress 2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/faster-site-generation-native-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/faster-site-generation-native-octopress/</guid>
      <description>Note: this article is an answer to a previous one, about the same topic: a tool for a faster site generation while developing / writing articles, using octopress 2.
Introduction Octopress 2 packs, out of the box, some tasks to speed up the site generation while you&amp;rsquo;re writing articles:
Isolate a post:
# usage rake isolate[my-post] desc &amp;#34;Move all other posts than the one currently being worked on to a temporary stash location (stash) so regenerating the site happens much more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster site generation for Octopress 2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/faster-site-generation-for-octopress-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 07:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/faster-site-generation-for-octopress-2/</guid>
      <description>2016-04 update: I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that the original Rakefile does a similar job. See here
After a while, the generation of the static site using Octopress 2 was starting to be slow (around 2 minutes for 85 posts) for the kind of fast feedback cycle I was expecting.
Inspired by their new features in Octopress 3, one of them being faster site generation, I decided to retrofit my installation with the same feature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
