<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filesystem on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/filesystem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Filesystem on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/filesystem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study-in-april-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study-in-april-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliberate-practice-what-it-is-and-why-you-need-it&#34;&gt;Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four essential components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailored (practice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetion
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language&#34;&gt;10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jooq.org/2016/03/31/10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list of features&lt;/a&gt; that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language. By Lukas Eder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: list, lukas-eder, kotlin, java, comparison, language, jooq&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-built-uber-engineering-s-highest-query-per-second-service-using-go&#34;&gt;How we built Uber engineering&amp;rsquo;s highest query per second service using Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.uber.com/go-geofence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kai Wei on a microservice they&amp;rsquo;ve built using Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the reasons for choosing that algorithm for geofencing, the performance they&amp;rsquo;re achieving, and the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uber, go, microservice, performance, geofence, geofencing, rps, go-memory-model, kai-wei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service&#34;&gt;Unwinding Uber&amp;rsquo;s Most Efficient Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@buckhx/unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service-406413c5871d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Buck Heroux commenting on the decisions of Uber for building the geofencing microservice (above read).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the different alternatives for algorithms in this problem space and has implemented them in go. Provides a benchmark for comparing those, including a profiling session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: s2, quadtree, rtree, brute-force, geofence, geofencing, uber, comment, buck-heroux, go, read-on-read, meta-read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawful-hacking-and-continuing-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Lawful Hacking and Continuing Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/03/lawful_hacking_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on the stance the FBI is taking in regards to vulnerabilities discovered in Apple&amp;rsquo;s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, apple, security, fbi, vulnerability, exploit, law, hacking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-life-learning&#34;&gt;A Side Project Helped Jumpstart My Career — Life Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/life-learning/a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-7cd6f8e9b07f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dave Gerhardt on how making a side project happen affected his life and his skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons for doing it include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It forces you to figure stuff out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way to learn is by doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gets your brain working on something other than your job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to create your own network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are the CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: long-life-learning, continuous-learning, side-project, dave-gerhardt, drift, professional-development, personal-development, business, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-jekyll-tricks&#34;&gt;Fun Jekyll Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.madebymarket.com/blog/dev/fun-jekyll-tricks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Knapp where he explains some tips and tricks of jekyll (in which octopress is based on): speed, deployment, subcategories inside the blog, _data, _includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brian-knapp, jekyll, octopress, tip-and-trick, improvement, subcategory, meta, automation, deployment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-ola-que-llega&#34;&gt;La ola que llega&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=f8a8ee92cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla, where he explains (in Spanish) the &amp;lsquo;contractor&amp;rsquo; phenomenon arriving to Spain, 2-3 years after being in other countries and the effects that this could have both for workers and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bonilista, david-bonilla, contractor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-razones-por-las-que-este-sábado-deberías-ir-a-un-code-retreat&#34;&gt;10 razones por las que este sábado deberías ir a un code retreat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://francho.org/2015/11/10/10-razones-para-ir-a-un-coderetreat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of reasons for attending a code retreat, by Francho Joven, who I met in the Global Day Of Code Retreat (GDCR) &amp;lsquo;15 in Zaragoza&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: francho-joven, list, zaragoza, code-retreat, gdcr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meaningful-work-through-passion-not-genius&#34;&gt;Meaningful Work through Passion, not Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIYUMwxKFzo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; on the importance of hard work and how it can be mistaken as genious. By Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: malcolm-gladwell, passion, genius, work, time-management, productivity, career, mastery-autonomy-purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name&#34;&gt;How to ask your wife for permission to spend $250,000 on a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Stockphoto.com/how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name-c27a3c2852e1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jon Yau on how they started StockPhoto.com, buying a $250,000 domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: startup, domain, stockphoto, jon-yau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong&#34;&gt;Sorry, developer bootcamps: I was wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@dillonforrest/sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong-ea37fcc5572c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dillon Forrest on the topic of developer bootcamps. Explains why developers should not be threatened by recent graduates of these programs and describes how people pursuing these programs usually are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bootcamp, developer-bootcamp, dev-bootcamp, dillon-forrest, intelligence, risk-appetite, resilience, self-investment, entrepreneurship, growth-trajectory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jvm-and-java-garbage-collection&#34;&gt;The JVM and Java Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoJr5QQYsl8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this webcast&lt;/a&gt; about how the JVM garbage collection works. By Michael W Williams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-williams, oracle, webcast, jvm, garbage-collection, gc,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;files-are-hard&#34;&gt;Files Are Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/file-consistency/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why software that writes on files is difficult, based on the different filesystems that are below, and the operating system. Written by Dan Luu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses software product to find bugs in filesystems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: filesystem, file, dan-luu, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusión-inquebrantable&#34;&gt;Contrata a un fracasado con ilusión inquebrantable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contunegocio.es/tecnologia/contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusion-inquebrantable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alberto Mena (in Spanish) on what are the qualities that define a good programmer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;illusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-mena, spanish, team-management, success, developer, quality, developer-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-react&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t react&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.avdi.org/2016/04/14/dont-react/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Avdi Grimm on how the action vs reaction attitude. Why to prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: action, reaction, social-media, avdi-grimm, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34;&gt;FTP is so 90&amp;rsquo;s. Let&amp;rsquo;s deploy via Git instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderwall.com/p/xczkaq/ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to deploy using git. By Kerrick Long&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kerrick-long, git, deployment, webapp, application, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-vs-career-10-key-differences-you-need-to-understand&#34;&gt;Job vs Career: 10 Key Differences You Need To Understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/job-vs-career&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what differentiates a job from a career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, infographic, job-vs-career, comparison, job, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-secret-to-employee-motivation&#34;&gt;The Secret To Employee Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/secret-employee-motivation-infographic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what motivates employess: mastery, autonomy and purpose. A direct reference to Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The puzzle of motivation&amp;rdquo; TED talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, motivation, employee, infographic, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-puzzle-of-motivation&#34;&gt;The puzzle of motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Pink on what motivates us: intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about the gap that exists between what science knows and what businesses propose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ted, ted-talk, video, dan-pink, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count&#34;&gt;Applying a ceiling to the bug count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techblog.king.com/applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, written by Susanna Berg, on how King has reduced the amount of bugs in their backlog using an agile technique, measuring and setting a limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: susanna-berg, king, agile, bug, bug-count, defect, defect-count, per-malmen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34;&gt;Coming up in 2016: Spring Framework 4.3 &amp;amp; 5.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://spring.io/blog/2015/08/03/coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this announcement&lt;/a&gt; of Spring&amp;rsquo;s new release, 5.0, which will require java 8 and will turn most of the features into the reactive programming paradigm. By Juergen Hoeller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: juergen-hoeller, spring, reactive-programming, release, announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die&#34;&gt;Why offices are where work goes to die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swizec.com/blog/why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die/swizec/6695&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Swizec Teller explaining the downsides of working in an office as compared to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: swizec-teller, remote, home-office, office, comparison, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Passionate Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bm2yogi/the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer-76a41d457304&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Ibarra on what are the implications of being a passionate developer, how it affects your tasks and what are the factors to a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-ibarra, passion, development, job, motivation, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mossack-fonseca-breach-wordpress-revolution-slider-plugin-possible-cause&#34;&gt;Mossack Fonseca Breach – WordPress Revolution Slider Plugin Possible Cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2016/04/mossack-fonseca-breach-vulnerable-slider-revolution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Maunder, which describes an hypothesis on how the Mossack Fonseca breach could have happened. Also describes and shows how to breach a Wordpress installation with a vulnerable Revolution Slider plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mark-maunder, security, breach, mossack-fonseca-breach, mossack-fonseca, hypothesis, attack, plugin, revolution-slider, wordpress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tim-urban-inside-the-mind-of-a-master-procrastinator&#34;&gt;Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; from Tim Urban on how the procrastinator&amp;rsquo;s mind works, exemplified by his own career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: procrastinator, procrastination, mind, time-management, tim-urban&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pep-20-the-zen-of-python&#34;&gt;PEP 20 &amp;ndash; The Zen of Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the PEP20&lt;/a&gt;, the zen of python, with special attention to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: pep-20, pep, python, zen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Why I switched from Octopress 2 to Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Franklin Chen on the change he made on the static site generator (SSG) he used. He considered hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo. Was decided between hakyll and hugo for their speed but, finally, decided to use hugo for their bigger community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: franklin-chen, comparison, ssg, static-site-generator, hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo, change, speed, statically-typed, dynamically-typed, golang, performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-incremental-regeneration-in-jekyll-3-0-is-such-a-big-deal&#34;&gt;Why incremental regeneration in Jekyll 3.0 is such a big deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/11/04/jekyll-30-released-incremental-regeneration-rocks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Johnson on one of the new features that jekyll 3.0 brings: incremental generation. How this can speed up the generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-johnson, incremental-generation, speed, performance, octopress-2, octopress-3, jekyll-3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-s3-travis-ci-oh-boy&#34;&gt;Hugo, S3, Travis CI, oh boy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://continuousfailure.com/post/s3_blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Scherger on how to set up a specific stack for developing and deploying a static site blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alan-scherger, static-site-generator, ssg, travis, hugo, s3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-your-blog-to-github-pages-automatically-using-hugo-and-travis&#34;&gt;Deploy your blog to github pages automatically using Hugo and Travis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcoedo.com/post/hugo-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Roman Coedo on how to deploy a hugo blog to github pages, using travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: roman-coedo, travis, hugo, github, github-pages, ssg, static-site-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;improve-octopress-with-advanced-tweaks-tips&#34;&gt;Improve Octopress with Advanced Tweaks &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.narga.net/improve-octopress-advanced-tweaks-tips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tips on how to improve the octopress (2) installation. By Nguyễn Đình Quân.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nguyen-dinh-quan, octopress-2, tip, tweak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;laboratorios&#34;&gt;Laboratorios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2014/11/12/laboratorios/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla, about laboratories to use a percentage of company time to investigate, innovate, learn and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, team-management, time-management, innovation, strategy, improvement, kaizen, laboratory, craftsmanship, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isn-t&#34;&gt;What Refactoring is, and what it isn’t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swreflections.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isnt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Bird, where he splits some practices into refactoring and not refactoring. Draws the line between these two different activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also cites scratch refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jim-bird, scratch-refactoring, refactoring, martin-fowler, kent-beck, definition, quote, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitfalls-of-unlimited-vacations&#34;&gt;Pitfalls of Unlimited Vacations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/archive/2016/02/18/unlimited-vaction-pitfalls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Phil Haack on the github, travis and netflix policies about unlimited vacations and the effects they have on the employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about minimum vacation periods, (paternity) paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: phil-haack, unlimited-vacation, holiday, vacation, team-management, burnout, github, travis, netflix, policy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultura-corporativa&#34;&gt;Cultura Corporativa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2011/02/06/cultura-corporativa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla about the corporate culture, and how &amp;ldquo;hanging a highly interchangeable sentence on a wall&amp;rdquo; does not represent it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, corporate culture, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code&#34;&gt;What It’s Really Like to Learn to Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sandjar/what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code-53f6d9156a32&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains firsthand how it is to learn programming for a novice student,even with a strong financial background and having completed a university degree. By Sandjar Kozubaev&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sandjar-kozubaev, learning, programming, student, firsthand, coding, story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>