<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prepared Kata on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/prepared-kata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prepared Kata on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 21:24:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/prepared-kata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown Bag Session: Clojure&#39;s Data and Code</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/23/brown-bag-session-clojures-data-and-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 21:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/23/brown-bag-session-clojures-data-and-code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today, at a client, I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated the brown-bag session on Clojure, introducing Lisp&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homoiconicity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;homoiconicity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;session-structure&#34;&gt;Session Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session was designed as a kata, first introducing participants in the problem, letting some time to read the initial version and to think about possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I structured the rest of the time as a prepared kata, where I was explaining in the beamer our current problems (day-to-day tasks) and possible solutions in Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration and extensibility: allowing for flexibility, define at configuration time new features without recompiling or modifying the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persisting and restoring certain state: this is a problem that could easily be solved persisting data in Lisp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explained, in private to those who asked, about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_(programming_language)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lisp&lt;/a&gt; and its dialects &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Lisp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Common Lisp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clojure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scheme_(programming_language)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scheme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback&#34;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They liked the effort of investigating new languages to solve problems we have in our current stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They liked introducing the language features with a back-story to better understand the concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They suggested to improve the level of the session: as the group as a whole is still starting with Clojure, leaving them on their own with code is too much. They asked for more guidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD microexercise: Tire pressure</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/tdd-microexercise-tire-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 23:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/tdd-microexercise-tire-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/@trikitrok&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manuel Rivero&lt;/a&gt; and I facilitated a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Barcelona-Software-Craftsmanship/events/221463037/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;workshop&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lucaminudel/TDDwithMockObjectsAndDesignPrinciples/tree/master/TDDMicroExercises/Java/TirePressureMonitoringSystem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tire pressure&lt;/a&gt; TDD microexercise. (More microexercises can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/{{site.category_dir}}/microexercise&#34;&gt;this category&lt;/a&gt;, also &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lucaminudel/TDDwithMockObjectsAndDesignPrinciples/tree/master/TDDMicroExercises&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We scheduled the session as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes introduction to the exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes to download the code and take a first look&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes explanation about the exercise, what the problem is, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 minutes for the attendees to explore the solution (on their own)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes for commenting the explored solutions, comments about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 minutes of prepared kata format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes of final explanations, questions and answers (Q&amp;amp;A)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total: 120 minutes or two hours, approximately&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that one would be mostly at the keyboard and the other mostly explaining. This allows for the speaker to introduce some concepts while the driver is performing a larger refactor / step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of our own feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have the kata prepared, clear all your doubts before doing it live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be very specific about the goal of the kata: the narrower the focus, the more we will learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If necessary, exercise your shortcuts / practices one last time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up the font as big as needed. Even remove some whitelines (present in your usual code) so more text can fit in the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was very useful for us to have a small script of what we would perform: what was the idea, where to stop to explain things, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A prepared kata is a show (like a movie), so the dialogs between the performing pair are important. Do not be afraid to tell the reasons why you did this last refactor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answer the questions as you go, do not wait until the end of the session
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some feedback we received:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would have been useful to do a recap at the end of the session, to refresh the most important concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In general the session was good, they were satisfied with the techniques shown there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exercise was concise and small, perfect for two hours&amp;rsquo; time
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to all the attendees and to Manuel: I learnt a lot from the session and renewed my energies to keep doing these workshop sessions. Also thanks to Luca Minudel for writing these awesome exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>