<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>prepared-kata on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/prepared-kata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in prepared-kata on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 21:24:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/prepared-kata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brown Bag Session: Clojure&#39;s Data and Code</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/23/brown-bag-session-clojures-data-and-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 21:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/23/brown-bag-session-clojures-data-and-code/</guid>
      <description>Today, at a client, I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated the brown-bag session on Clojure, introducing Lisp&amp;rsquo;s homoiconicity.
Session Structure The session was designed as a kata, first introducing participants in the problem, letting some time to read the initial version and to think about possible solutions.
Then, I structured the rest of the time as a prepared kata, where I was explaining in the beamer our current problems (day-to-day tasks) and possible solutions in Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD microexercise: Tire pressure</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/tdd-microexercise-tire-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 23:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/tdd-microexercise-tire-pressure/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Manuel Rivero and I facilitated a workshop using the tire pressure TDD microexercise. (More microexercises can be found in this category, also here)
We scheduled the session as follows:
 10 minutes introduction to the exercise 10 minutes to download the code and take a first look 10 minutes explanation about the exercise, what the problem is, etc 30 minutes for the attendees to explore the solution (on their own) 10 minutes for commenting the explored solutions, comments about it 40 minutes of prepared kata format 10 minutes of final explanations, questions and answers (Q&amp;amp;A)  Total: 120 minutes or two hours, approximately</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
