<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
