<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>slide on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/slide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in slide on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/slide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>How I use reveal.js This author explains how they use reveal.js.
The online editor (slides.com).
The author uses plain html for storing the slides.
Tags: slide, slideshare, reveal-js, reveal, presentation, slide-deck, michael-mccune
Id: 41e287b4-ae15-11e9-9e8a-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 07:16:33 +0000
All your digital life on a single timeline, stored locally Keep your digital life under your control
Tags: backup, local-data, encryption, control
Id: 4d115f64-ae17-11e9-bf0e-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:31:11 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB
Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable
Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000
Jepsen: Aerospike I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies
Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos
Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</guid>
      <description>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.
Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery
Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &amp;ldquo;Call me maybe&amp;rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
