<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>experience-report on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/experience-report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in experience-report on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/experience-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session: Refactoring legacy code</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/23/brown-bag-session-refactoring-legacy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 19:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/23/brown-bag-session-refactoring-legacy-code/</guid>
      <description>Today I have facilitated a brown bag session about refactoring legacy code applications, as this is the case with one of the applications we maintain and add new features to.
The contents of the session:
 Briefly exposing the problem to the team, me taking the role of the Product Owner (PO) Ask the dev team to add an easy feature Do it without tests, as it was so simple that they thought they could do it (using mob programming) Ask if they were satisfied by the patch / fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience report: Test-driven development intensive, by Jason Gorman</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 20:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This is an experience report on Jason Gorman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Test-driven development intensive workshop&amp;rdquo; on the April 11th, 2015
I attended this training in the Greenfell housing &amp;amp; training in South Wimbledon, London SW19 1JZ. The training spanned from 10:00 to 17:00 with a half an hour for lunch plus three or four 10-15 minute pauses. (7 - ,5 - 4 * 12/60 = ~5.7hours = 5 hours 45 minutes)
Introduction There were 23 of us, including me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Space: Code reviews</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed about code reviews on this open space
Notes These are my notes, in no particular order:
 reduce information silos all around the company, as everyone [technical] can participate in these events raise the &amp;ldquo;just arrived&amp;rdquo; people&amp;rsquo;s knowledge [Difficult to hit the ground up and running, but these code review sessions can help] invest one person as &amp;lsquo;sheriff&amp;rsquo; for the sprint: they will take care of static analysis tools (such as sonar) and continuous integration (CI; such as jenkins).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD Meetup Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 05:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we organized a TDD meetup at the FIB - Barcelona School of Informatics UPC, within Barcelona Software Craftsmanship sponsored by the Junior Empresa d&amp;rsquo;Informàtica. The meetup started at 9:00 until 18:00, with a one-hour pause in the middle.
Where  Please make sure the meetup space (e.g., classroom, meeting room) is available and ready to be used at least 15 minutes before the meetup starts The organizer and the event host should be there in advance to prepare the physical environment (chairs, wifi, beamer, etc) as well as mentally: getting comfortable with the space, loading the presentation, prepare the speaker notes, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Day of Code Retreat 2014</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/global-day-of-code-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 07:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/global-day-of-code-retreat/</guid>
      <description>One month ago (on November 15th) I facilitated my first Global Day of Code Retreat at eBay Enterprise International and had such a blast. Link to the event (Spanish)
Some thoughts After a month of thinking about it, here are some thoughts:
  This year&amp;rsquo;s GDCR was quite different that last one&amp;rsquo;s:
It&amp;rsquo;s OK: do not strive for repeating the same each year
  Heat map (in several dimensions): TDD x language</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
