<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>search on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in search on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/07/01/self-study-july-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/07/01/self-study-july-2022/</guid>
      <description>Zetk: CLI utilities, fzf-based scripts, C++ lib for managing your Zettelkasten Zettelkasten notes implemented as a library with a set of CLI utils
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31969931
Tags: zettelkasten, software, personal-knowledge, application, tool, cli, fzf, search, wiki, imported, hacker-news
Id: 5017abd4-fb79-11ec-ad8c-0242ac110003 Read: Sun Jul 3 18:38:57 2022
Show HN: C3 – A C alternative that looks like C https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32005678
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: d665c1c0-c1a4-11ed-a153-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Jul 6 19:31:01 2022
Formally Verifying Industry Cryptography https://news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</guid>
      <description>Work cycles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this Work Cycle framework to be more productive with your daily routine.
Suggests an alternative to Pomodoro technique, in which you are to write down the contents of the goal, then split in small chunks (periods) of time to complete the individual tasks, then debrief at the end of the period and at the end of the cycle.
An analogy could be a double-loop Pomodoro technique for tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching on a suite of failing tests</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/13/searching-on-a-suite-of-failing-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 16:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/13/searching-on-a-suite-of-failing-tests/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Today, at a client, in the green phase, we had a test suite which was failing: the whole suite fails but the test cases, individually, succeed.
So my first impression was that something was being shared between tests. Also confirmed because the failing class was an EndToEnd test, in which we load the whole spring context
A quick glance was not revealing anything interesting, so I decided to find which is the minimum suite (as opposed as to the whole suite) that makes the new testcase fail, expecting to narrow the search for possible causes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
