<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gardening on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/gardening/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gardening on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 12:41:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/gardening/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Software gardening manifesto</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/17/software-gardening-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 12:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/17/software-gardening-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend sent this &lt;a href=&#34;http://softwaregarden.io/manifesto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software Gardening Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is related to the idea of growing software vs building it, greatly exemplified by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests&lt;/a&gt; book (&lt;a href=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/{{site.category_dir}}/goos&#34;&gt;category here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trimming your plants</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/02/trimming-your-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 23:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/02/trimming-your-plants/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post belongs to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/{{site.category_dir}}/growing-software&#34;&gt;growing-software series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine this situation: the code works. You are at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/refactoring_a-first-example/commit/1ff7df4d45ee1ac5bc483b90da7ed1b68f27aef9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this stage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the tests, the production code is complete. Could be better, but it is ready if you are in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, picture your test as a plant in a plant pot: it might be healthy on the outside (external quality) but how are their roots (internal quality)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you imagine them in an ordered fashion or in a jungle of roots? Everything on the outside is connected to one or several roots? In case it is several, what / how much do they share?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trimming-the-roots&#34;&gt;Trimming the roots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s imagine you want to put the plant in a different plant pot. You don&amp;rsquo;t want the plant to be altered in any way: keep producing fruits as it was before, as green and shiny, etc. Just alter the container for business reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more tidy and organized the roots are related to the outside plant itself, the easier it is to reshape (or refactor) it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is exactly what refactoring is about: &amp;ldquo;keeping the same external behaviour, modifying the internal structure&amp;rdquo;. I like to explain as &amp;ldquo;modify how it is done but not what it does&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you trim the roots but leave unaltered the top, you are making it cheaper to modify the internal shape without affecting the rest. The plant will continue to grow, requiring more and more nutrients from the ground. Small increases that do not warrant a bigger plant pot, as the current one can withstand the new requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the analogy is no longer useful: when writing software, you&amp;rsquo;re also making it easier to reuse, modify and maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more tidied up you have your plants, the cheaper to maintain and modify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software implementation details are like roots: they expand to find any small hole where to expand. Even to scaffold expected behaviour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trim your plants early and often, always with the help of a test suite&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing software according to the season</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/29/growing-software-according-to-the-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 18:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/29/growing-software-according-to-the-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first post is of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/{{site.category_dir}}/growing-software&#34;&gt;growing-software series&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, while reading the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/@natpryce&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nat Pryce&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/@sf105&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Steve Freeman&lt;/a&gt;, I finally understood why the software needs to be grown and not built:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/natpryce&#34;&gt;@natpryce&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sf105&#34;&gt;@sf105&lt;/a&gt; With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/goos?src=hash&#34;&gt;#goos&lt;/a&gt; book I finally grasped the importance of growing, not building software. Thanks for writing it&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alvaro Garcia (@alvarobiz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvarobiz/status/570835142136049664&#34;&gt;February 26, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

A few days ago, I was thinking about new inspiration sources and this came to my mind:

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we want to grow software instead of building it, should we start looking at gardening and agriculture for new inspiration? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/goos?src=hash&#34;&gt;#goos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alvaro Garcia (@alvarobiz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvarobiz/status/581005906667687938&#34;&gt;March 26, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In agriculture, at least in this latitude, there are different seasons. Different plants have different temporal schedules: you need to plant, wait for it to bloom, produce fruits then collect. Maybe remove the plant and wait for the next time slot to appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When growing software, things are different (or we think so):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we need to plant? Yes, seed the project with resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for it to bloom? Yes, from an outside actor perspective, there is no result for a while, even if it is one sprint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait to produce fruits? Yes, usually some sprints past the minimum viable product (MVP) until the minimum lovable product (MLP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do we need to collect it? Yes, usually the final tests (e.g., regression) and ship it to production to be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, we might say that the process is not so different in both activities. Nothing to do related to tools or materials, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in agriculture, seasons vary in productivity for a certain activity or crop: during the cold months, not many plants are able to produce fruits. Meanwhile, during the hot months, harvest is much higher. (This only applies to outdoors gardening.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When producing software, there might be seasons too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seasons where productivity (harvest) varies

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowers when a new team member joins (see the Mythical Man-Month), the pressure is too high, salaries are low, &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increases when there are no information silos, the bus factor is high, the team is not affected by external distractions, &amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seasons where different harvests can be planted, but a subset of them will be the most effective

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A front-end developer can do back-end, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be as productive. In this area, one can learn other disciplines and get as effective as other professionals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many tasks to be done but the prioritized ones are more effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some harvests are more intense on the fields than others. After that, there is a required rest so the next season is as productive as the previous one

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some projects produce burn-out so some slack time is more productive than getting to work again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there might be differences too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geographical distribution: some crops cannot grow in certain conditions. I believe any geographic area (e.g., country) can produce any type of work (e.g., back-end, front-end, quality assurance, project management, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality distribution: same as before, many crops do not grow in Iceland (due to the harsh environment) or do it with lower quality as nearer to the Equator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/@XaV1uzz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Xavi Gost&lt;/a&gt; responded to my tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-conversation=&#34;none&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvarobiz&#34;&gt;@alvarobiz&lt;/a&gt; Conceptos como darle a las cosas su tiempo de crecer y madurar nos vendrian bien en la industria&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Xaviuzz (@XaV1uzz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/XaV1uzz/status/581063149203394560&#34;&gt;March 26, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Roughly translated: Concepts like allowing some time for things to grow and ripe would benefit the industry]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the tools out of the tool-shed and start buying seeds for this spring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>