<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>feature on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/feature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in feature on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/feature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>Advice for white men I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cate Huston about how advice affects different people.
 But here are some things to consider:
 Advice on failure is different for people who are judged on performance rather than potential. Advice on saying no is different for people who aren’t appreciated for doing work for the collective… but who are punished if they don’t. Advice on negotiation is different for people who are perceived negatively when they do negotiate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging is a feature</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/19/logging-is-a-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 23:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/19/logging-is-a-feature/</guid>
      <description>At a client, we&amp;rsquo;re facing this challenge: we cannot access production logs, as we don&amp;rsquo;t have access to production environments. The solution we&amp;rsquo;ve chose is to implement the logging component as a layer on top of Splunk.
This formatter layer &amp;ndash;per component&amp;ndash; accesses a generic layer &amp;ndash;for the whole company&amp;ndash; that accesses splunk. In this manner, it is very easy to reuse the splunk connection and configuration and inject mocks. Also helps with the local environment: you always log to console (even if in production you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to it) and can disable this in local, not needing a local splunk installation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
