<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</guid>
      <description>Managing projects with GNU Make, Third Edition book about GNU Make, with recipes and going into detail about how to use it
Tags: book, make, gnu-make, project, skeleton, ci, continuous-integration
Id: 028b0e1f-a181-4469-8789-900ce6641d97 Read: Sun, 01 Jul 2024 17:22:52 +0000
Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs a tool to diff pdfs visually
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319
Tags: hackernews, imported, olshansky, testing, test, diff-pdf, pdf, diff, git, e2e-testing, end-to-end-testing, tool
Id: 4fc53bae-d81c-45b4-9f6b-995ec5d4df6a Read: Tue, 02 Jul 2024 07:26:08 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/10/01/self-study-october-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/10/01/self-study-october-2022/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Logging https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33054741
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 02a22390-c1a1-11ed-b61a-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Oct 2 10:42:15 2022
“Rust is safe” is not some kind of absolute guarantee of code safety https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33056077
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 12483f20-c1a4-11ed-84be-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Oct 2 14:20:21 2022
Have lots of AWS accounts Using the physical separation of your AWS accounts as a way to isolate the data and services
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33069547
Tags: aws, aws-account, physical-isolation, isolation, data-isolation, risk-management, imported, hacker-news</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold I&amp;rsquo;ve read this listicle of docker myths. By Derick Bailey
Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth
Bored People Quit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.
Some interesting quotes:
 My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.
My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert a project from npm to yarn</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/03/convert-a-project-from-npm-to-yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 11:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/03/convert-a-project-from-npm-to-yarn/</guid>
      <description>At a client, we&amp;rsquo;re converting all projects (i.e., sites, services, libraries) from npm to yarn. Mostly for the speed (as it uses the internal cache).
Step by step guide  Install yarn in your local environment * https://yarnpkg.com/lang/en/docs/install/ Run yarn install * This will create a yarn.lock file * Add that file to the repo: git add yarn.lock Modify Dockerfile * Install yarn (in the Dockerfile). Idea: shortcut this execution with yarn --version in case it is installed * Configure the PATH variable (ENV PATH &amp;hellip;) * ADD yarn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session: docker</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/16/brown-bag-session-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 18:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/16/brown-bag-session-docker/</guid>
      <description>Today we have done a brown bag session about Docker. One of the team members explained to us the latest news, topics and how tos, including:
 the difference between a container and an image diffing image contents AUFS (Another Union FS) persistent vs non-persistent (volatile) filesystems running CMD and other commands on the instance problems of running with permission = root (or its group) downsides of it how to compare it with a virtual machine  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
