<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cpp on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/cpp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cpp on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 03:35:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/cpp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using a Native C Library in Android</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/05/02/native-c-library-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 03:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/05/02/native-c-library-android/</guid>
      <description>For a client, we needed to integrate a pure C library into an android application.
The library is written in C (not C++), the application in Kotlin.
Context We have created an Android application, that is using a native C library. This library provides an upgrade in performance over using a JVM library.
For this particular example, we&amp;rsquo;re showcasing how to integrate libsodium, but this can be expanded to any other library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
