<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-18T09:00:38+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global Day of Code Retreat 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/global-day-of-code-retreat/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-18T07:33:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/global-day-of-code-retreat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One month ago (on November 15th) I facilitated my first <a href="http://globalday.coderetreat.org/">Global Day of Code Retreat</a> at <a href="http://www.ebayenterprise.com/contact/locations.php">eBay Enterprise International</a> and had such a blast. <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Barcelona-Meetup/events/218211672/">Link to the event (Spanish)</a></p>

<h2>Some thoughts</h2>

<p>After a month of thinking about it, here are some thoughts:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>This year&rsquo;s GDCR was quite different that last one&rsquo;s:</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s OK: do not strive for repeating the same each year</p></li>
<li><p>Heat map (in several dimensions): TDD x language</p>

<p>Usually meetups have a clear goal, for the limited amount of time they run (see another bullet point).</p>

<p>This single goal can span across multiple skill sets (e.g., TDD and language specific), therefore we did a two-dimensional heat map: first dimension is TDD skill level and second dimension (discreet) would be language you master</p>

<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1LRmjLbvFEtqDskDwb3gVBKDfXckqDylAMJA7HB6ZLC8/edit">Example can be found here</a></p></li>
<li><p>As a facilitator, have a clear goal for the meetup, even though you don&rsquo;t need to share it with the assistants</p>

<p>Mine was to have fun and introduce some people to TDD</p>

<p>I shared the goal with the attendants because I wanted to explain the purpose of that day to newcomers.</p>

<p>Also, as a result of that day, I&rsquo;ve discovered some very motivated people in our host (eBay). Personally, I&rsquo;d like to continue doing meetups with their developers.</p></li>
<li><p>You need a mix of more seasoned attendants and more unexperienced ones.</p>

<p>This way, the knowledge is being transferred both ways; not only about the language but about strategies, patterns, shortcuts &amp; editors, languages, etc</p>

<p>If doing TDD in these events, it&rsquo;s even more important to mix people, as it&rsquo;s difficult for an unexperienced pair to start doing TDD for themselves.</p></li>
<li><p>You should only do your job as facilitator</p>

<p>Let others discuss, ask and answer questions. Your job should be as thin as possible. Don&rsquo;t try to answer too many questions</p>

<p>There will be attendants with more experience / expertise than you (most of them were in my case), so don&rsquo;t strive to teach them but to manage the discussions to the right place</p>

<p>Be strict about timing but find the balance. Sometimes it&rsquo;s useful to invest more time (~5 minutes) to a rich discussion and then reduce the next iteration.</p>

<p>Many people will complain about having to delete their code the first time. Explain to them that&rsquo;s part of the game and don&rsquo;t give in. The following iterations most of the people won&rsquo;t complain anymore</p>

<p>Last but not least, have fun!</p></li>
</ol>


<h2>Some critiques</h2>

<p>We organized the event a little bit late</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The difference from last year (<a href="http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Barcelona-Meetup/events/153967432/">December</a>) vs this year (<a href="http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Barcelona-Meetup/events/218211672/">November</a>) was relevant. We were expecting to do it later so it surprised us.</p></li>
<li><p>Due to that, many people couldn&rsquo;t come and I&rsquo;m sorry for it</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>We totally, definitely should do this more often.</p>

<p>You need to reinvent yourself for every global day or people will stop coming</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Joys of the Craft]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T22:46:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quoting the book,</p>

<blockquote><p>Why is programming fun? What delights may its practitioner expect as his reward?</p>

<p>First is the sheer joy of making things. As the child delights in his mud pie, so the adult enjoys building things, especially things of his own design [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Second is the pleasure of making things that are useful to other people. Deep within, we want other to use our work and to find it helpful. [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Third is the fascination of fashioning complex puzzle-like objects of interlocking moving parts and watching them work in subtle cycles, playing out the consequences of principles built in from the beginning. [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Fourth is the joy of always learning, which springs from the nonrepeating nature of the task. In one way or another the problem is ever new, and its solver learns something: sometimes practical, sometimes theoretical, and sometimes both.</p>

<p>Finally, there is the delight of working in such a tractable medium. The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from the pure thought-stuff. He builds his castles in the air, from air, creating by exertion of the imagination. Few media of creating are so flexible, so easy to polish and rework, so readily capable of realizing grand conceptual structures. (As we shall see later, this very tractability has its own problems.)</p>

<p><cite>Frederick P. Brooks, Jr</cite> in the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Mythical-Man-Month-Engineering-Anniversary/dp/0201835959">&ldquo;The Mythical Man-Month&rdquo;</a></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['Pocket' Application]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/pocket-application/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T23:40:13+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/pocket-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a free application I use quite often: <a href="http://getpocket.com/">pocket</a></p>

<p>They promote it as &ldquo;When you find something you want to view later, put it in Pocket.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I really use for that. Once you install it in your phone, some handy shortcuts appear both on Chrome for saving the page and on twitter when you hit the &ldquo;share&rdquo; button.</p>

<p>It is especially useful when you&rsquo;re on the tube and have no connection, as pocket saves an offline version of the page (warning: this doesn&rsquo;t work for video sites like youtube)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CAS2014 Wrap Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/cas2014-wrap-up/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T19:18:28+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/cas2014-wrap-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year&rsquo;s edition of the CAS 2014 has been awesome. There were several tracks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Enterprise Agile</li>
<li>Collaboration, Culture and Teams</li>
<li>Delighting Products</li>
<li>Agile+</li>
<li>Development Practices and Craftsmanship</li>
</ul>


<p>The last one is where I spent most of the time.</p>

<h2>The schedule</h2>

<p> The first day:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a>: talking about Software Craftsmanship</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/fiunchinho">Jose Manuel Armesto</a>: talking about Unit Testing sucks (and it&rsquo;s our fault)</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/rmarpozo">Rubén Martín Pozo</a>: talking about Specification by example - Historia de un equipo que no odia documentar</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/XaV1uzz">Xavi Gost</a>: talking about La economía del refactoring. Una visión desde la gestión económica del proyecto.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/_pedro_torres">Pedro Gustavo Torres</a>: talking about Pair Programming</li>
</ul>


<p> The second day:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/rafadc">Rafael de Castro</a>: talking about Generando tests</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/borillo">Ricardo Borillo</a>: talking about CQRS y los beneficios surgidos de la necesidad.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/cupcicm">Manu Cupcic</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/eidrien">Adrian Perreau de Pinninck</a>: talking about Delivery at Scale.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/jgabardini">Juan Gabardini</a>: talking about Testing en equipos infectados de test. This talk was also prepared by Juan Diego Vasco Moncada but he couldn&rsquo;t come.</li>
</ul>


<h2> Some thoughts</h2>

<p> The conferences were awesome, but I&rsquo;d preferred if most (if not all) were in English so this conference can attract more international speakers</p>

<p> There were 600+ people in the <a href="http://www.cccb.org/">CCCB</a>. That was only possible due to all the volunteers, organizers, caterers and the assistants.</p>

<h2> More info</h2>

<p> You can find more information on the <a href="http://cas2014.agile-spain.org/">official website</a> and on twitter using the hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23cas2k14&amp;src=tyah">#cas2014</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T17:20:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the obligatory &ldquo;Hello World!&rdquo; post</p>

<p>To get here and create your own blog using <a href="http://octopress.org/">octopress</a>, follow the
instructions below:</p>

<ul>
<li>Install ruby, as explained on the guide
<a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">here</a></li>
<li>I&rsquo;ve used Ruby 2.1.5p273 (2014-11-13 revision 48405) [x64-mingw32]
(<code>ruby --version</code>)</li>
<li>Configure your blog. See
<a href="http://octopress.org/docs/configuring/">here</a></li>
<li>Install octopress: <code>rake install</code></li>
<li>Start the server with <code>rake preview</code>. You should see a basic
template (CSS) with your blog name, the author, etcetera</li>
<li>Create your first post.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code class="`cmd">rake new_post["Hello World!"]
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>Refresh the browser and see the new post appear</li>
<li>Edit the .markdown file in &ldquo;source\_posts&rdquo; using a markup editor</li>
<li>Execute <code>rake preview</code> to see your first post (this)</li>
<li>Execute <code>rake setup_github_pages</code> for every computer you want to
publish from</li>
<li><p>Execute <code>rake generate &amp;&amp; rake deploy</code>. After a few minutes, you
should go to
<username>.github.io to find your new blog in there</p></li>
<li><p>Happy blogging!</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
