<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bootcamp | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/bootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-29T13:38:40+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in September 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-01T13:25:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.growth.supply/the-30-second-habit-with-a-lifelong-impact-2c3f948ead98">this article</a> list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.</p>

<p>Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott</p>

<h2>The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkhLZ7_KZ5w">this video</a> explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson</p>

<p>Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</p>

<h2>Poster de Extreme Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4nN6Gh79Yg8">this video</a> introducing eXtreme Programming. By Martín Salías</p>

<p>Tags: martin-salias, kleer, extreme-programming, xp</p>

<h2>Good Tech Lead, Bad Tech Lead</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.growth.supply/good-tech-lead-bad-tech-lead-948b2b806d86">this comparison</a> of good and bad traits in tech leads. By Jason Liszka.</p>

<p>Explains the differences between good and bad tech leads, even though many of these qualities are shared by plain team members</p>

<p>Tags: jason-liszka, tech-lead, comparison</p>

<h2>Why Procrastinators Procrastinate</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://waitbutwhy.com/2013/10/why-procrastinators-procrastinate.html">this article</a> by Tim Urban on procrastination: this article compares the procrastinator and the non-procrastinator brain with pictures, introducing the Rational part, the Instant Gratification Monkey and the Panic Monster. Shows some reasons why.</p>

<p>There is more on part 2: <a href="http://waitbutwhy.com/2013/11/how-to-beat-procrastination.html">How to beat procrastination</a></p>

<p>Tags: tim-urban, procrastination, rational-part, instant-gratification-monkey, panic-monster, brain, comparison</p>

<h2>Algebraic data type</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebraic_data_type">this wikipedia page</a>, that explains what this is, a few examples and the theory behind it.</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, data-type, algebraic-data-type</p>

<h2>Recursion</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recursion_(computer_science)">this wikipedia page</a>, that explains the recursion basic concepts, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>induction, coinduction</li>
<li>recursion, corecursion</li>
<li>implementation details in iterative vs recursive programs:

<ul>
<li>shortcutting recursion (i.e., arm-length&rsquo;s recursion)</li>
<li>wrapper function</li>
<li>tail-call optimization, related to tail-recursive functions</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>recursion and its relation to data structures</li>
<li>base case / recursive case and removing the need of the base one in corecursion or in non-strict languages</li>
<li>types of recursion:

<ul>
<li>direct, indirect, mutual</li>
<li>generative, structural</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: recursion, corecursion, induction, coinduction, tail-call-optimization, tail-recursion, direct-recursion, indirect-recursion, mutual-recursion, generative-recursion, structural-recursion, arm-length-recursion, iterative-function, recursive-function, base-case, recursive-case, wikipedia, data-structure</p>

<h2>Anonymous function</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_function">this wikipedia page</a>, that describes what is a lambda expression or an anonymous function. How it can be used (e.g., currying, higher-order function, closures) and gives examples in many languages.</p>

<p>Cites its invention (Church, 1936, lambda-calculus) and its first implementation (Lisp, 1958)</p>

<p>Tags: alonzo-church, anonymous-function, lambda-expression, closure, lambda-calculus, lisp, currying, higher-order-function, wikipedia</p>

<h2>Closure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closure_(computer_programming)">this wikipedia page</a>, that explains the concept of closures and the usual confusion between closure and lambda. Also some applications.</p>

<p>Discusses closures as a way of deferring execution and implementing object-oriented (OO) systems</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, closure, object-orientation, lambda-expression</p>

<h2>Zen Story: The Master Archer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.thedailyzen.org/2015/06/23/zen-story-the-master-archer/">this story</a> by Charlie Ambler about perfectionism and deep study, exemplified by the general that retires to study archery and the child who draws targets around the arrows.</p>

<p>Tags: charlie-amber, master, student, zen, story</p>

<h2>Loosely Coupled</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.bwhaley.com/loosely-coupled">this article</a> by Ben Whaley about how to loosely couple services introducing a queue and the difference in patterns between push and pull communication.</p>

<p>Tags: ben-whaley, push, pull, coupling, loose-coupling, service, queue, aws</p>

<h2>Being good at programming competitions correlates negatively with being good on the job</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched the small video and the discussion about programmers' talent at <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/programming-competitions-work-performance/">this page</a>. By Peteris Krumins.</p>

<p>The original video explains that being good at a programming contest correlates negatively with skill at a programming job, even if the company hires them.</p>

<p>The discussion explains the analogy with height and the NBA and concludes that this parameter should be preponderated with less importance than others.</p>

<p>Tags: google, peter-norvig, nba, analogy, programming-contest, programming-skill, peteris-krumins</p>

<h2>On Functors</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/on-functors/">this comparison</a> by Peteris Krumins of what the functors are in different languages:</p>

<ul>
<li>C++: function objects</li>
<li>Standard ML: generic implementation of interfaces. They allow to compose structures</li>
<li>Haskell: structure containing zero or more objects that can be converted to another structure containing the other objects. It&rsquo;s an homomorphism between two categories.</li>
<li>Prolog: built-in predicate for self-inspection and the atom at the start of the structure</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: peteris-krumins, comparison, haskell, c-plus-plus, standard-ml, prolog, functor</p>

<h2>Recursive Regular Expressions</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/recursive-regular-expressions/">this article</a> on recursive regular expressions by Peteris Krumins.</p>

<p>In it, he lightly describes how a regular expression relates to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-free_grammar">Context-Free Grammar</a> and the language support for Perl to include recursive regular expressions. Based on the examples (e.g., <code>0^n1^n</code>), it really clicked to me that this could be expressed as a recursive function, with its base case and the recursive one. Also that it &ldquo;depends on solutions to smaller instances of the same problem&rdquo; (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recursion_(computer_science)">wikipedia</a>)</p>

<p>Tags: peteris-krumins, regular-expression, recursion, recursive-regular-expression, perl, context-free-grammar, formal-language-theory</p>

<h2>In Functional Programming, what is a functor?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2030863/in-functional-programming-what-is-a-functor/2031421#2031421">this answer</a>, by Norman Ramsey, on what is a functor.</p>

<p>He explains in simple words what the concept is and how a type can belong to the class functor. Examples in haskell.</p>

<p>Tags: norman-ramsey, functor, stack-overflow, haskell, type-class, class, map, fmap</p>

<h2>Functors</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.clojure.net/2013/01/19/Functors/">this article</a> by Jim Duey explaining functors in Clojure. He introduces a couple of notes of Haskell but all of the examples are in Clojure. Explains functors, a subset of it called applicatives, and the two libraries he has created.</p>

<p>Tags: jim-duey, functor, clojure, haskell</p>

<h2>10 Tips for Proper Application Logging</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javacodegeeks.com/2011/01/10-tips-proper-application-logging.html">this article</a> by Tomasz Nurkiewicz about tips on logging:</p>

<ul>
<li>reduce side effects</li>
<li>use categories and levels</li>
<li>connection with external systems</li>
<li>handling exceptions</li>
<li>automatically / manually reading logging files</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: tomasz-nurkiewicz, logging, sl4j, log4j, tip</p>

<h2>What is &ldquo;duck typing&rdquo;?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ericlippert.com/2014/01/02/what-is-duck-typing/">this article</a> by Eric Lippert about duck typing</p>

<p>Tags: duck-typing, eric-lippert, type-system, c-sharp</p>

<h2>Yagni</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve reread <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/Yagni.html">this article</a> by Martin Fowler on the cost of developing features that are not needed</p>

<p>Tags: martin-fowler, yagni, article, misunderstanding</p>

<h2>Learn Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJlI5FPTbgE">this video</a> by Jordan Medlock on learning haskell, explaining the basics and how to use the REPL</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, repl, jordan-medlock, beginner, video</p>

<h2>Learn Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJlI5FPTbgE">this video</a> by Jordan Medlock on learning haskell, explaining the basics and how to use the REPL</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, repl, jordan-medlock, beginner, video</p>

<h2>TMUX - The Terminal Multiplexer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read these two parts: (<a href="http://blog.hawkhost.com/2010/06/28/tmux-the-terminal-multiplexer/">one</a>, <a href="http://blog.hawkhost.com/2010/07/02/tmux-%E2%80%93-the-terminal-multiplexer-part-2">two</a>) of an introduction guide to <code>tmux</code> (the unix terminal multiplexer) by Cody from Hawk Host.</p>

<p>In it, he explains the basics of tmux and the main differences with <code>screen</code></p>

<p>Tags: cody, hawk-host, tmux, how-to</p>

<h2>Thermodynamics and Garbage Collection</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pipeline.com/~hbaker1/ThermoGC.html">this paper</a> by Henry G. Baker that explains the analogy of the garbage collection (&ldquo;a freezer&rdquo;) and thermodynamics, where the state mutator (th program, also an oven) modifies the garbage heap and introduces / extracts entropy into the system.</p>

<p>Comparison between entropy and lack of information, using the theories from Shannon, Maxwell-Boltzmann. There&rsquo;s a reference to the knapsack problem and to simulated annealing.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s also a gentle introduction to thermodynamics in layman terms: heat, temperature, microstates, macrostates, reversability, etc.</p>

<p>In this paper it is also reflected (in macro vs micro states) that the sum all parts is simpler than the single ones (i.e., Information Hiding)</p>

<p>Tags: henry-baker, thermodynamics, microstate, macrostate, analogy, simulated-annealing, garbage-collection, shannon, information, maxwell-boltzmann, freezer, oven, entropy</p>

<h2>How we ended up with microservices</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://philcalcado.com/2015/09/08/how_we_ended_up_with_microservices.html">this article</a>, by Phil Calçado, where he talks about his stay at SoundCloud:</p>

<ul>
<li>the value stream map: from X days to Y</li>
<li>reorganizing teams into service teams</li>
<li>conway&rsquo;s law and teams being responsible for support. Also, being given full authority</li>
</ul>


<p>  Tags: phil-calcado, soundcloud, microservice, team-split, value-stream-mapping, conversion, reorganization</p>

<h2>Lisp is still a secret weapon</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://kep.io/is-lisp-still-a-secret-weapon/">this article</a> by Judd Keppel where he explains it is a good idea that Clojure / ClojureScript continues to be a secret, not known among developers. Cites the article &lsquo;Beating the averages&rsquo; by Paul Graham and the amount of available packages in npm, maven central, etc</p>

<p>Tags: paul-graham, judd-keppel, clojure, clojurescript, weapon, developer</p>

<h2>Perceptron</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perceptron">this wikipedia</a> article that explains the single-layer and multi-layer perceptron. First designed to be a machine (hardware), but later an algorithm for supervised machine learning. Worked by Minsky &amp; Papert and invented by Frank Rosenblatt in 1958.</p>

<p>Tags: peceptron, artificial-intelligence, machine-learning, frank-rosenblatt, 1958, marvin-minsky, seymour-papert</p>

<h2>Is C# a strongly typed or a weakly typed language?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ericlippert.com/2012/10/15/is-c-a-strongly-typed-or-a-weakly-typed-language/">this article</a>, in the form of a dialogue between Eric Lippert and himself about the C# language and its type system.</p>

<p>Tags: type-system, c-sharp, eric-lippert, dialogue, strongly-typed, weakly-typed, language</p>

<h2>Diseño por contratos: construyendo software confiable</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.revista.unam.mx/vol.4/num5/art11/sep_art11.pdf">this paper</a> that explains design by contract, based on the Hoare triplet, pre-post condition, method and class invariant. With examples in Eiffel, Java about a package sender company. Also explains pre/post with inheritance. By Gerardo Rossel and Andrea Manna. In Spanish.</p>

<p>Tags: gerardo-rossel, andrea-manna, design-by-contract, unam-mx, eiffel, java, precondition, postcondition, trust, quality, hoare-triplet, method-invariant, class-invariant</p>

<h2>The Inevitable Return of COBOL</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.hackerrank.com/the-inevitable-return-of-cobol/">this article</a> that explains the current state of COBOL in programming and systems. Written by Ritika Trikha</p>

<p>Tags: ritika-trikha, cobol, programming-language, retirement, median-age</p>

<h2>The Risky Eclipse of Statisticians</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.hackerrank.com/the-risky-eclipse-of-statisticians/">this article</a> where Ritika Trikha explains the current situation regarding Big Data and the statiscian jobs. How Big Data is in demand but the latter are not and what effects this might have.</p>

<p>Tags: ritika-trikha, bootcamp, programming, hiring, big-data, analysis, statistics</p>

<h2>Give it five minutes</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes">this article</a> by Jason Fried where he explains why we should give ideas time to sink in and marinate, before dismissing them. Ideas are so fragile that it is better to let them live for a while before dismissing them. This also applies for thoughts (other people&rsquo;s or your own).</p>

<p>Tags: jason-fried, idea, think, startup, blue-hat, thinking-hat,  six-thinking-hats, red-hat</p>

<h2>Reading Clojure Stacktraces</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jayfields.com/2012/06/reading-clojure-stacktraces.html">this article</a> by Jay Fields on reading clojure stacktraces. Very similar to &ldquo;Clojure Stack Traces for the Uninitiated&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: jay-fields, clojure, stacktrace</p>

<h2>Clojure Stack Traces for the Uninitiated</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/connor-mendenhall/2014/09/12/clojure-stacktraces.html">this article</a> on how to interpret clojure stacktraces. Written by Connor Mendenhall</p>

<p>Tags: connor-mendenhall, clojure, stacktrace</p>

<h2>JavaScript type inference</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve found (and played) with <a href="http://www.ccs.neu.edu/home/dimvar/jstypes.html">this JavaScript type inference engine</a>. Written in Javascript (and available online). Written by Dimitrios Vardoulakis.</p>

<p>Tags: javascript-type-inference, type-inference, type-inference-algorithm, dimitrios-vardoulakis, cfa2</p>

<h2>Alternatives to boolean parameters</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/dariusz-pasciak/2015/05/28/alternatives-to-boolean-parameters.html">this article</a> explaining alternatives to sending a boolean parameter to decide on the contents of the function. Written by Dariusz Pasciak</p>

<p>As I heard some time ago, if a function receives a boolean to decide on what to do, it will for sure have more than one responsibility: one for the false value and one for the true value.</p>

<p>Tags: dariusz-pasciak, boolean, srp, boolean-parameter</p>

<h2>Why Are Web Uploads So Painful?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/why-are-web-uploads-so-painful/">this article</a> on web uploads being painful. By Jeff Atwood. The screenshots feel old (2007) and some of the problems have already been solved.</p>

<p>Tags: jeff-atwood, article, upload, browser</p>

<h2>Can Your Team Pass The Elevator Test?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/can-your-team-pass-the-elevator-test/">this article</a> on the elevator test by Jeff Atwood.</p>

<p>Tags: jeff-atwood, article, elevator-test, assumption, microsoft-bob, vision, product, feature</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in May 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T14:41:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update: I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015
into a single post</p>

<h2>Programmer passion considered harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/on-coding/programmer-passion-considered-harmful-5c5d4e3a9b28">this article</a> on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.</p>

<h2>Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.coursereport.com/blog/software-craftsmanship-are-bootcamps-enough">this article</a> on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by <a href="https://twitter.com/kauerrolemodel">Ken Auer</a></p>

<h2>Improve your development environments with virtualization</h2>

<p>I have seen this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg_vPMnC7_k&amp;feature=youtu.be">Improve your development environments with virtualization</a> by Luke Sneeringer.</p>

<p>My notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>development should be exactly like production.</li>
<li>except where it is too painful. there it should be different</li>
</ul>


<h2>Buffer&rsquo;s take on values</h2>

<p>I have found these <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Bufferapp/buffer-culture-04">values</a>, written by Buffer, very interesting.</p>

<h2>Public static void</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kj5ApnhPAE">&ldquo;Public, static void&rdquo;</a> by Rob Pike. The slides can be found <a href="http://www.oscon.com/oscon2010/public/schedule/detail/13423">here</a></p>

<h3>My notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>too much bureaucracy</li>
<li>fighting the compiler</li>
<li>dynamic vs static typing</li>
<li>language too verbose</li>
<li><p>do not mix the two of them</p></li>
<li><p>a language niche:</p>

<ul>
<li>comprehensible</li>
<li>statically typed</li>
<li>light on the page</li>
<li>fast to work in</li>
<li>scales well</li>
<li>doesn&rsquo;t require tools but supports them well</li>
<li>good at networking and multiprocessing</li>
</ul>


<p>(minute 10:09)​</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://golang.org">Go</a> was born to fill this niche</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Nothing is something</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Software is eating the world</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>The Cost of Test Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.typemock.com/2009/03/the-cost-of-test-driven-development.html">this article</a>, on the cost of doing TDD, which refers to <a href="http://www.msr-waypoint.net/en-us/groups/ese/nagappan_tdd.pdf">this paper</a>: Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams (below)</p>

<h2>Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams</h2>

<p>This paper has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/12/paper-tdd-in-industrial-teams/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched the video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3T00X_sNg4Q">Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</a>, by Howard Abrams.</p>

<p>I guess this is a reference to the popular <a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/">Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!</a>.</p>

<p>He suggests many interesting resources for learning Lisp dialects. The live coding is in Clojure:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://landoflisp.com/">The land of Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/">Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs</a>. See also <a href="https://twitter.com/SICPQuotes">SICPQuotes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-schemer">The Little Schemer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/pdf/eintr.pdf">An Introduction to Programming in Emacs Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.4clojure.com/">4clojure Questions</a></li>
<li><a href="http://clojurekoans.com/">Clojure Koans</a></li>
</ul>


<p>On another topic, in the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/222418104/">Bank accounts exercise from Exercism</a> meetup, we discussed the book <a href="https://pragprog.com/book/shcloj2/programming-clojure">Programming Clojure (2nd edition)</a> by Stuart Halloway</p>

<h2>Professor Frisby&rsquo;s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/DrBoolean/mostly-adequate-guide">this guide</a> to functional programming. It is still work in progress (WIP) but still interesting. Written in javascript, so you can REPL in the browser.</p>

<h2>Learning Code Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video, by Saron Yitbarek: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-nsnAYRqYLA">Learn Code Good</a>.</p>

<h2>Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9FOchgTtLM">Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</a>, by Gregory Moeck.</p>

<p>In it, they point to the <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests</a> book (<a href="/blog/categories/goos">category here</a>), the paper <a href="www.jmock.org/oopsla2004.pdf">Mock Roles, not Objects</a> (also present in the GOOS book).</p>

<h2>Technical Debt: A Repayment Plan</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/tech-debt-repayment">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jeremyjarrell">Jeremy Jarrell</a> on technical debt how to repay it: schedule, taxes, default, etc</p>

<p>This has made me think of the <a href="http://scbcn.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Deuda-t%C3%A9cnica-origen-y-consecuencias/69782-25568">&ldquo;Deuda técnica, origen y consecuencias&rdquo; talk</a> (Technical debt: origin and consequences) (Spanish), that was delivered by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jgomezz">Javier Gómez</a> at the Software Craftsmanship 2014.</p>

<h2>Revisiting XP: be a thoughtful programmer by exercising more collective ownership</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/revisit-p-collective">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tiagooo_romero">Tiago Garcia</a> on the collective code ownership, as stated by Xtreme Programming (XP), with some example and guidelines.</p>

<h2>Where&rsquo;s the Real Bottleneck in Scientific Computing?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.americanscientist.org/issues/pub/wheres-the-real-bottleneck-in-scientific-computing/99999">this article</a> by Greg Wilson on the tools and procedures investigators use to produce software.</p>

<h2>Testing inside the Sprint</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ronjeffries.com/articles/2015-03-01-testing-in-sprints/">this article</a> by Ron Jeffries.</p>

<p>Discusses the need for testing and why this hasn&rsquo;t been communicated enough, as there still are people who have not understood it.</p>

<p>Also about why people equal something failing when using scrum with scrum failing.</p>

<h2>DTO vs Domain Models</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/05/dto-vs-domain-models/">this article</a> by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Homoiconicity isn’t the point</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://calculist.org/blog/2012/04/17/homoiconicity-isnt-the-point/">this article</a> by David Herman about homoiconicity, comparing Lisp dialects (have it) to others that don&rsquo;t. The main point is at the end, where it says:</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] homoiconicity isn’t the point, read is</p></blockquote>

<h2>So You Don&rsquo;t Want to be a Programmer After All</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/so-you-dont-want-to-be-a-programmer-after-all/">this article</a> by Jeff Atwood. Cites the golden handcuffs (also known as golden shackles), reasons to be and not to be a programmer, and how to be an average and outstanding programmer</p>

<h2>The Nature of Lisp</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.defmacro.org/ramblings/lisp.html">this article / introduction</a> to Lisp by Slava Akhmechet</p>

<h2>[David Pollak&rsquo;s] My Thoughts on Go</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.goodstuff.im/golang">these comments</a> on Go Lang from David Pollak</p>

<h2>The Well-Rounded Technologist</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/02/the-well-rounded-technologist.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Should I read papers?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/21/should-i-read-papers.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp-1 vs Lisp-2</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hornbeck.wordpress.com/2009/07/05/lisp-1-vs-lisp-2/">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/hornbeck">@Hornbeck</a> about the lisp 1 and lisp 2.</p>

<h2>Science Corps</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkQkafxFoIQ">TEDx talk</a> by Aza Raskin, featuring Data Banks and Science corps</p>

<h2>Healthy Codebase and Preparatory Refactoring</h2>

<p> I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://brewhouse.io/blog/2014/11/10/healthy-codebase-and-preparatory-refactoring.html">this article</a> by Philippe Creux about preparatory refactoring</p>

<h2>You Are Learning Haskell Right Now (Or Anything You Want Really)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/12/11/you-are-learning-haskell-right-now.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp is Abstract Syntax</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/16/lisp-is-abstract-syntax.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Two Things Types Have Taught Me</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/30/two-things-types-have-taught-me.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t Bet Against Yourself</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Learning Math: A Blank Is A Blank With A Blank</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>The False Economy Of Metaprogramming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/03/06/the-false-economy-of-generated-methods.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Management and Engineering, overlapping</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.quora.com/Does-Adam-DAngelo-feel-comfortable-with-the-transition-from-an-engineer-to-a-management-position?srid=3OC&amp;share=1">this Quora answer</a> by Adam D'Angelo. The original title is: Does Adam D'Angelo feel comfortable with the transition from an engineer to a management position?</p>

<h2>Evolution of The Twitter Stack</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/ly83zQkBjCxnIX">these slides</a> about changing the technology stack in Twitter: from Rails to JVM-based</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
