<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conference on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conference on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold I&amp;rsquo;ve read this listicle of docker myths. By Derick Bailey
Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth
Bored People Quit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.
Some interesting quotes:
 My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.
  My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>Lessons in Agile: Six Months at Pivotal I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Maryam Labib where she explains what she has learned in the last 6 months at Pivotal: how to pair program, how to TDD and some good practices to be a better developer.
Tags: maryam-labib, pivotal, career, professional-career, tdd, pair-programming, team, lessons-learned, experience
Hacking verbal communication systems I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Ryan Alexander on what kind of systems humans use to communicate and how to improve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CAS2014 Wrap up</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/cas2014-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 19:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/cas2014-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>This year&amp;rsquo;s edition of the CAS 2014 has been awesome. There were several tracks:
 Enterprise Agile Collaboration, Culture and Teams Delighting Products Agile+ Development Practices and Craftsmanship  The last one is where I spent most of the time.
The schedule The first day:
 Sandro Mancuso: talking about Software Craftsmanship Jose Manuel Armesto: talking about Unit Testing sucks (and it&amp;rsquo;s our fault) Rubén Martín Pozo: talking about Specification by example - Historia de un equipo que no odia documentar Xavi Gost: talking about La economía del refactoring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
