<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python 3 Boilerplate for Non-Productive environments (e.g., Kata, Study)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/28/python-3-boilerplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 10:03:01 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/28/python-3-boilerplate/</guid>
      <description>I have created a Python 3 boilerplate for non-productive environments. It can be found here: https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/python-boilerplate
Main features Its main features are:
 It can be run locally (local python) or in a docker container (official docker image) It has a Makefile with the most common commands to drive the project. Also, other makefiles in this folder Batteries included: mypy, pytest, pre-commit. Permissive license: MIT. The updated version is here Currently, it is using python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</guid>
      <description>Managing projects with GNU Make, Third Edition book about GNU Make, with recipes and going into detail about how to use it
Tags: book, make, gnu-make, project, skeleton, ci, continuous-integration
Id: 028b0e1f-a181-4469-8789-900ce6641d97 Read: Sun, 01 Jul 2024 17:22:52 +0000
Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs a tool to diff pdfs visually
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319
Tags: hackernews, imported, olshansky, testing, test, diff-pdf, pdf, diff, git, e2e-testing, end-to-end-testing, tool
Id: 4fc53bae-d81c-45b4-9f6b-995ec5d4df6a Read: Tue, 02 Jul 2024 07:26:08 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Threading Macro (clojure) equivalent in Python</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2023/07/22/threading-macro-equivalent-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:38:28 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2023/07/22/threading-macro-equivalent-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In any programming language, it is common to compose functions by pipelining functions: h = g ∘ f such that h(x) = g(f(x)).
The function f is applied first, then g, then the following. 1
For me, it would be more comfortable and easy to understand to write it f COMPOSE_THEN g, indicating that this function composition is not the usual, but a different operation.
Introduction in Clojure This function composition can be written in Clojure by pipelining or chaining functions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/11/01/self-study-november-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/11/01/self-study-november-2022/</guid>
      <description>Doing what you love when the money won’t follow https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33434326
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 509ce49c-c1a4-11ed-afdd-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Nov 2 12:01:16 2022
Ask HN: How to deal with burnout and its consequences? https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33434742
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 52f6012e-c1a4-11ed-b778-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Nov 2 12:38:33 2022
Embedded programming is like web development https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33450575
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 59ea8176-c1a4-11ed-9922-0242ac110004 Read: Thu Nov 3 13:24:05 2022
Ask HN: How to regain focus when you feel overwhelmed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/10/01/self-study-october-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/10/01/self-study-october-2022/</guid>
      <description>The Art of Logging https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33054741
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 02a22390-c1a1-11ed-b61a-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Oct 2 10:42:15 2022
“Rust is safe” is not some kind of absolute guarantee of code safety https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33056077
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 12483f20-c1a4-11ed-84be-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Oct 2 14:20:21 2022
Have lots of AWS accounts Using the physical separation of your AWS accounts as a way to isolate the data and services
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33069547
Tags: aws, aws-account, physical-isolation, isolation, data-isolation, risk-management, imported, hacker-news</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/08/01/self-study-august-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/08/01/self-study-august-2022/</guid>
      <description>A Tutorial on Portable Makefiles (2017) https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32303193
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a4860376-c1a0-11ed-ae57-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 07:43:01 2022
Software engineering books https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32305997
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a23a4924-c1a0-11ed-a585-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 13:57:25 2022
Show HN: Emery – Personal productivity workspace https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32312413
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a6dab644-c1a0-11ed-b024-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 21:42:53 2022
Minify your container https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32334741
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a94d30aa-c1a0-11ed-bb01-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Aug 3 17:42:44 2022
Against Discipline https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32340703</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting from Python to C, using Cython</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/06/18/connecting-cython-python-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/06/18/connecting-cython-python-c/</guid>
      <description>Connecting from Python to C, using Cython Have a look at the generate-kat-core repo. At the time of writing, it&amp;rsquo;s not open-source yet.
Takeaways Automate the creation of the library Create a make goal to:
 Copy the library LIBRARY from its origin to its destination Compile the cython code Execute the above when executing the test goal (to always have an up-to-date version when committing)  If needed, in PyCharm, require the test configuration to execute the make goal first (as a prerequisite)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/06/01/self-study-june-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/06/01/self-study-june-2022/</guid>
      <description>Meet developers 1:1 every week and team up on projects https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31627089
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: 96b84628-c1a0-11ed-b3f2-0242ac110004 Read: Sun Jun 5 01:42:05 2022
AirPlay and Touch Bar = Network Disaster An account of the interaction between AirPlay and Touch Bar (in mac)
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31706283
Tags: airplay, debugging, touch-bar, mac-os, imported, hacker-news
Id: f82bd9d0-ebf2-11ec-a47b-0242ac110003 Read: Sat Jun 11 17:31:03 2022
Cython: Extension types How to create a Cython class that can wrap a cdef field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>How I use reveal.js This author explains how they use reveal.js.
The online editor (slides.com).
The author uses plain html for storing the slides.
Tags: slide, slideshare, reveal-js, reveal, presentation, slide-deck, michael-mccune
Id: 41e287b4-ae15-11e9-9e8a-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 07:16:33 +0000
All your digital life on a single timeline, stored locally Keep your digital life under your control
Tags: backup, local-data, encryption, control
Id: 4d115f64-ae17-11e9-bf0e-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:31:11 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.
Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning
Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Being A Developer After 40 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:
 Forget The Hype Choose Your Galaxy Wisely Learn About Software History Keep on Learning Teach Workplaces Suck Know Your Worth Send The Elevator Down LLVM  He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in July 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post
Clojure made simple I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk Easy made simple
 polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter  Productive pair programming I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about pair programming, using the driver &amp;amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé
Building Automated REST APIs with Python Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
