<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/git/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On private but leaked information in a SaaS</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is another tool for your toolbox: how to uncorrelate public and private information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Context: there are clients who have sensitive information. Some is just &amp;lsquo;companies being stealth&amp;rsquo; (e.g., don&amp;rsquo;t want to make public until launching), some is just protected by a Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA), some are protected by security clearance. The more sensitive, the greater protection needed. This tool applies to all sensitive information, regardless of where it&amp;rsquo;s stored or how it is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More context: there are applications (i.e., SaaS) better installed in the cloud (e.g., expensive or impossible to install on-premise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having sensitive information on the cloud is delicate. There is a fine balance needed to achieve the perfect equilibrium between security, confort, data privacy, cost (among others). Even when using private resources, there is information leaking to the public (i.e., people not included in the designated circle).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example: we create a git repository in an organization, on an online git vendor. For that, we choose the strictest security measures available (e.g. private repositories; private organization details &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). Even then, there&amp;rsquo;s an overlooked piece of information that many times cannot be hidden: the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://gitvendor.com/organization/repository
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;code&gt;organization&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;repository&lt;/code&gt; can be leaked to the public. Even if they&amp;rsquo;re not published (i.e., only available with a link), you can check whether this has been registered or not. Should you have a exposed-enough profile, when there are rumours that your company will launch a new product, people can investigate whether this domain/repo/organization has been registered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one reason why, in the past, project are using a codename. Also, because the final project name has not been decided (e.g., removes choosing the project name from the critical path to start a project).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can use &amp;ndash;at least&amp;ndash; two techniques for using project &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Microsoft_codenames&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;codenames&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alias: choose a catchy name as a codename. Such as Utopia for Microsoft Bob, Longhorn for Windows Vista&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random data: choose a randomly-generated id (e.g., UUID), that is sufficiently random not to be guessed by chance, that does not relate in any way to the project. The downside to this is that it actually bears no relation to the thing, therefore difficult to remember.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: *nix-like systems can generate uuid with &lt;code&gt;uuidgen&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/uuidgen.1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;man page&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a wise choice of where to put your sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you can choose a SaaS solution, keep information private as needed. Be careful with the information you leak. When you are forced to use something public, you can use a codename or random data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;This is not available in all git vendors that I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically keeping the intermediate history of your work using git</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is another tool for your toolbox: using git to automatically document your development process (special cases only.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m spiking a feature, I usually get in the zone (e.g., Csikszentmihalyi&amp;rsquo;s Flow), and I can forget my good engineering practices, searching for that desired answer. After a few of those bouts of coding, you realize you&amp;rsquo;re wandering. You circle around, get lost, get back on track, then get lost again. You might or might not reach your goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes lose the path that took me to the solution. This is helpful when you want to get back on your tracks (e.g., you broke something along the way). But I forget to commit as often as I should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To document, I came up with a (very) simple tool to document the path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  date
  git add .
  git commit -am &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Automatic: Save progress&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  sleep &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create automatic (i.e., meaningless) commits every 10 seconds. It covers the need of &amp;ldquo;not forgetting to save the progress&amp;rdquo;. This script is so small, that there is no point in creating a tool around it. Type it as a one-liner when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create meaningful increments (e.g., a milestone), when you decide that you should save your progress, you can commit as well. The downside is that the automatic commits will pollute your log, and the diff will not represent the full delta. For that, you can create a marker (i.e., one that does not have any diff - use the &lt;code&gt;allow-empty&lt;/code&gt; parameter). That kind of commit is like a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marker_interface_pattern&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marker Interface Pattern&lt;/a&gt;, to pinpoint a specific delta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;git commit -am &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Marker: Completed the ....&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; --allow-empty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to see all the changes, &lt;code&gt;git diff&lt;/code&gt; between two commits (e.g., Markers) or you can rebase with squash (&lt;code&gt;git rebase --interactive&lt;/code&gt;) into another branch (so you keep this history).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic commits to save your progress. To save the progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual commits to pinpoint milestones. To document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tools help you be more productive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the existing choices</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/04/questioning-existing-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 07:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/04/questioning-existing-choices/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a client, we have worked on a service that works with files (containing sensitive data) that get corrupted very often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use case is generally:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two/Three file opens per day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One modification per 10 file opens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One corruption per 100 file opens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-solution&#34;&gt;Initial solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial solution was just to copy the file (&lt;code&gt;file.txt&lt;/code&gt;) before opening, after closing. This results in two files (&lt;code&gt;YYY-MM-DDTHH-mm-ss_before_file.txt&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;YYY-MM-DDTHH-mm-ss_after_file.txt&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this solution quickly became unmaintainable, the client developed a solution to hash the contents of the file and to remove the duplicated files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original cost for developing this was high, as in-house software was needed for comparing the hashes of the files, for comparing the files (remember this is sensitive data). Even if this was just a script, the possibility of deleting correct data is just too much risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if this was a pragmatic choice back then (as they did not realize about the cheaper solution), the danger of deleting data is still present as long as the old script is used. Maintainability wise, that script is simple enough but a defect could be potentially dangerous. (This is why the script for deleting the duplicated files does not actually delete files but generates a bash script for deleting them, which you can review before applying.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-solution&#34;&gt;Another solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about this solution, the client mentioned that this was working well enough. Which is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another solution could be to store this file in a git repository and only commit the changes when there actually are changes to commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The git repository solves both:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the problem of not having to delete data (as no duplicated data is generated)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the cost of writing in-house software, as a single script to commit files is enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This client was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/if_it_ain%27t_broke,_don%27t_fix_it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;if ain&amp;rsquo;t broke, don&amp;rsquo;t fix it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, with a good-enough solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not questioning the existing choice is expensive, putting you in a worse place that you could be. Questioning all the existing choices is expensive, and time-consuming (might lead to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_paralysis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;analysis paralysis&lt;/a&gt;). Finding the sweet spot (whether to question or not), depends heavily on the context.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-look-don-t-tell&#34;&gt;[Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-vida-de-las-ideas&#34;&gt;[La vida de las ideas]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, idea, startup, execution, value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c72f3522-7958-11e8-935c-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:51:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-re-frame-instead-of-om-next-http-t-dripemail2-com-c-eyjhy2nvdw50x2lkijoimzy1mtcxnyisimrlbgl2zxj5x2lkijoimte1ntgzote5mcisinvybci6imh0dhbzoi8vchvyzwx5znvuy3rpb25hbc50di9hcnrpy2xll3does1yzs1mcmftzs1pbnn0zwfklw9mlw9tlw5lehqvp19fcz1moxa2dmrwc2n0ymluagjxyne2eij9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.dripemail2.com/c/eyJhY2NvdW50X2lkIjoiMzY1MTcxNyIsImRlbGl2ZXJ5X2lkIjoiMTE1NTgzOTE5MCIsInVybCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vcHVyZWx5ZnVuY3Rpb25hbC50di9hcnRpY2xlL3doeS1yZS1mcmFtZS1pbnN0ZWFkLW9mLW9tLW5leHQvP19fcz1mOXA2dmRwc2N0YmluaGJxYnE2eiJ9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why re-frame instead of om next&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Eric Normand on why he chose to write a course on clojure front-end framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-normand, clojure, david-nolen, frontend, framework, reframe, om-next, comparison, course, mooc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea43a380-7959-11e8-bd3b-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:59:32 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lexnet-el-software-que-nunca-debió-existir&#34;&gt;[LexNET: el software que nunca debió existir]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on the software called LexNET and the scandal around it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, lexnet, bonilista, software, scandal, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1aa20256-795a-11e8-9b39-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 16:00:53 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;40&#34;&gt;[40]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read this bonilista by David Bonilla explaining some of the things he has learned from 40 years of experience in life. Explains some of his fears and how he has solved them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, birthday, reflection, fear, money, money-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 296a433e-795a-11e8-981e-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 16:01:18 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-lucha-por-la-red&#34;&gt;[La lucha por la Red]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on the net neutrality in Spain and in the European union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, net-neutrality, internet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 395a8984-795a-11e8-9102-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 16:01:45 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-machine-has-figured-out-rubik-s-cube-all-by-itself-https-www-technologyreview-com-s-611281-a-machine-has-figured-out-rubiks-cube-all-by-itself&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/611281/a-machine-has-figured-out-rubiks-cube-all-by-itself/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A machine has figured out Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cube all by itself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how an AI has solved the rubik cube by itself. The team, including McAleer, has used a technique called &amp;ldquo;autodidactic iteration: a way for the machine to create its own system of rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rubik, rubik-cube, ai, autodidactic-iteration, autodidactic, reward, mcaleer, artificial-intelligence, deep-learning, monte-carlo, monte-carlo-tree-search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0cb8305c-7a1d-11e8-9823-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:16:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-tienda&#34;&gt;[La tienda]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on how more and more investors are deciding to do it only on profitable startups rather than a more global strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, investor, startup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6735c620-7a1d-11e8-a2e9-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:18:53 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-not-a-woman-in-tech-https-communequation-wordpress-com-2017-07-05-im-not-a-woman-in-tech&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://communequation.wordpress.com/2017/07/05/im-not-a-woman-in-tech/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I’m not a woman in tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Maria Scrivener on how she does not consider herself a woman in tech. She prefers to lose the labels and just be considered her, herself. Advocates for being inclusive rather than exclusive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: feminism, women-in-tech, maria-scrivener, women, label, equality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7e2fbffc-7a1d-11e8-bbd2-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:19:32 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;password-security-alert-https-blog-8tracks-com-2017-06-27-password-security-alert&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.8tracks.com/2017/06/27/password-security-alert/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PASSWORD SECURITY ALERT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Porter in which they alert their users that their database has been leaked, therefore some passwords are at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The passwords were hashed and salted, not stored in plain text, but those who share a password across services could be at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack has been successful given that a developer didn&amp;rsquo;t have two-factor authentication (2FA) on their github account and the company was using GitHub LFS (git large file system) to store database backups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-porter, backup, storage, configuration, github, 2fa, plain-text, password, security, security-alert, lfs, git-lfs, github-lfs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 97212f3c-7a1d-11e8-bdcd-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:20:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-green-https-blog-cryptographyengineering-com-2017-07-02-beyond-public-key-encryption&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2017/07/02/beyond-public-key-encryption/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Matthew Green&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Matthew Green on the ideas presented by Shamir in 1984: Identity Based Cryptography (IBE), Attribute Based Cryptography (ABE)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rsa, matthew-green, cryptography, identity-based-cryptography, attribute-based-cryptography, shamir, public-key, encryption, private-key&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a942bf96-7a1d-11e8-b122-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:20:44 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starbucks-should-really-make-their-apis-public-https-blog-tendigi-com-starbucks-should-really-make-their-apis-public-6b64a1c2e923&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.tendigi.com/starbucks-should-really-make-their-apis-public-6b64a1c2e923&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Starbucks should really make their APIs public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Nick Lee in which he explains how he has reverse-engineered the Starbucks API so you can connect to it from another device (not only phones, with the app installed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: certificate-pinning, tendigi, nick-lee, security, man-in-the-middle, proxy, api, attribute-fingerprinting, open-api, starbucks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b3ffb61e-7a1d-11e8-a08c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:21:02 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-toggles-are-one-of-the-worst-kinds-of-technical-debt-https-dzone-com-articles-feature-toggles-are-one-worst&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/feature-toggles-are-one-worst&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feature Toggles are one of the Worst kinds of Technical Debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the ups and downs of using feature toggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially with long lived branches and feature by abstraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: feature-by-abstraction, feature-toggle, canary-test, jim-bird, technical-debt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dbb1ff46-7a1d-11e8-b40e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:22:09 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testcontainers-making-java-integration-tests-easy-https-zeroturnaround-com-rebellabs-java-integration-testing-with-testcontainers&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/java-integration-testing-with-testcontainers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TestContainers: making Java integration tests easy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to start a new docker container from Java code (using a junit @rule).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the library TestContainers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: testcontainers, rebel-labs, anton-arhipov, test, docker, image, integration-test, testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f13f63bc-7a1d-11e8-a6a2-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:22:45 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-health-to-comment-or-not-to-comment-http-testing-googleblog-com-2017-07-code-health-to-comment-or-not-to-comment-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://testing.googleblog.com/2017/07/code-health-to-comment-or-not-to-comment.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code Health: To Comment or Not to Comment?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about comments in code: where to use them and when not to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dori-reuveni, kevin-bourrillion, comment, clean-code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 15740b0c-7a1e-11e8-9169-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:23:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saints-and-traders-the-john-henry-fable-reconsidered-https-www-ribbonfarm-com-2014-06-04-saints-and-traders-the-john-henry-fable-reconsidered&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2014/06/04/saints-and-traders-the-john-henry-fable-reconsidered/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Saints and Traders: The John Henry Fable Reconsidered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the guardian syndrome and the Saint syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the story of John Henry, who died right after winning a drilling contest with a machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the finite game and the infinite game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: finite-game, infinite-game, saint-syndrome, guardian-syndrome, comparison, philosophy, venkatesh-rao, john-henry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5228464e-7a1e-11e8-9125-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:25:28 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stacked-pull-requests-keeping-github-diffs-small-https-graysonkoonce-com-stacked-pull-requests-keeping-github-diffs-small&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://graysonkoonce.com/stacked-pull-requests-keeping-github-diffs-small/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stacked Pull Requests: Keeping GitHub Diffs Small&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on using a technique (stacked pull requests) to keep pull requests small and get more feedback, more comments from teammates, therefore reducing the code review fatigue. By Grayson Koonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: grayson-koonce, fatigue, code-fatigue, pull-request, pull-request-fatigue, stacked-pull-request, technique, comment, feedback, teammate, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6e3df860-7a1e-11e8-ba6a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:26:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-hate-almost-all-software-http-tinyclouds-org-rant-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyclouds.org/rant.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I hate almost all software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Ryan Dahl on the focus of the software and the inherent complexity of today&amp;rsquo;s software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ryan-dahl, complexity, software, rant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7ab3fcd4-7a1e-11e8-9590-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:26:36 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-reason-for-developers-salaries-stagnation-https-simpleprogrammer-com-developers-salaries-stagnation&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://simpleprogrammer.com/developers-salaries-stagnation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Real Reason for Developers’ Salaries Stagnation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Im this article, the author speaks of developer salaries related to their skills, proficiency, area of interest and role. Also about the real purchasing power stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: salary, skill, role, position, money, career, career-management, fiodar-sazanavets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a4e26bee-7a1e-11e8-ac68-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:27:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-10x-programmer-https-dev-to-nathanepstein-what-is-a-10x-programmer&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/nathanepstein/what-is-a-10x-programmer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;10x&amp;rdquo; Programmer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about makes a good programmer, under the label of the mythical 10x programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different groups of things in the list: things you are/have (skills) and things you do (actitudes). On the former, writing code (good, business code that is correctly organized, architected, designed), to know a lot. On the latter, ownership for the project (implication, care), teaching and learning from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: 10x, author, productivity, skill, attitude, aptitude, attitude-vs-aptitude, nathan-epstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e5d53f46-7a1e-11e8-9097-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:29:35 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-podcasts-have-become-popular-http-www-donnfelker-com-why-podcasts-have-become-popular&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.donnfelker.com/why-podcasts-have-become-popular/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Podcasts Have Become Popular&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Donn Felker on the effect that the Internet is having on consumers: they now decide when to consume the resources, instead of passively waiting for the resources to appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the suggested explanation for on-demand video vs television, podcasts vs radio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: podcast, on-demand, consumer, internet, donn-felker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f7f8a73a-7a1e-11e8-836d-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:30:06 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-know-what-you-want-improve-these-7-universal-skills-self-discipline-get-better-at-ignoring-the-negative-voice-in-your-head-get-out-of-your-bed-go-to-the-gym-don-t-listen-to-i-don-t-want-to&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Self-Discipline: Get better at ignoring the negative voice in your head. Get out of your bed. Go to the gym. Don’t listen to “I don’t want to.”&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Don’t Know What You Want? Improve These 7 Universal Skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal Effectiveness: Learn how to maximize the results you can get during the 16–18 hours you’re awake. Get more done — effectively.
Communication: We think we’re all master communicators. But the truth is that we suck. Communication is both art and science. And our ability to work with others depends on it.
Negotiation: You negotiate all the time. With your spouse, kids, parents, teachers, friends, co-workers, managers, etc. Learn to get the best deal for all parties.
Persuasion: Learn how to get what you want in an ethical way.
Physical Strength &amp;amp; Stamina: Getting stronger is a skill. Pull your own weight. It’s something every human should be able to do.
Flexibility: Sitting all day long behind your computer or in your car turns you into a stiff being. Learn how to stretch your hips, lower back, hamstrings, and calves — the most common weak points of desk workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0862fbca-7a1f-11e8-83fb-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:30:33 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-concentration-training-program-11-exercises-that-will-strengthen-your-attention-https-www-artofmanliness-com-2014-01-30-your-concentration-training-program-11-exercises-that-will-strengthen-your-attention&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/01/30/your-concentration-training-program-11-exercises-that-will-strengthen-your-attention/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Your Concentration Training Program: 11 Exercises That Will Strengthen Your Attention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Brett &amp;amp; Kate McKay on exercises for training the attention&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brett-mckay, kate-mckay, training, concentration, exercise, focus, attention&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 14f5e064-7a1f-11e8-be86-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:30:54 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-attention-heist-https-lareviewofbooks-org-article-the-great-attention-heist&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/the-great-attention-heist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Great Attention Heist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Bell, John Zada on the current war for attention, what they call the &amp;lsquo;attention heist&amp;rsquo;: publishers fight for your attention, selling it to third parties. The more they can lure you to spend your (finite) attention with them, the higher the profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They talk about two kinds of attention: short span and long span. Reading news is the first while reading a book or a long article is the second one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They mention unplugging (i.e., a &amp;ldquo;digital sabbath&amp;rdquo;) to help improving the level of concentration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(this was a book review, of &amp;lsquo;The attention merchants&amp;rsquo;, by Tim Wu)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-bell, john-zada, attention-heist, attention, app, smartphone, book-review, tim-wu, book, sabbath, digital-sabbath, long-article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3f41e6ec-7a1f-11e8-85fc-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:32:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-read-more-books-http-verraes-net-2012-12-2012-12-23-how-to-read-more-books&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://verraes.net/2012/12/2012-12-23-how-to-read-more-books/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to read more books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mathias-verraes, reading, tips-and-tricks, self-study, training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c451a048-7a1f-11e8-82f7-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:35:49 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serving-100-gbps-from-an-open-connect-appliance-https-medium-com-netflix-techblog-serving-100-gbps-from-an-open-connect-appliance-cdb51dda3b99&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/netflix-techblog/serving-100-gbps-from-an-open-connect-appliance-cdb51dda3b99&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Serving 100 Gbps from an Open Connect Appliance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how Netflix has optimized their servers to be able to send TLS content at 100 Gbps, using openbsd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: netflix, openbsd, performance, optimization, drew-gallatin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dc8f92dc-7a1f-11e8-818a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:36:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rebellabs-developer-productivity-report-2017-why-do-you-use-the-java-tools-you-use-https-zeroturnaround-com-rebellabs-developer-productivity-report-2017-why-do-you-use-java-tools-you-use&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/developer-productivity-report-2017-why-do-you-use-java-tools-you-use/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RebelLabs Developer Productivity Report 2017: Why do you use the Java tools you use?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: java-ee, spring, kotlin, java, jvm, scala, clojure, productivity, rebel-labs, oleg-shelajev, zero-turnaround, 2017, report, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1c603222-7a20-11e8-8f75-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:38:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-paper-is-the-real-killer-app-http-www-bbc-com-capital-story-20170120-why-paper-is-the-real-killer-app&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20170120-why-paper-is-the-real-killer-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why paper is the real &amp;lsquo;killer app&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alison Birrane on how working on a low-tech device is different than on a high-tech device (e.g., taking notes on a paper sheet vs on a laptop). On how it stimulates different parts of the brain. The multiple uses of the paper as compared to the narrowness of the apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alison-birrane, killer-app, comparison, media, social-media, gadget, low-tech, technology, smartphone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 2ac58bdc-7a20-11e8-a82d-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:38:40 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-study-guide-to-machine-learning-https-machinelearningmastery-com-self-study-guide-to-machine-learning&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://machinelearningmastery.com/self-study-guide-to-machine-learning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Self-Study Guide to Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: self-study, machine-learning, jason-brownlee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 388125f6-7a20-11e8-aae6-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:39:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-up-the-behemoth&#34;&gt;[Breaking Up the Behemoth]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Sandi Metz explaining how applications evolve, and what we might do if we&amp;rsquo;re unhappy with the results using:  Design Stamina Hypothesis (Fowler), Procedural vs Object-Oriented Code and X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ood, object-orientation, sandi-metz, martin-fowler, design-stamina, quality, behemoth, monolith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 457003ea-7a20-11e8-a3ff-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:39:25 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-hard-things-to-start-doing-for-yourself-http-www-marcandangel-com-2017-09-24-10-hard-things-to-start-doing-for-yourself&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marcandangel.com/2017/09/24/10-hard-things-to-start-doing-for-yourself/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10 Hard Things to Start Doing for Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this self-help article on how to help yourself by doing hard things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start letting go of unnecessary ideals
Start putting your heart and soul into the things you do
Start stretching yourself just beyond the edge of comfort
Start taking more deep breaths, so you can mindfully collect more lessons for the long run
Start side-stepping senseless drama
Start staying true to your values and convictions
Start looking for silver linings
Start focusing inward more often
Start embracing your humanness and giving yourself more credit
Start taking the next small, insignificant step (one at a time, every day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Marc Chernoff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: marc-chernoff, self-help, meditation, breathing, comfort-zone, help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 53a89846-7a20-11e8-abd1-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:39:49 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;happiness-is-overrated-finding-deep-meaning-in-life-comes-down-to-4-pillars-http-www-businessinsider-com-emily-esfehani-smith-finding-meaning-life-4-pillars-2017-9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/emily-esfehani-smith-finding-meaning-life-4-pillars-2017-9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Happiness is overrated — finding deep meaning in life comes down to 4 &amp;lsquo;pillars&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about what life is about: not happiness but four pillars: belonging and purpose, transcendence and storytelling
storytelling helps people create meaning because it allows people to create, edit, and transform the story of their lives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: happiness, life, fulfillment, pillar, belonging, purpose, flow, transcendence, storytelling,, chris-weller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9737002a-7a20-11e8-a864-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:41:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-time-to-kill-the-web-https-blog-plan99-net-its-time-to-kill-the-web-974a9fe80c89&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.plan99.net/its-time-to-kill-the-web-974a9fe80c89&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;It’s time to kill the web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains the background of the web and how it wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed to support applications but documents. Explains the downsides and security profile of a webapp as compared to a desktop/native application. By Mike Hearn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, web-app, application, app, desktop-app, native-app, mike-hearn, security, html, html5, javascript, web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a3e1c936-7a20-11e8-8fbe-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:42:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-stay-focused-when-you-re-working-from-home-https-hbr-org-2017-09-how-to-stay-focused-when-youre-working-from-home-formcheck-bc3e82f422e9567c25d37e403ee877e6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/09/how-to-stay-focused-when-youre-working-from-home&amp;amp;formCheck=bc3e82f422e9567c25d37e403ee877e6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Stay Focused When You’re Working from Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on structuring your workday while being at home (remote work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure for success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedule your day: when it&amp;rsquo;s work-related time and when not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Elizabeth Grace Saunders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, hbr, harvard-business-review, elizabeth-saunders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b2ddd326-7a20-11e8-9af5-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:42:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cognitive-biases-in-programming-https-hackernoon-com-cognitive-biases-in-programming-5e937707c27b&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/cognitive-biases-in-programming-5e937707c27b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cognitive Biases in Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains some cognitive biases (prejudices of our mind) while programming:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperbolic Discounting: Going for an immediate payoff instead of a delayed larger one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IKEA Effect:Overvaluing your own solutions to a problem, and thus in contrast undervalue other solutions. Also called the &amp;ldquo;Not-Invented-Here (NIH) Syndrome&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premature Optimization: Optimizing before you know that you need to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning Fallacy: Optimistically underestimating the time required to complete a task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recency Bias: Placing higher value on recent events than ones that occurred further in the past&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can never completely eliminate our biases, by being aware of how it is affecting us, we can somewhat mitigate the problems it causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Yash Ranadive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: yash-ranadive, bias, programming, mind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c8742b18-7a20-11e8-b36f-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:43:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keybase-launches-encrypted-git-https-keybase-io-blog-encrypted-git-for-everyone&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/blog/encrypted-git-for-everyone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keybase launches encrypted git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read how to encrypt git repositories using keybase&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: keybase, git, encryption, security, private-key, public-key, storage, archive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dcd43756-7a20-11e8-b0ee-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:43:39 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-and-surprising-http-paulgraham-com-sun-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/sun.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;General and Surprising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how information can be classified as general vs specific and surprising vs unsurprising. How it&amp;rsquo;s best to find a small surprising general thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: paul-graham, surprising, general, information, classification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f611b626-7a20-11e8-8172-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:44:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-built-a-server-less-telegram-bot-over-a-weekend-and-here-s-what-i-learned-https-medium-com-moses-soh-how-to-build-a-server-less-telegram-bot-227f842f4706&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@moses.soh/how-to-build-a-server-less-telegram-bot-227f842f4706&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I built a server-less Telegram bot over a weekend and here’s what I learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on creating a telegram chatbot for a specific purpose. Connects two people (first one subscribes, then the other asks for help and the first is contacted) so the first helps the second. By Moses Soh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: telegram, chatbot, app, moses-soh, side-project, pet-project, project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 25b1e5d6-7a21-11e8-a838-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:45:41 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reviewing-ethereum-smart-contracts-https-blog-gdssecurity-com-labs-2017-9-27-reviewing-ethereum-smart-contracts-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.gdssecurity.com/labs/2017/9/27/reviewing-ethereum-smart-contracts.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reviewing Ethereum Smart Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how to review ethereum contracts and a concrete example of an attack to a smart contract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ethereum, smart-contract, crypto-currency, ico, trustless, security, code-review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5d73322c-7a21-11e8-8e1a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:47:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keep-calm-and-carry-on-scaling-your-org-with-microservices-https-bridgetkromhout-com-speaking-2017-srecon&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2017/srecon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keep Calm and Carry On - Scaling Your Org with Microservices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the slides of this presentation by Bridget Kromhout and Charity Majors about organizations and microservices: the main problem is the communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: charity-majors, bridget-kromhout, microservice, organization, communication, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea81381c-7a21-11e8-b418-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:51:12 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;guía-al-movimiento-noestimates-https-jeronimopalacios-com-2016-09-guia-al-movimiento-noestimates&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeronimopalacios.com/2016/09/guia-al-movimiento-noestimates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guía al movimiento #NoEstimates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jeronimo Palacios, giving an overview of the no estimates movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: no-estimates, jeronimo-palacios, agile, scrum, estimate, forecast, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f6c70a98-7a21-11e8-a896-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:51:32 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-competence-http-www-economist-com-node-12231124&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/node/12231124&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Core competence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article describing what a core competence is and how can we find out if a competence is considered core or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: economy, definition, core-competence, core-business, management, prahalad, gary-hamel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 01a58660-7a22-11e8-b4f8-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:51:50 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-stopped-procrastinating-learned-to-code-and-launched-my-first-product-https-dev-to-lynnetye-how-i-stopped-procrastinating-learned-to-code-and-launched-my-first-product-2i1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/lynnetye/how-i-stopped-procrastinating-learned-to-code-and-launched-my-first-product-2i1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How I stopped procrastinating, learned to code, and launched my first product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining some tips and tricks to launch a side project. By Lynne Tye&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lynne-tye, tips-and-tricks, product, side-project, launch, business, lean, startup, product-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0e85e3f2-7a22-11e8-b818-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:12 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-are-citi-bikes-faster-than-taxis-in-new-york-city-http-toddwschneider-com-posts-taxi-vs-citi-bike-nyc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://toddwschneider.com/posts/taxi-vs-citi-bike-nyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;When are Citi Bikes Faster than Taxis in New York City?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Todd Schneider analysing how city bikes compare to taxis in New York city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good analysis, using a Monte Carlo simulation, written in R. Good data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: todd-schneider, data-visualization, map, city-bike, taxi, cab, new-york, new-york-city, comparison, data, data-analytics, monte-carlo, simulation, r&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 18bc20c0-7a22-11e8-9209-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-9-and-intellij-idea-https-blog-jetbrains-com-idea-2017-09-java-9-and-intellij-idea&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2017/09/java-9-and-intellij-idea/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Java 9 and IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Trisha Gee about upcoming features to IntelliJ Idea 2017.3, centered around java 9 features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: trisha-gee, java-9, jdk-9, java, jdk, intellij-idea, ide, ide-support, jetbrains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 23b8350e-7a22-11e8-a9f3-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:48 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-from-your-attackers-ssh-honeypot-https-www-robertputt-co-uk-learn-from-your-attackers-ssh-honeypot-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robertputt.co.uk/learn-from-your-attackers-ssh-honeypot.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learn from your attackers - SSH HoneyPot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to setup a honey pot machine using honssh. By Robert Putt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-putt, honey-pot, security, honeypot, honssh, attacker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 2e36336e-7a22-11e8-9424-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:53:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-type-or-not-to-type-quantifying-detectable-bugs-in-javascript-https-blog-acolyer-org-2017-09-19-to-type-or-not-to-type-quantifying-detectable-bugs-in-javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.acolyer.org/2017/09/19/to-type-or-not-to-type-quantifying-detectable-bugs-in-javascript/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;To type or not to type: quantifying detectable bugs in JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this paper commentary by Adrian Colyer (on a paper by Zheng Gao, Christian Bird, Earl T. Barr) on a study that tries to reproduce fixes for defects based on the dynamic to static typing system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;both Flow and TypeScript are pretty good, and conservatively either of them can prevent about 15% of the bugs that end up in committed code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see these effects quantified:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the binomial test on the results shows that, at the confidence level of 95%, the true percentage of detectable bugs for Flow and TypeScript falls into [11.5%, 18.5%] with mean 15%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, some recommendations for the future: for typescript and flow to be compatible for more gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original paper: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttendency.cs.ucl.ac.uk/projects/type_study/documents/type_study.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ttendency.cs.ucl.ac.uk/projects/type_study/documents/type_study.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zheng-gao, christian-bird, earl-barr, typescript, javascript, flow, bug, defect, type-system, dynamic-typing, static-typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 398cc606-7a22-11e8-b33c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:53:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-artificial-intelligence-can-be-used-for-password-guessing-https-medium-com-heyfebin-how-artificial-intelligence-can-be-used-for-password-guessing-cf4fd4184a46&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@heyfebin/how-artificial-intelligence-can-be-used-for-password-guessing-cf4fd4184a46&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How Artificial Intelligence Can Be Used For Password Guessing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Febin John James on how neural networks can learn from the leaked passwords and try to guess passwords for existing users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: febin-james, ai, artificial-intelligence, generative-adversarial-neural-network, gann, gan, nn, neural-network, guessing, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 44fe19ae-7a22-11e8-8e06-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:53:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chrome-to-force-dev-domains-to-https-via-preloaded-hsts-https-ma-ttias-be-chrome-force-dev-domains-https-via-preloaded-hsts&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ma.ttias.be/chrome-force-dev-domains-https-via-preloaded-hsts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chrome to force .dev domains to HTTPS via preloaded HSTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Mattias Geniar explaining the having the new Chrome redirecting .dev domains to https means that people using said .dev for local development will have to either provide a https server on their machines or change to another domain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mattias-geniar, chrome, http, https, server, development, test, machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 509c472c-7a22-11e8-81d7-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:54:03 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;six-ways-to-functional-fizzbuzz-with-vavr-https-www-sitepoint-com-functional-fizzbuzz-with-vavr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/functional-fizzbuzz-with-vavr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Six Ways to Functional FizzBuzz with Vavr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Gregor Trefs about solving the fizzbuzz kata using vavr, importing some concepts from functional programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: functional-programming, gregor-trefs, vavr, case-statement, pattern-matching, functional, kata, fizzbuzz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6866497a-7a22-11e8-af91-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:54:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-women-take-on-role-of-cfo-at-home-https-paidpost-nytimes-com-northern-trust-more-women-take-on-role-of-cfo-at-home-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paidpost.nytimes.com/northern-trust/more-women-take-on-role-of-cfo-at-home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More Women Take on Role of CFO — at Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how women act as CFO of their houses (managing 30% of the world&amp;rsquo;s wealth), how they teach money and meaning to their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: money-management, cfo, women, gender, home, house&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 74f60720-7a22-11e8-a9a3-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:55:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-internet-of-things-is-sending-us-back-to-the-middle-ages-https-thenextweb-com-lifestyle-2017-09-13-internet-things-sending-us-back-middle-ages&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thenextweb.com/lifestyle/2017/09/13/internet-things-sending-us-back-middle-ages/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Internet of Things is sending us back to the Middle Ages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by JOSHUA A.T. FAIRFIELD on the right-to-own, right-to-repair and property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the difference in the real property of a smartphone vs a car. On the imaginary, they are the same, but in contractual terms, there is a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joshua-fairfield, right-to-repair, bill, law, property, smartphone, eula, license, clause, imaginary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 80c233ee-7a22-11e8-8743-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:55:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-in-depth-guide-to-personal-cybersecurity-https-medium-com-nickrosener-an-in-depth-guide-to-personal-cybersecurity-be98ba47c968&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@nickrosener/an-in-depth-guide-to-personal-cybersecurity-be98ba47c968&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;An In-Depth Guide to Personal Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this guide to personal security in the net, by Nick Rosener. Examples include 2fa, password management, app security, phone security, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nick-rosener, 2fa, mfa, password, security, phone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 92c637d4-7a22-11e8-baba-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:55:54 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;como-generar-fake-data-en-nuestros-tests-de-aceptación-http-programmeratwork-com-2017-09-06-como-generar-fake-data-en-nuestros-tests-de-aceptacion&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://programmeratwork.com/2017/09/06/Como-generar-fake-data-en-nuestros-tests-de-aceptacion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Como generar &amp;ldquo;fake data&amp;rdquo; en nuestros tests de aceptación&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article (in Spanish) by Ricardo Borillo on using and generating fake data for our tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ricardo-borillo, borillo, fake-data, npm, npm-module, acceptance-testing, test, test-data, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a0be3cd8-7a22-11e8-a5aa-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:56:17 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-crash-bandicoot-gool-part-9-http-all-things-andy-gavin-com-2011-03-12-making-crash-bandicoot-gool-part-9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://all-things-andy-gavin.com/2011/03/12/making-crash-bandicoot-gool-part-9/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Making Crash Bandicoot – GOOL – part 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Andy Gavin on making a lisp for games, an embedded language inside another language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOOL prefers the power and maintainability of a lisp rather than the raw power of a lower-level programming language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: andy-gavin, lisp, gool, crash-bandicoot, game, game-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 46ffc936-7a23-11e8-882f-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:00:56 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-symbolics-lisp-machines-rebuttal-to-stallman-s-story-about-the-formation-of-symbolics-and-lmi-https-danluu-com-symbolics-lisp-machines&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://danluu.com/symbolics-lisp-machines/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;History of Symbolics lisp machines - Rebuttal to Stallman’s Story About The Formation of Symbolics and LMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan Weinreb on the history of lisp machines, the AI winter and the rebuttal of some stories by Richard M. Stallman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-weinreb, lisp, symbolics, rms, richard-stallman, lisp-machine, lmi, dan-luu, ai-winter, ai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5174beda-7a23-11e8-bf1e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:01:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-for-dev-https-github-com-ripienaar-free-for-dev-blob-master-readme-md&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ripienaar/free-for-dev/blob/master/README.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;free-for-dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of (free) resources for programmers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: free-resource, resource, service, amazon, aws, free-tier, free-trial, github&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5bd0ece6-7a23-11e8-8014-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:01:31 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-programmer-should-know-https-github-com-mr-mig-every-programmer-should-know&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mr-mig/every-programmer-should-know&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Every Programmer Should Know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this page on things a programmer should know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: github, programmer, knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 67c8032c-7a23-11e8-9ab7-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:01:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;haste-makes-waste-when-you-over-staff-to-achieve-schedule-compression-http-www-qsm-com-risk-02-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qsm.com/risk_02.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Haste Makes Waste When You Over-Staff to Achieve Schedule Compression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Quantitative Software Management (QSM) on how software projects are affected by the size of the team producing it, with charts and based on previous investigation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: research, meta-research, quality, software, software-quality, qsm, quantitative-software-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 72b999a8-7a23-11e8-b831-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:02:10 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacking-back-considered-harmful-https-blog-0day-rocks-hacking-back-considered-harmful-1ea38f882e8f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.0day.rocks/hacking-back-considered-harmful-1ea38f882e8f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hacking back considered harmful?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by x0rz, a security researcher, on hacking back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;active countermeasure that result in limiting the attacker capabilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whether it is ethical to do it, even if it were illegal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethics is knowing the difference between what you have a right to do and what is right to do. — Potter Stewart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: x0rz, security, hacking, hacking-back, ethic, legality, law, quote, potter-stewart, countermeasure, attacker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7d3d216a-7a23-11e8-8d31-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:02:27 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kurt-gödel-separating-truth-from-proof-in-mathematics-http-science-sciencemag-org-content-sci-298-5600-1899-full-pdf-sid-c031062c-8030-4e2c-8716-04409d7abefb&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/sci/298/5600/1899.full.pdf?sid=c031062c-8030-4e2c-8716-04409d7abefb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kurt Gödel—Separating Truth from Proof in Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Keith Devlin on Goedel&amp;rsquo;s work, especially on the Incompleteness theorem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kurt-godel, kurt-goedel, incompleteness-theorem, bertrand-russell, alfred-north, principia-mathematica, david-hilbert, mathematics, theorem, computability, philosophy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 8bda1c3c-7a23-11e8-b1cb-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:02:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ml-for-the-working-programmer-2nd-edition-chapter-5-https-www-cl-cam-ac-uk-lp15-mlbook-pdf-chapter5-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~lp15/MLbook/PDF/chapter5.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ML for the working programmer, 2nd edition - chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this chapter, to better understand finite and infinite data structures. Talks about streams (called sequences in ML), HOFs, lambda calculus. The book is by Lawrence Paulson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my examples are in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/haskell-simple-sessions/blob/master/trees/src/Trees.hs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/haskell-simple-sessions/blob/master/trees/src/Trees.hs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/javascript-simple-sessions/tree/master/streams&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/javascript-simple-sessions/tree/master/streams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: book, chapter, lawrence-paulson, ml, sequence, hof, lambda-calculus, combinator, stream, lazy-list, data-structure, infinite-list, higher-order-function, function-composition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 97e67a7a-7a23-11e8-bc72-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:03:12 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-hack-the-uk-tax-system-i-guess-https-medium-com-zemnmez-how-to-hack-the-uk-tax-system-i-guess-3e84b70f8b&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Zemnmez/how-to-hack-the-uk-tax-system-i-guess-3e84b70f8b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;how to hack the uk tax system, i guess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this investigation of how a security investigator found a security defect in the UK tax system page and the process of reporting it and seeing it fixed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zemnmez, open-source, uk, hmrc, responsible-disclosure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a4263c08-7a23-11e8-86c0-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:03:33 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;indirect-sale-value-models-http-www-catb-org-esr-writings-magic-cauldron-magic-cauldron-9-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catb.org/esr/writings/magic-cauldron/magic-cauldron-9.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Indirect Sale-Value Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on models for selling/monetising open source. By Eric S. Raymond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-raymond, open-source, monetization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b0788d3a-7a23-11e8-82df-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:03:53 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ll-never-bring-my-phone-on-an-international-flight-again-neither-should-you-https-medium-freecodecamp-org-ill-never-bring-my-phone-on-an-international-flight-again-neither-should-you-e9289cde0e5f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/ill-never-bring-my-phone-on-an-international-flight-again-neither-should-you-e9289cde0e5f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I’ll never bring my phone on an international flight again. Neither should you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Quincy Larson on what happens when you bring your phone over to the US&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: us, phone, privacy, quincy-larson, international-flight, cross-border-flight, flight, device, laptop, burner-phone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: bc93aaf0-7a23-11e8-8ffe-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:04:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remote-starter-kit-http-www-remotestarterkit-com&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.remotestarterkit.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Remote Starter Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this page detailing some tools for a remote position&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, remote-tool, tool, starter-kit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: cfe1bdfe-7a23-11e8-b024-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:04:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-java-forward-faster-https-mreinhold-org-blog-forward-faster&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mreinhold.org/blog/forward-faster&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Moving Java Forward Faster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Mark Reinhold, explaining his proposal for a faster java release train, changing from every two years to every six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: release, mark-reinhold, release-management, release-train, java, sun, oracle, brian-goetz, jre, jdk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dc842498-7a23-11e8-8b35-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:05:07 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keeping-a-tidy-life-https-medium-com-ctrlaltjustine-keeping-a-tidy-life-f01bbe2a9b3e&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ctrlaltjustine/keeping-a-tidy-life-f01bbe2a9b3e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keeping a tidy life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Justine Arreche on how she manages her productivity tools: calendar, todo list; for all the activities in her life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: justine-arreche, productivity, management, calendar, todo-list, activity, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e799c860-7a23-11e8-9f75-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:05:26 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-understand-rising-inequality-consider-the-janitors-at-two-top-companies-then-and-now-https-www-nytimes-com-2017-09-03-upshot-to-understand-rising-inequality-consider-the-janitors-at-two-top-companies-then-and-now-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/03/upshot/to-understand-rising-inequality-consider-the-janitors-at-two-top-companies-then-and-now.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;To Understand Rising Inequality, Consider the Janitors at Two Top Companies, Then and Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Neil Irwin on inequality, explaining the professional career of two janitors at two different companies, in a different period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: neil-irwin, inequality, kodak, apple, janitor, mercer, drucker, management, career-management, career, cto, cio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f66efafe-7a23-11e8-ae3d-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:05:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;episode-8-interview-with-ryan-dahl-creator-of-node-js-https-www-mappingthejourney-com-single-post-2017-08-31-episode-8-interview-with-ryan-dahl-creator-of-nodejs&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mappingthejourney.com/single-post/2017/08/31/Episode-8-Interview-with-Ryan-Dahl-Creator-of-Nodejs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Episode 8: Interview with Ryan Dahl, Creator of Node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read [the transcription of] this interview, to Ryan Dahl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, he describes his view of Node.js and how it is not well-suited for building massive web servers, but could be appropriate for web applications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ryan-dahl, go, microservice, web-app, interview, podcast, web-server, go, golang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 03cbbfca-7a24-11e8-927a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:06:13 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-recovering-programmer-http-prog21-dadgum-com-56-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://prog21.dadgum.com/56.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Recovering Programmer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Hague on the user-centric vision and how he faces the problems related to programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: programming, user-centric, vision, game, assembler, james-hague, recovering-programmer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0db84e2c-7a24-11e8-ac3c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:06:30 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-who-value-simplicity-have-built-incomprehensible-machines-http-prog21-dadgum-com-139-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://prog21.dadgum.com/139.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;We Who Value Simplicity Have Built Incomprehensible Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by  James Hague on examples of libraries that went wrong. How we should have said &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo; early on instead of accepting it. A blog post about simplicity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: james-hague, simplicity, library, complexity, example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 192eae72-7a24-11e8-bc6c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:06:49 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rapid-release-at-massive-scale-https-code-facebook-com-posts-270314900139291-rapid-release-at-massive-scale&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.facebook.com/posts/270314900139291/rapid-release-at-massive-scale/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rapid release at massive scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 24c02266-7a24-11e8-bddd-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:07:08 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;having-a-work-wife-or-work-husband-is-good-for-your-career-https-www-linkedin-com-pulse-having-work-wife-husband-good-your-career-rebecca-holman&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/having-work-wife-husband-good-your-career-rebecca-holman&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Having a &amp;ldquo;work wife&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;work husband&amp;rdquo; is good for your career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rebecca Holman explaining what is a work spouse (i.e., a trusted equal to bounce off ideas, discuss, advance together). Not a mentor, not a trusted boss, not someone reporting to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some of the benefits of finding that role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rebecca-holman, work-wife, work-husband, work-spouse, team-management, work, job, pairing, mentor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3136db02-7a24-11e8-b84e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:07:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rest-apis-are-rest-in-peace-apis-long-live-graphql-https-medium-freecodecamp-org-rest-apis-are-rest-in-peace-apis-long-live-graphql-d412e559d8e4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/rest-apis-are-rest-in-peace-apis-long-live-graphql-d412e559d8e4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;REST APIs are REST-in-Peace APIs. Long Live GraphQL.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about GraphQL and its comparison to REST APIs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: graphql, rest, api, data, comparison, samer-buna&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3df70628-7a24-11e8-9c3c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:07:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-lisp-http-www-formal-stanford-edu-jmc-history-lisp-lisp-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-formal.stanford.edu/jmc/history/lisp/lisp.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;History of Lisp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this paper by John McCarthy explaining the history of lisp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-mccarthy, lisp, invention, language, list-processing, s-expression, m-expression, data, code, lisp-dialect, fortran, ibm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 492eebb4-7a24-11e8-bcec-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:08:10 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-development-450-words-per-minute-https-www-vincit-fi-en-blog-software-development-450-words-per-minute&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vincit.fi/en/blog/software-development-450-words-per-minute/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software development 450 words per minute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article in which Tuukka Ojala explains how his tools for a (blind) software developer: the screen reader, the browser, the braille reader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tuukka-ojala, blindness, accesibility, browser, screen-reader, braille-reader, braille, disability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 54e4e076-7a24-11e8-abd6-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:08:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;compare-your-efforts-30-vs-3000-loc-for-very-simple-mean-app-http-blog-allcountjs-com-post-128771961651-compare-efforts&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.allcountjs.com/post/128771961651/compare-efforts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Compare your efforts: 30 vs 3000 LOC for very simple MEAN app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains the difference between business value and technical value: a feature for the business could be very valuable but technically costly; also the other way around: they are independent variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains that some value in development can be obtained quicker by using a framework, such as the tool that allcountjs provides: 30 lines to generate the equivalent business features to 3000 lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: allcountjs, mean, comparison, crud, framework, javascript, frontend, productivity, business-value, technical-value, cost&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5eea69ce-7a24-11e8-8842-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:08:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-integration-https-medium-com-leanpub-github-integration-6f6d81847230&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@leanpub/github-integration-6f6d81847230&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how to integrate leanpub with github: write your book (e.g., in markdown) and store it in git, then publish automatically to leanpub&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leanpub, github, integration, self-publishing, publishing, book, tool, toolchain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 699d067e-7a24-11e8-9962-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:09:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wysiwtf-https-alistapart-com-column-wysiwtf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alistapart.com/column/wysiwtf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WYSIWTF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Karen McGrane explaining the desktop publishing and the difference between writing and formatting for the web. Also, inline editing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: karen-mcgrane, editing, formatting, desktop-publishing, medium, wysiwyg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7b5f342c-7a24-11e8-b858-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:09:34 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-m-talking-about-when-i-talk-about-tdd-https-medium-com-ramtop-what-im-talking-about-when-i-talk-about-tdd-546a383468be&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ramtop/what-im-talking-about-when-i-talk-about-tdd-546a383468be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What I’m talking about when I talk about TDD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Uberto Barbini in which he describes his re-discovery of TDD as a tool to design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uberto-barbini, tdd, rediscovery, kent-beck, test-driven-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 866b41b2-7a24-11e8-9c54-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:09:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;se-radio-episode-273-steve-mcconnell-on-software-estimation-http-www-se-radio-net-2016-11-se-radio-episode-273-steve-mcconnell-on-software-estimation&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.se-radio.net/2016/11/se-radio-episode-273-steve-mcconnell-on-software-estimation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SE-Radio Episode 273: Steve McConnell on Software Estimation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sven Johann interviews Steve McConnell about software estimation and planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks about intrinsic risk management and extrinsic risk management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains that you should manage the risk so the most uncertain is tackled in the beginning. At the retro (following the demo), you get risk identification (as root cause analysis based on not delivering as expected)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Agile was not to be able to change all the time, but to adapt to change&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embrace change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cone-of-uncertainty, agile, project-management, risk, sven-johann, steve-mcconnell, iteration, scrum, risk-identification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9c543506-7a24-11e8-8c9b-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:10:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-psychology-with-bjorn-freeman-benson-https-softwareengineeringdaily-com-2017-03-28-software-psychology-with-bjorn-freeman-benson&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/03/28/software-psychology-with-bjorn-freeman-benson/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software Psychology with Bjorn Freeman Benson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this podcast on psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: software-engineering-daily, bjorn-benson, psychology, walled-garden&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a90cf1ac-7a24-11e8-a69e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:10:50 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-cqrs-to-make-controllers-lean-with-derek-comartin-https-softwareengineeringdaily-com-2017-03-10-using-cqrs-to-make-controllers-lean-with-derek-comartin&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/03/10/using-cqrs-to-make-controllers-lean-with-derek-comartin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using CQRS to Make Controllers Lean with Derek Comartin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this podcast on CQRS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cqrs, derek-comartin, command-query-responsibility-segregation, greg-young, udi-dahan, red-book, ddd, domain-driven-design, podcast, software-engineering-daily&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b2056db6-7a24-11e8-97d3-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;elm-in-production-25-000-lines-later-https-functional-works-hub-com-blog-elm-in-production-25-000-lines-later&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://functional.works-hub.com/blog/Elm-In-Production-25-000-Lines-Later&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elm In Production: 25,000 Lines Later&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Christian Charukiewicz explaining how he started a new project and a new feature in Elm. How he explained this new technology to his teammates and how it is going now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the pros and cons for the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christian-charukiewicz, elm, compiler, experience-report, frontend, functional-language, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: bc6e1190-7a24-11e8-b19a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:23 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-up-with-alexa-https-www-technologyreview-com-s-608430-growing-up-with-alexa&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/608430/growing-up-with-alexa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Growing Up with Alexa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c2416c52-7a24-11e8-b692-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:33 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jony-s-patience-https-medium-com-mkruz-jony-s-patience-670d5a3dc128&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mkruz/jony-s-patience-670d5a3dc128&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jony’s Patience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Mike Kruzeniski explaining part of John Ive career at Apple and explaining part of the design process the Apple Watch had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ux, design, apple, watch, john-ive, mike-kruzeniski, career, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: cb789e76-7a24-11e8-bdb2-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:48 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-four-month-bug-jvm-statistics-cause-garbage-collection-pauses-http-www-evanjones-ca-jvm-mmap-pause-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evanjones.ca/jvm-mmap-pause.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Four Month Bug: JVM statistics cause garbage collection pauses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this blog post by Evan Jones as an example of unknown unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: evan-jones, unknown-unknown, java, mmap, garbage-collector, pause, unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d4b6a596-7a24-11e8-b245-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:12:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pleasure-of-building-big-things-http-rc3-org-2015-03-24-the-pleasure-of-building-big-things&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rc3.org/2015/03/24/the-pleasure-of-building-big-things/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The pleasure of building big things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining that big projects take time to be created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temptation is all around us, to accelerate feedback loops, create products more quickly, release earlier. That has the tension of being &amp;lsquo;half-baked&amp;rsquo; products, that have not achieved the minimum level of loveable feature and, thus, not used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time, focus, rafe-colburn, product, lean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dddee4c6-7a24-11e8-b11f-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:12:19 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;choose-boring-technology-http-mcfunley-com-choose-boring-technology&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Choose Boring Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan McKinley about how choosing boring (i.e., well-proven) technology can help you focus on your company goals and how &amp;lsquo;the best tool for the job&amp;rsquo; is not always the case, as the job depends on who you ask: developers, ops, business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-mckinley, boring, technology, proven, production-ready, development, operations, focus, business, goal, best-tool-for-the-job&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e91565cc-7a24-11e8-8849-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:12:38 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exclusive-here-s-the-full-10-page-anti-diversity-screed-circulating-internally-at-google-updated-https-gizmodo-com-exclusive-heres-the-full-10-page-anti-diversity-screed-1797564320&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gizmodo.com/exclusive-heres-the-full-10-page-anti-diversity-screed-1797564320&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Exclusive: Here&amp;rsquo;s The Full 10-Page Anti-Diversity Screed Circulating Internally at Google [Updated]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read this document&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: google, scandal, sexism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: fe723d14-7a24-11e8-ab5c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:13:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-your-work-https-8thlight-com-blog-connor-mendenhall-2013-10-31-check-your-work-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://8thlight.com/blog/connor-mendenhall/2013/10/31/check-your-work.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check Your Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 172e94e2-7a25-11e8-86cc-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:13:55 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volver&#34;&gt;¿Volver?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raulavila.com/2017/01/volver/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;donkey-code&#34;&gt;Donkey code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://einarwh.wordpress.com/2017/01/21/donkey-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: einar-host, donkey-code, ddd, domain-driven-development, domain, abstraction, missing-abstraction, business-logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men&#34;&gt;10 Habits That Change Boys Into Men&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men-b103c47d47e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on why some men are still boys (e.g., expectations from society) and what can boys do to turn into men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, psychology, learning, evolution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-command-line-utilities&#34;&gt;My favorite command-line utilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/macbook-my-command-line-utilities-f8a121c3b019#.3hpq7suhj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Vitaly Belman in which he explains his curated list of utilities for the terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: vitaly-belman, terminal, cli, application, utility, tig, git&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-common-mistakes-of-the-first-time-tech-lead&#34;&gt;Three Common Mistakes of the First Time Tech Lead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/three-common-mistakes-first-time-tech-lead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Kua, in which he explains what are the anti-patterns (or mistakes) of a tech lead. They do not only apply to first timers, but more experienced ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially like a comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take all blame and give all credit: I ensure I always take the blame from the stakeholders when something is broken but when they praise, I say its all my teams efforts and I am just guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/by/ravensnowbird/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ravensnowbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: patrick-kua, tech-lead, leadership, team-management, mistake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimental-versioning&#34;&gt;Sentimental Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sentimentalversioning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (unknown author) on alternatives to semver (semantic versioning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: semver, semantic-versioning, sentimental-versioning, humor, parody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devoxx-2015-how-to-become-a-java-champion&#34;&gt;Devoxx 2015: How to Become a Java Champion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http//www.youtube.com/watch?v=otMc_3Dz3hU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Arun Gupta in which he explains what is a Java champion and how to become one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, arun-gupta, java-champion, devoxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-become-a-champion-programmer&#34;&gt;How Can I Become a Champion Programmer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaspecialists.eu/archive/Issue227.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Heinz M. Kabutz on how to become a java champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: heinz-kabutz, java-champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-using-scala-as-a-better-java&#34;&gt;The myth of using Scala as a better Java&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedscala.com/blog/2017/myth-of-scala-as-better-java/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Denis Kalinin disproving &amp;lsquo;Java as a better Scala&amp;rsquo;. He covers dependency injection, database access, serialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scala, java, comparison, orm, denis-kalinin, macwire, dependency-injection, serialization, database, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y&#34;&gt;The eigenvector of &amp;ldquo;Why we moved from language X to language Y&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://erikbern.com/2017/03/15/the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Erik Bern on the statistical analysis (based on people writing blog posts) of moving from language X to language Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can help predict which languages will be more prevalent in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eigenvector, statistic, erik-bern, language, programming-language, java, c, cplusplus, go, python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;facebook-s-code-quality-problem&#34;&gt;Facebook’s code quality problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.darkcoding.net/software/facebooks-code-quality-problem/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Graham King on the problems that Facebook is facing, at the code level, and how they solve some of them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: graham-king, facebook, quality, architecture, code-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-key-lesson-from-our-serverless-migration&#34;&gt;The key lesson from our serverless migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=abe09ce689751513abf6f095f&amp;amp;id=6ecb59a937&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gojko Adzic on serverless, a kind of lessons learned. Explains that their system can take 50% more users at 50% of the original cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains three ways of authenticating users: use IAM users, use Cognito, pre-sign URLs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lessons-learned, gojko-adzic, serverless, paas, platform-as-a-service, retrospective, money, total-cost-of-ownership, tco,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-automation-goes-horribly-wrong&#34;&gt;When automation goes horribly wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Gojko Adzic on a story of a manual process that was automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it focused too much on replacing humans instead of assisting them, MiDAS actually made it more difficult for clerks to access the data they needed for review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of the framework vs library discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in frameworks you relinquish the control, putting your code into the allocated holes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using the automated system, you can only check the claim at a certain spot, where the system lets you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system and the framework have been designed to take control of the situation. Both successful at what they do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gojko-adzic, automation, framework, library, framework-vs-library, comparison, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-store-my-1-s-and-0-s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy&#34;&gt;How I Store My 1’s and 0’s: ZFS  Bargain HP Microserver = JOY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mocko.org.uk/b/2012/06/17/how-i-store-my-1s-and-0s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Alex stores his backups, using a microserver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: backup, microserver, raid, zfs, backup-strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-policy&#34;&gt;Meeting policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/ueno/meeting-policy-9b04593d1b28&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by the Ueno team on how they handle meetings. Interesting that they require manager approval for meetings over a certain threshold (more than four people or more than half an hour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ueno, meeting-policy, meeting, approval&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-random-numbers&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Random Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/a-brief-history-of-random-numbers-9498737f5b6c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carl Tashian on how random numbers have evolved (from dice to pseudo random number generator and random number generators). Explain how some companies that need true randomness (e.g., certificates company) generate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: carl-tashian, dice, random-number, randomness, prng, pseudo-random-number-generator, random-number-generator, number-generator, true-random-number-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word&#34;&gt;Unlock honest feedback with this one word&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word-dcaf3839e7ee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Claire Lew, in which she suggests to ask for &amp;lsquo;advice&amp;rsquo; instead of asking for &amp;lsquo;feedback&amp;rsquo; as a way of getting more honest and better responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: claire-lew, advice, feedback, feedback-process, improvement&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliberate-practice-what-it-is-and-why-you-need-it&#34;&gt;Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four essential components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailored (practice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetion
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language&#34;&gt;10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jooq.org/2016/03/31/10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list of features&lt;/a&gt; that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language. By Lukas Eder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: list, lukas-eder, kotlin, java, comparison, language, jooq&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-built-uber-engineering-s-highest-query-per-second-service-using-go&#34;&gt;How we built Uber engineering&amp;rsquo;s highest query per second service using Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.uber.com/go-geofence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kai Wei on a microservice they&amp;rsquo;ve built using Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the reasons for choosing that algorithm for geofencing, the performance they&amp;rsquo;re achieving, and the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uber, go, microservice, performance, geofence, geofencing, rps, go-memory-model, kai-wei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service&#34;&gt;Unwinding Uber&amp;rsquo;s Most Efficient Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@buckhx/unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service-406413c5871d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Buck Heroux commenting on the decisions of Uber for building the geofencing microservice (above read).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the different alternatives for algorithms in this problem space and has implemented them in go. Provides a benchmark for comparing those, including a profiling session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: s2, quadtree, rtree, brute-force, geofence, geofencing, uber, comment, buck-heroux, go, read-on-read, meta-read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawful-hacking-and-continuing-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Lawful Hacking and Continuing Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/03/lawful_hacking_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on the stance the FBI is taking in regards to vulnerabilities discovered in Apple&amp;rsquo;s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, apple, security, fbi, vulnerability, exploit, law, hacking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-life-learning&#34;&gt;A Side Project Helped Jumpstart My Career — Life Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/life-learning/a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-7cd6f8e9b07f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dave Gerhardt on how making a side project happen affected his life and his skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons for doing it include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It forces you to figure stuff out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way to learn is by doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gets your brain working on something other than your job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to create your own network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are the CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: long-life-learning, continuous-learning, side-project, dave-gerhardt, drift, professional-development, personal-development, business, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-jekyll-tricks&#34;&gt;Fun Jekyll Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.madebymarket.com/blog/dev/fun-jekyll-tricks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Knapp where he explains some tips and tricks of jekyll (in which octopress is based on): speed, deployment, subcategories inside the blog, _data, _includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brian-knapp, jekyll, octopress, tip-and-trick, improvement, subcategory, meta, automation, deployment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-ola-que-llega&#34;&gt;La ola que llega&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=f8a8ee92cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla, where he explains (in Spanish) the &amp;lsquo;contractor&amp;rsquo; phenomenon arriving to Spain, 2-3 years after being in other countries and the effects that this could have both for workers and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bonilista, david-bonilla, contractor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-razones-por-las-que-este-sábado-deberías-ir-a-un-code-retreat&#34;&gt;10 razones por las que este sábado deberías ir a un code retreat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://francho.org/2015/11/10/10-razones-para-ir-a-un-coderetreat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of reasons for attending a code retreat, by Francho Joven, who I met in the Global Day Of Code Retreat (GDCR) &amp;lsquo;15 in Zaragoza&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: francho-joven, list, zaragoza, code-retreat, gdcr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meaningful-work-through-passion-not-genius&#34;&gt;Meaningful Work through Passion, not Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIYUMwxKFzo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; on the importance of hard work and how it can be mistaken as genious. By Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: malcolm-gladwell, passion, genius, work, time-management, productivity, career, mastery-autonomy-purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name&#34;&gt;How to ask your wife for permission to spend $250,000 on a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Stockphoto.com/how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name-c27a3c2852e1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jon Yau on how they started StockPhoto.com, buying a $250,000 domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: startup, domain, stockphoto, jon-yau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong&#34;&gt;Sorry, developer bootcamps: I was wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@dillonforrest/sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong-ea37fcc5572c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dillon Forrest on the topic of developer bootcamps. Explains why developers should not be threatened by recent graduates of these programs and describes how people pursuing these programs usually are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bootcamp, developer-bootcamp, dev-bootcamp, dillon-forrest, intelligence, risk-appetite, resilience, self-investment, entrepreneurship, growth-trajectory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jvm-and-java-garbage-collection&#34;&gt;The JVM and Java Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoJr5QQYsl8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this webcast&lt;/a&gt; about how the JVM garbage collection works. By Michael W Williams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-williams, oracle, webcast, jvm, garbage-collection, gc,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;files-are-hard&#34;&gt;Files Are Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/file-consistency/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why software that writes on files is difficult, based on the different filesystems that are below, and the operating system. Written by Dan Luu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses software product to find bugs in filesystems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: filesystem, file, dan-luu, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusión-inquebrantable&#34;&gt;Contrata a un fracasado con ilusión inquebrantable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contunegocio.es/tecnologia/contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusion-inquebrantable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alberto Mena (in Spanish) on what are the qualities that define a good programmer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;illusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-mena, spanish, team-management, success, developer, quality, developer-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-react&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t react&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.avdi.org/2016/04/14/dont-react/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Avdi Grimm on how the action vs reaction attitude. Why to prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: action, reaction, social-media, avdi-grimm, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34;&gt;FTP is so 90&amp;rsquo;s. Let&amp;rsquo;s deploy via Git instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderwall.com/p/xczkaq/ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to deploy using git. By Kerrick Long&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kerrick-long, git, deployment, webapp, application, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-vs-career-10-key-differences-you-need-to-understand&#34;&gt;Job vs Career: 10 Key Differences You Need To Understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/job-vs-career&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what differentiates a job from a career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, infographic, job-vs-career, comparison, job, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-secret-to-employee-motivation&#34;&gt;The Secret To Employee Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/secret-employee-motivation-infographic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what motivates employess: mastery, autonomy and purpose. A direct reference to Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The puzzle of motivation&amp;rdquo; TED talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, motivation, employee, infographic, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-puzzle-of-motivation&#34;&gt;The puzzle of motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Pink on what motivates us: intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about the gap that exists between what science knows and what businesses propose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ted, ted-talk, video, dan-pink, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count&#34;&gt;Applying a ceiling to the bug count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techblog.king.com/applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, written by Susanna Berg, on how King has reduced the amount of bugs in their backlog using an agile technique, measuring and setting a limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: susanna-berg, king, agile, bug, bug-count, defect, defect-count, per-malmen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34;&gt;Coming up in 2016: Spring Framework 4.3 &amp;amp; 5.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://spring.io/blog/2015/08/03/coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this announcement&lt;/a&gt; of Spring&amp;rsquo;s new release, 5.0, which will require java 8 and will turn most of the features into the reactive programming paradigm. By Juergen Hoeller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: juergen-hoeller, spring, reactive-programming, release, announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die&#34;&gt;Why offices are where work goes to die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swizec.com/blog/why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die/swizec/6695&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Swizec Teller explaining the downsides of working in an office as compared to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: swizec-teller, remote, home-office, office, comparison, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Passionate Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bm2yogi/the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer-76a41d457304&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Ibarra on what are the implications of being a passionate developer, how it affects your tasks and what are the factors to a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-ibarra, passion, development, job, motivation, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mossack-fonseca-breach-wordpress-revolution-slider-plugin-possible-cause&#34;&gt;Mossack Fonseca Breach – WordPress Revolution Slider Plugin Possible Cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2016/04/mossack-fonseca-breach-vulnerable-slider-revolution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Maunder, which describes an hypothesis on how the Mossack Fonseca breach could have happened. Also describes and shows how to breach a Wordpress installation with a vulnerable Revolution Slider plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mark-maunder, security, breach, mossack-fonseca-breach, mossack-fonseca, hypothesis, attack, plugin, revolution-slider, wordpress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tim-urban-inside-the-mind-of-a-master-procrastinator&#34;&gt;Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; from Tim Urban on how the procrastinator&amp;rsquo;s mind works, exemplified by his own career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: procrastinator, procrastination, mind, time-management, tim-urban&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pep-20-the-zen-of-python&#34;&gt;PEP 20 &amp;ndash; The Zen of Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the PEP20&lt;/a&gt;, the zen of python, with special attention to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: pep-20, pep, python, zen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Why I switched from Octopress 2 to Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Franklin Chen on the change he made on the static site generator (SSG) he used. He considered hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo. Was decided between hakyll and hugo for their speed but, finally, decided to use hugo for their bigger community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: franklin-chen, comparison, ssg, static-site-generator, hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo, change, speed, statically-typed, dynamically-typed, golang, performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-incremental-regeneration-in-jekyll-3-0-is-such-a-big-deal&#34;&gt;Why incremental regeneration in Jekyll 3.0 is such a big deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/11/04/jekyll-30-released-incremental-regeneration-rocks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Johnson on one of the new features that jekyll 3.0 brings: incremental generation. How this can speed up the generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-johnson, incremental-generation, speed, performance, octopress-2, octopress-3, jekyll-3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-s3-travis-ci-oh-boy&#34;&gt;Hugo, S3, Travis CI, oh boy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://continuousfailure.com/post/s3_blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Scherger on how to set up a specific stack for developing and deploying a static site blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alan-scherger, static-site-generator, ssg, travis, hugo, s3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-your-blog-to-github-pages-automatically-using-hugo-and-travis&#34;&gt;Deploy your blog to github pages automatically using Hugo and Travis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcoedo.com/post/hugo-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Roman Coedo on how to deploy a hugo blog to github pages, using travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: roman-coedo, travis, hugo, github, github-pages, ssg, static-site-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;improve-octopress-with-advanced-tweaks-tips&#34;&gt;Improve Octopress with Advanced Tweaks &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.narga.net/improve-octopress-advanced-tweaks-tips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tips on how to improve the octopress (2) installation. By Nguyễn Đình Quân.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nguyen-dinh-quan, octopress-2, tip, tweak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;laboratorios&#34;&gt;Laboratorios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2014/11/12/laboratorios/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla, about laboratories to use a percentage of company time to investigate, innovate, learn and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, team-management, time-management, innovation, strategy, improvement, kaizen, laboratory, craftsmanship, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isn-t&#34;&gt;What Refactoring is, and what it isn’t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swreflections.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isnt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Bird, where he splits some practices into refactoring and not refactoring. Draws the line between these two different activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also cites scratch refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jim-bird, scratch-refactoring, refactoring, martin-fowler, kent-beck, definition, quote, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitfalls-of-unlimited-vacations&#34;&gt;Pitfalls of Unlimited Vacations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/archive/2016/02/18/unlimited-vaction-pitfalls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Phil Haack on the github, travis and netflix policies about unlimited vacations and the effects they have on the employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about minimum vacation periods, (paternity) paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: phil-haack, unlimited-vacation, holiday, vacation, team-management, burnout, github, travis, netflix, policy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultura-corporativa&#34;&gt;Cultura Corporativa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2011/02/06/cultura-corporativa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla about the corporate culture, and how &amp;ldquo;hanging a highly interchangeable sentence on a wall&amp;rdquo; does not represent it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, corporate culture, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code&#34;&gt;What It’s Really Like to Learn to Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sandjar/what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code-53f6d9156a32&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains firsthand how it is to learn programming for a novice student,even with a strong financial background and having completed a university degree. By Sandjar Kozubaev&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sandjar-kozubaev, learning, programming, student, firsthand, coding, story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: using tortoise credentials in git CLI</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/using-tortoise-credentials-from-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/using-tortoise-credentials-from-cli/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tortoisegit-part&#34;&gt;TortoiseGit part&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to a repo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;right button, Settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git -&amp;gt; Credential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a creadential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Config type: global&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helper: wincred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sync once using your HTTPS password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cli-part&#34;&gt;CLI part&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the &lt;code&gt;$REPO/.git/config&lt;/code&gt; and add&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[credential]
	helper = wincred
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remote git operations should not ask for credentials anymore&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two persons involved in a git commit, in github</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/14/two-persons-involved-in-a-git-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 17:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/14/two-persons-involved-in-a-git-commit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-git&#34;&gt;On git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have multiple persons involved in a single git commit: an author and a committer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is explained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/repo-discuss/6aH9rH8nUdo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Manuel Doninger&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is the one who did the code change.
The committer is the person who committed that change to a repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;an example, by the same author:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m not a committer in the EGit project, so i have no rights
to push directly to the EGit repository at Eclipse. But i contribute
to EGit, so my changes have the author set to my name and email. If my
change gets reviewed by the EGit team, and submitted, the committer
field contains the name and email of the person who submitted the
change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-github&#34;&gt;On github&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is represented in github with this format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/uploads/commit-with-two-persons.png
&#34; alt=&#34;two persons involved&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of them is &amp;ldquo;sharplet&amp;rdquo; and the other one is &amp;ldquo;gfontenot&amp;rdquo;. Both are github users that match a github-registered mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a shallow inspection, the commit does not reveal anything special:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ g log 17a96dba38479de78cdb3b3aae1c802f4d54f485 -n1 --full-diff
commit 17a96dba38479de78cdb3b3aae1c802f4d54f485
Author: XXXX &amp;lt;xxxx@example.com&amp;gt;
Date:   Wed Dec &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;:44:52 &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt; +1100

    Clarify specs by defining • as the composition operator
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but looking a bit closer&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ g log 17a96dba38479de78cdb3b3aae1c802f4d54f485 -n1 --dense --full-diff --format&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;%H, %h, %T, %t, %P, %p, %an, %aN, %ae, %aE, %ad, %aD, %ar, %at, %ai, %cn, %cN, %ce, %cE, %cd, %cD, %cr, %ct, %ci, %cI, %d, %D, %e, %s, %f, %b, %B&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; less
17a96dba38479de78cdb3b3aae1c802f4d54f485, 17a96db, 6bc2a33e3a069b78b9fd36124f5ed039a125303e, 6bc2a33, 29488bc0be27c5c03b6af7d115c7d45645382a7a, 29488bc, XXXX, XXXX, xxxx@example.com, xxxx@example.com, Wed Dec &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;:44:52 &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt; +1100, Wed, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; Dec &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;:44:52 +1100, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; months ago, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1449027892&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;-12-02 &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;:44:52 +1100, YYYY, YYYY, yyyy@example.com, yyyy@example.com, Tue Dec &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;09&lt;/span&gt;:30:28 &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt; -0800, Tue, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt; Dec &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;09&lt;/span&gt;:30:28 -0800, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; weeks ago, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1450200628&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/span&gt;-12-15 &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;09&lt;/span&gt;:30:28 -0800, %cI, , %D, , Clarify specs by defining • as the composition operator, Clarify-specs-by-defining-as-the-composition-operator, , Clarify specs by defining • as the composition operator
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or, just the emails:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ g log 17a96dba38479de78cdb3b3aae1c802f4d54f485 -n1 --dense --full-diff --format&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;%ae %ce&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
xxxx@example.com yyyy@example.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a single commit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;GIT_COMMITTER_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;John Doe&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;john@example.com&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; git commit -m &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;...&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a session:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export GIT_COMMITTER_NAME=&#39;John Doe&#39;
export GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL=&#39;john@example.com&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken from &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/a/23108169/1181094&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this StackOverflow answer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be useful for a pairing session or for some kinds of git history rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 2016-10: We have this script to make it easier to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;pair_with&lt;/code&gt; to pair with someone and &lt;code&gt;solo&lt;/code&gt; to work on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place this on your &lt;code&gt;~/.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~/.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; or similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; solo &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;unset&lt;/span&gt; GIT_COMMITTER_NAME
  &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;unset&lt;/span&gt; GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL
&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; pair_with_ &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;GIT_COMMITTER_NAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;export&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;GIT_COMMITTER_EMAIL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; pair_with_john &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    pair_with_ &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;John Doe&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;jd@example.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 2, 2016-10: This script also helps with managing the variables: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/git-duet/git-duet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;git-duet&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dhatanian&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;David Hatanian&lt;/a&gt; for the tip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;also explained in &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/6755824/what-is-the-difference-between-author-and-committer-in-git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this StackOverflow post&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;this list has been generated from the available arguments at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-log&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;pretty formats&amp;rdquo; at the git-log page&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool: Building a local pipeline</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a client, one of the projects has a long building process and the tests are mostly slow, so I use a local building &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pipeline_(software)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pipeline&lt;/a&gt;, an example of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/library/dn568100.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pipes and Filters&lt;/a&gt; pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows for executing manually only the fast unit tests, then automatically (no user intervention, no time spent) executing the rest of them before pushing. In case the latter fails, it is possible to do &lt;code&gt;git push -f&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;pipeline&lt;/code&gt; without corrupting the central repository (&lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt;) history, possibly disturbing others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This strategy also allows for parallel modification of sources: you can continue working on your IDE while the compiler is working on the other working directory. Should you introduce any syntax / logical error on your working code, the compiler is not affected, as it has a working copy just for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementation&#34;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This requires two git repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;local&lt;/code&gt; or working copy. Configure it so it has a remote called &lt;code&gt;pipeline&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt;, the repository you cloned from. This is a non-bare repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pipeline&lt;/code&gt;, used for building. This also is a non-bare repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;local&lt;/code&gt; you can do the development and local commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re done, instead of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;git push origin &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;git push pipeline &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the git hook is installed, this will trigger the pipeline execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;git-hook&#34;&gt;Git hook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;pipeline&lt;/code&gt;, in the &lt;code&gt;.git/hooks/post-receive&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ch&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;
chmod +x pipeline.sh
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt; oldrev newrev refname
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# whatever you want to execute&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;branch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;git rev-parse --symbolic --abbrev-ref &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$refname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  ./pipeline.sh &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above script, we&amp;rsquo;re telling git to execute the &lt;code&gt;pipeline.sh&lt;/code&gt; with the received branch as argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pipeline-executor&#34;&gt;Pipeline executor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;pipeline&lt;/code&gt; repository, in &lt;code&gt;.git/pipeline.sh&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ch&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; -e
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; -o pipefail

&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; cleanup &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  git checkout develop
  git pull develop
&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# upon failure, tell the user&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; err &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  cleanup
  growlnotify &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;pipeline fails&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# trap signal ERR, executing function &amp;#39;err&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;trap&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;err&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; ERR

&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;branch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt; -z &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;need to specify a branch&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt; -1
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

git checkout &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt;
mvn clean install &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; tee output.log
git push --set-upstream origin &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt;
cleanup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;pipeline-executor-explanation&#34;&gt;Pipeline executor explanation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We prepare the bash environment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-e&lt;/code&gt;: fail the script when a command fails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-o pipefail&lt;/code&gt;: fail the script when some command fails in a pipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;err&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;trap&lt;/code&gt;: create a hook to be executed when the signal is trapped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We require a branch to execute this script.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Checkout to that branch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean, compile &amp;amp; execute tests&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Push to origin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean up&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case this fails, the script will stop and notify the user with &lt;code&gt;growl&lt;/code&gt; and clean up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean up: checkout to develop (or any other branch that always exists), leaving the system prepared to execute again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notifications-telling-the-user&#34;&gt;Notifications: telling the user&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program &lt;code&gt;growlnotify&lt;/code&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growlforwindows.com/gfw/help/growlnotify.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CLI notifier&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;code&gt;growl&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growlforwindows.com/gfw/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mattn.github.io/growl-for-linux/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;linux&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the tests should be faster, and executing them locally should always be possible, maybe in the &lt;code&gt;pre-commit&lt;/code&gt; hook. Whenever this is not possible, a local pipeline can reduce the time spent waiting for test execution and remove the lock on the working directory while the compiler is working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pipeline aims to be simple, without many customizations and being single-user. For more complex workflows and other restrictions, it might be better to drop this project and start investigating continuous integration (CI) tools such as e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://jenkins-ci.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Travis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://atlassian.com/software/bamboo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bamboo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-work&#34;&gt;Further work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jobs in the &lt;code&gt;pipeline&lt;/code&gt; could be queued, so it is possible to push to the pipeline before the previous job has started. See reference below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tldp.org/LDP/Bash-Beginners-Guide/html/sect_12_02.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/bash/manual/html_node/The-Set-Builtin.html#The-Set-Builtin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Set Builtin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://idolinux.blogspot.com/2008/08/bash-script-error-handling.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sample bash error handling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://superuser.com/questions/220364/how-to-run-commands-as-in-a-queue&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Queuing bash jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;appendix&#34;&gt;Appendix&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script will push to the pipeline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;ch&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

git push pipeline  &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; /dev/null &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: massively reverting local changes</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-massively-reverting-local-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-massively-reverting-local-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was changing a massive amount of files (&amp;gt;1000) for a repeated code. The search and replace query was not too exact and it broke many tests in the system. For that, I preferred reverting those tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it automatically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy all the failing tests to a text editor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;testSearchXMLDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testCreateXMLDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testUpdateXFPageMetadata(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testCreateDocumentCrop(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testUpdateCropMetadata(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testDeleteDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testUpdateXmlDocumentMetadata(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testUpdateXML(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testSearchXFPage(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testCreateXFPage(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testUpdatePage(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testSearchCrop(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testUpdateCrop(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testMoveDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
testGetDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;regex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(tested in Sublime 3, build 3083, Windows 64)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;find what: &lt;code&gt;^[^(]+\([a-Z.]*\.(.*)\)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;replace with: &lt;code&gt;$1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regex explanation for &lt;code&gt;^[^(]+\([a-Z.]*\.(.*)\)&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;^&lt;/code&gt;: beginning of line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;[^(]+&lt;/code&gt;: every character except parenthesis, one or more times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\([a-Z.]*&lt;/code&gt;: start with one parenthesis, any number of a-z, A-Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\.&lt;/code&gt;`: a dot, as I&amp;rsquo;m using regex replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;(.*)&lt;/code&gt;: any character, zero or more times, captured in group &lt;code&gt;$1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;\)&lt;/code&gt;: closing parenthesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
DocumentControllerTest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;copy that to file &lt;code&gt;a.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revert all the changes in these files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; i in &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;cat a.txt &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; uniq&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  git checkout -- *&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$i&lt;/span&gt;*
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: committing to the repo file by file</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-committing-to-the-repo-file-by-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-committing-to-the-repo-file-by-file/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was prefer committing to the repo with commits that are as small as possible as long as it makes sense. It makes it much easier to rever the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I have some scripts to commit all the changes, even with the same message. This is one of them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; f in &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;git status -s &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;grep &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;^M&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;awk &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;{print $2}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  git add &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;$f&lt;/span&gt;
  git commit -m &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;generic commit for all files&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015
into a single post&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;le-monitoring-de-flux-par-l-exemple&#34;&gt;Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.octo.com/le-monitoring-de-flux-par-lexemple/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-micro-service-architecture&#34;&gt;The First Micro-service Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2015/05/28/TheFirstMicroserviceArchitecture.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-learned-to-balance-my-life-with-remote-work&#34;&gt;How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.bufferapp.com/remote-work/?utm_content=bufferaa5a2&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;demystified-cqrs&#34;&gt;Demystified CQRS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codecentric.de/en/2015/05/demystified-cqrs/?utm_content=buffer35b18&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about CQRS by Nino Martincevic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-perils-of-programmer-education-in-the-bazaar&#34;&gt;The perils of programmer education in the bazaar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.practicingruby.com/2015/06/04/the-perils-of-programmer-education-in-the-bazaar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gregory Brown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-useful-and-lesser-known-git-commands&#34;&gt;6 useful and lesser-known git commands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.joncairns.com/2015/05/6-useful-and-lesser-known-git-commands/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about git commands (log, checkout, stash, cherry-pick, annotate) by Jon Cairns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-your-scrum-standup-slowing-you-down&#34;&gt;Is Your Scrum Standup Slowing You Down?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sitepoint.com/scrum-standup-slowing-down/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by M. David Green&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;me-duele-indra&#34;&gt;Me duele Indra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=67ce79e01b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this Bonilista&lt;/a&gt; (Spanish) by David Bonilla&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tdd-bdd-add-every-other-method-that-promises-software-quality-here-and-the-tea-tasting-lady&#34;&gt;TDD, BDD, [add every other method that promises software quality here] and the tea tasting lady&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blinkingcaret.wordpress.com/2012/10/02/tdd-bdd-add-every-other-method-that-promises-software-quality-here-and-the-tea-tasting-lady/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rui Figueiredo about the scientific method, TDD / BDD and how to scientifically detect if the &amp;lsquo;how&amp;rsquo; affects the result. In this case, exemplified by how to prepare your tea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-metaprogramming-in-java&#34;&gt;The Art of Metaprogramming in Java&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/PolymathicCoder/the-art-of-metaprogramming-in-java&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by Abdelmonaim Remani&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-tdd-does-not-work&#34;&gt;When TDD does not work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/04/30/When-tdd-does-not-work.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Uncle Bob on situations where TDD might not be appropiate, especially around the borders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mi-primera-semana-como-aprendiz&#34;&gt;Mi primera semana como aprendiz&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ronnyancorini.es/blog/index.php/2015/06/08/mi-primera-semana-como-aprendiz/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ronny Ancorini&amp;rsquo;s experiences&lt;/a&gt; in his first week as apprentince with Carlos Blé &amp;amp; Associates (Spanish)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;refactoring-without-good-tests&#34;&gt;Refactoring without good tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codeclimate.com/blog/2013/12/05/refactoring-without-good-tests/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Peter Bell on how to deal with a legacy codebase, what are the effects of not having tests and how to deal with. How to add tests to a codebase that is not ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-ball-of-mud&#34;&gt;Big Ball of Mud&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.laputan.org/mud/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt;, containing a collection of patterns and antipatterns (disguised as notes) by Brian Foote and Joseph Yoder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;comparision-of-different-concurrency-models-actors-csp-disruptor-and-threads-sic&#34;&gt;Comparision of different concurrency models: Actors, CSP, Disruptor and Threads [sic]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://java-is-the-new-c.blogspot.com.es/2014/01/comparision-of-different-concurrency.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comparison of concurrency models&lt;/a&gt; by Rüdiger Möller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-whys&#34;&gt;5 Whys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; article on the technique called &amp;ldquo;5 Whys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expectations-outcomes-and-challenges-of-modern-code-review&#34;&gt;Expectations, Outcomes, and Challenges of Modern Code Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/apps/pubs/default.aspx?id=180283&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/pubs/180283/ICSE%202013-codereview.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;direct link&lt;/a&gt;, by Alberto Bacchelli and Christian Bird on code review at Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They explain how they do it, the exact methodology they are using and why they do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reasons to code review are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finding defects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alternative solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;knowledge transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;team awareness and transparency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve development process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid build breaks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;share code ownership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track rationale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;team assessment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-quality-wheel&#34;&gt;The quality wheel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jessitron.com/2015/04/the-quality-wheel.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jessica Kerr about the qualities of beautiful code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-minute-physics&#34;&gt;5 Minute Physics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6FKT-KafRk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; on interactions with the mobile devices and related to physics by David DeSandro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise-of-the-transpilers&#34;&gt;Rise of the Transpilers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DspYurD75Ns&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; on the rise of the transpilers and coffeescript by Jeremy Ashkenas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;drawing-lines-with-bresenham-s-line-algorithm&#34;&gt;Drawing Lines with Bresenham&amp;rsquo;s Line Algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zytBpLlSHms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; about how to apply the Bresenham&amp;rsquo;s algorithm to draw lines (implemented in pseudo-code and javascript) by Jenn Schiffer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-with-minified-javascript&#34;&gt;Working with Minified JavaScript&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SuFNR7-XjKI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by John Crepezzi on how to mix javascript files (clients and yours), how to decompile javascript in chrome, dev &amp;amp; debug tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-ran-our-legacy-code-retreat&#34;&gt;How we ran our Legacy Code Retreat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://pboop.wordpress.com/2012/02/19/how-we-ran-our-legacy-code-retreat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Andreas Leidig, looking for inspiration on running a legacy code retreat / brown-bag session. The experience report &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../2015/06/23/brown-bag-session-refactoring-legacy-code/&#34;&gt;is here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shift-left-testing-earlier-in-development&#34;&gt;Shift Left: Testing Earlier in Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://wirfs-brock.com/blog/2015/06/18/shift-left&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rebecca Wirfs-Brock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;polymorphic-equality&#34;&gt;Polymorphic Equality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carlosble.com/2015/06/polymorphic-equality/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on implementing polymorphic equality on C#, by Carlos Blé&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;commit-messages-are-not-titles&#34;&gt;Commit messages are not titles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://antirez.com/news/90&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on git commit messages and how to use them, by antirez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oracle-considers-g1-garbage-collector-for-java-9&#34;&gt;Oracle Considers G1 Garbage Collector for Java 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://adtmag.com/articles/2015/06/22/oracle-java-9.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;press article&lt;/a&gt; on the G1 and CMS collector, by John K. Waters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-tech-newbies-need&#34;&gt;What Tech Newbies Need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://storify.com/jesslynnrose/what-tech-newbies-need&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this set of tweets&lt;/a&gt;, grouped by Jessica Rose about the most helpful things beginners can do to improve their programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-for-cats&#34;&gt;JavaScript For Cats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://jsforcats.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this introductory guide&lt;/a&gt; to javascript by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maxogden&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Max Ogden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-doesn-t-python-have-switch-case&#34;&gt;Why Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Python Have Switch/Case?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pydanny.com/why-doesnt-python-have-switch-case.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on the switch case in the python language by Daniel Roy Greenfeld&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;joseph-moniz-s-notes-on-clojure&#34;&gt;[Joseph Moniz&amp;rsquo;s] Notes on Clojure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read Joseph Moniz&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.plasmaconduit.com/notes-on-clojure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Notes on Clojure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chemical-computing-with-clojure&#34;&gt;Chemical Computing with Clojure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://gigasquidsoftware.com/chemical-computing/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an article&lt;/a&gt; on performing abstract computations with chemicals, written in Clojure by Carin Meier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lenses&#34;&gt;Lenses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haskellforall.com/2012/01/haskell-for-mainstream-programmers_28.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on writing lenses for haskell, a way of importing imperative getters / setters to a Data. Written by Gabriel Gonzalez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note, the first part, about writing getters and setters in the naive way, is also explained in Learn you a Haskell &amp;gt; Chapter 8 Making Our Own Types and Typeclasses &amp;gt; Record syntax&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microservices-in-haskell&#34;&gt;Microservices in Haskell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AlexanderAA/haskell-microservices/blob/gh-pages/haskell-microservices.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these notes&lt;/a&gt; on implementing a microservice in haskell, by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AlexanderAA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AlexanderAA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overcoming-resistance-to-change-isn-t-it-obvious&#34;&gt;Overcoming Resistance to Change - Isn&amp;rsquo;t It Obvious?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hcz1aZ60k7w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; in the channel of The World with Theory of Constraints&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bacon-is-bad-for-you&#34;&gt;Bacon is bad for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/garann/bacon-is-bad-for-you&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt;
 on professionalism and the programmer culture, by Garann Means&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-is-a-job&#34;&gt;Code is a job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/garann/code-is-a-job&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt;, that are the continuation of &amp;ldquo;Bacon is bad for you&amp;rdquo;, by the same author, Garann Means&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-newline-schism&#34;&gt;The Great Newline Schism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codinghorror.com/the-great-newline-schism/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on the difference in newline character(s)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-ten-reasons-why-i-won-t-use-your-open-source-project&#34;&gt;Top ten reasons why I won’t use your open source project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://changelog.com/top-ten-reasons-why-i-wont-use-your-open-source-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on what&amp;rsquo;s necessary for an open-source project to be usable by others. Written by Adam Stacoviak&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>