<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On private but leaked information in a SaaS</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: how to uncorrelate public and private information.
Context Context: there are clients who have sensitive information. Some is just &amp;lsquo;companies being stealth&amp;rsquo; (e.g., don&amp;rsquo;t want to make public until launching), some is just protected by a Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA), some are protected by security clearance. The more sensitive, the greater protection needed. This tool applies to all sensitive information, regardless of where it&amp;rsquo;s stored or how it is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically keeping the intermediate history of your work using git</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: using git to automatically document your development process (special cases only.)
Context When I&amp;rsquo;m spiking a feature, I usually get in the zone (e.g., Csikszentmihalyi&amp;rsquo;s Flow), and I can forget my good engineering practices, searching for that desired answer. After a few of those bouts of coding, you realize you&amp;rsquo;re wandering. You circle around, get lost, get back on track, then get lost again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the existing choices</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/04/questioning-existing-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 07:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/04/questioning-existing-choices/</guid>
      <description>Context For a client, we have worked on a service that works with files (containing sensitive data) that get corrupted very often.
The use case is generally:
 Two/Three file opens per day One modification per 10 file opens One corruption per 100 file opens  Initial solution The initial solution was just to copy the file (file.txt) before opening, after closing. This results in two files (YYY-MM-DDTHH-mm-ss_before_file.txt, YYY-MM-DDTHH-mm-ss_after_file.txt).
As this solution quickly became unmaintainable, the client developed a solution to hash the contents of the file and to remove the duplicated files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: using tortoise credentials in git CLI</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/using-tortoise-credentials-from-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/using-tortoise-credentials-from-cli/</guid>
      <description>TortoiseGit part  Go to a repo right button, Settings Git -&amp;gt; Credential Add a creadential Config type: global Helper: wincred  Sync once using your HTTPS password
CLI part Open the $REPO/.git/config and add
[credential] helper = wincred Remote git operations should not ask for credentials anymore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two persons involved in a git commit, in github</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/14/two-persons-involved-in-a-git-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 17:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/14/two-persons-involved-in-a-git-commit/</guid>
      <description>On git You can have multiple persons involved in a single git commit: an author and a committer.
The difference is explained by Manuel Doninger 1:
 The author is the one who did the code change. The committer is the person who committed that change to a repository.
 an example, by the same author:
 Example: I&amp;rsquo;m not a committer in the EGit project, so i have no rights to push directly to the EGit repository at Eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool: Building a local pipeline</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Motivation At a client, one of the projects has a long building process and the tests are mostly slow, so I use a local building pipeline, an example of the Pipes and Filters pattern.
This allows for executing manually only the fast unit tests, then automatically (no user intervention, no time spent) executing the rest of them before pushing. In case the latter fails, it is possible to do git push -f to the pipeline without corrupting the central repository (origin) history, possibly disturbing others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: massively reverting local changes</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-massively-reverting-local-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-massively-reverting-local-changes/</guid>
      <description>I was changing a massive amount of files (&amp;gt;1000) for a repeated code. The search and replace query was not too exact and it broke many tests in the system. For that, I preferred reverting those tests.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it automatically:
Copy all the failing tests to a text editor:
Input:
testSearchXMLDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testCreateXMLDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testUpdateXFPageMetadata(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testCreateDocumentCrop(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testUpdateCropMetadata(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testDeleteDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testUpdateXmlDocumentMetadata(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testUpdateXML(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testSearchXFPage(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testCreateXFPage(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testUpdatePage(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testSearchCrop(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testUpdateCrop(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testMoveDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) testGetDocument(io.company.controller.dms.DocumentControllerTest) regex:
(tested in Sublime 3, build 3083, Windows 64)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: committing to the repo file by file</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-committing-to-the-repo-file-by-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/08/tip-committing-to-the-repo-file-by-file/</guid>
      <description>I was prefer committing to the repo with commits that are as small as possible as long as it makes sense. It makes it much easier to rever the changes.
This is why I have some scripts to commit all the changes, even with the same message. This is one of them:
for f in $(git status -s |grep &amp;#34;^M&amp;#34;|awk &amp;#39;{print $2}&amp;#39;); do git add $f git commit -m &amp;#34;generic commit for all files&amp;#34; done </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
