<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>speed on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/speed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in speed on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/speed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB
Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable
Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000
Jepsen: Aerospike I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies
Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos
Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
