<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code-review on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/code-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code-review on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/code-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Space: Code reviews</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed about code reviews on this open space
Notes These are my notes, in no particular order:
 reduce information silos all around the company, as everyone [technical] can participate in these events raise the &amp;ldquo;just arrived&amp;rdquo; people&amp;rsquo;s knowledge [Difficult to hit the ground up and running, but these code review sessions can help] invest one person as &amp;lsquo;sheriff&amp;rsquo; for the sprint: they will take care of static analysis tools (such as sonar) and continuous integration (CI; such as jenkins).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open discussion: On code reviews</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/open-discussion-on-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 18:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/open-discussion-on-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>At a client, I organized an open discussion on code reviews. We had a great conversation.
The main idea was to discuss about it and share the ideas each one had. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want it to turn into a masterclass (see the white belt)
Benefits These are the main benefits we saw in it:
 Increased trust Learning from others, other approaches Less defects, more quality Increased bus factor, decreased information silos Also:  Getting out of your comfort zone Communicating more often (code style, edge cases, complaining, etc)    Pair programming Then we discussed about the topic of code reviews and pair programming:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
