<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Craftsmanship | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/craftsmanship/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-13T08:06:06+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in May 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T16:41:10+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update: I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015
into a single post</p>

<h2>Programmer passion considered harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/on-coding/programmer-passion-considered-harmful-5c5d4e3a9b28">this article</a> on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.</p>

<h2>Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.coursereport.com/blog/software-craftsmanship-are-bootcamps-enough">this article</a> on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by <a href="https://twitter.com/kauerrolemodel">Ken Auer</a></p>

<h2>Improve your development environments with virtualization</h2>

<p>I have seen this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg_vPMnC7_k&amp;feature=youtu.be">Improve your development environments with virtualization</a> by Luke Sneeringer.</p>

<p>My notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>development should be exactly like production.</li>
<li>except where it is too painful. there it should be different</li>
</ul>


<h2>Buffer&rsquo;s take on values</h2>

<p>I have found these <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Bufferapp/buffer-culture-04">values</a>, written by Buffer, very interesting.</p>

<h2>Public static void</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kj5ApnhPAE">&ldquo;Public, static void&rdquo;</a> by Rob Pike. The slides can be found <a href="http://www.oscon.com/oscon2010/public/schedule/detail/13423">here</a></p>

<h3>My notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>too much bureaucracy</li>
<li>fighting the compiler</li>
<li>dynamic vs static typing</li>
<li>language too verbose</li>
<li><p>do not mix the two of them</p></li>
<li><p>a language niche:</p>

<ul>
<li>comprehensible</li>
<li>statically typed</li>
<li>light on the page</li>
<li>fast to work in</li>
<li>scales well</li>
<li>doesn&rsquo;t require tools but supports them well</li>
<li>good at networking and multiprocessing</li>
</ul>


<p>(minute 10:09)​</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://golang.org">Go</a> was born to fill this niche</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Nothing is something</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Software is eating the world</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>The Cost of Test Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.typemock.com/2009/03/the-cost-of-test-driven-development.html">this article</a>, on the cost of doing TDD, which refers to <a href="http://www.msr-waypoint.net/en-us/groups/ese/nagappan_tdd.pdf">this paper</a>: Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams (below)</p>

<h2>Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams</h2>

<p>This paper has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/12/paper-tdd-in-industrial-teams/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched the video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3T00X_sNg4Q">Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</a>, by Howard Abrams.</p>

<p>I guess this is a reference to the popular <a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/">Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!</a>.</p>

<p>He suggests many interesting resources for learning Lisp dialects. The live coding is in Clojure:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://landoflisp.com/">The land of Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/">Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs</a>. See also <a href="https://twitter.com/SICPQuotes">SICPQuotes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-schemer">The Little Schemer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/pdf/eintr.pdf">An Introduction to Programming in Emacs Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.4clojure.com/">4clojure Questions</a></li>
<li><a href="http://clojurekoans.com/">Clojure Koans</a></li>
</ul>


<p>On another topic, in the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/222418104/">Bank accounts exercise from Exercism</a> meetup, we discussed the book <a href="https://pragprog.com/book/shcloj2/programming-clojure">Programming Clojure (2nd edition)</a> by Stuart Halloway</p>

<h2>Professor Frisby&rsquo;s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/DrBoolean/mostly-adequate-guide">this guide</a> to functional programming. It is still work in progress (WIP) but still interesting. Written in javascript, so you can REPL in the browser.</p>

<h2>Learning Code Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video, by Saron Yitbarek: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-nsnAYRqYLA">Learn Code Good</a>.</p>

<h2>Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9FOchgTtLM">Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</a>, by Gregory Moeck.</p>

<p>In it, they point to the <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests</a> book (<a href="/blog/categories/goos">category here</a>), the paper <a href="www.jmock.org/oopsla2004.pdf">Mock Roles, not Objects</a> (also present in the GOOS book).</p>

<h2>Technical Debt: A Repayment Plan</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/tech-debt-repayment">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jeremyjarrell">Jeremy Jarrell</a> on technical debt how to repay it: schedule, taxes, default, etc</p>

<p>This has made me think of the <a href="http://scbcn.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Deuda-t%C3%A9cnica-origen-y-consecuencias/69782-25568">&ldquo;Deuda técnica, origen y consecuencias&rdquo; talk</a> (Technical debt: origin and consequences) (Spanish), that was delivered by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jgomezz">Javier Gómez</a> at the Software Craftsmanship 2014.</p>

<h2>Revisiting XP: be a thoughtful programmer by exercising more collective ownership</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/revisit-p-collective">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tiagooo_romero">Tiago Garcia</a> on the collective code ownership, as stated by Xtreme Programming (XP), with some example and guidelines.</p>

<h2>Where&rsquo;s the Real Bottleneck in Scientific Computing?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.americanscientist.org/issues/pub/wheres-the-real-bottleneck-in-scientific-computing/99999">this article</a> by Greg Wilson on the tools and procedures investigators use to produce software.</p>

<h2>Testing inside the Sprint</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ronjeffries.com/articles/2015-03-01-testing-in-sprints/">this article</a> by Ron Jeffries.</p>

<p>Discusses the need for testing and why this hasn&rsquo;t been communicated enough, as there still are people who have not understood it.</p>

<p>Also about why people equal something failing when using scrum with scrum failing.</p>

<h2>DTO vs Domain Models</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/05/dto-vs-domain-models/">this article</a> by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Homoiconicity isn’t the point</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://calculist.org/blog/2012/04/17/homoiconicity-isnt-the-point/">this article</a> by David Herman about homoiconicity, comparing Lisp dialects (have it) to others that don&rsquo;t. The main point is at the end, where it says:</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] homoiconicity isn’t the point, read is</p></blockquote>

<h2>So You Don&rsquo;t Want to be a Programmer After All</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/so-you-dont-want-to-be-a-programmer-after-all/">this article</a> by Jeff Atwood. Cites the golden handcuffs (also known as golden shackles), reasons to be and not to be a programmer, and how to be an average and outstanding programmer</p>

<h2>The Nature of Lisp</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.defmacro.org/ramblings/lisp.html">this article / introduction</a> to Lisp by Slava Akhmechet</p>

<h2>[David Pollak&rsquo;s] My Thoughts on Go</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.goodstuff.im/golang">these comments</a> on Go Lang from David Pollak</p>

<h2>The Well-Rounded Technologist</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/02/the-well-rounded-technologist.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Should I read papers?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/21/should-i-read-papers.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp-1 vs Lisp-2</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hornbeck.wordpress.com/2009/07/05/lisp-1-vs-lisp-2/">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/hornbeck">@Hornbeck</a> about the lisp 1 and lisp 2.</p>

<h2>Science Corps</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkQkafxFoIQ">TEDx talk</a> by Aza Raskin, featuring Data Banks and Science corps</p>

<h2>Healthy Codebase and Preparatory Refactoring</h2>

<p> I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://brewhouse.io/blog/2014/11/10/healthy-codebase-and-preparatory-refactoring.html">this article</a> by Philippe Creux about preparatory refactoring</p>

<h2>You Are Learning Haskell Right Now (Or Anything You Want Really)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/12/11/you-are-learning-haskell-right-now.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp is Abstract Syntax</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/16/lisp-is-abstract-syntax.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Two Things Types Have Taught Me</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/30/two-things-types-have-taught-me.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t Bet Against Yourself</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Learning Math: A Blank Is A Blank With A Blank</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>The False Economy Of Metaprogramming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/03/06/the-false-economy-of-generated-methods.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Management and Engineering, overlapping</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.quora.com/Does-Adam-DAngelo-feel-comfortable-with-the-transition-from-an-engineer-to-a-management-position?srid=3OC&amp;share=1">this Quora answer</a> by Adam D&#8217;Angelo. The original title is: Does Adam D&#8217;Angelo feel comfortable with the transition from an engineer to a management position?</p>

<h2>Evolution of The Twitter Stack</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/ly83zQkBjCxnIX">these slides</a> about changing the technology stack in Twitter: from Rails to JVM-based</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Guardian of the Source]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/the-guardian-of-the-source/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-17T22:01:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/the-guardian-of-the-source</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Overheard today at the office, while they were discussing the approval of a pull request:</p>

<blockquote><p>[Pull request reviewer] - I&rsquo;m sorry, can&rsquo;t approve this: I don&rsquo;t really agree with this design. Isn&rsquo;t there an alternative for this?</p>

<p>[Pull request author] - [redacted], of course you don&rsquo;t, you&rsquo;re the guardian of the source</p>

<p>[PR reviewer] - Well, sometimes I&rsquo;m a bit picky about introducing bad code into our codebase.</p></blockquote>

<p>This has made me think about Gandalf blocking the path of Balrog Demon, shouting &ldquo;<a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/you-shall-not-pass">you shall not pass</a>&rdquo; while on top of the bridge.</p>

<p>This is part of the objectives of doing a pull request before merging code: stop the bad code<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> before it is merged to the codebase.</p>

<p>Later, as you start having <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broken_windows_theory">broken windows</a> in your codebase, it is easier that you start introducing more. Exactly about this is the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broken_windows_theory">broken windows theory</a>.</p>

<p>On the other hand, if you try to block that bad code before it is merged, it is cheaper to remove it: nothing depends on it, you introduce no repetition, etc<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p>This also connects with the idea present in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Software-Craftsman-Professionalism-Pragmatism/dp/0134052501">Software Craftsmanship, now called The Software Craftsman</a>, about preserving value for investors and treat software as an investment (with positive ROI) rather than a sunk cost.</p>

<p>It is being picky and, to the most of our possibilities, do not letting any defects nor bad code into the codebase. A hedge fund manager would not let any toxic or dubious asset into the managed funds. This would be counterproductive in the long run (maybe even in the short one) and would be not doing their job correctly. Why is it that some developers suggest or accept these toxic assets?</p>

<p>So, at least for me, would be an honor to be called the &ldquo;Guardian of the Source&rdquo; by someone I respect, as long as this is a serious proposition (i.e., not a joke of some kind).</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Bad code can be expressed in many ways: long methods, bad naming, breaking design principles (e.g., SOLID, KISS, DRY - OAOO), code with defects, no tests or no coverage, etc.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>A source is <a href="http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?DiscoverDefectsEarly">Discover defects early</a>. Another is <a href="http://developers.slashdot.org/story/03/10/21/0141215/software-defects---do-late-bugs-really-cost-more">this paper</a> that cites the ratio of fixing it later to 5:1 (five times more expensive).<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Space: Code Reviews]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-16T22:44:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we&rsquo;ve discussed about code reviews on <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Barcelona-Software-Craftsmanship/events/220293683/">this open space</a></p>

<h2>Notes</h2>

<p>These are my notes, in no particular order:</p>

<ul>
<li>reduce information silos all around the company, as everyone [technical] can participate in these events</li>
<li>raise the &ldquo;just arrived&rdquo; people&rsquo;s knowledge [Difficult to hit the ground up and running, but these code review sessions can help]</li>
<li>invest one person as &lsquo;sheriff&rsquo; for the sprint: they will take care of static analysis tools (such as sonar) and continuous integration (CI; such as jenkins). They will make sure others follow the working agreements</li>
<li>In the academic environment, some teams do share their patches via mailing lists and this makes it much slower to adapt and review changes [As compared to an on-line sharing system - like web-based interfaces to distributed version control systems] As this team doesn&rsquo;t have a CI tool, they must test it / try it manually before reviewing the code.</li>
<li>Pair programming does not remove the need for code review [This has been surfaced twice]</li>
<li>Your work is not more important than your team members&#8217; one. [Related to not having time to code review]</li>
<li>Do code reviews include architecture? [We&rsquo;ve agreed that the architecture to some degree should be discussed before code reviews]</li>
<li>&ldquo;Troll review&rdquo;</li>
<li>Anyone can veto pull requests [By opening a question; do not allow for pull requests to be closed with open questions]</li>
<li>A 15-minute time slot everyday to code review [As code hygiene; Done right after lunch,  breakfast or just before leaving, when you&rsquo;re tired]</li>
<li>Code review tasks have higher priority than other tasks [Do not take other tasks if there are code reviews to do]</li>
<li>Code reviews put a lot of pressure so people learn and the knowledge level equalizes across the team</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p> My conclusions, even though some of them were not shared by everyone:</p>

<ul>
<li>Most of the people approve of code review practices: either they are doing them or are trying to apply them at their clients. (Warning: this was a code review meetup, so there&rsquo;s a bias: people not interested in them won&rsquo;t come). No one was against doing them.</li>
<li>Code reviews have a cost, although it is beneficial to do them</li>
<li>Should your teammates not want to participate in the code review after agreeing on doing them, appeal to their professionalism / accountability, then to their time (stated before), then troll them: after a few (healthy) trolling code review sessions, people will feel more comfortable reviewing and being reviewed. Special mention to Miguel who coined (?)<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> the term: troll review.</li>
<li>Great way of equalizing the (technical) knowledge level within the team</li>
<li>Great way of reduce information silos across the whole company</li>
<li>They can be fun if you do them properly</li>
<li>The need for code reviews do not disappear when pair programming: as long as you have a personal attachment to the code, you might not see its defects.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Your own</h2>

<p>Should you have any conclusions to share, please add a pull request to this <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/blog_source">repository</a> or do it as a comment.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>after searching some ten minutes on the internet, there are only a couple of questions on meta.codereview stackoverflow, but not related to this. <strong>Update</strong>: In <a href="https://twitter.com/mallyvai/status/314260072798752768">here</a>, Vaibhav Mallya talks about a #trollReview, related to code. So, unfortunately, Miguel, you&rsquo;re not the first one. But there are fewer than 10 results on twitter.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polishing Your Tools]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/22/polishing-your-tools/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-22T09:30:20+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/22/polishing-your-tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The toolsmith</h2>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fred_Brooks">Frederick P Brooks, Jr</a> quoted / explained a theory explained by Mills and Baker<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> around 1971-72:</p>

<blockquote><p>Chapter 3: The Surgical Team</p>

<p>[&hellip;] but the team be organized like a surgical team rather than a hog-butchering team. That is, instead of each member cutting away on the problem, one does the cutting and the others give him[her] every support that will enhance his[her] effectiveness and productivity.</p>

<p>[&hellip;]</p>

<p><quote> Brooks, F. - The Mythical Man-Month, chapter 3: The Surgical Team </quote></p></blockquote>

<p>(Text between square brackets is mine)</p>

<p>The author goes on to explain the job descriptions for the surgeon, copilot, administrator, editor, secretaries, program clerk, toolsmith, tester and the language lawyer.</p>

<p>The one that will be covered in this post is the toolsmith:</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>The toolsmith</strong>. File-editing, text-editing, and interactive debugging services are now readily available, so that a team will rarely need its own machine and machine-operating crew. But these services must be available with unquestionably satisfactory response and reliability; and the surgeon must be sole judge of the adequacy of the service available to him. He needs a toolsmith, responsible for ensuring this adequacy of the basic service and for constructing, maintaining, and upgrading special tools &ndash;mostly interactive computer services&ndash; needed by his team. Each team will need its own toolsmith, regardless of the excellence and reliability of any centrally provided service, for his job is to see to the tools needed or wanted by his surgeon, without regard to any other team&rsquo;s needs. The tool-builder will often construct specialized utilities, cataloged procedures, macro libraries.</p>

<p><quote> Brooks, F. - The Mythical Man-Month, chapter 3: The Surgical Team </quote></p></blockquote>

<p>Even though the chapter reads a bit outdated, especially with the part about genders and methodologies (i.e., waterfall), the part about roles is interesting. The surgical team, as the author presents will be composed by 9 &frac12; (nine and a half) as the language lawyer can be shared among two or three teams.</p>

<h2>Day to day practices</h2>

<p>So, one full-time job is to build tools to service the surgeon and the copilot (1:8,5 ratio), or approximately 12% of a full-time position.</p>

<p>These tools can make the surgeon and the copilot more effective, ranging from a single digit percentage to orders of magnitude in other tasks.</p>

<p>As agile teams no longer have a toolsmith and the scrum master is not necessarily a technical expert who can build tools for the whole team, the tasks of creating tools must be taken care by everyone. No one better than yourself can know your needs and tailor solutions for them.</p>

<p>The only downside is you have to invest ~5h (for a full time position) per week into creating and polishing tools for your work: it is a need for achieving more productivity when working.</p>

<p>Nowadays that IDEs are configurable, this time might be invested on learning more advanced features as other shortcuts, refactoring techniques, other design patterns, etc. I like having my own live templates (see <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/creating-and-editing-live-templates.html#d1333587e219">description</a>), especially for tests, as I saw on the <a href="https://skillsmatter.com/courses/503-sandro-mancuso-s-crafting-code-course#programme">Crafting Code workshop</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a></p>

<p></p>

<p>It may also include other activities as setting up your bash alias, cleaning your desk, trying a new UML diagram modeler, etc. Anything that improves the productivity of your main task.</p>

<p>If we consider our experience and knowledge part of our tools (as we are knowledge workers), training could be considered part of polishing our tools. Short, daily or weekly training sessions (even internal) can make a great impact on breadth (not depth) of knowledge among your teammates. This shallow knowledge can open doors for more knowledge to be gained outside of company time, or used to practice and test other methods.</p>

<p>This training is so useful for everyone (&ldquo;when one teaches, two learn&rdquo;) that I recommend my clients to do it. This has helped them cope with changing technologies, knowledge transfer and even some team building.</p>

<h2>Company provided or not?</h2>

<p>Should the company provide for this time to improve? Although I don&rsquo;t know the answer, it would greatly affect the programmers&#8217; productivity to do so. I would say, provide this time as long as what is produced is useful. How do you measure useful? This is a subjective opinion, so it depends on each one.</p>

<p>Some companies acknowledge that this is so important as to invest part of their resources (0-2 hours per week) into training.</p>

<p>Either way, should your company provide it for your or not, you are the one in charge of your career (from Mancuso, <a href="https://leanpub.com/socra">Software Craftsmanship</a> - now called <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Software-Craftsman-Professionalism-Pragmatism-Robert/dp/0134052501/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1416521895&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+software+craftsman">The Software Craftsman</a>). If you are not allowed to invest company time for your own benefit, you could use some of your personal time to do so. It is not required, but you will soon enjoy its profits.</p>

<h2>Examples</h2>

<ul>
<li>Every sprint, one of my clients (as of 2015-05) wants to review the work done using some slides and a live demo. The &lsquo;sample&rsquo; slides with the format, layout is useful. Everything that should be replaced (timestamp, contents, etc) is marked with a TODO</li>
<li>Every day, I commit plenty of times to the control version system (i.e., git). I have an alias for commit, diff, status, etc, that saves me some keystrokes on the most common commands</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<p>Mills, H., &ldquo;Chief programmer teams, principles, and procedures,&rdquo; IBM Federal Systems Division Report FSC 715108, Gaithersburg, Md., 1971.</p>

<p>Baker, F. T., &ldquo;Chief programmer team management of production programming,&rdquo; IBM Sys. J., 11, 1 (1972).</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Original references in &ldquo;The Mythical Man-Month&rdquo; (Notes and References, page 294) point to these:<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
