<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/amazon/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/amazon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-ended-up-paying-150-for-a-single-60gb-download-from-amazon-glacier-https-medium-com-karppinen-how-i-ended-up-paying-150-for-a-single-60gb-download-from-amazon-glacier-6cb77b288c3e&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@karppinen/how-i-ended-up-paying-150-for-a-single-60gb-download-from-amazon-glacier-6cb77b288c3e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How I ended up paying $150 for a single 60GB download from Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Marko Karppinen that explains how a mistake in understanding the pricing model of AWS Glacier cost 150$ instead of the expected 0.86$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When cloud providers use uncommon and/or unpredictable pricing models, even your informed hunch about the cost can be off by several orders of magnitude, like the price differential between an iPad and a Ferrari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to avoid this is by reading, very carefully, through the laughably long passages of meandering technical trivia that constitute the Glacier FAQ or, indeed, this Medium post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: quote, glacier, amazon, aws, amazon-web-service, marko-karppinen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debian-9-stretch-released-https-www-debian-org-news-2017-20170617&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/News/2017/20170617&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Debian 9 Stretch released&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the release notes for Debian 9 &amp;ldquo;Stretch&amp;rdquo;. By the Debian team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: debian, release-note, stretch, linux, distribution, distro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-we-re-betting-against-real-time-team-messaging-https-blog-doist-com-why-were-betting-against-real-time-team-messaging-521804a3da09&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.doist.com/why-were-betting-against-real-time-team-messaging-521804a3da09&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why we’re betting against real-time team messaging &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Amir Salihefendic on why they have created a tool for online async communication, where the online presence icon is disabled and communications happen around threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to transform the online (from real-time to async) communications to leave spaces for deep work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: amir-salihefendic, deep-work, todoist, doist, twist, app, slack, online-communication, communication, productivity, async, real-time, work, chat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;crypto-tokens-a-breakthrough-in-open-network-design-https-medium-com-cdixon-crypto-tokens-a-breakthrough-in-open-network-design-e600975be2ef&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@cdixon/crypto-tokens-a-breakthrough-in-open-network-design-e600975be2ef&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Crypto Tokens: A Breakthrough in Open Network Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Chris Dixon that explains what is a crypto currency, what is a smart contract and how this can revolutionize the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains public vs private networks and tokens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chris-dixon, public-network, private-network, token, ethereum, bitcoin, cryptocurrency, contract, smart-contract, miner, mining, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jsx-vs-clojurescript-the-showdown-http-ingesolvoll-github-io-2017-06-22-plain-react-vs-reagent-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ingesolvoll.github.io/2017/06/22/plain-react-vs-reagent.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JSX vs Clojurescript: the showdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article comparing the Reagent vs React (clojurescript vs javascript), going into details for both technologies. By Inge Solvoll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Code vs Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I managed to show you a few things that Reagent brings to the table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concise and compact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating functional style components is super easy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immutable data is the default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But the thing that fundamentally separates it from React/JSX is the data focus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JSX creates instructions: React.createElement(&amp;lsquo;div&amp;rsquo;).
Reagent creates data structures: [:div].
The former is opaque, hard to inspect at runtime. The latter is highly transparent, and easily inspectable in more than one way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your app is declared using nothing but pure data, using nothing but plain functions to manipulate the data. The very rich Clojure standard library with functions like map, filter and reduce at your disposal, without any funky new syntax to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clojurescript, comparison, javascript, react, reagent, om, cljs, js, inge-solvoll&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iot-goes-nuclear-creating-a-zigbee-chain-reaction-https-blog-acolyer-org-2017-06-22-iot-goes-nuclear-creating-a-zigbee-chain-reaction&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.acolyer.org/2017/06/22/iot-goes-nuclear-creating-a-zigbee-chain-reaction/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IoT goes nuclear: creating a ZigBee chain reaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by on the security of Philips Hue lightbulbs, a kind of IoT device that has been hacked using a defect in their protocols&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrian-colyer, zigbee, philips, hue, philips-hue, iot, defect, hack, security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-the-chain-https-googleprojectzero-blogspot-com-es-2016-11-breaking-chain-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://googleprojectzero.blogspot.com.es/2016/11/breaking-chain.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Breaking the Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Forshaw, in which they explain how the Chrome browser does not use the Win32k system calls (under certain conditions), to reduce the attack surface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: attack-surface, rasq, security, chrome, chromium, project-zero, win32k, win32, windows, google, flash, ppapi, james-forshaw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;language-server-protocol-lsp-rust-and-emacs-https-christian-kellner-me-2017-05-31-language-server-protocol-lsp-rust-and-emacs&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://christian.kellner.me/2017/05/31/language-server-protocol-lsp-rust-and-emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Language Server Protocol (lsp), rust and Emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Christian Kellner about a common way of operating with a program&amp;rsquo;s Language Server Protocol (LSP) so all languages could benefit from standard tools. Then, a new editor would just have to implement the bindings to LSP to support those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to what LLVM is to some languages: once you specify your syntax in terms of LLVM, you can benefit from the improvements that LLVM provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christian-kellner, lsp, emacs, rust, ast, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-create-a-mooc-in-28-days-https-www-indiehackers-com-sknthla-how-to-create-a-mooc-in-28-days&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiehackers.com/@sknthla/how-to-create-a-mooc-in-28-days&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Create a MOOC in 28 Days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Saku Panditharatne on how she has created a massively open online course (MOOC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: saku-panditharatne, mooc, passive-income, business, side-project, side-business&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-in-agile-six-months-at-pivotal&#34;&gt;Lessons in Agile: Six Months at Pivotal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/built-to-adapt/lessons-in-agile-six-months-at-pivotal-66b4c57386a4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Maryam Labib where she explains what she has learned in the last 6 months at Pivotal: how to pair program, how to TDD and some good practices to be a better developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: maryam-labib, pivotal, career, professional-career, tdd, pair-programming, team, lessons-learned, experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacking-verbal-communication-systems&#34;&gt;Hacking verbal communication systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/album/4045988/video/173255458&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Alexander on what kind of systems humans use to communicate and how to improve them. Explains the hand signals at Occupy movement (called (Occupy movement hand signals)[&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals]&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals]&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: conference, ryan-alexander, lead-dev, conf, hand-signals, occupy-movement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ni-titulitis-ni-cuñadismo-spanish&#34;&gt;Ni titulitis, ni cuñadismo (Spanish)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.koalite.com/2016/06/ni-titulitis-ni-cunadismo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the regulation or no regulation of the programmer trade, by Juan María Hernández&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: regulation, opinion, title, degree, university, juan-hernandez, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-semicolons-necessary-in-javascript&#34;&gt;Are Semicolons Necessary in JavaScript?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gsfbh17Ax9I&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Kyle Robinson Young on whether semicolons are necessary in javascript and why he purposely does not use them, to teach people how to do it. Suggests going for a month with the opposite way (write / don&amp;rsquo;t write) to see how it feels and take an informed decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javascript, semicolon, style, syntax, kyle-young&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;race-conditions-on-the-web&#34;&gt;Race conditions on the web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josipfranjkovic.com/blog/race-conditions-on-web&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Josip Franjković on the race conditions that can happen using REST APIs, related to eventual consistency matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eventual-consistency, josip-franjkovic, race-condition, rest-api, rest, web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nist-declares-the-age-of-sms-based-2-factor-authentication-over&#34;&gt;NIST declares the age of SMS-based 2-factor authentication over&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/25/nist-declares-the-age-of-sms-based-2-factor-authentication-over/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Devin Coldewey, where he explains that the US NIST has published a draft that suggests using SMS for two-factor authentication in a different way: check that they are real phones and not VoIP to reduce the tampering with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  devin-coldewey, 2fa, sms, nist, us-nist, security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-interviews-with-amazon&#34;&gt;My Interviews with Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesocietea.org/2016/07/my-interviews-with-amazon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Aaron Krauss, where he explains his experience interviewing with Amazon at Seattle. Explains the whole process and insights from some phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: aaron-krauss, amazon, interview-process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devops-students-learn-the-value-of-uptime-with-3-a-m-calls&#34;&gt;DevOps Students Learn the Value of Uptime With 3 a.m. Calls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linux.com/news/devops-students-learn-value-uptime-3-am-calls&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the practices related to &amp;ldquo;on call&amp;rdquo; at Holberton School and their students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sylvain-kalache, holberton-school, on-call, full-stack-developer, devops, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;constant-confusion-why-i-still-use-javascript-function-statements&#34;&gt;Constant confusion: why I still use JavaScript function statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/constant-confusion-why-i-still-use-javascript-function-statements-984ece0b72fd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains the comparison of declaring functions in javascript (ES2015 and above), with the short notation for a function. By Bill Sourour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the temporal dead zone (TDZ):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] JavaScript binds the declaration of “sayHelloTo” — reads it first, puts it at the top, and creates a space in memory to hold its value — but it doesn’t set “sayHelloTo” to anything until it reaches it during execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time between “sayHelloTo” being bound and “sayHelloTo” being initialized is called the temporal dead zone (TDZ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdz, temporal-dead-zone, bill-sourour, javascript, es2015, function, const, var, binding, lifecycle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>