<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>internal on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/internal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in internal on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 22:20:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/internal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internal training: BPM: Process and tools for developers</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/02/internal-training-bpm-tool-and-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 22:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/02/internal-training-bpm-tool-and-process/</guid>
      <description>At a client, I&amp;rsquo;ve presented today an internal training on &amp;ldquo;BPM: Process and tools for developers&amp;rdquo;
In it, we have introduced the BPM concept and the main ideas in Activiti BPM.
Also techniques for hotswapping processes, tips and how-tos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal training: QA &amp;amp; how to test</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/18/internal-training-qa-and-how-to-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 22:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/18/internal-training-qa-and-how-to-test/</guid>
      <description>At a client, we&amp;rsquo;ve done today an internal training on &amp;ldquo;QA &amp;amp; how to test&amp;rdquo;. In it, the most skilled person with the QA role in the dev team has explained to us some techniques and concepts for testing
My notes Verification vs validation: building the product right vs building the right product.
Principles Extracted from ISTQB:
 testing shows presence of defects exhaustive testing is impossible early testing is better than later testing defect clustering: areas with bigger defect ratio or more critical, etc should be tested more thoroughly pesticide paradox testing is context-dependent absence of errors fallacy: the absence of defects does not imply perfect software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal training: Testing is hard - just do it</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/05/internal-training-testing-is-hard-just-do-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 23:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/05/internal-training-testing-is-hard-just-do-it/</guid>
      <description>At a client, last week I&amp;rsquo;ve organized an internal training, in the form of a discussion about this article: Testing is hard - just do it
Our thoughts  When a bug is found, prove it exists with a test
 This immediately reduces defect rate: the same regression cannot be introduced again
 fix a bug a second time
 If fixing a bug (having defects in your code) was &amp;lsquo;waste&amp;rsquo;, as defined by lean methodologies, it also is wast fixing it for the following times</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal training: Introduction to AngularJs</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/30/internal-training-introduction-to-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 20:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/30/internal-training-introduction-to-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>At a client, today I&amp;rsquo;ve done an internal training on angular js: we&amp;rsquo;ve prepared some slides and a live demo.
The repository with all the information can be found here.
Apparently, the training has been a success, given that most of the talent in the team is backend focused (as opposed to full-stack) and changing from java to javascript is not straight-forward.
Note: this post has been created a posteriori, dated with the correct training timestamp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
