<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/belief/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/belief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-reason-why-the-spotify-model-is-broken&#34;&gt;The real reason why the Spotify model is broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://kernelmag.dailydot.com/issue-sections/staff-editorials/12136/spotify-royalty-payment-model/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-of-7-badass-developer-gets-a-rude-awakening&#34;&gt;[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, they wanted a professional problem solver who could jump in and deliver what the company needed, to meet THEIR customers&amp;rsquo; demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking for ways that I could add value to my employer outside of the code I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed my &amp;ldquo;soft skills&amp;rdquo;—my ability to communicate, learn quickly, and pass my knowledge on to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-sonmez, programmer, language-programmer, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-rules-to-live-by-when-you-work-in-an-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34;&gt;6 Rules To Live By When You Work In An Office But Have Remote Team Members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/6-mistakes-when-you-work-in-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Lauren Moon about how trello works remotely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value Individuals Over Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Impromptu Meetings At Someone’s Desk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If One Person Is On A Video Call, EVERYONE Is On A Video Call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication Is Asynchronous. Deal With It.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socializing Is Not Around A Watercooler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tools You’re Using Matter. A Lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, lauren-moon, listicle, trello, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;princeton-s-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34;&gt;Princeton’s Ad-Blocking Superweapon May Put an End to the Ad-Blocking Arms Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/princetons-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Koebler on the tool a university has written and published, that using computer vision, is able to detect sponsored content in native form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jason-koebler, computer-vision, ad, advertisement, ublock, adblock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hasta-pronto&#34;&gt;Hasta pronto…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javiergarzas.com/2016/07/hasta-pronto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Garzás, where he explains that he&amp;rsquo;ll stop blogging for a while and why&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javier-garzas, blog, personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-principles-of-clean-architecture&#34;&gt;The principles of Clean Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video about the clean architecture (with a client&amp;rsquo;s lunch and learn initiative). By Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the plugin is vulnerable to the plugged-in system, at the source code level&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate the detail from the general things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clean-architecture, uncle-bob, robert-martin, video, mvp, model-view-presenter, model-view-controller, mvc, quote, plugin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-languages-which-almost-became-css&#34;&gt;The Languages Which Almost Became CSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eager.io/blog/the-languages-which-almost-were-css/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zack Bloom on the origins of CSS and the languages to add representation to HTML pages / markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes the origins of these languages (e.g., RPP, PWP, CHSS, PSL, FOSI, DSSSL) and how the acceptance of CSS came to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was the technology which was easiest for a beginner to pick up which won, rather than those which were most powerful for an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt; Zack Bloom&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: css, html, history, zack-bloom, mosaic, violawww&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-not-going-to-believe-what-i-m-about-to-tell-you&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not going to believe what I&amp;rsquo;m about to tell you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/believe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Inman about how we process information from outside, especially when it conflicts with our beliefs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-inman, comic, oatmeal, belief&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-perfectly-unhappy&#34;&gt;How to be perfectly unhappy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/unhappy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Inman about the definition of happiness and how it affects the author&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-inman, oatmeal, happiness, comic, definition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spotify-engineering-culture-part-1&#34;&gt;Spotify Engineering Culture - part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/85490944&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; about the Spotify engineering culture: team organization, the terms they introduce and some general culture about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: team-management, people, spotify, henrik-kniberg, squad, chapter, guild, tribe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speak-like-a-leader&#34;&gt;Speak like a leader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bGBamfWasNQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TEDx Talk&lt;/a&gt; by Simon Lancaster in which he explains the importance of rhetoric in our speech. Explains 6 techniques for achieving better communication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three breathless sentences: &amp;ldquo;Mangia Bene, Ridi Spesso, ama molto&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ein Volk, ein Reich, ein Fuhrer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three repetitive sentences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three balancing statements: if we hear the statements as balanced, we imagine that the underlaying thinking is balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metaphor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exaggeration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: simon-lancaster, tedx, ted, quote, speech, leadership, communication&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>