<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>release-it on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/release-it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in release-it on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 12:49:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/release-it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change, 2nd Edition by Kent Beck and Cynthia Andres, again. Building Microservices, Designing Fine-Grained Systems, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Reinventing Organizations by Frederic Laloux. Blog posts under the tag reinventing-organizations  Non-technical:
 L&amp;rsquo;acabadora, by Michela Murgia Disrupted: My Misadventure in the Start-Up Bubble by Dan Lyons  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stability terms from &#34;Release it!&#34;, a quote</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/26/stability-terms-from-release-it-a-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 22:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/26/stability-terms-from-release-it-a-quote/</guid>
      <description>In Release It!, terms related to stability:
 transaction: is an abstract unit of work processed by the system mixed workload: is a combination of different transaction types processed by a system. system: the complete, interdependent set of hardware, applications, and services required to process transactions for users stability: resilient system keeps processing transactions, even when there are transient impulses, persistent stresses, or component failures disrupting normal processing stress (to the system): is a force applied to the system over an extended period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
