<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tdd | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/tdd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-12T00:07:42+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paper: TDD in Industrial Teams]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/12/paper-tdd-in-industrial-teams/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-12T00:02:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/12/paper-tdd-in-industrial-teams</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.msr-waypoint.net/en-us/groups/ese/nagappan_tdd.pdf">this paper</a> by Nagappan, Maximilien, Bhat and Williams on the cost, advantages, pitfalls of doing TDD in industrial teams (private companies who create software).</p>

<h2>My notes</h2>

<p>Abstract:</p>

<blockquote><p>little empirical evidence supports or refutes the utility of this practice in an industrial context</p></blockquote>

<ul>
<li>they seem to be talking about inside-out tdd as in chapter 2 (page 291), they talk about small units and then integrating them in a bigger context</li>
</ul>


<h3>Benefits</h3>

<p>taken from chapter 2 (page 292)</p>

<ul>
<li>Better design</li>
<li>Efficiency</li>
<li>Test assets</li>
<li>Reducing defect injection</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusions</h3>

<blockquote><p>TDD seems to be applicable in various domains</p>

<p>[TDD] can significantly reduce the defect density of developed software without significant productivity reduction [&hellip;]</p>

<p>[&hellip;] an important aspect of TDD is the creation of tests assets.</p></blockquote>

<p>Recommendations (this is all quotes):</p>

<ul>
<li>Start TDD from the beginning of projects</li>
<li>For a team new to TDD, introduce automated build test integration towards the second third of the development phase</li>
<li>[&hellip;] add new tests every time a problem is found</li>
<li>Get the test team involved and knowledgeable about the TDD approach</li>
<li>Constantly running the unit tests [&hellip;]</li>
<li>Encourage fast unit test execution and efficient unit testing design</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talk: Software Is Eating the World]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-10T21:00:52+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://reaktor.com/blog/erik-meijer-software-eating-world/">this talk</a> by Erik Meijer</p>

<h2>My notes</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Agile-The-Good-Hype-Ugly/dp/3319051547">Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly</a></p></li>
<li><p>The hacker way</p>

<ul>
<li>code always wins vs manager always wins</li>
<li>source: <a href="http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter/">http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter/</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>we&rsquo;re doing maths => we&rsquo;re building a proof</li>
<li>reinforcement learning

<ul>
<li>agent is the company</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>related to &ldquo;build, measure, learn&rdquo; by Eric Ries (<a href="http://theleanstartup.com/book">the lean startup</a>)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Feedback systems</h3>

<ul>
<li>Open (no) feedback system, such as timed sprinklers</li>
<li>Closed feedback system</li>
<li>Output only system</li>
</ul>


<h3>Why everything is software</h3>

<ul>
<li>Examples of everything is software</li>
<li>Software is eating the world</li>
<li>Even hardware is modeled as software</li>
</ul>


<h3>Modeling as a Finite State Machine (FSM)</h3>

<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s memory in the feedback loop. See the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finite-state_machine">finite state machine</a></li>
<li>A lesson from &ldquo;World War Z&rdquo;: &ldquo;When nine people agree on something, it&rsquo;s the tenth man&rsquo;s responsibility to disagree no matter how improbable the idea&rdquo;. &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t believe your own [ideas]&rdquo;. There&rsquo;s an article <a href="http://lifehacker.com/plan-more-effectively-with-the-tenth-man-rule-1689738373">here</a> and <a href="http://evidencemag.com/world-war-z/">here</a>, but they don&rsquo;t cite any official source related to this. The second one cites World War Z again, so it might be <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">confirmation bias</a>.</li>
<li>Test in production (e.g., <a href="https://github.com/Netflix/SimianArmy/wiki/Chaos-Monkey">chaos monkey</a> from Netflix) rather than doing TDD</li>
<li>No evidence of TDD as effective, he sees it as waste</li>
<li>Move fast and break things</li>
</ul>


<h3>About layered organizations</h3>

<ul>
<li>Layered architecture. Examples: OSI, Catholic Church, Army</li>
<li>Analogy: Software development as a professional team structure (also cited from Netflix)</li>
<li>Book: Creativity from Constraints: the psychology of breakthrough. Focus, constraint, creativity</li>
<li>Presentation: <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Developing-Expertise-Dave-Thomas">Developing Expertise: Herding Racehorses, Racing Sheep</a></li>
<li>Analogy: Developers are like junkies, we want to be high all the time</li>
<li>Answering a new proposal: instead of &ldquo;no, but&rdquo; (black hat), &ldquo;yes and&rdquo; (blue hat). Reference to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bossypants-Tina-Fey-ebook/dp/B0047Y0FGY">Bossypants</a> by Tina Fey</li>
<li>Your knives, your tools. &ldquo;How can we make millions if we don&rsquo;t value our tools?&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>About software:</p>

<blockquote><p>software will take over the world, and developers are the ones who make it happen.</p></blockquote>

<p>About methodologies:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Programming, motherfucker. Do you speak it?&rdquo; (<a href="http://programming-motherfucker.com/">Source</a>)</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internal Training: Testing Is Hard - Just Do It]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/05/internal-training-testing-is-hard-just-do-it/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-05T23:00:17+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/05/internal-training-testing-is-hard-just-do-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At a client, last week we did an internal training, in the form of a discussion about this article: <a href="http://davidsouther.com/#/posts/2013/10/30/testing-its-hard-just-do-it/">Testing is hard - just do it</a></p>

<h2>Our thoughts</h2>

<blockquote><p>When a bug is found, prove it exists with a test</p></blockquote>

<p>This immediately reduces defect rate: the same regression cannot be introduced again</p>

<blockquote><p> fix a bug a second time</p></blockquote>

<p>If fixing a bug (having defects in your code) was &lsquo;waste&rsquo;, as defined by lean methodologies, it also is wast fixing it for the following times</p>

<blockquote><p>testing requires discipline</p></blockquote>

<p>Agree. See quote by Larry Wall (this same article)</p>

<blockquote><p>[Three requirements for a good test suite]:</p>

<ol>
<li>The tests need to be easier to write</li>
<li>The test suite must run, and pass, before any code is allowed out the door</li>
<li>Support from the project&rsquo;s leadership</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p>Agree.</p>

<blockquote><p>Programming is like drawing water from a well</p></blockquote>

<p>Good analogy</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;m going to assume you are smarter than me [&hellip;]</p></blockquote>

<p>This is related to &lsquo;doing clever things&rsquo;: when I write &lsquo;clever code&rsquo;, that has neither comments, nor it is massaged to be Clean Code, it will cost me many times more to modify / understand in the future vs massage it a little bit.</p>

<p>For me, an example of clever code are certain bitwise operations. Even though these operations are publicly available on websites and books, you must know about them before understanding the code.</p>

<p>Another example of clever code is taking assumptions, even if they are valid. Example: always return the second element because the first one is the header</p>

<pre><code class="java">private String select(List&lt;String&gt; elements){
    return elements.get(2);
}
</code></pre>

<p>vs</p>

<pre><code class="java">private String selectFirstValidLine(List&lt;String&gt; elements){
    List&lt;String&gt; validElements = skipHeader(elements);
    return validElements.get(1);
}
</code></pre>

<h2>Open questions / other ideas</h2>

<ul>
<li>There are tests that are more important than others. Is there a tool to assign them weights and inform about which preponderation of the codebase is broken? The same (i.e., more importance) can happen for production code.</li>
<li>Is SCRUM apt for junior developers? In the sense of the increased autonomy, more decisions, more required technical skills / values, etc</li>
<li>We discussed what differentiates a project with a shorter deadline from one with a longer deadline. The consensus was: you should do tests for any kind of project, the shorter deadline project won&rsquo;t allow as much time for refactoring</li>
<li>Tests iff (i.e., if and only if) working code</li>
<li>Tests do not guarantee lack of defects</li>
<li>Bijectiveness between tests and features (production code)
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demand for TDD and Refactor]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/demand-for-tdd-and-refactor/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-25T13:28:20+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/demand-for-tdd-and-refactor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I went to the Jason Gorman&rsquo;s TDD workshop (experience report <a href="../../../../2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop">here</a>), he said something interesting regarding refactor and TDD:</p>

<blockquote><p>In job offers / advertisements, TDD is much more in demand than refactor. But the latter is included in the former as an integral part.</p>

<p>Jason Gorman</p></blockquote>

<p>I agree with the second thought: you cannot properly do TDD without refactoring, as it is an integral part; also the third phase.</p>

<p>For me, sometimes refactoring is the difference between code and &ldquo;Clean Code&rdquo; (as defined in the book by the same title). If I cannot find the (algorithmic) pattern for the software I&rsquo;m writing, I try to introduce scaffolds to keep investigating until I can find a viable, general solution (if the problem requires it.)</p>

<p>Even after doing the refactor <code>replace algorithm</code>, the code might not have the responsibilities in the right place, the methods might be long, value objects not extracted yet, etc. This is where further refactor is needed to introduce all those qualities in the piece of software.</p>

<p>I believe that we programmers have done a bad job of communicating with the rest of the organization what refactoring is about. It has nothing to do with beauty, style or design (in the visual sense) but is related to maintainability, coupling, defects and quality. Money, in the long run, as its objective is to make it cheaper to change in the future, a better investment and ROI. This is the common language that the rest of the company understands.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redesign as a New TDD Phase]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/13/redesign-as-a-new-tdd-phase/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-13T22:00:45+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/13/redesign-as-a-new-tdd-phase</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last TDD workshop (experience report <a href="../../../../2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop">here</a>), a conversation with <a href="http://twitter.com/@garymcleanhall">Gary McLean Hall</a> introduced to me this new concept of &ldquo;Redesign&rdquo; as a TDD phase.</p>

<h2>Concept</h2>

<p>As Gary introduced it to me<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, it is a phase that might appear after refactor.</p>

<p>It is about changing the outside design without changing the expected behavior. I thought this was also included in the refactor phase.</p>

<h2>How I do redesign</h2>

<p>I usually do this &ldquo;changing of the outside design&rdquo; by applying a series of refactors <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> to the production code but not changing the test code; using a bridge / adapter to get to the new API from the old one. Later you can inline the scaffold and use the new API directly.</p>

<p>The same for the test code: when you want to change design in the test code, do not modify production code (a.k.a. model code).</p>

<h2>Other thoughts</h2>

<p>Merriam-Webster defines &ldquo;<a href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/redesign">redesign</a>&rdquo; as</p>

<blockquote><p>to change the design of (something)</p></blockquote>

<p>or</p>

<blockquote><p>to revise in appearance, function, or content</p></blockquote>

<p>an example:</p>

<blockquote><p>The book&rsquo;s cover has been redesigned for the new edition.</p></blockquote>

<p>The Refactoring book (by Martin Fowler) describes &ldquo;refactoring&rdquo; as</p>

<blockquote><p>Refactoring is the process of changing a software system in such a way that it does not alter the external behavior of the code yet improves its internal structure</p></blockquote>

<p>Taken literally, the public API is not internal but external structure, so changing it, should belong to a phase that is not refactor (see definition), nor red (no failing tests), not green (making it pass). Maybe this phase is &ldquo;redesign&rdquo; or we have to take the refactoring phase less literally so it includes redesign. Any thoughts?</p>

<h2>Other references</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve searched for redesign and refactor and <a href="https://practicingruby.com/articles/refactoring-is-not-redesign">this blog post</a> came up. They cite redesign as a way of rewriting</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/80758/1181094">This answer</a> and the <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/80758/1181094">original question</a> in StackOverflow is interesting</p>

<p>Redesign also appears cited in <a href="http://blog.testdouble.com/posts/2014-01-25-the-failures-of-intro-to-tdd.html">this blog post</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Excuse me if you explained it differently and I understand it wrong; you can always open a pull request to fix it <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/blog_source/tree/source/source/_posts">here</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>thanks for the clarifying refactor vs refactoring <a href="http://blog.4mm.co.uk/2012/12/11/pet-peeve-726.html">here</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
