<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tdd | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/tdd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-16T07:20:58+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TDD Meetup Retrospective]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-16T05:42:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday we organized a TDD meetup at the <a href="http://www.fib.upc.edu/fib.html">FIB - Barcelona School of Informatics UPC</a>, within <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Barcelona-Software-Craftsmanship/">Barcelona Software Craftsmanship</a> sponsored by the <a href="http://jediupc.com/">Junior Empresa d&#8217;Informàtica</a>. The meetup started at 9:00 until 18:00, with a one-hour pause in the middle.</p>

<h2>Where</h2>

<ul>
<li>Please make sure the meetup space (e.g., classroom, meeting room) is available and ready to be used at least 15 minutes before the meetup starts</li>
<li>The organizer and the event host should be there in advance to prepare the physical environment (chairs, wifi, beamer, etc) as well as mentally: getting comfortable with the space, loading the presentation, prepare the speaker notes, etc.</li>
<li>Plan for the worse and hope for the best: in this particular meetup, the beamer was not available, so the host gracefully lent us some 23 inch screen as a second monitor.</li>
</ul>


<h2>What</h2>

<ul>
<li>The speaker should have had already decided what they are going to cover on the meetup and not deviate much from this. Leave some empty buffer space at the end because you will cumulate some deviation during the day.</li>
<li>Of course, have the slides ready if you plan on using them</li>
<li>I prefer having more conversations during the meetup rather than a masterclass-style one. The organizer(s) should act as conversation moderators, often guiding the conversation where (they think) it is most useful. Sometimes, it is a good idea to interrupt the conversation when someone is getting bored or losing focus<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>.</li>
<li>Be prepared to ask to your attendees what do they want: they are your target</li>
<li>Please ask to your attendees to bring their laptop with git, dependency manager, IDE / editor, test double framework installed. Otherwise, most of the first session is invested in downloading / configuring these.</li>
<li>Please try to be communicative / funny in some way. This makes the slides easier to understand</li>
</ul>


<h2>Meetup details</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>We did two sessions of slides:</p>

<ul>
<li>Introduction to TDD</li>
<li>TDD on a daily basis: learn TDD for a greater good</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>We did three katas:</p>

<ul>
<li>LinkedList: <a href="http://codekata.com/kata/kata21-simple-lists/">source</a>. Originally by <a href="http://twitter.com/@pragdave">Dave &ldquo;Pragmatic Dave&rdquo; Thomas</a></li>
<li>Password: <a href="https://gist.github.com/trikitrok/c031d6b621f28b85ce0d">source</a>. Taken from <a href="http://twitter.com/@trikitrok">Manuel Rivero</a>, also seen on a <a href="http://twitter.com/@carlosble">Carlos Blé</a> workshop</li>
<li>Bank Kata: <a href="https://github.com/sandromancuso/Bank-kata">source</a>. Originally from <a href="http://twitter.com/@sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>The format was this: the first set of slides, the two first katas, some discussion, then lunch; coffee (mandatory); the second set of slides, the third kata (done by them), later done by me at the beamer, explaining the situation and my mental process.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Useful feedback</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>About the event:</p>

<ul>
<li>One 8-hour event is much more effective / efficient that 4 2-hour ones</li>
<li>No one complained about the lack of beamer. So don&rsquo;t worry too much if your host doesn&rsquo;t have one, as long as everybody can get close to the (big) screen.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>About the LinkedList kata:</p>

<ul>
<li>This, as a first TDD example was too complex. Getting into TDD with classes, and serveral functions at the same time might be difficult.</li>
<li>Too academic. This is an example you will usually never implement yourself, as there are libraries who provide it. Therefore, not applicable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>About the Password kata:</p>

<ul>
<li>They graded this kata easier than the linkedList</li>
<li>Start with this as it is only a function</li>
<li>This has didactic value as there are some gotchas with this kata</li>
<li>More likely to be implemented by yourself, as most systems require some kind of user authentication</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>About the Bank kata:</p>

<ul>
<li>More resembling of a day-to-day problem</li>
<li>This is a difficult kata if you haven&rsquo;t learned about mocks / test doubles</li>
<li>Interesting interactions between objects</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>For me:</p>

<ul>
<li>They liked both the format and the speaker (a.k.a., me)</li>
<li>They thought this meetup was well prepared in advance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>My own feedback:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is difficult to ask the attendees to rate their own level or for you to rate it. I thought the linkedlist example would be so easy they would finish it in half the allowed time<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>, but it wasn&rsquo;t this way</li>
<li>The productivity level varies hugely from person to person. There were some pairs that dug thoroughly on the problem and others who got stuck (sometimes with the language). Even though both types of pairs were working hard on the proposed problem</li>
<li>We still haven&rsquo;t solved the problem with reservations: many people book a seat on the event but later won&rsquo;t come. This makes other (interested) attendees to not have a seat.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Should you want to, please share your feedback / comments via the comments section below or sending a pull request to this <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/blog_source">repository</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>a good indicator of this is body language or position and whether they are doodling on a paper sheet.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>I did prepare against this adding more possible requirements to the kata, although we finally didn&rsquo;t use them<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mob Programming String Calculator Kata]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T04:46:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we did a kata<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> using a projector the string calculator <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> using pair programming, TDD and some mob-programming for the last refactoring.</p>

<p>We used a projector (beamer) so everyone could see it. I tried to take really small baby steps but the adding part was done in ~6 cycles<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve all learnt about shotcuts, live user templates for the IDE <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>, TDD methodology, other ways of tackling the problem, how to refactor as a group, clean code, etc</p>

<p>These sessions are necessary to share some knowledge among the teammates and have another chance of doing code review, releasing some pressure from daily practices or bad abstractions / designs (that will be taken care of in the future)</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had such a great time, learning together, that would be a candidate for a weekly interaction.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mob_programming">Mob programming</a> is such an eye opening practice. It forces you to reconsider your previous dogma and to understand the others&#8217; positions. Wikipedia reads &ldquo;early use of phrase [&hellip;] was made in &lsquo;Extreme Programming Perspectives&rsquo;&rdquo; but this practice is practiced by some, such as <a href="https://twitter.com/carlosble">Carlos Blé</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a> among others; also at the <a href="http://www.softwarecraftsmanshipbarcelona.org/">Software Craftsmanship Barcelona</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/scbcn2013?src=hash">2013</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SCBCN14?src=hash">2014</a> and the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/socracan?src=hash">SoCra Canaries 2015</a></p>

<h2>One goal</h2>

<p>Our goal for this session was to practice TDD and baby steps, so the team can improve its ability on these skills.</p>

<p>In any case, my objective for the katas (or deliberate practice) is not to get there as fast as we can but to improve our automated routines. This can affect our daily performance, as it becomes natural. It is not about the getting to the destination but enjoying the path along the way. In this manner, you are not so hurried up about a slow train but enjoy the views across the window.</p>

<p>It was good that QA people in the team came to the session. He even participated with some tips / implementations during the refactors. Always fruitful to discuss (and learn) mixed skills (QA / dev) from the other side of the wall</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I still haven&rsquo;t mastered the recipe (algorithm) for knowing when it is a scaffold and when it&rsquo;s time to refactor using &ldquo;replace algorithm&rdquo;. For know, I just use the three (3) rule and a bit of gut feeling on the side. The bad thing is that this can not be easily taught to someone else. Just learnt by osmosis and practice.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>matching none of the styles explained in <a href="http://johannesbrodwall.com/2011/12/18/how-to-start-a-coding-dojo/">here</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>This is a very good beginner&rsquo;s kata, created by <a href="https://twitter.com/royosherove">Roy Osherove</a>. Can be found <a href="http://osherove.com/tdd-kata-1/">here</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>One piece of feedback I received is that I talk too much while coding, as these 6 cycles took us about 45 minutes, total<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>There are some for <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/live-templates.html">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4022367/what-is-the-eclipse-equivalent-of-intellij-live-templates">Eclipse</a> too<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kata: Persistent Linked List]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/23/kata-persistent-linked-list/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-23T23:19:57+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/23/kata-persistent-linked-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve just written a new kata, about a persistent linked list.</p>

<p>It is using the same project as for the <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/kata-linkedlist">linked list kata</a>.</p>

<p>For now, only the <code>add</code>, <code>contains</code> and <code>size</code> methods are implemented.</p>

<p>If you have any comments or code review, please let me know</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Diseño Ágil Con TDD (Spanish)]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-02T21:32:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve read this book <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/libro-tdd/">Diseño Ágil con TDD</a> (Spanish) by
<a href="https://twitter.com/carlosble">Carlos Blé</a> from cover to cover,
when previously I had only read the theoretical parts (Part I and Chapter 12 in Part II).</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s worth noting that this is the first TDD book in Spanish (I haven&rsquo;t found any book in Spanish predating this one - also backed by the author; published in January 2010) and, as such, there are some translations that could be improved. Not that it makes it more difficult to read. Sometimes it&rsquo;s a good idea to roughly translate concepts into English and then you&rsquo;ll understand the point.</p>

<h2>First part</h2>

<p>The first part is very interesting, a theoretical introduction into TDD, ATDD and Agile methodologies. Points to some good books as a reference (e.g., Growing Object Oriented Software, Guided by Tests; Working Effectively with Legacy Code; Refactoring; etc)</p>

<p>He explains the TDD algorithm (chapter 2) and the ATDD one (chapter 3). These two are maybe the two most important ones on the book. Should you read only a part of this book, I&rsquo;d recommend to read the motivational intro (the fable on the preface) and these two.</p>

<p>He gives excellent pieces of advice who, correctly applied, would set the basis for good software development, such as SOLID, Object Oriented Design (OOD), Inversion of Control (IoC), etc. (See chapter 7, &ldquo;Diseño orientado a objetos&rdquo;).</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a chapter (number 6) on &ldquo;Mocks and other test doubles&rdquo; (translation is mine)</p>

<h2>Second part</h2>

<p>The second part, as many other books where the source code is printed, was dense for me. Other books, such as <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">GOOS</a>, show differences in content with bold typeface, to ease the reader&rsquo;s task.  In my opinion, it would be useful to color the diffs, show them on the left and right, or even show the raw diff (e.g., <code>+++</code> <code>---</code>). I&rsquo;m envisioning a typing program as LaTeX where you could specify a commit with its parent and a range of lines to output.</p>

<p>The second part is written in C# and python, to show a TDD session with him. Warning: it&rsquo;s much better in person than reading his book!</p>

<p>The chapter 12 is a set of antipatterns you might find after starting with TDD. Even after you keep practicing TDD for a while, you will not get rid of these smells. Highly recommended.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s also an appendix on Continuous Integration, although there are better books for this.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Recommend this book if you are starting with TDD, or you are more advanced but it&rsquo;s difficult for you to read in English.</p>

<p>Always good as a refresher to read the theoretical part and the antipatterns</p>

<p>PS: This book is free to read, published under a Creative Commons license (don&rsquo;t know exactly which one)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bank Kata in Java]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/bank-kata-in-java/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T22:52:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/bank-kata-in-java</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/trikitrok">Manuel Rivero</a> and I did a subset of the <a href="https://github.com/sandromancuso/Bank-kata">bank kata</a>, proposed by <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a>.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve used java (mockito, hamcrest, junit), outside-in TDD. The code is spread among several sessions. We have not committed after each step, only at the end of the session.</p>

<p>The source code is on <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/bank-kata">github</a></p>

<p>You can read Manuel&rsquo;s take on the kata on <a href="http://garajeando.blogspot.com.es/2015/01/kata-bank-account-in-java.html">his blog</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
