<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/dummy/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/dummy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-haskell-pyramid-https-patrickmn-com-software-the-haskell-pyramid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://patrickmn.com/software/the-haskell-pyramid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Haskell Pyramid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-verde-más-verde-https-mailchi-mp-bonillaware-verde-mas-verde-e-68e22b460d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/bonillaware/verde-mas-verde?e=68e22b460d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;El verde más verde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, project-management, slack-time, sabbatical, vertical-slice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ef00176e-7ddc-11e8-a33b-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 09:47:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer-https-dev-to-lewismenelaws-how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer-4opl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/lewismenelaws/how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer--4opl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Fix Burnout as a Developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on burnout and how to fix it:
Stop working so much.
Prioritize your health.
Try something new.
Patience is key.
Talk to your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lewis-menelaws, burnout, burn-out, productivity, listicle, career, psychology, management, time-management, career-management, health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 40d68542-7dff-11e8-89f2-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 13:53:09 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-what-is-the-first-thing-you-implement-at-a-new-company-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-17353854&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17353854&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: What is the first thing you implement at a new company?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the first things that people do when joining a new client.
Mentions the Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence: You don’t want to change something until you understand why it’s there in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chesterton-fence, hacker-news, contractor, client, onboarding, fix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9003a91a-7dff-11e8-a366-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 13:55:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fallacy-of-chesterton-s-fence-https-abovethelaw-com-2014-01-the-fallacy-of-chestertons-fence&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://abovethelaw.com/2014/01/the-fallacy-of-chestertons-fence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Fallacy Of Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Fence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence.
&amp;gt; don’t ever take a fence down until you know the reason why it was put up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author explains that the walls (or contracts, or clauses, or practices) were put in place to cover for a specific need. Do not assume that this need does not exist now, before understanding what the need was in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chesterton-fence, keith-lee, consulting, tip, analogy, discovery, process, people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 736e269e-7e00-11e8-ac4a-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 14:01:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-the-uuid-https-segment-com-blog-a-brief-history-of-the-uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-uuid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A brief history of the UUID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief history of UUID: of how it was developed, why, and a new library in go called ksuid
Explains the origins of networked computers (as opposed to personal computers without any networking) in the 1980s.
Also explains the origins of the UUID, some algorithms for generating them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ksuid, uuid, golang, go, rick-branson, history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c20e6ac4-8fe5-11e8-b54e-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:36:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivering-billions-of-messages-exactly-once-https-segment-com-blog-exactly-once-delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Delivering billions of messages exactly once&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how this company (segment) has solved the problem of delivering the messages once and only once (OAOO), using RocksDB, Kafka, UUIDs. Deployed to AWS, lowers the cost of the previous system (memcached-based).
Impressive numbers: 1.5 TB worth of keys stored on disk in RocksDB
a 4-week window of de-duplication before aging out old keys
approximately 60B keys stored inside our RocksDB instances
200B messages passed through the dedupe system
Also explains in depth how RocksDB works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rocksdb, facebook, database, once-and-only-once, oaoo, message, exactly-once-delivery, delivery, message-delivery, kafka, uuid, client, aws, segment, topic, cloud-scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 962c0c26-8fe6-11e8-bf2c-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:41:55 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;object-collaboration-stereotypes-http-www-mockobjects-com-2006-10-different-kinds-of-collaborators-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mockobjects.com/2006/10/different-kinds-of-collaborators.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Object Collaboration Stereotypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post describes the relationships between two objects:
Dependencies are services that the object needs from its environment so that it can fulfil its responsibilities.
Notifications are other parts of the system that need to know when the object changes state or performs an action.
Policies are objects that tweak or adapt the object&amp;rsquo;s behaviour to the needs of the system.
Parts are components in the implementation that are not controlled from outside the object after being set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dependency, notification, policy, part, collaborator, relationship, steve-freeman, goos, growing-object-oriented-software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f7e738c8-8fe6-11e8-89be-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:44:39 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mocks-fakes-stubs-and-dummies-http-xunitpatterns-com-mocks-20fakes-20stubs-20and-20dummies-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xunitpatterns.com/Mocks,%20Fakes,%20Stubs%20and%20Dummies.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mocks, Fakes, Stubs and Dummies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bibliography for mocks, stubs, fakes, dummies, spies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mock, stub, test-double, dummy, xunit, xunit-pattern, gerard-meszaros, xunitpatterns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea7281ee-9012-11e8-bd95-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 13:59:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-developer-after-40&#34;&gt;Being A Developer After 40&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/being-a-developer-after-40-3c5dd112210c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forget The Hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose Your Galaxy Wisely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn About Software History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep on Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workplaces Suck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know Your Worth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send The Elevator Down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take conscious decisions in your life. Be aware of your actions and their effect. Do not blush or be embarrased for changing your opinions. Say “I’m sorry” when required. Listen. Do not be a hotshot. Have integrity and self-respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommends these books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealers of Lightning by Michael A. Hiltzik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revolution in the Valley by Andy Hertzfeld&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar by Eric S. Raymond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Success of Open Source by Steven Weber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Old New Thing by Raymond Chen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mythical Man Month by Frederick P. Brooks Jr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peopleware by Tom DeMarco and Tim Lister&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Psychology of Software Programming by Gerald M. Weinberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facts and Fallacies of Software Engineering by Robert L. Glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Design of Everyday Things by Don Norman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly by Bertrand Meyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geekonomics by David Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrian-kosmaczewski, career, profession, age, galaxy, long-term, book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;firing-people&#34;&gt;Firing people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://zachholman.com/talk/firing-people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Holman on firing people at your current work, both from the perspective of the employee (fired), employer, coworker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains his personal experience of being fired from Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll know the difference between doing far and away your best work, and doing work that is still good, but just nominally better than what you’ve been doing. Once you catch yourself adjusting to that incremental progression… maybe it’s time to leave, to change things up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zach-holman, github, team-management, firing, coworker, employee, employer, job, relationship, next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-design-principles-for-developers&#34;&gt;10 design principles — for developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@nirbenita/the-10-design-heuristics-for-developers-1e70a9dc58a7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains what are the 10 design principles for programmers, as outlined by Jakob Nielsen. The article itself is by Nir Benita&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: design-principle, ux, jakob-nielsen, nir-benita, usability, testing, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two&#34;&gt;Design Patterns — Coming Full Circle, Part Two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two-ced2c69e4724#.x8ud7eeqm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains how design patterns can be observed and then discovered and shows a list of four patterns dot working with data, by flux.io. Article by Jen Carlile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: design-pattern, data, pattern, flux, flux-io, pattern-catalog, jen-carlile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days&#34;&gt;Why I’m Ending my Github Streak after 844 Days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@karan/why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days-80fd014dc8df&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Karan Goel on the mechanics of following a pattern, of an activity sliced in small parts (1 problem a day or half an hour) and how this can be counterproductive sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discusses ROI of this type of activity at the beginning of your career and later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: karan-goel, github, streak, python, code, everyday, practice, deliberate-practice, career, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs&#34;&gt;Good lessons learned from past jobs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kartones.net/post/good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Diego &amp;lsquo;Kartones&amp;rsquo; on a synopsis of his work experience, job by job and what he has learned on each job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: diego-kartones, job, professional-career, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;too-much-work-in-progress&#34;&gt;Too Much Work In Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://monospacedmonologues.com/post/144137568985/too-much-work-in-progress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Samir Talwar on factors that indicate work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wip, work-in-progress, list, samir-talwar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testdouble&#34;&gt;TestDouble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.martinfowler.com/bliki/TestDouble.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Martin Fowler describing the test doubles that Gerard Meszaros describes in xUnit Test Patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: test-double, martin-fowler, gerard-meszaros, stub, fake, mock, dummy, spy, xunit, junit, pattern, test-pattern&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it&#34;&gt;Scaling to 12 Million Concurrent Connections: How MigratoryData Did It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrotaru.wordpress.com/2013/10/10/scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mihai Rotaru on how MigratoryData scaled to 12 million concurrent connections in a 1U server. They explain what optimizations they did in order to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: migratorydata, mihai-rotaru, concurrent-connection, 1u-server, scalability, websocket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-what-you-love&#34;&gt;Do what you love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/do-what-you-love-jorge-diaz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jorge Diaz on doing what takes you out of your comfort zone, changing careers, and life-work in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/scott_dinsmore_how_to_find_work_you_love/transcript?language=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TED talk: How to find work you love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jorge-diaz, work, life, career, comfort-zone, scott-dinsmore, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app&#34;&gt;JHipster - The best way to breed a new app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/olbpetersson/jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by Ola Petersson, where he describes the architecture and contents of the jHipster, its pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jhipster, ola petersson, java, code-generation, code-generator, microservice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-going-to-coding-events-helped-me-get-an-awesome-job&#34;&gt;How going to coding events helped me get an awesome job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/networking-at-meet-ups-getting-hired-f0f7c4f4681a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gwendolyn Faraday on how to kickstart a career in web development, attending events, pairing and networking. That netted her some interviews to start programming for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: networking, gwendolyn-faraday, event, job, learn-to-code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maze-generation-algorithm-recap&#34;&gt;Maze Generation: Algorithm Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2011/2/7/maze-generation-algorithm-recap&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of maze-generation algorithms by Jamis Buck. Including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recursive backtracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eller’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kruskal’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prim’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recursive division algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aldous-Broder algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilson’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunt-and-Kill algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing Tree algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary Tree algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidewinder algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: recursive-backtracker,eller-algorithm,kruskal-algorithm,prim-algorithm,recursive-division-algorithm,aldous-broder-algorithm,wilson-algorithm,hunt-and-kill-algorithm,growing-tree-algorithm,binary-tree-algorithm,sidewinder-algorithm, jamis-buck, maze, maze-generation, algorithm, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-poverty-of-constraints&#34;&gt;The Poverty of Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2016/3/19/poverty-of-constraints.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jamis Buck on interpreting two Korean proverbs in the world of software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dutiful son comes from a poor home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A poor house has many children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: proverb, korea, philosophy, software, constraint, jamis-buck&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>