<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Day Of Code Retreat on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/global-day-of-code-retreat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Global Day Of Code Retreat on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 07:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/global-day-of-code-retreat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Day of Code Retreat 2014</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/global-day-of-code-retreat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 07:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/18/global-day-of-code-retreat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One month ago (on November 15th) I facilitated my first &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalday.coderetreat.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Global Day of Code Retreat&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebayenterprise.com/contact/locations.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eBay Enterprise International&lt;/a&gt; and had such a blast. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Barcelona-Meetup/events/218211672/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link to the event (Spanish)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-thoughts&#34;&gt;Some thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a month of thinking about it, here are some thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s GDCR was quite different that last one&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s OK: do not strive for repeating the same each year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat map (in several dimensions): TDD x language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually meetups have a clear goal, for the limited amount of time they run (see another bullet point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This single goal can span across multiple skill sets (e.g., TDD and language specific), therefore we did a two-dimensional heat map: first dimension is TDD skill level and second dimension (discreet) would be language you master&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1LRmjLbvFEtqDskDwb3gVBKDfXckqDylAMJA7HB6ZLC8/edit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Example can be found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a facilitator, have a clear goal for the meetup, even though you don&amp;rsquo;t need to share it with the assistants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mine was to have fun and introduce some people to TDD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared the goal with the attendants because I wanted to explain the purpose of that day to newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as a result of that day, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered some very motivated people in our host (eBay). Personally, I&amp;rsquo;d like to continue doing meetups with their developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need a mix of more seasoned attendants and more unexperienced ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, the knowledge is being transferred both ways; not only about the language but about strategies, patterns, shortcuts &amp;amp; editors, languages, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If doing TDD in these events, it&amp;rsquo;s even more important to mix people, as it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for an unexperienced pair to start doing TDD for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should only do your job as facilitator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let others discuss, ask and answer questions. Your job should be as thin as possible. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to answer too many questions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be attendants with more experience / expertise than you (most of them were in my case), so don&amp;rsquo;t strive to teach them but to manage the discussions to the right place&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be strict about timing but find the balance. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s useful to invest more time (~5 minutes) to a rich discussion and then reduce the next iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people will complain about having to delete their code the first time. Explain to them that&amp;rsquo;s part of the game and don&amp;rsquo;t give in. The following iterations most of the people won&amp;rsquo;t complain anymore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-critiques&#34;&gt;Some critiques&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We organized the event a little bit late&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The difference from last year (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Barcelona-Meetup/events/153967432/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;December&lt;/a&gt;) vs this year (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Agile-Barcelona-Meetup/events/218211672/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;November&lt;/a&gt;) was relevant. We were expecting to do it later so it surprised us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to that, many people couldn&amp;rsquo;t come and I&amp;rsquo;m sorry for it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We totally, definitely should do this more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to reinvent yourself for every global day or people will stop coming&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>