<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal-knowledge-base on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/personal-knowledge-base/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal-knowledge-base on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/personal-knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/01/self-study-may-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/01/self-study-may-2019/</guid>
      <description>The Problem of Thinking Too Much An example of what happens when you think too much. The paralysis that comes from it
Tags: persi-diaconis, stanford, stated-meeting-report, barry-mazur, spin-a-penny, decision-making, decision
Id: e14aba08-7add-11e9-9e23-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 20 May 2019 09:01:39 +0000
Personal web archives; a report Creating a personal web archive, based on the tools they created.
a browser extension for storing web pages, a web archive server hosting such snapshots, a(nother) browser extension to query such archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters  In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
