<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wewlc on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/wewlc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wewlc on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:56:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/wewlc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quote: Characterization tests</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/quote-characterization-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/quote-characterization-tests/</guid>
      <description>In Working effectively with legacy code, Michael Feathers talks a type of tests to define or characterize the current behavior of the legacy system:
 In nearly every legacy system, what the system does is more important than what it is supposed to do.
A characterization test is a test that characterizes the actual behavior of a piece of code. [&amp;hellip;] The test document the actual current behavior of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What legacy code is about</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/21/what-legacy-code-is-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 22:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/21/what-legacy-code-is-about/</guid>
      <description>In his book Working effectively with legacy code, Michael Feathers describes:
 [&amp;hellip;] legacy code as code without tests. It is a good working definition, and it points to a solution [&amp;hellip;]
M Feathers, in the preface of Working effectively with legacy code
 I really like this definition. It is objective and measurable. But this is also a downside. Let&amp;rsquo;s take any concurrent code, for example: you can achieve 100% coverage on a single thread and the program could have defects when executed in parallel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Diseño Ágil con TDD (Spanish)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book Diseño Ágil con TDD (Spanish) by Carlos Blé from cover to cover, when previously I had only read the theoretical parts (Part I and Chapter 12 in Part II).
It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that this is the first TDD book in Spanish (I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any book in Spanish predating this one - also backed by the author; published in January 2010) and, as such, there are some translations that could be improved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
