<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>profession on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/profession/</link>
    <description>Recent content in profession on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/profession/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>Scientific glassblower continues century-old campus tradition (2021) the story of a glassblower dedicated to producing specialized hardware for a university
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40549209
Tags: hackernews, imported, dredmorbius, glassblower, university, hardware, profession, glass
Id: e07b0ed2-185b-4cf7-bdbe-a134c555d797 Read: Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:26:29 +0000
Half a century of SQL https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40561440
Tags: hackernews, imported, pseudolus, sql, programming-language, anniversary, birthday
Id: f971c65c-8034-47c1-b2f5-24358c2de7b4 Read: Mon, 03 Jun 2024 11:04:06 +0000
Entropy, a CLI that scans files to find high entropy lines (might be secrets) https://news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Being A Developer After 40 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:
 Forget The Hype Choose Your Galaxy Wisely Learn About Software History Keep on Learning Teach Workplaces Suck Know Your Worth Send The Elevator Down LLVM  He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
