<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 2); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 1); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy My Story, Al Maktoum; non-technical  My Story, Al Maktoum  This important collection of anecdotes and reminiscences from Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum is published to mark the occasion of his fifty years in public service, which began with his appointment as Dubai’s Minister of Defence in 1968.
These stories tell of the vision behind Dubai’s meteoric growth from a small and bustling trading port to an international metropolis at the heart of global business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/01/self-study-september-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/01/self-study-september-2019/</guid>
      <description>Profiling Memory Allocations In iOS With Instruments Describes a technique for profiling memory allocations
Tags: memory-management, memory-allocation, tool, technique, ios, matt-eaton
Id: 237dd71a-dc50-11e9-b201-0242ac110003 Read: Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:13:56 +0000
Programming as translation  Converting the real world into digital abstractions requires distillation. And, like literary translators, developers must understand their biases.
 Tags: alvaro-videla, old_sound, analogy, metaphor, quote, umberto-eco
Id: a2c0f458-dc50-11e9-95d7-0242ac110003 Read: Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:17:29 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>How I use reveal.js This author explains how they use reveal.js.
The online editor (slides.com).
The author uses plain html for storing the slides.
Tags: slide, slideshare, reveal-js, reveal, presentation, slide-deck, michael-mccune
Id: 41e287b4-ae15-11e9-9e8a-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 07:16:33 +0000
All your digital life on a single timeline, stored locally Keep your digital life under your control
Tags: backup, local-data, encryption, control
Id: 4d115f64-ae17-11e9-bf0e-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:31:11 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein; own-it, finance, non-technical Candide; Voltaire; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Simple path to wealth, the; Collins; own-it, non-technical, finance Lagom; Brantmark; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Comment revivre par le jeune; Lützner; own-it, non-technical Educación financiera avanzada desde cero; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance Pensiones públicas, la esclavitud de nuestra época; Hernández; non-technical, own-it, finance On the shortness of life; Séneca; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Código del dinero, el; Samsó; own-it, non-technical, finance Más cosas sobre la bolsa; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance  4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein Candide; Voltaire Came across this book as the source for the term &amp;lsquo;Panglossian&amp;rsquo; or extreme optimist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/01/self-study-may-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/01/self-study-may-2019/</guid>
      <description>The Problem of Thinking Too Much An example of what happens when you think too much. The paralysis that comes from it
Tags: persi-diaconis, stanford, stated-meeting-report, barry-mazur, spin-a-penny, decision-making, decision
Id: e14aba08-7add-11e9-9e23-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 20 May 2019 09:01:39 +0000
Personal web archives; a report Creating a personal web archive, based on the tools they created.
a browser extension for storing web pages, a web archive server hosting such snapshots, a(nother) browser extension to query such archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</guid>
      <description>This quarter I&amp;rsquo;ve focused my efforts on a mix of everything:
 business books: Traction, The Goal philosophy: Stoicism and personal philosophy some finance: classic: Malkiel, personal finance: Robin some classic psychology: Frankl a classic novel: The Metamorphosis (Kafka)  Read this quarter:
 Hombre en busca del sentido, el; Frankl; own-it, non-technical Metamorfosis; Kafka; own-it, non-technical Your money or your life; Dominguez, Robin; non-technical, finance, own-it Traction; Wickman; own-it, non-technical How to Be a Stoic: Using Ancient Philosophy to Live a Modern Life; Pigliucci; own-it, non-technical Guide to the Good Life, The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy, a; Irvine; non-technical, own-it Goal, the; Goldratt (+); own-it Random walk down wall street a; Malkiel [Parts I, II, III]; own-it  Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB
Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable
Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000
Jepsen: Aerospike I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies
Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos
Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</guid>
      <description>Work cycles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this Work Cycle framework to be more productive with your daily routine.
Suggests an alternative to Pomodoro technique, in which you are to write down the contents of the goal, then split in small chunks (periods) of time to complete the individual tasks, then debrief at the end of the period and at the end of the cycle.
An analogy could be a double-loop Pomodoro technique for tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
