<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>garbage-collection on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/garbage-collection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in garbage-collection on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/garbage-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Build a Compiler, by Jack Crenshaw Crenshaw&amp;rsquo;s tutorial on building a compiler
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36054416
Tags: hackernews, imported, synack, compiler, crenshaw, brian-kernighan, rob-pike, programming, programming-language
Id: 3b2e9382-1144-4cfe-bdaf-72b30e8c3712 Read: Sat, 1 Jun 2024 09:14:25 +0000
Scientific glassblower continues century-old campus tradition (2021) the story of a glassblower dedicated to producing specialized hardware for a university
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40549209
Tags: hackernews, imported, dredmorbius, glassblower, university, hardware, profession, glass
Id: e07b0ed2-185b-4cf7-bdbe-a134c555d797 Read: Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:26:29 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
