<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/dave-dunfield/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/dave-dunfield/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defense of Tooling</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/30/defense-tooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/30/defense-tooling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quote (on a curriculum vitae) that I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a firm believer in the value of tools, and often spend significant time at the beginning of a project developing tools specific to the needs of the project. This always pays off in the long run. I use tools to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform tasks not otherwise achievable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automate tedious/repetative processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplify steps in the build/debug cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate &amp;ldquo;human error&amp;rdquo; in scanning, translation etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access internal information easily and efficiently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more &amp;hellip; the tools used in a project depend greatly on the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am also a big fan of automation. When you automate a process, you not only make it easier and faster to perform, but you also remove variability in the execution of that process. This means fewer procedural errors, a faster development process, and a more stable and reliable product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reliance on tools and automation means that you will see me sitting in front of a command line interface (easy to automate) more frequently than graphical one (difficult to automate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dunfield.maknonsolutions.com/dave.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dave Dunfield&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, it reminds me of how Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce try to remove as much uncertainty from a software project in the beginning of the project, not at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tooling is very important for everyday efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>