<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) Oliver Twist; Dickens Building evolutionary architecture; Ford, Parsons Selfie: How We Became So Self-Obsessed and What It’s Doing To Us; Storr. Just chapter 1: The dying self Sota la cistella; Gasol  Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) I&amp;rsquo;ve re-read this classic book (How to win friends and influence people), by Carnegie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/01/self-study-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/01/self-study-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>One year nomad - a review Tags: nomad, felix-krause, digital-nomad, remote, life
Id: 7784a1da-fc82-11e8-a2cc-0242ac110002 Read: Mon, 10 Dec 2018 13:49:51 +0000
The Reason Many Ultrarich People Aren’t Satisfied With Their Wealth How the rich are motivated to earn more money
 really rich people are often motivated to acquire more money by the thrill that comes with multiplying one’s fortune by making investments, buying up businesses
  Those two ways of putting money to use—as a way of covering expenses or as a way of building a bigger fortune—</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles Book of Transformation; Dalai Lama  Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book on philosophy and ethics. This book contains an analysis of the relationship between the personality, intelligence and happiness.
Tries to describe what &amp;lsquo;virtues&amp;rsquo; are, that they belong in a continuum of acts, aand the good term is always in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Quien se ha llevado mi queso; Johnson; own-it, guillem One minute manager, the; Blanchard; own-it, non-technical, guillem En defensa de los ociosos; Stevenson; non-technical, own-it Ladybird Book of Mindfulness, the (Ladybirds for Grown-Ups); Hazeley, Morris; non-technical Art of the start, the; Kawasaki; own-it, non-technical, guillem Getting started with NoFap; non-technical Emotional intelligence; Goleman; non-technical  Quien se ha llevado mi queso I&amp;rsquo;ve read this fable explaining the little story of two mice and two lilliputians that end up without any cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/05/01/self-study-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/05/01/self-study-may-2018/</guid>
      <description>Research Shows a Simple Way to Increase Your Engagement at Work
I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article By Michael Parke, Justin Weinhardt:
 We found that increasing your engagement and productivity at work could be as simple as making a plan for the day
 They talk about two types of planning: time management and contingent planning. The latter is about considering possible disruptions or interruptions they may face and a plan to tackle them (if they happen).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/04/01/self-study-april-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/04/01/self-study-april-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
Note: the tag &amp;ldquo;guillem&amp;rdquo; is for books suggested by Guillem Fernandez
 Odessa; Forsyth; non-technical, own-it Bogle on mutual funds: new perspectives for the intelligent investor; Bogle; own-it, non-technical, finance Perros de la guerra, los; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical avaro y el oro, el; Esopo; non-technical Aulularia; Plauto; own-it, non-technical Tus zonas erróneas; Dyer; non-technical, own-it Alternativa del Diablo, la; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Guía, el; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Pied piper; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Hunt for the Red October, the; Clancy; own-it, non-technical Peopleware; DeMarco, Lister (+); own-it Time to kill, a; Grisham; own-it, non-technical Ética promiscua; Easton, Hardy; own-it, non-technical Checklist manifesto, the; Gawande; own-it, non-technical, guillem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/01/self-study-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/01/self-study-march-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/02/01/self-study-february-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/02/01/self-study-february-2018/</guid>
      <description>Contract test I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bliki article by Martin Fowler on how to test the integration with external service providers. On how it should be integrated into the building pipeline, but maybe not fail exactly as the rest.
Tags: bliki, martin-fowler, contract-test, microservices, pact, integration-test, pipeline, continuous-integration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/01/01/self-study-january-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/01/01/self-study-january-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
