<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Difference | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/difference/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-21T00:10:22+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in February 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-01T00:55:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Software and all that comes with it</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2011/fromthefront/sgfgw/">these slides</a> about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini</p>

<p>Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile</p>

<h2>Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2011/ddd-day-it/shzym">these slides</a> about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini</p>

<p>Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</p>

<p>Tags: ddd, model, entity, aggregate, team-management, dba, agile, ubiquitous-language, alberto-brandolini, bus-factor, slide</p>

<h2>Shorter Feedback is not Always Bett</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://facebook.com/notes/kent-beck/shorter-feedback-is-not-always-bett/1097086386990891">this note</a> from Kent Beck on why shorter feedback loops might not always be better. I.e., why some processes take time to set in and results are not observable until that time.</p>

<p>Tags:  kent-beck, feedback-loops, open-question, analogy</p>

<h2>La Regla del Triple Check para ir a eventos</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bonillaware.com/regla-triple-check-para-ir-a-eventos">this article</a> by David Bonilla about a rule to help you decide attendance to events, in Spanish</p>

<p>Tags: rule, time-management, david-bonilla, event, spanish, triple-check</p>

<h2>An interview with Charles Wetherell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://demin.ws/blog/english/2012/08/25/interview-with-charles-wetherell/">this interview</a> by Alexander Demin about the interviewee&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Etudes for Programmers&rdquo;. In it, they talk about the origin of the études, the author&rsquo;s research interests and activities. Also about the book (written in 1978) and how computer science has changed since then.</p>

<p>When asked about three things a programmer should know:</p>

<blockquote><p>Some ability to do formal mathematics. The level necessary to understand Hopcroft and Ullman combined with a little graph theory is enough. Discrete mathematics is essential; calculus is only necessary for folks working in special application areas.</p>

<p>Some ability to write clearly in their native language. Dijkstra said that if a person couldn’t write their own language, they couldn’t write a correct program. (Well, that’s what I hope Dijkstra said!). Writing programs is essentially the same as writing a non-fiction essay. If you can’t make the step-by-step connections clearly in your own language, why would we think you could in C, for example?</p>

<p>Remember that a program is primarily for communication with humans, not computers. When you write a program, the computer will do whatever you say. You must convince the humans who read the program that what you have asked the computer to do is the correct thing to do. Remember, the computer doesn’t care about correctness.</p>

<p> The answer to the last question means that programs should always have the form of paragraphs of comments that describe the intention of the program followed by paragraphs of code that implement that intention. All of the formatting should be designed to make readers as able as possible to read the code easily; the compiler doesn’t care. In particular, follow conventions of mathematics and your native language, not those you found in some random language manual. Write the comments first and then write the code, not the other way around. If you don’t know what you want to achieve and why, any code you write is, by definition, incorrect.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: charles-wetherell, alexander-demin, interview, book, etude, etudes-for-programmers, practice, ability, skill, list</p>

<h2>How to fix Javascript… maybe</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@wob/how-to-fix-javascript-maybe-8857819bfa16">this article</a> by Drew Hamlett about the lack of style guide for javascript and how this affects the adoption of the language and the sprout of similar libraries.</p>

<p>Suggests the creation of a standard style guide for javascript.</p>

<p>Tags: drew-hamlett, javascript, style-guide, analysis</p>

<h2>Isomorphic JavaScript: #DevBeat Master Class</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/spikebrehm/a-28174727">these slides</a> by Spike Brehm on Isomorphic JavaScript and why it&rsquo;s important: initial pageload and speed, reducing effort and duplication, SEO (crawlability).</p>

<p>Tags: isomorphic-javascript, isomorphism, javascript, seo, crawler, frontend, app, application, fat-client, fat-server, thin-client, thin-server, ria-spike-brehm, slide</p>

<h2>Open-sourcing our docker images</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.modulus.io/open-sourcing-our-docker-images">this article</a> by Brandon Cannaday about the Docker images that they have.</p>

<p>Tags: docker, brandon-annaday, open-ource, image, container, modulus</p>

<h2>growing up in an open source world</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://fiveisprime.me/2015/02/18/growing-up-in-open-source/">this article</a> by Matt Hernandez where he explains that fixing the style guide can limit your creativity and how the software is written in enterprise and open-source environments.</p>

<p>Also about how developers grow when exposed to different style guides.</p>

<p>Tags: style-guide, matt-hernandez, creativity, dreyfus-model, enterprise, open-source, programming</p>

<h2>Hanlon&rsquo;s Razor and working with young engineers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://fiveisprime.me/2013/07/27/young-engineers/">this article</a> by Matt Hernandez on the importance of understanding (and empathising) towards others' positions and worries.</p>

<p>Cites the Hanlon Razor:</p>

<blockquote><p>Never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by ignorance.</p></blockquote>

<p> Tags:  hanlon-razor, empathy, team-management, ignorance, malice, matt-hernandez</p>

<h2>Intro to sails.js</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://youtu.be/GK-tFvpIR7c">this video</a>, an introduction to the sails.js framework: a realtime nodejs server for creating REST APIs, inspired by Ruby on Rails.</p>

<p>Tags: sailsjs, ruby-on-rails, ror, framework, video, introduction, mvc, rest-api, realtime, nodejs,</p>

<h2>Node.js and hapi - creating a rest api</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.modulus.io/nodejs-and-hapi-create-rest-api">this article</a> about creating a REST API using <a href="http://hapijs.com/">Hapi</a>, a nodejs framework. Written by Matt Hernandez</p>

<p>Tags: matt-hernandez, rest-api, nodejs, hapi, framework</p>

<h2>Introducing Pokedex.org: a progressive webapp for Pokémon fans</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pocketjavascript.com/blog/2015/11/23/introducing-pokedex-org">this article</a> by Nolan Lawson about the challenge of having a 60 fps application on a mobile device, making it offline.</p>

<p>Uses Angular 2, javascript 7, PouchDB as well as LocalForage for storage. All processing on WebWorkers, except for DOM manipulation.</p>

<p>Tags: angular-2, javascript-7, angular, javascript, pouchdb, localforage, cloudant, 60fps, mobile, app, offline-first, offline, pokemon, api, nolan-lawson, web-worker, flip-technique, css, progressive, pokedex, svgomg, frontend</p>

<h2>LambdaConf 2015 - How to Learn Haskell in Less Than 5 Years Chris Allen</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bg9ccYzMbxc">this video</a> by Chris Allen on how to learn haskell, what are some common pitfalls while learning it and how learning and teaching (it) are different.</p>

<p>Talks about his (with a coauthor) book, focused on not reducing the readers that make it to the end and, finally, increasing the amount of haskell users.</p>

<p>References <a href="https://yow.eventer.com/yow-2014-1222/stop-treading-water-learning-to-learn-by-edward-kmett-1750">this talk</a> by Kmett.</p>

<p>Tags: chris-allen, haskell, learning-to-learn, meta-learning, lambda-conf, talk</p>

<h2>Extreme Continuous Delivery - at Unruly</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.xpdays.de/2014/downloads/002-extreme-continuous-delivery-at-unruly/cd_javaone.pdf">these slides</a> about how the company Unruly does continuous delivery (CD), maximizing business value, minimizing time to market (TTM). Also describes how they do deployments and how to organize teams.</p>

<p>References: Extreme Programming Explained (Beck), Continuous Delivery (Humble &amp; Farley)</p>

<p>Tags: silo, team-management, culture, continuous-delivery, tdd, nagdd, shared-infrastructure, acceptance-testing, module-testing, conway-law, cross-pollination, continuous-investment, slide</p>

<h2>Building chat applications and robots for Skype</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://opensourcehacker.com/2013/03/28/building-chat-applications-and-robots-for-skype/">this article</a> on building robots for skype. By Mikko Ohtamaa</p>

<p>Tags: skype, robot, bot, mikko-ohtamaa, slack, integration, api</p>

<h2>Why I never wrote down our company values</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/swlh/why-i-never-wrote-down-our-company-values-8143520497e8">this article</a> by Mikael Cho on the subject of having company values, preaching or writing them down. Also, what happens when hard times come, regarding your values.</p>

<p>Tags: mikael-cho, value, company-value, analogy</p>

<h2>Interview with Jesper Louis Andersen about Erlang, Haskell, OCaml, Go, Idris, the JVM, software and protocol design </h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this interview (<a href="https://medium.com/this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial/interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-b0de06440fbd">part 1</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial/interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-5628fe591295">part 2</a>) to Jesper Louis Andersen, interviewed by Federico Carrone.</p>

<p>The first part is about a comparison of languages, what/why he uses them, and protocol design. The second is more about the Erlang language, the BEAM VM, and some experiences.</p>

<p>Tags: federico-carrone, erlang, interview, jesper-andersen, jesper-louis-andersen, haskell, ocaml, go, idris, the-jvm, protocol-design, software-design, language, functional-programming, protocol, land-of-lisp, northern-war</p>

<h2>Migrating to Hugo From Octopress</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://nathanleclaire.com/blog/2014/12/22/migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress/">this guide</a> by Nathan LeClaire on migrating the blog from Octopress to Hugo</p>

<p>Tags: static-site-generator, hugo, go, octopress, ruby, jekyll, nathan-leclaire, migration, blog, meta</p>

<h2>Dynamic Static Site Generators strategies</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://timnash.co.uk/dynamic-static-site-generators-strategies/">this article</a> explaining what are static site generators, and an example with Jekyll. By Tim Nash</p>

<p>Tags: tim-nash, static-site-generator, jekyll, strategy, explanation, comparison</p>

<h2>Blog like a confused hacker</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://timnash.co.uk/using-wordpress-static-site-generator/">this article</a> by Tim Nash on what tools he recomends for static site generation.</p>

<p>Tags: tim-nash, static-site-generator, jekyll, hide, strategy, explanation, comparison, sublime, wordpress, amazon-s3, cdn</p>

<h2>Resolving the Frontend/Backend API Design Conflict</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://launchany.com/resolving-the-frontendbackend-api-design-conflict/">this article</a> that explains the &ldquo;Backend for Frontend&rdquo; (BFF) pattern, for solving the different needs of data depending on each device / client. By James Higginbotham</p>

<p>Tags: james-higginbotham, bff, pattern, backend-for-frontend, api, soa, microservice, frontend, backend, architecture</p>

<h2>What If We Forget To Write The Tests?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=f70f14b644&amp;e=4a925444f9">this article</a> by J. B. Rainsberger on the trust issues related to starting to use a new methodology (TDD in this case) and how to see what impacts it might have in your day to day.</p>

<p>Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, tdd, motivation, team-management</p>

<h2>API microservices, the Unix philosophy, and the Richardson Maturity Model - a practical perspective</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@chrstphrhrt/microservices-the-unix-philosophy-and-the-richardson-maturity-model-425abed44826">this article</a> by Chris Hart on why startups and companies alike should be careful when choosing th latest technology and how this applies to microservices.</p>

<p>Tags: microservice, chris-hart, startup, analysis, company, technical-debt, bounded-context, ddd, rest-api</p>

<h2>Effective programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@sebas5384/effective-programming-d7e5bb2f3b80">this article</a> by Sebastian Ferrari on the importance of clean code, systems thinking and functional programming.</p>

<p>Specifies the important difference between effectiveness and efficiency.</p>

<p>Links to this talk by <a href="https://youtu.be/OqEeIG8aPPk">Russ Ackoff</a>. States the difference between &ldquo;the right thing&rdquo; and &ldquo;the thing right&rdquo;, by Drucker.</p>

<p>Tags: drucker, thing-right, right-thing, sebastian-ferrari, system-thinking, russ-ackoff, video, ted, difference, clean-code, functional-programming</p>

<h2>Learning how to learn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@thejameskyle/learning-how-to-learn-7f04d6f42c1e">this article</a> by James Kyle about the &ldquo;how to learn&rdquo; as one important skill for programmers and how having the solution at a few keystrokes limits / handicaps this ability.</p>

<p>Tags: programmer, learn-to-learn, james-kyle, stack-overflow, skill</p>

<h2>Why do some functional programmers criticize design patterns in OOP languages as a sign of language deficiency, while Monad is also a design pattern?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.quora.com/Why-do-some-functional-programmers-criticize-design-patterns-in-OOP-languages-as-a-sign-of-language-deficiency-while-Monad-is-also-a-design-pattern/answer/Edward-Kmett?srid=hVnO&amp;share=12410d1e">this answer</a> by Edward Kmett comparing the design patterns in OOP to the design patterns in functional languages.</p>

<p>Tags: functional-language, object-oriented-language, edward-kmett, oop, pattern, monad, interface, quora, answer</p>

<h2>Should We Even Debate Refactoring With Stakeholders?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=215f7f649b&amp;e=4a925444f9">this article</a> by J. B. Rainsberger on the power balance between stakeholders and programmers and how it can be inclined to a &lsquo;more trust&rsquo; / &lsquo;less trust&rsquo; by following some actions. The analogy is to a trade you cannot understand, therefore you have to hope that the taken decisions are in your best interest.</p>

<p>Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, refactor, business-need, communication, stakeholder</p>

<h2>The Eternal Struggle Between Business and Programmers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.thecodewhisperer.com/permalink/the-eternal-struggle-between-business-and-programmers">this article</a> by J. B. Rainsberger on the discussion between business (&lsquo;we want more features, now&rsquo;) and the programmers (&lsquo;we want more refactoring, now&rsquo;). Concludes that both players need each other, in a symbiotic fashion, to keep their jobs at the company.</p>

<p>He suggests that Scrum cannot work without the XP practices and that we need to refactor aggressively after having finished our initial design, to keep the costs down. In fact, agreeing with both parts in this discussion.</p>

<p>References one of his own videos, at Oredev'13, &ldquo;Fundamental Theorem of Agile Software Development&rdquo;, where he describes the relationship between accidental / essential complexity in the cost of a feature, attributing most of it to accidental (&lsquo;we&rsquo;re not good at our jobs&rsquo;) and describing the need for more design / refactor after the initial design.</p>

<p>Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, refactor, business-need, design, oredev, talk, agile, xp, scrum, software-development, accidental-complexity, essential-complexity, mythical-man-month</p>

<h2>Turning code to cash — How to make money as a Web Developer and live to tell the tale.</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@kurtrohlandt/turning-code-to-cash-how-to-make-money-as-a-web-developer-and-live-to-tell-the-tale-f5eedc557b3e">this article</a> by Kurt Rohlandt with a list of items to check while dealing with clients as a freelancer:</p>

<ul>
<li>Nothing is simple</li>
<li>Know your skill set — and let your client know it</li>
<li>Be clear about what they are buying</li>
<li>Learn to use the best tool for the job</li>
<li>To your client you’re more than just a developer</li>
<li>Sign off your jobs</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: freelancer, kurt-rohlandt, list, tip, client</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in November 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-02T13:25:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://aphyr.com/posts/315-call-me-maybe-rabbitmq">this article</a> by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.</p>

<p>Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery</p>

<p>Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &ldquo;Call me maybe&rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</p>

<p>Tags: rabbitmq, kyle-kingsbury, lock, cap-theorem, distributed-system, jepsen, knossos, at-most-once-delivery, at-least-once-delivery, counterexample, mutex</p>

<h2>Everyone is potentially a teacher</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/09/everyone-is-potentially-a-teacher">this article</a> by Carlos Blé where he explains that everyone can have ideas worth spreading and that the knowledge not only comes from others but also from the relationships that tie you to other people.</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, teaching, pedagogy, idea, teacher, relationship</p>

<h2>Ragel State Machine Compiler</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.colm.net/open-source/ragel/">this article</a> explaining what the Ragel project is about: a code generator from regex to code in languages such as C#, Java, etc. It is limited to finite state machines (FSM), with determinism. It can also handle some indeterminism. Written by Adrian D. Thurston</p>

<p>Tags: adrian-thurston, fsm, state-machine, finite-state-machine, code-generation, ragel</p>

<h2>HTTP is obsolete. It&rsquo;s time for the distributed, permanent web</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmNhFJjGcMPqpuYfxL62VVB9528NXqDNMFXiqN5bgFYiZ1/its-time-for-the-permanent-web.html">this article</a> by Kyle Drake explaining the need for a permanent, distributed web archive.</p>

<p>Using a distributed file system (IPFS) and software similar to Bitcoin, they can host parts of the web locally, making it immutable and distributed</p>

<p>Tags: kyle-drake, web-archive, centralization, decentralization, distribution, permanent-web, ipfs, federation,</p>

<h2>Recovering From the Integrated Tests Scam</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=42e61e203e&amp;e=4a925444f9">this article</a> from J. B. Rainsberger on the integrated test scam and how to solve it: refactoring.</p>

<p>Tags: jbrains, tdd, integrated-test, integration-test, j-rainsberger</p>

<h2>Broken windows theory</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broken_windows_theory">this wikipedia article</a> that talks about the broken windows theory, that states that controlling and monitoring public spaces leads to lowering the serious crimes.</p>

<p>Cites three causes for this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Social norms and conformity</li>
<li>Lack of routing monitoring</li>
<li>Social signaling and signal crime</li>
</ul>


<p>Also discusses examples in the US and in the Netherlands, as well as criticisms.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read it to better understand how to apply this theory to software development, on a day-to-day basis.</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, theory, broken-window</p>

<h2>Scsh</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scsh">the wikipedia page</a> for Scsh, the Scheme shell.</p>

<h2>Why is Scala&rsquo;s type inference not as powerful as Haskell&rsquo;s?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the reasoning why Haskell supports other type inferences that are not present in Scala, in <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7234095/why-is-scalas-type-inference-not-as-powerful-as-haskells">this StackOverflow question</a></p>

<p>Tags: scala, haskell, type-inference, hindley-milner, type-inference-algorithm</p>

<h2>The Future of the LispM</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://arrdem.com/2014/11/28/the_future_of_the_lispm/">this article</a> explaining the past and current situation in the Lisp world: from Lisp, to LispM, to the MIT and Symbolics Inc., to Clojure and Scheme.</p>

<p>Also talks about integration with the operating system and its execution in the microprocessor. Written by Reid McKenzie</p>

<p>Tags: reid-mckenzie, lisp, lispm, clojure, scheme, symbolics</p>

<h2>The Lisp Curse</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.winestockwebdesign.com/Essays/Lisp_Curse.html">this essay</a> by Rudolf Winestock, where he explains the low barrier (or low cost) for people in powerful languages (such as Lisp) to not accept the status quo in their project and fork / start their own.</p>

<p>It also compares languages and the people attracted to them. Cites Mark Tarver&rsquo;s essays several times, including the Brilliant Bipolar Mind (BBM) in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150308085419/http://www.lambdassociates.org/blog/bipolar.htm">this other</a> essay (from WebArchive). Compares the BBM and the normal worker in usefulness to companies.</p>

<p>Cites the Pareto principle (80-20 rule): a single hacker will port 80% the library from another language, leaving it buggy, undocumented and only understandable by the original author (assuming this is only 20% of the work). The rest (e.g., documentation, bugfixing, maintenance) are dropped and never taken care of.</p>

<p>Cites that this could be somewhat based on the facility of creating new features for the language. A small effort implies small implementation time, leaving no margin for thinking it through and seeing other corner cases. Also, a single person working on the project means no code review. The style might be coherent (always the same one), but might not be idiomatic, understandable by others, maintainable, etc.</p>

<p>Closes the essay with this quote:</p>

<blockquote><p>The expressive power of Lisp has drawbacks. There is no such thing as a free lunch.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: rudolf-winestock, essay, pareto-principle, hacking, one-man-band, lisp, no-free-lunch, quote</p>

<h2>The Bipolar Lisp Programmer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150308085419/http://www.lambdassociates.org/blog/bipolar.htm">this essay</a> by Mark Tarver on the Bipolar Lisp programmmer or the koan of Lisp.</p>

<p>It explains the history of the Brilliant Bipolar Mind (BBM) when they attend high school and college. The freedom they&rsquo;re given, exactly the same as in Lisp, as you don&rsquo;t need to mix and socialize with others to create a good-enough solution.</p>

<p>In this fashion, he says, most of the projects are 80% finished, not documented, not maintained. The same problems that worry enterprises.</p>

<p>Cites the article &ldquo;Lisp: Good News, Bad News, How to Win Big&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: essay, mark-tarver, bipolar-lisp-programmer, lisp-programmer, programmer, brillian-bipolar-mind, blp, bbm, koan</p>

<p>Note: this article was no longer present on its original site. Fetched it from the Web Archive (WayBack Machine).</p>

<h2>Writing readable Clojure code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jiriknesl/writing-readable-clojure-code">these slides</a> by Jiří Knesl, that explains how to write better clojure code:</p>

<ul>
<li>Macros</li>
<li>HOFs</li>
<li>left-to-right vs right-to-left code</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: clojure, jiri-knesl, macro, hof, thread, slide</p>

<h2>How can I get a reference to a method?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/485151/how-can-i-get-a-reference-to-a-method">this question</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4294485/how-do-i-reference-a-function-in-ruby">another question</a> from StackOverflow</p>

<p>Tags: stackoverflow, question, ruby, functional-programming, method-reference</p>

<h2>Implicit and Explicit Blocks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://rubymonk.com/learning/books/4-ruby-primer-ascent/chapters/18-blocks/lessons/55-new-lesson">this lesson from rubyMonk</a></p>

<p>Tags: rubymonk, lesson, block, ruby</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s Point-free Programing?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://xahlee.info/comp/point-free_programing.html">this article</a> by Xah Lee explaining point-free programming, which requires a glance at function decomposition (currying)</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] “point-free programing” is:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is about a particular <strong>syntax</strong> for <strong>function definition</strong>.</li>
<li>When <strong>defining a function</strong>, no symbol is used for function parameter.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<h2>Oracle’s “planned obsolescence” for Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://jaxenter.com/oracle-and-javas-planned-obsolescence-121144.html">this article</a> by Coman Hamilton on the possible Java&rsquo;s planned obsolescence by Oracle.</p>

<p>Discusses features pushed to future releases, comparing it to other legacy languages.</p>

<p>Tags: obsolescence, legacy-language, planned-obsolescence, java, java-ee, oracle, fortran, cobol, coman-hamilton</p>

<h2>Your first Ruby native extension: C</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.jcoglan.com/2012/07/29/your-first-ruby-native-extension-c/">this article</a> about writing a native extension for ruby. Written by James Coglan</p>

<p>Tags: james-coglan, ruby, c, native-extension</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s the difference between equal?, eql?, ===, and ==?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7156955/whats-the-difference-between-equal-eql-and">this stackoverflow</a> question regarding Ruby operators: equal?, eql?, ===, ==:</p>

<ul>
<li>==: generic equality</li>
<li>===: case equality (for case - when)</li>
<li>eql?: hash equality</li>
<li>equal?: identity comparison (pointer comparison)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: comparison, stackoverflow, ruby, equal, eq, ==, ===, question, answer, jtbandes</p>

<h2>Kanban</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban">the wikipedia page</a> for Kanban (Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, kanban, agile-methodology, management</p>

<h2>Is your Scrum team Agile?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.thesoftwarecraft.com/2014/04/is-your-scrum-team-agile.html">this article</a> by  Bart Bakker where he discusses some common patterns in Agile implementations (in software companies)</p>

<p>Tags: scrum, team, agile, scrum-implementation, bart-bakker</p>

<h2>Mejora tu trabajo en equipo con el método Kanban</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hipertextual.com/archivo/2013/11/que-es-kanban/">this article</a> that explains then kanban management framework, with its principles and its values. Written by Jose López (in Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: kanban, management, agile-methodology, management-framework, principle, value, jose-lopez</p>

<h2>¿Qué es el método Kanban para la gestión de proyectos?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javiergarzas.com/2011/11/kanban.html">this article</a> (Spanish) written by Javier Garzás where it is explained the kanban methodology and three of its main rules:</p>

<ul>
<li>visualize workflow</li>
<li>limit WIP</li>
<li>measure {lead, cycle} time</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: kanban, management, agile-methodology, management-framework, principle, value, javier-garzas</p>

<h2>describe vs. context in rspec</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lmws.net/describe-vs-context-in-rspec">this article</a> that explains the (lack of) functional difference between RSpec&rsquo;s <code>describe</code> and <code>context</code> methods. The difference is contextual (i.e., the amount of information they convey). Written by LM</p>

<p>Tags: rspec, ruby, describe, context, difference</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
