<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>barcelona-software-craftsmanship on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/barcelona-software-craftsmanship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in barcelona-software-craftsmanship on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/barcelona-software-craftsmanship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding dojo: Goldbach Conjecture</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/17/coding-dojo-goldbach-conjecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 23:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/17/coding-dojo-goldbach-conjecture/</guid>
      <description>At the Barcelona Software Craftsmanship meetup, today I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated a coding dojo on the Goldbach Conjecture. The problem was prepared by Manuel Rivero.
The meetup event is here and there are plenty of solutions prepared by the pairs:
 Java C# Haskell PHP Java PHP Haskell  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Space: Code reviews</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed about code reviews on this open space
Notes These are my notes, in no particular order:
 reduce information silos all around the company, as everyone [technical] can participate in these events raise the &amp;ldquo;just arrived&amp;rdquo; people&amp;rsquo;s knowledge [Difficult to hit the ground up and running, but these code review sessions can help] invest one person as &amp;lsquo;sheriff&amp;rsquo; for the sprint: they will take care of static analysis tools (such as sonar) and continuous integration (CI; such as jenkins).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
