<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dependency | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/dependency/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-30T07:58:37+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recognizing Dependencies]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/08/recognizing-dependencies/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-08T12:11:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/08/recognizing-dependencies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From the Chapter 3, Managing Dependencies, from the book Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby, by Sandi Metz:</p>

<blockquote><p>An object has a dependency when it knows:</p>

<ul>
<li>The name of another class. [&hellip;]</li>
<li>The name of a message that it intends to send to someone other than self. [&hellip;]</li>
<li>The arguments that a message requires. [&hellip;]</li>
<li>The order of those arguments. [&hellip;]</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>If an object knows any of these facts about another object, it has dependencies to the other.</p>

<p>This is not to say that having dependencies to others is bad, as</p>

<blockquote><p>A single object cannot know everything, so inevitably it will have to talk to another object.
Chapter 3, Managing Dependencies, Introduction</p></blockquote>

<p>For this latter purpose, there is the section &ldquo;Writing loosely coupled code&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Defines a Dependency]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/what-defines-a-dependency/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-13T05:48:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/what-defines-a-dependency</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend and I were arguing about this code (<a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/cos/blob/7bf866bdfb9006d73a0124e00152e55c520d98a4/src/main/java/users/Registry.java">fragment</a>):</p>

<pre><code class="java">public void register (final String userName)  {
    try {
        registeredUsers.add(new User(userName));
    } catch (AlreadyRegisteredUserException e) {
        resultListener.alreadyRegistered(userName);
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>I would have said that <code>resultListener</code> is a dependency as, first, it was injected by the constructor, second, it is necessary for the execution (negative case).</p>

<p>He suggested that:</p>

<ul>
<li>being injected through  the constructor is usually what happens with dependencies, but does not make it one (i.e., something can be injected by the constructor and not be a dependency)</li>
<li>what defines a dependency is related to the business: if this behavior is mandatory for the business, then it is a dependency.</li>
</ul>


<p>As a conclusion, <code>resultListener</code> would be a notification, as business does not require it.</p>

<p>On a later commit, we decided to inject it to <code>registeredUsers</code> (<a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/cos/blob/c89bec1a2de388165676f095c2218afeb1321374/src/main/java/users/InMemoryRegisteredUsers.java">fragment</a>)</p>

<pre><code class="java">public void add (User user, final RegistryResultListener resultListener) {
    if(contains(user)) {
        resultListener.alreadyRegistered(user.name());
        return;
    }

    users.add(user);
    resultListener.successfullyRegistered(user.name());
}
</code></pre>

<p>Note: for cases when no one needs to be informed about the users being registered or not, a null-object pattern will suffice, as there is no check for null reference in the parameter <code>resultListener</code>.</p>

<p>Note: more information on object stereotypes can be found <a href="../../../../2015/07/13/object-peer-stereotypes/">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Object Peer Stereotypes]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/object-peer-stereotypes/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-13T05:36:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/object-peer-stereotypes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>We categorize an object&rsquo;s peers (loosely) into three types of relationship. An object might have:</p>

<ul>
<li>Dependencies: Services that the object requires from its peers so it can perform its responsibilities. The object cannot function without these services. It should not be possible to create the object without them. For example, a graphics package will need something like a screen or canvas to draw on&ndash;it doesn&rsquo;t make sense without one.</li>
<li>Notifications: Peers that need to be kept up to date with the object&rsquo;s activity. The object will notify interested peers whenever it changes state or performs a significant action. Notifications are &ldquo;fire and forget&rdquo;; the object neither knows nor cares which peers are listening. Notifications are so useful because they decouple objects from each other. For example, in a user interface system, a button component promises to notify any registered listeners when it&rsquo;s clicked, but does not know what those listeners will do. Similarly, the listeners expect to be called but know nothing of the way the user interface dispatches its events.</li>
<li>Adjustments: Peers that adjust the object&rsquo;s behavior to the wider needs of the system. This includes policy objects that make decisions on the object&rsquo;s behalf (the Strategy pattern in [Gamma94]) and component parts of the object if it&rsquo;s a composite. For example, a Swing JTable will ask a TableCellRenderer to draw a cell&rsquo;s value, perhaps as RGB (Red, Green, Blue) values for a color. If we change the renderer, the table will change its presentation, now displaying the HSB (Hue, Saturation, Brightness) values.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Source is Growing Object-Oriented Software, Guided by Tests > Chapter 6, Object-Oriented Style > Object Peer Stereotypes, page 52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
