<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2021</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Perfect Media Server Hacker News discussion on a media server, half open source (?).
Tags: hacker-news, media-server, perfect, tool, software
Id: c37b0f2a-4dc5-11eb-8048-0242ac110002 Read: Sun, 03 Jan 2021 13:15:34 +0000
How your startup can survive technical debt Mentions the paradox of success: you need debt to start quickly, yet too quickly leaves no time to pay debt. Hence your prototype turns into an MVP, and that is your first piecce of technical debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters  In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in May 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015 into a single post
Programmer passion considered harmful I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.
Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by Ken Auer
Improve your development environments with virtualization I have seen this video: Improve your development environments with virtualization by Luke Sneeringer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
