<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: February | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/february/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-07T18:38:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in February 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-01T00:55:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>

<h2>Software and all that comes with it</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2011/fromthefront/sgfgw/">these slides</a> about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini</p>

<p>Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile</p>

<h2>Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2011/ddd-day-it/shzym">these slides</a> about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini</p>

<p>Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</p>

<p>Tags: ddd, model, entity, aggregate, team-management, dba, agile, ubiquitous-language, alberto-brandolini, bus-factor, slide</p>

<h2>La Regla del Triple Check para ir a eventos</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bonillaware.com/regla-triple-check-para-ir-a-eventos">this article</a> by David Bonilla about a rule to help you decide attendance to events, in Spanish</p>

<p>Tags: rule, time-management, david-bonilla, event, spanish, triple-check</p>

<h2>An interview with Charles Wetherell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://demin.ws/blog/english/2012/08/25/interview-with-charles-wetherell/">this interview</a> by Alexander Demin about the interviewee&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Etudes for Programmers&rdquo;. In it, they talk about the origin of the études, the author&rsquo;s research interests and activities. Also about the book (written in 1978) and how computer science has changed since then.</p>

<p>When asked about three things a programmer should know:</p>

<blockquote><p>Some ability to do formal mathematics. The level necessary to understand Hopcroft and Ullman combined with a little graph theory is enough. Discrete mathematics is essential; calculus is only necessary for folks working in special application areas.</p>

<p>Some ability to write clearly in their native language. Dijkstra said that if a person couldn’t write their own language, they couldn’t write a correct program. (Well, that’s what I hope Dijkstra said!). Writing programs is essentially the same as writing a non-fiction essay. If you can’t make the step-by-step connections clearly in your own language, why would we think you could in C, for example?</p>

<p>Remember that a program is primarily for communication with humans, not computers. When you write a program, the computer will do whatever you say. You must convince the humans who read the program that what you have asked the computer to do is the correct thing to do. Remember, the computer doesn’t care about correctness.</p>

<p> The answer to the last question means that programs should always have the form of paragraphs of comments that describe the intention of the program followed by paragraphs of code that implement that intention. All of the formatting should be designed to make readers as able as possible to read the code easily; the compiler doesn’t care. In particular, follow conventions of mathematics and your native language, not those you found in some random language manual. Write the comments first and then write the code, not the other way around. If you don’t know what you want to achieve and why, any code you write is, by definition, incorrect.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: charles-wetherell, alexander-demin, interview, book, etude, etudes-for-programmers, practice, ability, skill, list</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
