<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Carlos-ble | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/carlos-ble/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-15T12:06:51+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in November 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-02T13:25:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://aphyr.com/posts/315-call-me-maybe-rabbitmq">this article</a> by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.</p>

<p>Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery</p>

<p>Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &ldquo;Call me maybe&rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</p>

<p>Tags: rabbitmq, kyle-kingsbury, lock, cap-theorem, distributed-system, jepsen, knossos, at-most-once-delivery, at-least-once-delivery, counterexample, mutex</p>

<h2>Everyone is potentially a teacher</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/09/everyone-is-potentially-a-teacher">this article</a> by Carlos Blé where he explains that everyone can have ideas worth spreading and that the knowledge not only comes from others but also from the relationships that tie you to other people.</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, teaching, pedagogy, idea, teacher, relationship</p>

<h2>Ragel State Machine Compiler</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.colm.net/open-source/ragel/">this article</a> explaining what the Ragel project is about: a code generator from regex to code in languages such as C#, Java, etc. It is limited to finite state machines (FSM), with determinism. It can also handle some indeterminism. Written by Adrian D. Thurston</p>

<p>Tags: adrian-thurston, fsm, state-machine, finite-state-machine, code-generation, ragel</p>

<h2>HTTP is obsolete. It&rsquo;s time for the distributed, permanent web</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmNhFJjGcMPqpuYfxL62VVB9528NXqDNMFXiqN5bgFYiZ1/its-time-for-the-permanent-web.html">this article</a> by Kyle Drake explaining the need for a permanent, distributed web archive.</p>

<p>Using a distributed file system (IPFS) and software similar to Bitcoin, they can host parts of the web locally, making it immutable and distributed</p>

<p>Tags: kyle-drake, web-archive, centralization, decentralization, distribution, permanent-web, ipfs, federation,</p>

<h2>Recovering From the Integrated Tests Scam</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=42e61e203e&amp;e=4a925444f9">this article</a> from J. B. Rainsberger on the integrated test scam and how to solve it: refactoring.</p>

<p>Tags: jbrains, tdd, integrated-test, integration-test, j-rainsberger</p>

<h2>Broken windows theory</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broken_windows_theory">this wikipedia article</a> that talks about the broken windows theory, that states that controlling and monitoring public spaces leads to lowering the serious crimes.</p>

<p>Cites three causes for this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Social norms and conformity</li>
<li>Lack of routing monitoring</li>
<li>Social signaling and signal crime</li>
</ul>


<p>Also discusses examples in the US and in the Netherlands, as well as criticisms.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read it to better understand how to apply this theory to software development, on a day-to-day basis.</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, theory, broken-window</p>

<h2>Scsh</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scsh">the wikipedia page</a> for Scsh, the Scheme shell.</p>

<h2>Why is Scala&rsquo;s type inference not as powerful as Haskell&rsquo;s?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the reasoning why Haskell supports other type inferences that are not present in Scala, in <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7234095/why-is-scalas-type-inference-not-as-powerful-as-haskells">this StackOverflow question</a></p>

<p>Tags: scala, haskell, type-inference, hindley-milner, type-inference-algorithm</p>

<h2>The Future of the LispM</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://arrdem.com/2014/11/28/the_future_of_the_lispm/">this article</a> explaining the past and current situation in the Lisp world: from Lisp, to LispM, to the MIT and Symbolics Inc., to Clojure and Scheme.</p>

<p>Also talks about integration with the operating system and its execution in the microprocessor. Written by Reid McKenzie</p>

<p>Tags: reid-mckenzie, lisp, lispm, clojure, scheme, symbolics</p>

<h2>The Lisp Curse</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.winestockwebdesign.com/Essays/Lisp_Curse.html">this essay</a> by Rudolf Winestock, where he explains the low barrier (or low cost) for people in powerful languages (such as Lisp) to not accept the status quo in their project and fork / start their own.</p>

<p>It also compares languages and the people attracted to them. Cites Mark Tarver&rsquo;s essays several times, including the Brilliant Bipolar Mind (BBM) in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150308085419/http://www.lambdassociates.org/blog/bipolar.htm">this other</a> essay (from WebArchive). Compares the BBM and the normal worker in usefulness to companies.</p>

<p>Cites the Pareto principle (80-20 rule): a single hacker will port 80% the library from another language, leaving it buggy, undocumented and only understandable by the original author (assuming this is only 20% of the work). The rest (e.g., documentation, bugfixing, maintenance) are dropped and never taken care of.</p>

<p>Cites that this could be somewhat based on the facility of creating new features for the language. A small effort implies small implementation time, leaving no margin for thinking it through and seeing other corner cases. Also, a single person working on the project means no code review. The style might be coherent (always the same one), but might not be idiomatic, understandable by others, maintainable, etc.</p>

<p>Closes the essay with this quote:</p>

<blockquote><p>The expressive power of Lisp has drawbacks. There is no such thing as a free lunch.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: rudolf-winestock, essay, pareto-principle, hacking, one-man-band, lisp, no-free-lunch, quote</p>

<h2>The Bipolar Lisp Programmer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150308085419/http://www.lambdassociates.org/blog/bipolar.htm">this essay</a> by Mark Tarver on the Bipolar Lisp programmmer or the koan of Lisp.</p>

<p>It explains the history of the Brilliant Bipolar Mind (BBM) when they attend high school and college. The freedom they&rsquo;re given, exactly the same as in Lisp, as you don&rsquo;t need to mix and socialize with others to create a good-enough solution.</p>

<p>In this fashion, he says, most of the projects are 80% finished, not documented, not maintained. The same problems that worry enterprises.</p>

<p>Cites the article &ldquo;Lisp: Good News, Bad News, How to Win Big&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: essay, mark-tarver, bipolar-lisp-programmer, lisp-programmer, programmer, brillian-bipolar-mind, blp, bbm, koan</p>

<p>Note: this article was no longer present on its original site. Fetched it from the Web Archive (WayBack Machine).</p>

<h2>Writing readable Clojure code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jiriknesl/writing-readable-clojure-code">these slides</a> by Jiří Knesl, that explains how to write better clojure code:</p>

<ul>
<li>Macros</li>
<li>HOFs</li>
<li>left-to-right vs right-to-left code</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: clojure, jiri-knesl, macro, hof, thread, slide</p>

<h2>How can I get a reference to a method?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/485151/how-can-i-get-a-reference-to-a-method">this question</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4294485/how-do-i-reference-a-function-in-ruby">another question</a> from StackOverflow</p>

<p>Tags: stackoverflow, question, ruby, functional-programming, method-reference</p>

<h2>Implicit and Explicit Blocks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://rubymonk.com/learning/books/4-ruby-primer-ascent/chapters/18-blocks/lessons/55-new-lesson">this lesson from rubyMonk</a></p>

<p>Tags: rubymonk, lesson, block, ruby</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s Point-free Programing?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://xahlee.info/comp/point-free_programing.html">this article</a> by Xah Lee explaining point-free programming, which requires a glance at function decomposition (currying)</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] “point-free programing” is:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is about a particular <strong>syntax</strong> for <strong>function definition</strong>.</li>
<li>When <strong>defining a function</strong>, no symbol is used for function parameter.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<h2>Oracle’s “planned obsolescence” for Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://jaxenter.com/oracle-and-javas-planned-obsolescence-121144.html">this article</a> by Coman Hamilton on the possible Java&rsquo;s planned obsolescence by Oracle.</p>

<p>Discusses features pushed to future releases, comparing it to other legacy languages.</p>

<p>Tags: obsolescence, legacy-language, planned-obsolescence, java, java-ee, oracle, fortran, cobol, coman-hamilton</p>

<h2>Your first Ruby native extension: C</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.jcoglan.com/2012/07/29/your-first-ruby-native-extension-c/">this article</a> about writing a native extension for ruby. Written by James Coglan</p>

<p>Tags: james-coglan, ruby, c, native-extension</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s the difference between equal?, eql?, ===, and ==?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7156955/whats-the-difference-between-equal-eql-and">this stackoverflow</a> question regarding Ruby operators: equal?, eql?, ===, ==:</p>

<ul>
<li>==: generic equality</li>
<li>===: case equality (for case - when)</li>
<li>eql?: hash equality</li>
<li>equal?: identity comparison (pointer comparison)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: comparison, stackoverflow, ruby, equal, eq, ==, ===, question, answer, jtbandes</p>

<h2>Kanban</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban">the wikipedia page</a> for Kanban (Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, kanban, agile-methodology, management</p>

<h2>Is your Scrum team Agile?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.thesoftwarecraft.com/2014/04/is-your-scrum-team-agile.html">this article</a> by  Bart Bakker where he discusses some common patterns in Agile implementations (in software companies)</p>

<p>Tags: scrum, team, agile, scrum-implementation, bart-bakker</p>

<h2>Mejora tu trabajo en equipo con el método Kanban</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hipertextual.com/archivo/2013/11/que-es-kanban/">this article</a> that explains then kanban management framework, with its principles and its values. Written by Jose López (in Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: kanban, management, agile-methodology, management-framework, principle, value, jose-lopez</p>

<h2>¿Qué es el método Kanban para la gestión de proyectos?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javiergarzas.com/2011/11/kanban.html">this article</a> (Spanish) written by Javier Garzás where it is explained the kanban methodology and three of its main rules:</p>

<ul>
<li>visualize workflow</li>
<li>limit WIP</li>
<li>measure {lead, cycle} time</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: kanban, management, agile-methodology, management-framework, principle, value, javier-garzas</p>

<h2>describe vs. context in rspec</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lmws.net/describe-vs-context-in-rspec">this article</a> that explains the (lack of) functional difference between RSpec&rsquo;s <code>describe</code> and <code>context</code> methods. The difference is contextual (i.e., the amount of information they convey). Written by LM</p>

<p>Tags: rspec, ruby, describe, context, difference</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in August 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-02T19:45:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Humble Object</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the <a href="http://xunitpatterns.com/Humble%20Object.html">Humble Object</a> list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>humble dialog</li>
<li>humble executable</li>
<li>humble transaction controller</li>
<li>humble container adapter</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros</p>

<h2>How you know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve reread <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/know.html">this small essay</a> by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.</p>

<p>Tags: paul-graham, reread, read</p>

<h2>Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.martinfowler.com/ieeeSoftware/protectedVariation.pdf">this article</a> by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software > Design.</p>

<p>Discusses Information Hiding, Protected Variation and the Open-Closed Principle.</p>

<p>Tags: craig-larman, ocp, open-closed principle, design, information-hiding, ih, protected-variation, pv,</p>

<h2>Lambda, Javascript Micro-Services on AWS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.jayway.com/2014/12/18/lambda-javascript-micro-services-aws/">this post</a> explaining how to deploy a microservice on AWS on top of Lambda. Written by Anders Janmyr</p>

<p>The cool thing is that you get billed by milliseconds!</p>

<p>Tags: anders-janmyr, devops, microservice, lambda, aws</p>

<h2>Migrating To Clojure. So Much Fn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hv4slaRydRM">this talk</a> by Jan Stępień where he talks about his experience on migrating part of an application to clojure from ruby on rails</p>

<p>Tags: jan-stepien, clojure, migration, ruby-on-rails, talk, wrocloverb</p>

<h2>Te recomiendo escribir en un blog</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/07/te-recomiendo-escribir-en-un-blog/">this article</a> from Carlos Blé in which he recommends writing a blog, on things we discover along the way. (Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, meta, blog, long-way</p>

<h2>We need enough technical debt</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.svpino.com/2015/08/05/we-need-enough-technical-debt">this article</a> on why we need to accumulate a bit of technical debt, as a way of being less perfectionist and deliver more features / value to our stakeholders. Written by Santiago L. Valdarrama.</p>

<p>Tags: santiago-valdarrama, technical-debt, perfectionism</p>

<h2>Escribe mejores tests en Javascript</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://carlosvillu.com/escribe-mejores-tests-en-javascript/">this list</a> of tips to write better javascript tests (Spanish). By Carlos Villuendas</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-villuendas, javascript, test</p>

<h2>Down the Rabbit Hole</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/brettwooldridge/HikariCP/wiki/Down-the-Rabbit-Hole">this wiki</a> page on how to tune some aspects of the server hotspot JVM, by Brett Wooldridge</p>

<p>Tags: performance, jvm, hotspot, inline, bytecode, brett-wooldridge</p>

<h2>XP Manchester Lightning Talks 2015 Live broadcast</h2>

<p>I have watched the first two <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VD4UEW2i7hU">lightning talks</a> from XP Manchester, edition number 61.</p>

<p>Tags: lightning-talk, broadcast, simplicity, manchester, 2015</p>

<h2>Counting hash collisions with the birthday paradox</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/counting-hash-collisions/">this article</a> on the birthday paradox, or the percentage of chance of people sharing the same birthday. This could be applied to hash function, as the title says, but is not included in the article. Written by Matt Might</p>

<h2>Why I&rsquo;m The Best Programmer In The World*</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/why-im-the-best-programmer-in-the-world/">this ironically-titled article</a> by Jeff Atwood on humility and how to improve as a programmer.</p>

<p>Tags: jeff-atwood</p>

<h2>The Key to Giving and Receiving Negative Feedback</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hbr.org/2015/08/the-key-to-giving-and-receiving-negative-feedback?">this article</a> by Joseph Grenny about how to give and receive negative feedback. It is exemplified by the plant manager who was expecting another kind of feedback from his subordinates and was surprised by their negative feedback.</p>

<p>Tags: joseph-grenny, negative-feedback, feedback, by-example</p>

<h2>Testing Clojure web applications with Kerodon</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://semaphoreci.com/community/tutorials/testing-clojure-web-applications-with-kerodon">this guide</a> on how to test compojure-based applications with kerodon. Written by Nebojša Stričević</p>

<p>Tags: nebojsa-stricevic, compojure, kerodon, clojure, testing, guide</p>

<h2>Using The Option Type Effectively</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uku-taht/2015/04/29/using-the-option-type-effectively.html">this article</a> on how to use the <code>Option</code> type (in rust), similar to <code>Optional</code> in java or <code>Maybe</code> in haskell. Written by Uku Taht.</p>

<p>Tags: uku-taht, option, maybe, optional, rust</p>

<h2>When Should You Think?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/03/11/when-to-think.html">this post</a> by Robert C Martin on when to think and the hypothesis that TDD does not allow you to think before coding.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, robert-c-martin, design, hypothesis</p>

<h2>Orthogonal latin squares: an application of experiment design to compiler testing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://barbie.uta.edu/~mehra/20_an%20application%20of%20experiment%20design%20to%20compiler%20testing.pdf">this paper</a> by Robert Mandl on techniques that can be applied to reduce the burden of exhaustive testing to compilers. Preferring &ldquo;surely all relevant distinct combinations&rdquo; we can reduce the amount of testing. This paper tries to formalize the concept of &ldquo;near-exhaustive testing&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: latin-square, robert-mandl, compiler, testing, near-exhaustive-testing, optimization, exhaustive-testing</p>

<h2>  Practical Type System Benefits</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://themonadreader.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/nccb.pdf">this article</a> by Neil Brown on benefits of the type system, with examples in haskell. He goes on to explore the benefits of involving the type-checker at compile time to remove type errors and ease the programming effort:</p>

<blockquote><p>I find that several problems in Haskell can be solved by involving the type system
further: The trick is to involve the type system in ways that provide a big benefit
for the cost, but not going so far that the type system gets in the way of code
that you know &ndash;but can’t easily prove to the compiler&ndash; is safe</p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also learned the concept of the quasi-quoter: similar to a preprocessor, executed at compile time and type-checked</p>

<p>Tags: neil-brown, quote, quasi-quoter, preprocessor, haskell, monad-reader</p>

<h2>ClojureScript and the Blub Paradox</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article comparing javascript and clojurescript using the fizzbuzz kata. There is a nice example of the pattern matching for the cases (i.e. &ldquo;switch&rdquo;) of the fizz, buzz. Written by Nate Wildermuth</p>

<p>Tags: clojurescript, javascript, fizzbuzz, kata, nate-wildermuth</p>

<h2>No malinterpretes tu carrera</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2011/02/no-malinterpretes-tu-carrera/">this article</a> on (not) changing careers from programmer to designer, analyst, team manager. About the programmer&rsquo;s passion and why not to misinterpret your career. Written by Carlos Blé. In Spanish.</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, career, programming, management, career-change</p>

<h2>Just Haskell or Nothing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://cheecheeo.github.io/just_haskell_or_nothing.html">these slides</a> on packaging values in (Just a) or Nothing for possibly failed computations in haskell. Written by John Chee</p>

<p>Tags: john-chee, haskell, just, nothing, maybe, functor</p>

<h2>Tracking Joy at Work</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://begriffs.com/posts/2015-03-15-tracking-joy-at-work.html">this article</a> about quantifying happiness at the office (or at work). Joe Nelson, the author of the article, uses the quantifying method described int the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Experience-Sampling-Method-Measuring-Everyday/dp/1412925576/">Experience Sampling Method</a> (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experience_sampling_method">wikipedia page</a>) by Hektner, Schmidt, Csikszentmihalyi.</p>

<p>The last one, not coincidentally is the author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Flow-The-Psychology-Optimal-Experience/dp/0061339202">Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience</a>.</p>

<p>Tags: mihaly-csikszentmihalyi, flow, quantification, data, experience-sampling, article, joe-nelson</p>

<h2>Going &ldquo;Write-Only&rdquo;</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://begriffs.com/posts/2015-04-20-going-write-only.html">this article</a> by Joe Nelson on going &ldquo;write-only&rdquo; on social media, blogs, news, etc, as opposed to read-only (only consuming media) or read-write (consuming and producing). He cites another programmer, <a href="http://joey.hess.usesthis.com/">Joey Hess</a> and about the quality and durability of your work.</p>

<p>Tags: article, joe-nelson, write-only, social-media, reading, philosophy, thoreau, nietzsche, joey-hess</p>

<h2>Create a static site with Hakyll, Github and Travis CI</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://begriffs.com/posts/2014-08-12-create-static-site-with-hakyll-github.html">this article</a> on how to create your blog with hakyll and travis ci. Written by Joe Nelson</p>

<p>Travis ci is used to do continuous integration and automatically deploy each commit to production (github pages).</p>

<p>Tags: hakyll, haskell, joe-nelson, meta, blog, continuous-deployment, github, github-pages, travis-ci</p>

<h2>Falling in Love with Computer Science</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=haxusGuUyt4">this video</a> by Kathy Pham, an American that discovered her passion, her love to computer science a few years ago. She tells the events around computer science from the beginning of college to the current moment.</p>

<p>Tags: kathy-pham, passion, love, computer-science, autobiography, time-lapse, google-developers</p>

<h2>Duck Typing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h0rTF__RNo4">this video</a> by Dan Grossman, part of the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/proglang">&ldquo;Programming Languages&rdquo; MOOC</a>, in which he explains what is a Duck Type and how to use (and abuse) them in ruby.</p>

<p>Tags: ruby, dan-grossman, mooc, mooc-programming-languages</p>

<h2>Not-So-Private Clojure Functions</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://christophermaier.name/blog/2011/04/30/not-so-private-clojure-functions">this article</a> explaining how to bypass private functions in clojure: either create a lambda or create a different namespace. Written by Christopher Maier</p>

<p>Tags: private-variable, clojure, testing, joy-of-clojure, christopher-maier, private-function, namespace</p>

<h2>Frege (and Clojure)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://seancorfield.github.io/blog/2015/02/13/frege-and-clojure/">this article</a> that tells the Pragmatic Programmer&rsquo;s advice to learn a new language every year and the author (Sean Corfield) explains his trajectory learning them. He also cites the Lein plugin he&rsquo;s built: <code>lein-fregec</code> and how to connect clojure and frege (a.k.a JVM&rsquo;s haskell).</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, frege, jvm, clojure, ffi, pragmatic-programmer, advice, lein-fregec,  sean-corfield, comparison</p>

<h2>Two months early. 300k under budget</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://thoughtworks.github.io/p2/issue09/two-months-early/">the tale</a> of a Thoughtworks Project Manager who convinced his client to start using clojure to deliver a custom-made CMS. Written by Dave Elliman.</p>

<p>Tags: dave-elliman, thoughtworks, project-manager, clojure, cms, microservice</p>

<h2>Convince your boss to use Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/convince-your-boss-to-use-clojure">this guide</a> by Eric Normand on how to convince your boss or your company to start using clojure.</p>

<p>Tags: company, clojure, eric-normand, how-to, guide</p>

<h2>A brief introduction to Prolog</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1NAUo8nWLfNvvW3Wb7HJMunljjDJbzu7mo-5twKeGDvc/edit#slide=id.g63daf4745_0_56">these slides</a> about a brief introduction to prolog and how to do web development in it. By Jaelle Scheuerman</p>

<p>Tags: jaelle-scheuerman, prolog, web-development, rest, slide</p>

<h2>Arrayzing - The JavaScript array cheatsheet</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://gist.github.com/ourmaninamsterdam/1be9a5590c9cf4a0ab42">this cheatsheet</a> for javascript arrays. Written by Justin Perry</p>

<p>Tags: cheatsheet, array, javascript, gist, justin-perry</p>

<h2>Some words on lazy evaluation and sharing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://pseudo.fixme.fi/~opqdonut/blog/Some_words_on_lazy_evaluation_and_sharing.html">this article</a> comparing the <code>fix</code> definition with a hand-made one and its &ldquo;sharing&rdquo; problems. Written by Joel E. Kaasinen</p>

<p>Tags: joel-kaasinen, haskell, fix, sharing, non-strictness, lazy-evaluation</p>

<h2>Hammock Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f84n5oFoZBc">this video</a> by Rich Hickey. A few notes:</p>

<p>A: identifying a problem that we&rsquo;re trying to solve</p>

<p>D: assessing if the proposed solution solves the problem</p>

<p>the union of the features is not the purpose of the product / is not the product</p>

<p>proramming is not completing features</p>

<p>avoiding problems /= solving problems</p>

<p>book: how to solve it - G. Polya. Practices &amp; techniques for solving mathematic problems</p>

<p>How to solve the problem</p>

<ul>
<li>state the problem</li>
<li>understand the problem:

<ul>
<li>what do you know: facts, context, constraints.</li>
<li>what do you don&rsquo;t know</li>
<li>are there related problems? solutions to related problems. find an analogy: starting from scratch vs incremental step</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>be discerning</li>
<li>more input, better output:

<ul>
<li>read about your domain problem, research papers (maybe ACM)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>tradeoffs:

<ul>
<li>find at least two options (ups and downs) to compare before taking a decision</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Focus time for programmers like alone time for kids. Hammock time is important mind&rsquo;s eye time</p>

<p>Waking mind:</p>

<ul>
<li>critical thinking</li>
<li>analysis</li>
<li>tactics</li>
<li>prone to local maxima</li>
<li>feed work to background mind</li>
<li>analyze its products</li>
</ul>


<p>Background mind:</p>

<ul>
<li>making connections</li>
<li>synthesis</li>
<li>strategy</li>
<li>abstracts, analogies</li>
<li>solves most non-trivial problems</li>
</ul>


<p>loading it: work it hard in the waking mind to be included in the background mind</p>

<p>abstraction = software strategy</p>

<p>tip: small answer is better than big answer (occam&rsquo;s razor?)​</p>

<p>Tags: rich-hickey, hammock-driven-development, background-mind, waking-mind, solve-problem, george-polya, book, analysis, design, talk</p>

<h2>Parallelism /= Concurrency</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://ghcmutterings.wordpress.com/2009/10/06/parallelism-concurrency/">this article</a> on the differences between parallelism and concurrency, with examples in the haskell compiler GHC. Written by <a href="https://ghcmutterings.wordpress.com/author/simonmar/">simonmar</a></p>

<p>Tags: haskell, concurrency, parallelism, ghc, simonmar, comparison</p>

<h2>Parallelism vs. Concurrency</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://wiki.haskell.org/Parallelism_vs._Concurrency">this page</a> from the haskell wiki.</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, concurrency, parallelism, ghc, comparison</p>

<h2>Writing code that writes code — with Hack Codegen</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://code.facebook.com/posts/1624644147776541/writing-code-that-writes-code-with-hack-codegen/">this article</a> about metaprogramming (code that generates code) in PHP. Written by Alejandro Marcu.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve arrived to this from this tweet:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-cards="hidden" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is what happens when your programming language doesn&#39;t have macros <a href="https://t.co/ZfsEe2EJIj">https://t.co/ZfsEe2EJIj</a>. Yuck.</p>&mdash; David Nolen (@swannodette) <a href="https://twitter.com/swannodette/status/634495099607613440">August 20, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Tags: alejandro-marcu, metaprogramming, php, macro, lisp, clojure</p>

<h2>How katas can help you learn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://codurance.com/2015/08/18/How-katas-can-help-you-learn/">this article</a> on learning from katas, with the example of the Roman Numerals kata in Objective-C. Written by Sandro Mancuso.</p>

<p>Tags: sandro-mancuso, kata, learning, roman-numeral, objective-c</p>

<h2>Java 8: Definitive guide to CompletableFuture</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.nurkiewicz.com/2013/05/java-8-definitive-guide-to.html">this article</a> about Java 8&rsquo;s feature, the <code>CompletableFeature</code>. Written by Tomasz Nurkiewicz</p>

<p>Tags: tomasz-nurkiewicz, java-8, completable-future, future, non-blocking, reactive-programming</p>

<h2>Are You Making These 10 DDD Mistakes?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://danielwhittaker.me/2015/07/05/are-you-making-these-10-ddd-mistakes/#">this infographic</a> on 10 DDD common mistakes, by Daniel Whittaker.</p>

<p>Tags: ddd, daniel-whittaker, bounded-context, ubiquitous-language, infographic</p>

<h2>Haste: Full-Stack Haskell for Non-PhD Candidates</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3v03NFcyvzc">this talk</a> at the Strange Loop Conference 2014 about Haste language, a haskell version that compiles to javascript, therefore letting you write haskell in the browser. By Erin Swenson-Healey and James Cooper</p>

<p>In this talk they recommend the <a href="http://www.seas.upenn.edu/~cis194/lectures.html">CIS194 course</a></p>

<p>Tags: haste, haskell, james-cooper, erin-swenson-healey, strange-loop, 2014, talk</p>

<h2>A Year of Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wZ0RQG3mFPw">this talk</a> about experiences using haskell professionally, by the American Justin Leitgeb in a Equatorian company in Quito, Stack Builders. He goes on to explain the haskell language in comparison to ruby on rails, what he mostly used with his clients.</p>

<p>Also explains what sells and doesn&rsquo;t (mostly productivity, not security) and gives pointer for applying it to a company</p>

<p>Tags: justin-leitgeb, ecuador, haskell, stack-builders, lambda-days, 2015, client, professional, consulting, consultancy</p>

<h2>A Taste of Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched a lesson by Simon Peyton-Jones, that introduces haskell to experienced programmers, not in the language but in programming in general. At the conference OSCON 2007</p>

<p>Links: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jLj1QV11o9g">part 1</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IqXTUbdLig0">part 2</a>, <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/oscon2007/os-peytonjones">slides</a></p>

<p>Tags: oscon, 2007, haskell, introduction, lesson, simon-peyton-jones</p>

<h2>Programming - Why Haskell is Great</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RqvCNb7fKsg">this video</a> introducing some features of haskell. The most basic features, the REPL,  function composition. By FrungyKing</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, introduction, video, screencast, repl, frungyking</p>

<h2>History of Haskell: being lazy with class</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3bjXGrycMhQ">this video</a> by Simon Peyton-Jones at the &ldquo;History of Programming Languages Conference III&rdquo; which explains how the language was designed and written, a language timeline, what options they took, how they decided about monadic IO, etc.</p>

<p>Tags: simon-peyton-jones, 2007, history-of-programming-languages-conference, haskell, talk</p>

<h2>The Humble Programmer</h2>

<p>​I&rsquo;ve read [this EWD][ewd-340]​ about the necessary humbleness for being a programmer and the slow expansion of the trade, as compared to hardware engineers.</p>

<p>He cites six reasons for preferring to be a humble programmer:</p>

<ul>
<li>the programmer only needs to manage simple programs</li>
<li>simple programs imply reducing the search space</li>
<li>construct a program from a mathematical proof instead of test its properties after building the software. see quote below</li>
<li>a good abstraction can hide much complexity and difficulty</li>
<li>the importance of the used tool in the final product</li>
<li>&ldquo;the only problems we can satisfactory solve are the ones that admit a factored solution&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>In this essay I&rsquo;ve found the idea of</p>

<blockquote><p>Testing shows the presence, not the absence of bugs</p></blockquote>

<p>That <a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Edsger_W._Dijkstra">Wikiquote</a> attributes to an earlier paper (in 1969). In this paper, the verbatim quote is:</p>

<blockquote><p>program testing can be a very effective way to show the presence of bugs, but is hopelessly inadequate for showing their absence.</p></blockquote>

<p>This idea also connects to the &ldquo;lower bounds&rdquo; and &ldquo;upper bounds&rdquo; of program correctness expressed in the article <a href="https://cdsmith.wordpress.com/2011/01/09/an-old-article-i-wrote/">An Old Article I Wrote</a> which is about static types, by Cdsmith. Admittedly, much later, in 2008, so this idea could be inspired by the Dijkstra&rsquo;s article.</p>

<p>Tags: edsger-dijkstra, ewd, dijkstra, humble-programmer, essay, comparison, absence-of-bugs, quote</p>

<h2>Building a Link Shortener with Snaplets</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://vimeo.com/59109358">this video</a> of how to build a link shortener webapp in haskell with the framework snap. By Ryan Trinkle. Found it in the <a href="http://snapframework.com/docs">snap docs</a> page.</p>

<p>Tags: snap, haskell, link-shortener, talk, webapp, framework, ryan-trinkle</p>

<h2>Comparing Haskell Web Frameworks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.edofic.com/posts/2014-02-23-haskell-web.html">this comparison</a> of haskell web frameworks, by Andraz Bajt (a.k.a, edofic)</p>

<p>Tags: andraz-bajt, edofic, haskell, web-framework, framework, comparison</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in July 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/self-study-in-july-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-30T23:08:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/self-study-in-july-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post</p>

<h2>Clojure made simple</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VSdnJDO-xdg">this talk</a> by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy">Easy made simple</a></p>

<ul>
<li>polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter</li>
</ul>


<h2>Productive pair programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/07/productive-pair-programming/">this article</a> about pair programming, using the driver &amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Building Automated REST APIs with Python</h2>

<p>Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jeffknupp/building-automated-rest-apis-with-python">these slides</a> about it</p>

<h2>Backwards Compatibility Testing For Your Clojure Project</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jenkster.com/2014/02/backwards-compatibility-testing-your-clojure-project.html">this article</a> on making leiningen test the application on several clojure versions. Written by Kris Jenkins.</p>

<h2>Succeeding with Automated Integration Tests</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://jeremydmiller.com/2015/06/25/succeeding_with_integration_testing/">this article</a> by Jeremy Miller on integration testing and how to succeed with it. Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Choose the Quickest, Useful Feedback Mechanism, even if that means testing the backend and frontend separately</li>
<li>Prefer white-box than black-box testing</li>
<li>Use quick tests, that can be run locally in an easy fashion</li>
<li>Do not share databases, as they introduce risks of flaky tests</li>
</ul>


<h2>Applied DDD in a Java EE 7 and Open Source World</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9D_-7E7Mrzw">this video</a> by Edson Yanaga in the Java One, about DDD using Java EE 7, JSFs and lambdas on top of glassfish</p>

<h2>Integrated tests are a scam</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read, again, <a href="http://blog.thecodewhisperer.com/2010/10/16/integrated-tests-are-a-scam/">this article</a> by J. B. Rainsberger on integrated tests and why not to use them. From a numerical / combinatorics point of view.</p>

<h2>Functional Programming should be your #1 priority for 2015</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@jugoncalves/functional-programming-should-be-your-1-priority-for-2015-47dd4641d6b9">this introduction</a> to functional programming by Ju Gonçalves. Explains some functional concepts, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>First-Class Functions</li>
<li>High-Order Functions</li>
<li>Pure Functions</li>
<li>Closures</li>
<li>Immutable State</li>
</ul>


<p>Also recommends a few books on the subject (e.g., SICP, HTDP).</p>

<h2>A Tutorial Introduction to the Lambda Calculus</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.inf.fu-berlin.de/lehre/WS03/alpi/lambda.pdf">this paper</a>, an introduction to the lambda calculus. Haven&rsquo;t done the exercises. Written by Raúl Rojas</p>

<h2>20 common mistakes when doing Test-Driven Development</h2>

<p>I had thought of converting all of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=svpino%20%23tdd%20mistake&amp;src=typd">his tweets</a> into a blog post, but he has already done this for us: I&rsquo;ve read a <a href="https://blog.svpino.com/2015/05/29/20-common-mistakes-when-doing-test-driven-development">list of common mistakes</a> when doing TDD by <a href="https://twitter.com/svpino">Santiago Pino</a></p>

<h2>Reducing coupling</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the article by Martin Fowler <a href="http://martinfowler.com/ieeeSoftware/coupling.pdf">Reducing Coupling</a> in the IEEE SOFTWARE July/August 2001</p>

<h2>Comparing Java Mock Frameworks – Part 2: Creating Mock Objects</h2>

<p><a href="https://softwareinabottle.wordpress.com/2010/10/06/comparing-java-mock-frameworks-part-2-creating-mock-objects/">List of mock frameworks for java</a>. Have only read the jMock, mockito and jMockit part.</p>

<h2> Software Craftsmanship book review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://meaganwaller.com/software-craftsmanship-book-review/">this review</a> for a book that is already pending in my book list: Software Craftsmanship by Pete McBreen.</p>

<p>The review has been written by Megan Waller, an (ex-)apprentice at 8th Light.</p>

<h2>Fundamental concepts in programming languages</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~crary/819-f09/Strachey67.pdf">this paper</a> containing the contents for lectures in Computer Programming in the year 1967. Written by Christopher Strachey.</p>

<p>Note: I&rsquo;ve also seen this paper recommended in the repo <a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love/tree/master/plt">Papers We Love > plt</a> (Programming Language Theory)</p>

<h2>What is reification?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.angelikalanger.com/GenericsFAQ/FAQSections/TechnicalDetails.html#FAQ101A">this FAQ</a> on reification by Angelika Langer</p>

<h2>Type erasure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wikipedia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_erasure">page on type erasure</a></p>

<h2>How to make an IntelliJ IDEA plugin in less than 30 minutes</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://bjorn.tipling.com/how-to-make-an-intellij-idea-plugin-in-30-minutes">this article</a> on creating new IntelliJ IDEA plugin, by Bjorn Tipling</p>

<h2>How to Write Clean, Testable Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched, again, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XcT4yYu_TTs">this video</a> by Miško Hevery. Discusses what are the characteristics of tested and untested code, how to get from one to the other. Discusses techniques for testing code. At the end, there are questions but they cannot be heard (lack of microphone), so it is harder to follow.</p>

<h2>How to Find a Mentor</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/letters-to-my-mother/how-to-find-a-mentor-27fb978a8f1">this opinion</a> on the importance of role models and mentors. The difference between them and a personal experience. Written by Joanne Wilson</p>

<h2>Type theory</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wiki page on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_theory">type theory</a></p>

<p>Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;type systems [&hellip;] language feature used to reduce bugs&rdquo;</li>
<li>two types: Church&rsquo;s typed λ-calculi and Martin-Löf&rsquo;s intuitionistic type theory.</li>
<li>notation:

<ul>
<li>typing judgement: <code>M : A</code>. Term <code>M</code> has type <code>A</code></li>
<li>example: <code>nat</code> may be a type</li>
<li><code>2 : nat</code>, like in Scala</li>
<li>function: &ldquo;arrow&rdquo;</li>
<li>apply function to argument: no parenthesis</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>conversion rule: rule for rewriting terms

<ul>
<li>reduction rule: conversion rule that only works in one direction</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>normal form: a form that cannot be further reduced</li>
<li>element: all closed elements that can be reduced to the same normal form</li>
<li>closed term: a term without parameters. Opposite is an open term</li>
<li>convertibility: property of terms, both open and closed. Said to be convertible if two terms can be reduced to the same term

<ul>
<li>warning: x + 1 and 1 + x are not convertible because they are in normal form and not the same</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Type system</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wiki page on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_system">type system</a></p>

<p>Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;The depth of type constraints and the manner of their evaluation affect the typing of the language&rdquo;</li>
<li>Type polymorphism</li>
<li>{compile time, runtime} x {manually annotated, inferred}</li>
<li>&ldquo;A program associates each value with at least one particular type, but it also can occur that one value is associated with many subtypes.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Classification of types:

<ul>
<li>data type – a type of a value</li>
<li>class – a type of an object</li>
<li>kind – a type of a type, or metatype</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>the type inference might be undecidable (for more complex type inference)</li>
<li>&ldquo;Strong typing offers more safety, but cannot guarantee complete type safety.&rdquo; An example is the division by zero, altough some languages may declare a dependent type &ldquo;non-zero numbers&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h2>The 3 things you should know about hashCode()</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://eclipsesource.com/blogs/2012/09/04/the-3-things-you-should-know-about-hashcode/">this article</a> on the hashCode() method in java, written by Ralf Sternberg.</p>

<h2>Reduce Complexity with Variants</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/reduce-complexity-with-variants">this article</a> on variants in clojure by Eric Normand</p>

<h2>What is new in SQL:2011</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.sigmod.org/publications/sigmod-record/1203/pdfs/10.industry.zemke.pdf">this white paper</a> on the new features in SQL 2011. Written by Fred Zemke</p>

<h2>5 Error Tracking Tools Java Developers Should Know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javacodegeeks.com/2014/09/5-error-tracking-tools-java-developers-should-know.html">this article</a> about tracking tools for java written by Alex Zhitnitsky, featuring:</p>

<ul>
<li>Raygun</li>
<li>Sentry</li>
<li>Takipi</li>
<li>Airbrake</li>
<li>StackHunter</li>
<li>[Bonus] ABRT</li>
<li>Comments cite <a href="http://squash.io">Squash</a> (server written in ruby, java client available) and <a href="http://rollbar.com">Rollbar</a> (home says supports android but not says anything about java)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Data clump</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DataClump.html">this article</a> on the bliki, by Martin Fowler</p>

<h2>NP-Complete problems</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://webdiis.unizar.es/asignaturas/TC/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/L15_NPcompletos.pdf">these slides</a> by Prof. Elvira Mayordomo about NP-Complete problems, how to reduce them to other problems and practical applications. (In Spanish)</p>

<h2>Removal of sun.misc.Unsafe in Java 9 - A disaster in the making</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.dripstat.com/removal-of-sun-misc-unsafe-a-disaster-in-the-making/">this article</a> about the removal of this Unsafe class in Java 9, by the DripStat team</p>

<h2>How To Write Directly to a Memory Locations In Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://robaustin.wikidot.com/how-to-write-to-direct-memory-locations-in-java">this guide</a> on how to write directly to a memory position in java, by Rob Austin</p>

<h2>Interesting uses of sun.misc.Unsafe</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://bytescrolls.blogspot.com.es/2011/04/interesting-uses-of-sunmiscunsafe.html">this article</a> by Haris A.L.</p>

<h2>Introduction to the theory of np-completeness</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.site.uottawa.ca/~lucia/courses/4105-02/np.pdf">these notes / slides</a> to the introductory course of NP-completeness, by Prof Lucia Moura</p>

<h2>JS Code Kata: Linked List</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/yitznewton/js-code-kata-linked-list">these slides</a> on the kata linked list, by Yitz Schaffer. The slide #13 talks about the transformations:</p>

<ul>
<li>refactor: change form without changing behavior</li>
<li>transform: change behavior while changing form as little as possible</li>
</ul>


<p>Also about the Transformation Priority Premise (TPP) (also in this month)</p>

<h2>The Transformation Priority Premise</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read, again, <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2013/05/27/TheTransformationPriorityPremise.html">this article</a> by Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)</p>

<h2>Data structures</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the wiki page for</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SPQR_tree">SPQR tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_search_tree">BSR tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red%E2%80%93black_tree">Red black tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judy_array">Judy array</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Also, The <a href="http://bigocheatsheet.com/">Big-O notation complexity cheatsheet</a></p>

<h2>On benchmarks: Numbers every programmer should know and their impact on benchmarks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hype-free.blogspot.com/2014/03/on-benchmarks.html">this post</a> on doing back-of-the-envelope calculations on publicly available benchmarks, written by Attila-Mihaly Balazs</p>

<h2>Top Java IDE Keyboard Shortcuts for Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA &amp; NetBeans</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/top-java-ide-keyboard-shortcuts-for-eclipse-intellij-idea-netbeans/">these slides</a> on the topic of keyboard shortcuts for java IDEs, written by Oleg Šelajev</p>

<h2>The hacker’s summer training guide – part 1</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.paymill.com/hackers-training-guide-1">this post</a> by Paymill, that suggests which new languages to learn this summer: rust, go, elixir, ocaml, scala, livescript.</p>

<h2>Applications built extremely right</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://apiumtech.com/blog/applications-build-with-outsourcing/">this post</a> with a list of candidates for building nice products, written by Xavi Hidalgo.</p>

<h2>Agile project seed. Infrastructure by default.</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://apiumtech.com/blog/seed-de-proyecto-agile-infraestructura-por-defecto/">this post</a> on an agile seed project. Reminded me of the 12-factor app</p>

<h2>What an agile developer should know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.apiumtech.com/blog/lo-que-un-desarrollador-agile-deberia-saber/">this post</a> by Xavi Hidalgo</p>

<h2>Bad Apples that can destroy a team</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve listened to <a href="http://www.scrum-master-toolbox.com/2015/03/podcast/dominic-krimmer-describes-the-types-of-bad-apples-that-can-destroy-a-team/">this podcast</a> about the bad apples in a team. Presented by Vasco Duarte and Dominic Krimmer as the main speaker</p>

<h2>How Scala compares with 20 other programming languages according to Reddit analysis</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.typesafe.com/blog/how-scala-compares-20-programming-languages-reddit-analysis">this analysis</a> of the language comparison, written by Oliver White</p>

<h2>Javascript patterns book review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2047-javascript-patterns-by-stoyan-stefanov.htm">this review</a> by Ben Nadel on the book Javascript Patterns, by Stoyan Stefanov</p>

<h2>Monogamous TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/04/25/MonogamousTDD.html">this article</a> on the fundamentalism of TDD, written by Robert C Martin</p>

<h2>Encapsulating LocalStorage Access In AngularJS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2861-encapsulating-localstorage-access-in-angularjs.htm">this article</a> on why encapsulate the access to the localStorage, written by Ben Nadel</p>

<h2>Anatomy of a zero-knowledge web application</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://clipperz.is/blog/2007/08/24/anatomy_zero_knowledge_web_application/">this article</a> on a zero-knowledge web application, by the clipperz team</p>

<h2>Refactorización de Código Legado Clase Maestra</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VBgCKKevhyI">this video</a> about refactoring a legacy code in C#, by Danijel Arsenovski</p>

<h2>Taming Javaagents</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/shelajev/taming-javaagents-bcn-jug-2015">these slides</a>, again, from a conference I went to a few months ago about java agents. Written by Oleg Šelajev.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/shelajev/ResourceLeakAgent">This</a> is the repository containing the memory leak agent he talks about</p>

<h2>Mathematics for Computer Science, Lecture 1</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched by <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/math_for_comp_science_mit/lessons/Lecture1/">the first recitation</a> in <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/math_for_comp_science_mit/index.php">this course</a>, offered by MIT Open Course Ware (OCW). Recited by Tom Leighton</p>

<h2>Programming Abstractions: Lecture 7</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/programming_abstractions_stanford/lessons/Lecture7/">this lecture</a> by Julie Zelensky about the comparison operator, recursion and a live coding session calculating the most ocurring anagram word in a file.</p>

<p>She uses small outputs to check the correctness of her programs to get short feedback cycles, even if they are manual.</p>

<h2>5 Ways To Launch a JMeter Test without Using the JMeter GUI</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blazemeter.com/blog/5-ways-launch-jmeter-test-without-using-jmeter-gui">this guide</a> on using jmeter without a GUI, by Dmitri Tikhanski</p>

<h2>Clojure unraveled, chapter 5</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the <a href="http://funcool.github.io/clojurescript-unraveled/#language-advanced-topics">fifth chapter</a>, on the topics of Transducers, Transients, Metadata, Macros, Core protocols. Written by Andrey Antukh and Alejandro Gómez</p>

<h2>A guide to the Basics of Data Structures</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/data-structures-basics/">this guide</a> to data structures, covering the stack, the queue, the heap, the tree and the hashmap. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>Government Abandonware</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://techblog.bozho.net/government-abandonware/">this post</a> on abandoned, public software that is not opensource. Dubbed by the author as &ldquo;Government Abandonware&rdquo;. Written by Bozhidar Bozhanov</p>

<h2>The Art of Incremental Stream Processing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mth.io/talks/streams/">these slides</a> on incremental stream processing. The examples are in haskell and scala. Written by Mark Hibberd</p>

<h2>Reader as Link Author</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hapgood.us/2015/07/22/follow-up-reader-as-link-author/">this insight</a> into federated wikis by Mike Caulfield</p>

<h2>Kafkapocalypse: a postmortem on our service outage</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.parsely.com/post/1738/kafkapocalypse/">this post-mortem analysis</a> of the service outage at parse.ly, by Andrew Montalenti</p>

<h2>Loving a Log-Oriented Architecture</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.parsely.com/post/1550/kreps-logs/">this post</a> on experiences using the log-based architecture, by Andrew Montalenti. Cites the books <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Logs-Stream-Processing-Integration/dp/1491909382">I Heart Logs</a>,  and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290343">Big Data: Principles and best practices of scalable realtime data systems</a> the essay <a href="http://engineering.linkedin.com/distributed-systems/log-what-every-software-engineer-should-know-about-real-time-datas-unifying">The Log</a></p>

<h2>A guide to Algorithmic Complexity</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/algorithmic-complexity">this guide</a> to algorithmic complexity, explaining Big-Oh notation (Big-Oh, Big-Theta, Big-Omega), with examples. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>A guide to Recursion</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/recursion">this guide</a> to recursion explaining the gist of it. Examples include the Fibonacci sequence and the Hanoi Towers problem. Later, an introduction to the chaos theory and fractals. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>Bootstrapped ClojureScript FAQ</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/clojure/clojurescript/wiki/Bootstrapped-ClojureScript-FAQ">this FAQ</a> related to bootstrapping clojurescript</p>

<h2>Applying property-based testing on my binary search tree implementation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://garajeando.blogspot.com/2015/07/applying-property-based-testing-on-my.html">this article</a>, written by Manuel Rivero, on applying test-check (a property-based testing framework, similar to quickcheck) to a Binary Search Tree (BST) he did.</p>

<h2>Do Extraterrestrials Use Functional Programming?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://yowconference.com.au/slides/yowlambdajam2013/Chakravarty-Extraterrestrials-Keynote.pdf">these slides</a>, an introduction to lambda calculus, the Turing machine and the Halting Problem. Later, continues to describe ways of solving problems in a functional way. Also performance and optimizations; monads as well. Written by Manuel M T Chakravarty</p>

<h2>WIP Limits</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://theagileist.wordpress.com/2015/06/15/wip-limits/">this post</a> by Tomas Rybing</p>

<h2>Applied capacity planning</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://theagileist.wordpress.com/2015/07/27/applied-capacity-planning/">this post</a> by Tomas Rybing.</p>

<h2>Don’t Get Attached to Programming Languages</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mikecavaliere.com/dont-get-attached-programming-languages">this post</a> by Mike Cavaliere</p>

<h2>The Top 5 Skills of Rock Star Software Engineers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://softwareplusplus.com/2015/06/24/the-top-5-skills-of-rock-star-software-engineers/">this post</a> by Cory Berg</p>

<h2>5 Reasons to Use Protocol Buffers Instead of JSON For Your Next Service</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codeclimate.com/blog/2014/06/05/choose-protocol-buffers/">this article</a> on Protocol Buffers, written by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Data Serialization Formats</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://gist.github.com/joshsz/11299196">this comparison</a> between MsgPack, JSON, Protocol Buffers, by Josh Szmajda.</p>

<h2>Protocol Buffer Basics: Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/javatutorial">this introduction</a> to Protocol Buffers in Java, by Google</p>

<h2>RESTful Considered Harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/restful-considered-harmful?oid=top_title">this article</a>, commenting downsides to using JSON / RESTful APIs, written by Tomasz Nurkiewicz</p>

<h2>“Considered Harmful” Essays Considered Harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://meyerweb.com/eric/comment/chech.html">this post</a>, by Eric Meyer, on why &ldquo;Considered Harmful&rdquo; are harmful as well.</p>

<h2>Keep Lambdas Cohesive</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.agiledeveloper.com/2015/07/keep-lambdas-cohesive.html">this post</a> with recommendations on keeping the java lambdas cohesive. Written by Venkat Subramaniam</p>

<h2>The Joy of Flying Robots with Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty9QDqV-_Ak">this video</a> by Carin Meier at the OSCON 2013 about communicating with robots in Clojure</p>

<h2>How to Learn TDD Without Getting Overwhelmed</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.justinweiss.com/blog/2014/06/02/how-to-learn-tdd-without-getting-overwhelmed/">this article</a> on learning TDD, by Justin Weiss</p>

<h2>Kata - the Only Way to Learn TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.peterprovost.org/blog/2012/05/02/kata-the-only-way-to-learn-tdd/">this article</a> on learning TDD, by Peter Provost</p>

<h2>Koan: Past Perfect</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thecodelesscode.com/case/180">this koan</a>, past perfect, reflecting on the people who prefer the past over the present. Who think that the past was simpler than currently is.</p>

<h2>Koan: Future Imperfect</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thecodelesscode.com/case/181">this koan</a>, continuation from past perfect.</p>

<h2>Why “Agile” and especially Scrum are terrible</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://michaelochurch.wordpress.com/2015/06/06/why-agile-and-especially-scrum-are-terrible/">this article</a> on downsides of Agile and Scrum, written by Michael Church.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in June 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-03T11:13:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update: I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015
into a single post</p>

<h2>Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.octo.com/le-monitoring-de-flux-par-lexemple/">this article</a> about monitoring, in the way of &ldquo;by example&rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)</p>

<h2>The First Micro-service Architecture</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2015/05/28/TheFirstMicroserviceArchitecture.html">this article</a> about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin</p>

<h2>How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://open.bufferapp.com/remote-work/?utm_content=bufferaa5a2&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">this article</a> about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</p>

<h2>Demystified CQRS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.codecentric.de/en/2015/05/demystified-cqrs/?utm_content=buffer35b18&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">this article</a> about CQRS by Nino Martincevic</p>

<h2>The perils of programmer education in the bazaar</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.practicingruby.com/2015/06/04/the-perils-of-programmer-education-in-the-bazaar/">this article</a> by Gregory Brown</p>

<h2>6 useful and lesser-known git commands</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.joncairns.com/2015/05/6-useful-and-lesser-known-git-commands/">this article</a> about git commands (log, checkout, stash, cherry-pick, annotate) by Jon Cairns</p>

<h2>Is Your Scrum Standup Slowing You Down?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.sitepoint.com/scrum-standup-slowing-down/">this article</a> by M. David Green</p>

<h2>Me duele Indra</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;id=67ce79e01b">this Bonilista</a> (Spanish) by David Bonilla</p>

<h2>TDD, BDD, [add every other method that promises software quality here] and the tea tasting lady</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blinkingcaret.wordpress.com/2012/10/02/tdd-bdd-add-every-other-method-that-promises-software-quality-here-and-the-tea-tasting-lady/">this article</a> by Rui Figueiredo about the scientific method, TDD / BDD and how to scientifically detect if the &lsquo;how&rsquo; affects the result. In this case, exemplified by how to prepare your tea</p>

<h2>The Art of Metaprogramming in Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/PolymathicCoder/the-art-of-metaprogramming-in-java">these slides</a> by Abdelmonaim Remani</p>

<h2>When TDD does not work</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/04/30/When-tdd-does-not-work.html">this article</a> by Uncle Bob on situations where TDD might not be appropiate, especially around the borders</p>

<h2>Mi primera semana como aprendiz</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ronnyancorini.es/blog/index.php/2015/06/08/mi-primera-semana-como-aprendiz/">Ronny Ancorini&rsquo;s experiences</a> in his first week as apprentince with Carlos Blé &amp; Associates (Spanish)</p>

<h2>Refactoring without good tests</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codeclimate.com/blog/2013/12/05/refactoring-without-good-tests/">this article</a> by Peter Bell on how to deal with a legacy codebase, what are the effects of not having tests and how to deal with. How to add tests to a codebase that is not ready for it.</p>

<h2>Big Ball of Mud</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.laputan.org/mud/">this paper</a>, containing a collection of patterns and antipatterns (disguised as notes) by Brian Foote and Joseph Yoder</p>

<h2>Comparision of different concurrency models: Actors, CSP, Disruptor and Threads [sic]</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://java-is-the-new-c.blogspot.com.es/2014/01/comparision-of-different-concurrency.html">this comparison of concurrency models</a> by Rüdiger Möller</p>

<h2>5 Whys</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys">this wikipedia</a> article on the technique called &ldquo;5 Whys&rdquo;</p>

<h2>Expectations, Outcomes, and Challenges of Modern Code Review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/apps/pubs/default.aspx?id=180283">this paper</a>, <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/pubs/180283/ICSE%202013-codereview.pdf">direct link</a>, by Alberto Bacchelli and Christian Bird on code review at Microsoft.</p>

<p>They explain how they do it, the exact methodology they are using and why they do it.</p>

<p>The main reasons to code review are:</p>

<ul>
<li>finding defects</li>
<li>code improvement</li>
<li>alternative solutions</li>
<li>knowledge transfer</li>
<li>team awareness and transparency</li>
<li>also:

<ul>
<li>improve development process</li>
<li>avoid build breaks</li>
<li>share code ownership</li>
<li>track rationale</li>
<li>team assessment</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>The quality wheel</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jessitron.com/2015/04/the-quality-wheel.html">this article</a> by Jessica Kerr about the qualities of beautiful code</p>

<h2>5 Minute Physics</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n6FKT-KafRk">this video</a> on interactions with the mobile devices and related to physics by David DeSandro</p>

<h2>Rise of the Transpilers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DspYurD75Ns">this video</a> on the rise of the transpilers and coffeescript by Jeremy Ashkenas</p>

<h2>Drawing Lines with Bresenham&rsquo;s Line Algorithm</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zytBpLlSHms">this video</a> about how to apply the Bresenham&rsquo;s algorithm to draw lines (implemented in pseudo-code and javascript) by Jenn Schiffer</p>

<h2>Working with Minified JavaScript</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SuFNR7-XjKI">this video</a> by John Crepezzi on how to mix javascript files (clients and yours), how to decompile javascript in chrome, dev &amp; debug tools</p>

<h2>How we ran our Legacy Code Retreat</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://pboop.wordpress.com/2012/02/19/how-we-ran-our-legacy-code-retreat/">this article</a> by Andreas Leidig, looking for inspiration on running a legacy code retreat / brown-bag session. The experience report <a href="../../../../2015/06/23/brown-bag-session-refactoring-legacy-code/">is here</a></p>

<h2>Shift Left: Testing Earlier in Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://wirfs-brock.com/blog/2015/06/18/shift-left">this article</a> by Rebecca Wirfs-Brock</p>

<h2>Polymorphic Equality</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/06/polymorphic-equality/">this article</a> on implementing polymorphic equality on C#, by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Commit messages are not titles</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://antirez.com/news/90">this article</a> on git commit messages and how to use them, by antirez</p>

<h2>Oracle Considers G1 Garbage Collector for Java 9</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this <a href="https://adtmag.com/articles/2015/06/22/oracle-java-9.aspx">press article</a> on the G1 and CMS collector, by John K. Waters</p>

<h2>What Tech Newbies Need</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://storify.com/jesslynnrose/what-tech-newbies-need">this set of tweets</a>, grouped by Jessica Rose about the most helpful things beginners can do to improve their programming skills.</p>

<h2>JavaScript For Cats</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://jsforcats.com/">this introductory guide</a> to javascript by <a href="https://twitter.com/maxogden">Max Ogden</a></p>

<h2>Why Doesn&rsquo;t Python Have Switch/Case?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pydanny.com/why-doesnt-python-have-switch-case.html">this article</a> on the switch case in the python language by Daniel Roy Greenfeld</p>

<h2>[Joseph Moniz&rsquo;s] Notes on Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read Joseph Moniz&rsquo;s <a href="http://blog.plasmaconduit.com/notes-on-clojure/">Notes on Clojure</a>.</p>

<h2>Chemical Computing with Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://gigasquidsoftware.com/chemical-computing/index.html">an article</a> on performing abstract computations with chemicals, written in Clojure by Carin Meier</p>

<h2>Lenses</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.haskellforall.com/2012/01/haskell-for-mainstream-programmers_28.html">this tutorial</a> on writing lenses for haskell, a way of importing imperative getters / setters to a Data. Written by Gabriel Gonzalez.</p>

<p>On another note, the first part, about writing getters and setters in the naive way, is also explained in Learn you a Haskell > Chapter 8 Making Our Own Types and Typeclasses > Record syntax</p>

<h2>Microservices in Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/AlexanderAA/haskell-microservices/blob/gh-pages/haskell-microservices.md">these notes</a> on implementing a microservice in haskell, by <a href="https://github.com/AlexanderAA">AlexanderAA</a></p>

<h2>Overcoming Resistance to Change - Isn&rsquo;t It Obvious?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hcz1aZ60k7w">this video</a> in the channel of The World with Theory of Constraints</p>

<h2>Bacon is bad for you</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/garann/bacon-is-bad-for-you">these slides</a>
 on professionalism and the programmer culture, by Garann Means</p>

<h2>Code is a job</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/garann/code-is-a-job">these slides</a>, that are the continuation of &ldquo;Bacon is bad for you&rdquo;, by the same author, Garann Means</p>

<h2>The Great Newline Schism</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/the-great-newline-schism/">this article</a> by Jeff Atwood on the difference in newline character(s)</p>

<h2>Top ten reasons why I won’t use your open source project</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://changelog.com/top-ten-reasons-why-i-wont-use-your-open-source-project/">this article</a> on what&rsquo;s necessary for an open-source project to be usable by others. Written by Adam Stacoviak</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in May 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T14:41:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update: I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015
into a single post</p>

<h2>Programmer passion considered harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/on-coding/programmer-passion-considered-harmful-5c5d4e3a9b28">this article</a> on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.</p>

<h2>Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.coursereport.com/blog/software-craftsmanship-are-bootcamps-enough">this article</a> on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by <a href="https://twitter.com/kauerrolemodel">Ken Auer</a></p>

<h2>Improve your development environments with virtualization</h2>

<p>I have seen this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg_vPMnC7_k&amp;feature=youtu.be">Improve your development environments with virtualization</a> by Luke Sneeringer.</p>

<p>My notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>development should be exactly like production.</li>
<li>except where it is too painful. there it should be different</li>
</ul>


<h2>Buffer&rsquo;s take on values</h2>

<p>I have found these <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Bufferapp/buffer-culture-04">values</a>, written by Buffer, very interesting.</p>

<h2>Public static void</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kj5ApnhPAE">&ldquo;Public, static void&rdquo;</a> by Rob Pike. The slides can be found <a href="http://www.oscon.com/oscon2010/public/schedule/detail/13423">here</a></p>

<h3>My notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>too much bureaucracy</li>
<li>fighting the compiler</li>
<li>dynamic vs static typing</li>
<li>language too verbose</li>
<li><p>do not mix the two of them</p></li>
<li><p>a language niche:</p>

<ul>
<li>comprehensible</li>
<li>statically typed</li>
<li>light on the page</li>
<li>fast to work in</li>
<li>scales well</li>
<li>doesn&rsquo;t require tools but supports them well</li>
<li>good at networking and multiprocessing</li>
</ul>


<p>(minute 10:09)​</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://golang.org">Go</a> was born to fill this niche</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Nothing is something</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Software is eating the world</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>The Cost of Test Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.typemock.com/2009/03/the-cost-of-test-driven-development.html">this article</a>, on the cost of doing TDD, which refers to <a href="http://www.msr-waypoint.net/en-us/groups/ese/nagappan_tdd.pdf">this paper</a>: Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams (below)</p>

<h2>Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams</h2>

<p>This paper has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/12/paper-tdd-in-industrial-teams/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched the video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3T00X_sNg4Q">Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</a>, by Howard Abrams.</p>

<p>I guess this is a reference to the popular <a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/">Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!</a>.</p>

<p>He suggests many interesting resources for learning Lisp dialects. The live coding is in Clojure:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://landoflisp.com/">The land of Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/">Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs</a>. See also <a href="https://twitter.com/SICPQuotes">SICPQuotes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-schemer">The Little Schemer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/pdf/eintr.pdf">An Introduction to Programming in Emacs Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.4clojure.com/">4clojure Questions</a></li>
<li><a href="http://clojurekoans.com/">Clojure Koans</a></li>
</ul>


<p>On another topic, in the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/222418104/">Bank accounts exercise from Exercism</a> meetup, we discussed the book <a href="https://pragprog.com/book/shcloj2/programming-clojure">Programming Clojure (2nd edition)</a> by Stuart Halloway</p>

<h2>Professor Frisby&rsquo;s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/DrBoolean/mostly-adequate-guide">this guide</a> to functional programming. It is still work in progress (WIP) but still interesting. Written in javascript, so you can REPL in the browser.</p>

<h2>Learning Code Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video, by Saron Yitbarek: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-nsnAYRqYLA">Learn Code Good</a>.</p>

<h2>Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9FOchgTtLM">Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</a>, by Gregory Moeck.</p>

<p>In it, they point to the <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests</a> book (<a href="/blog/categories/goos">category here</a>), the paper <a href="www.jmock.org/oopsla2004.pdf">Mock Roles, not Objects</a> (also present in the GOOS book).</p>

<h2>Technical Debt: A Repayment Plan</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/tech-debt-repayment">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jeremyjarrell">Jeremy Jarrell</a> on technical debt how to repay it: schedule, taxes, default, etc</p>

<p>This has made me think of the <a href="http://scbcn.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Deuda-t%C3%A9cnica-origen-y-consecuencias/69782-25568">&ldquo;Deuda técnica, origen y consecuencias&rdquo; talk</a> (Technical debt: origin and consequences) (Spanish), that was delivered by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jgomezz">Javier Gómez</a> at the Software Craftsmanship 2014.</p>

<h2>Revisiting XP: be a thoughtful programmer by exercising more collective ownership</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/revisit-p-collective">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tiagooo_romero">Tiago Garcia</a> on the collective code ownership, as stated by Xtreme Programming (XP), with some example and guidelines.</p>

<h2>Where&rsquo;s the Real Bottleneck in Scientific Computing?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.americanscientist.org/issues/pub/wheres-the-real-bottleneck-in-scientific-computing/99999">this article</a> by Greg Wilson on the tools and procedures investigators use to produce software.</p>

<h2>Testing inside the Sprint</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ronjeffries.com/articles/2015-03-01-testing-in-sprints/">this article</a> by Ron Jeffries.</p>

<p>Discusses the need for testing and why this hasn&rsquo;t been communicated enough, as there still are people who have not understood it.</p>

<p>Also about why people equal something failing when using scrum with scrum failing.</p>

<h2>DTO vs Domain Models</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/05/dto-vs-domain-models/">this article</a> by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Homoiconicity isn’t the point</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://calculist.org/blog/2012/04/17/homoiconicity-isnt-the-point/">this article</a> by David Herman about homoiconicity, comparing Lisp dialects (have it) to others that don&rsquo;t. The main point is at the end, where it says:</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] homoiconicity isn’t the point, read is</p></blockquote>

<h2>So You Don&rsquo;t Want to be a Programmer After All</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/so-you-dont-want-to-be-a-programmer-after-all/">this article</a> by Jeff Atwood. Cites the golden handcuffs (also known as golden shackles), reasons to be and not to be a programmer, and how to be an average and outstanding programmer</p>

<h2>The Nature of Lisp</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.defmacro.org/ramblings/lisp.html">this article / introduction</a> to Lisp by Slava Akhmechet</p>

<h2>[David Pollak&rsquo;s] My Thoughts on Go</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.goodstuff.im/golang">these comments</a> on Go Lang from David Pollak</p>

<h2>The Well-Rounded Technologist</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/02/the-well-rounded-technologist.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Should I read papers?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/21/should-i-read-papers.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp-1 vs Lisp-2</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hornbeck.wordpress.com/2009/07/05/lisp-1-vs-lisp-2/">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/hornbeck">@Hornbeck</a> about the lisp 1 and lisp 2.</p>

<h2>Science Corps</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkQkafxFoIQ">TEDx talk</a> by Aza Raskin, featuring Data Banks and Science corps</p>

<h2>Healthy Codebase and Preparatory Refactoring</h2>

<p> I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://brewhouse.io/blog/2014/11/10/healthy-codebase-and-preparatory-refactoring.html">this article</a> by Philippe Creux about preparatory refactoring</p>

<h2>You Are Learning Haskell Right Now (Or Anything You Want Really)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/12/11/you-are-learning-haskell-right-now.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp is Abstract Syntax</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/16/lisp-is-abstract-syntax.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Two Things Types Have Taught Me</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/30/two-things-types-have-taught-me.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t Bet Against Yourself</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Learning Math: A Blank Is A Blank With A Blank</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>The False Economy Of Metaprogramming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/03/06/the-false-economy-of-generated-methods.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Management and Engineering, overlapping</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.quora.com/Does-Adam-DAngelo-feel-comfortable-with-the-transition-from-an-engineer-to-a-management-position?srid=3OC&amp;share=1">this Quora answer</a> by Adam D'Angelo. The original title is: Does Adam D'Angelo feel comfortable with the transition from an engineer to a management position?</p>

<h2>Evolution of The Twitter Stack</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/ly83zQkBjCxnIX">these slides</a> about changing the technology stack in Twitter: from Rails to JVM-based</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
