<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lisp on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/lisp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lisp on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/lisp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Threading Macro (clojure) equivalent in Python</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2023/07/22/threading-macro-equivalent-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:38:28 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2023/07/22/threading-macro-equivalent-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In any programming language, it is common to compose functions by pipelining functions: h = g ∘ f such that h(x) = g(f(x)).
The function f is applied first, then g, then the following. 1
For me, it would be more comfortable and easy to understand to write it f COMPOSE_THEN g, indicating that this function composition is not the usual, but a different operation.
Introduction in Clojure This function composition can be written in Clojure by pipelining or chaining functions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2023</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/03/01/self-study-march-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/03/01/self-study-march-2023/</guid>
      <description>Emacs is not just an editor (2015) An overview of Emacs as compared to vim (just an editor).
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35107806
Tags: emacs, vim, editor, operating-system, platform, lisp, ide, macro, doom-emacs, doom, imported, hacker-news
Id: 03d88f06-c197-11ed-a96e-0242ac110004 Read: Sat Mar 11 12:37:03 2023
CS 6120: Advanced Compilers: The Self-Guided Online Course An interesting course from Cornell about Compilers. Self-paced.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35130975
Tags: cornell, education, university, self-paced, compiler, mooc, mit, imported, hacker-news
Id: 19890060-c197-11ed-b449-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Mar 13 04:14:38 2023</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</guid>
      <description>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.
Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery
Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &amp;ldquo;Call me maybe&amp;rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown Bag Session: Clojure&#39;s Data and Code</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/23/brown-bag-session-clojures-data-and-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 21:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/23/brown-bag-session-clojures-data-and-code/</guid>
      <description>Today, at a client, I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated the brown-bag session on Clojure, introducing Lisp&amp;rsquo;s homoiconicity.
Session Structure The session was designed as a kata, first introducing participants in the problem, letting some time to read the initial version and to think about possible solutions.
Then, I structured the rest of the time as a prepared kata, where I was explaining in the beamer our current problems (day-to-day tasks) and possible solutions in Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in May 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015 into a single post
Programmer passion considered harmful I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.
Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by Ken Auer
Improve your development environments with virtualization I have seen this video: Improve your development environments with virtualization by Luke Sneeringer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inserting clojure code in octopress</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/14/inserting-clojure-code-in-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 23:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/14/inserting-clojure-code-in-octopress/</guid>
      <description>Inserting this code in the blog:
```clojure (defn all-access[k] (let [{:keys [a b] :as k}] (do a) (do (:b k)))) ```  the octopress processor throws the error:
Error: Pygments can&#39;t parse unknown language: clojure Error: Run jekyll build --trace for more information.  A solution would be to include it as lisp code:
```lisp (defn all-access[k] (let [{:keys [a b] :as k}] (do a) (do (:b k)))) ```  this is an example:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
