<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workshop on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workshop on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Kinesis Zombieland</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/28/aws-kinesis-zombieland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/28/aws-kinesis-zombieland/</guid>
      <description>I attended a workshop on AWS Kinesis, called AWS Kinesis Zombieland by Javi Moreno at capside.
Notes AWS Kinesis Zombieland
 muy importante escoger bien la clave de particionado (id de shard) KPL librería de kinesis que te permite hacer batching, timeout, &amp;hellip;  la otra se llama KCL. KCL permite mantener estado   cuando te pidan una app de big data, pregunta para qué lo quieren, lo mismo que con cualquier proyecto de software latitud = Y, longitud = x el canal se llama stream, la capacidad se llama shard  el shard sólo permite 5 lecturas por segundo, 2MB/s   usar el shard como buffer usar la clave de particionado como algoritmo de agregación cada vez que tienes una tabla en dynamodb, tienes que poner una alerta de throughput nota: lo que no puedes hacer es guardarlos todos y luego procesarlo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demand for TDD and Refactor</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/demand-for-tdd-and-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 13:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/demand-for-tdd-and-refactor/</guid>
      <description>When I went to the Jason Gorman&amp;rsquo;s TDD workshop (experience report here), he said something interesting regarding refactor and TDD:
 In job offers / advertisements, TDD is much more in demand than refactor. But the latter is included in the former as an integral part.
Jason Gorman
 I agree with the second thought: you cannot properly do TDD without refactoring, as it is an integral part; also the third phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience report: Test-driven development intensive, by Jason Gorman</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 20:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This is an experience report on Jason Gorman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Test-driven development intensive workshop&amp;rdquo; on the April 11th, 2015
I attended this training in the Greenfell housing &amp;amp; training in South Wimbledon, London SW19 1JZ. The training spanned from 10:00 to 17:00 with a half an hour for lunch plus three or four 10-15 minute pauses. (7 - ,5 - 4 * 12/60 = ~5.7hours = 5 hours 45 minutes)
Introduction There were 23 of us, including me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
