<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>repl on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/repl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in repl on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/repl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating CSV data in clojure</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/15/validating-data-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 11:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/15/validating-data-clojure/</guid>
      <description>At a client, we have CSVs of data that can be simplified to this 1:
(def data [ [&amp;#34;total&amp;#34; 6 8 13] [&amp;#34;0&amp;#34; 1 2 3] [&amp;#34;0&amp;#34; 2 0 4] [&amp;#34;0&amp;#34; 3 0 6] ]) In this case, some of the row named total is the sum of the rest of the rows, but only for some columns (second and fourth). We do not want to get rid of the columns, as they need to be printed at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure and the macro and</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/08/clojure-and-the-macro-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 17:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/08/clojure-and-the-macro-and/</guid>
      <description>While on the REPL, I tried this:
simple.core=&amp;gt; (reduce and true [true]) CompilerException java.lang.RuntimeException: Can&amp;#39;t take value of a macro: #&amp;#39;clojure.core/and, compiling:(form-init7116694665186998245.clj:1:1) Reading the clojuredocs for and, you can find this:
 Note add is a macro, so you cannot apply it. For example, there is a vector of some Boolean values [true true false true], which you want to test to see if they are all true. The code below will not work:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session and Dojo: Beginning Clojure</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/brown-bag-session-and-dojo-beginning-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 01:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/brown-bag-session-and-dojo-beginning-clojure/</guid>
      <description>At a client, today I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated a brown-bag session introducing the Clojure language to a group of java programmers.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started hands-on, live coding on a REPL. To make things easier, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a maven project that imports the clojure jar and lets you obtain dependencies from clojars. The repo is here. This repo wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the clojure maven plugin, written by Mark Derricutt.
I&amp;rsquo;ve more or less followed this guide</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for Java 9 (beta)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/03/resources-for-java-9-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 01:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/03/resources-for-java-9-beta/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found this list of links for Java 9, while in beta, useful:
 Contents of the new version Java REPL workshop, with useful commands and questions &amp;amp; answers for installing the REPL REPL tutorial PDF Another getting started guide, by JClarity Yet another getting started guide, by Arun Gupta Information on the REPL project, (codenamed Kulla)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
