<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pair-programming | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/pair-programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-05T01:09:33+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kata: Mars Rover in Clojure]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/kata-mars-rover-in-clojure/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-05T00:33:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/kata-mars-rover-in-clojure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday at the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/220773795/">clojure meetup</a> we<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> did the <a href="http://dallashackclub.com/rover">mars rover</a> in clojure and today I&rsquo;ve tried my hand at it again. Original, from the three of us <a href="https://github.com/jesusdiez/kata-rover-clojure">here</a> and my <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/kata-rover-clojure">results here</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jorgeavila_ss">Jorge Ávila</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/jdiezc">Jesús Díez</a> and I<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mob Programming String Calculator Kata]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T04:46:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we did a kata<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> using a projector the string calculator <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> using pair programming, TDD and some mob-programming for the last refactoring.</p>

<p>We used a projector (beamer) so everyone could see it. I tried to take really small baby steps but the adding part was done in ~6 cycles<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve all learnt about shotcuts, live user templates for the IDE <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>, TDD methodology, other ways of tackling the problem, how to refactor as a group, clean code, etc</p>

<p>These sessions are necessary to share some knowledge among the teammates and have another chance of doing code review, releasing some pressure from daily practices or bad abstractions / designs (that will be taken care of in the future)</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had such a great time, learning together, that would be a candidate for a weekly interaction.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mob_programming">Mob programming</a> is such an eye opening practice. It forces you to reconsider your previous dogma and to understand the others&#8217; positions. Wikipedia reads &ldquo;early use of phrase [&hellip;] was made in &lsquo;Extreme Programming Perspectives&rsquo;&rdquo; but this practice is practiced by some, such as <a href="https://twitter.com/carlosble">Carlos Blé</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a> among others; also at the <a href="http://www.softwarecraftsmanshipbarcelona.org/">Software Craftsmanship Barcelona</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/scbcn2013?src=hash">2013</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SCBCN14?src=hash">2014</a> and the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/socracan?src=hash">SoCra Canaries 2015</a></p>

<h2>One goal</h2>

<p>Our goal for this session was to practice TDD and baby steps, so the team can improve its ability on these skills.</p>

<p>In any case, my objective for the katas (or deliberate practice) is not to get there as fast as we can but to improve our automated routines. This can affect our daily performance, as it becomes natural. It is not about the getting to the destination but enjoying the path along the way. In this manner, you are not so hurried up about a slow train but enjoy the views across the window.</p>

<p>It was good that QA people in the team came to the session. He even participated with some tips / implementations during the refactors. Always fruitful to discuss (and learn) mixed skills (QA / dev) from the other side of the wall</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I still haven&rsquo;t mastered the recipe (algorithm) for knowing when it is a scaffold and when it&rsquo;s time to refactor using &ldquo;replace algorithm&rdquo;. For know, I just use the three (3) rule and a bit of gut feeling on the side. The bad thing is that this can not be easily taught to someone else. Just learnt by osmosis and practice.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>matching none of the styles explained in <a href="http://johannesbrodwall.com/2011/12/18/how-to-start-a-coding-dojo/">here</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>This is a very good beginner&rsquo;s kata, created by <a href="https://twitter.com/royosherove">Roy Osherove</a>. Can be found <a href="http://osherove.com/tdd-kata-1/">here</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>One piece of feedback I received is that I talk too much while coding, as these 6 cycles took us about 45 minutes, total<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>There are some for <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/live-templates.html">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4022367/what-is-the-eclipse-equivalent-of-intellij-live-templates">Eclipse</a> too<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Discussion: On Code Reviews]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/open-discussion-on-code-reviews/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-07T18:54:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/open-discussion-on-code-reviews</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a great conversation yesterday about code reviews.</p>

<p>The main idea was to discuss about it and share the ideas each one had. I didn&rsquo;t want it to turn into a masterclass (see <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch02.html#the_white_belt">the white belt</a>)</p>

<h2>Benefits</h2>

<p>These are the main benefits we saw in it:</p>

<ul>
<li>Increased trust</li>
<li>Learning from others, other approaches</li>
<li>Less defects, more quality</li>
<li>Increased <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">bus factor</a>, decreased information silos</li>
<li>Also:

<ul>
<li>Getting out of your comfort zone</li>
<li>Communicating more often (code style, edge cases, complaining, etc)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Pair programming</h2>

<p>Then we discussed about the topic of <a href="/blog/categories/code-review">code reviews</a> and <a href="/blog/categories/pair-programming/">pair programming</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>How do they mix</p>

<ul>
<li>Is the need for code review reduced when doing pair programming?</li>
<li>It is cheaper to catch defects when pairing than code review (e.g., less to modify, mental caches are hot, &hellip;), so why do code reviews? <a href="https://twitter.com/jbrains">J. B. Rainsberger</a> has an <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=acc77a0fb2&amp;e=4a925444f9">article</a> about it</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Does it give you the same benefits?</p>

<ul>
<li>I argued that it does, some of my colleagues argued against as one is &ldquo;while doing&rdquo; and the other is after.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Practice, Practice, Practice</h2>

<p>This is also a reference to a chapter by the same name (<a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch05.html#practice_comma_practice_comma_practice">here</a>)</p>

<p>We proposed this problem:</p>

<blockquote><p>Receive a list of numbers to a command-line (CLI) application and print their sum</p></blockquote>

<p>I wrote simple code listing and we reviewed it. The code is <a href="https://gist.github.com/alvarogarcia7/258faea12cb9375539fe">here as a gist</a></p>

<p>(Just in case, I wrote this listing with some defects / smells on purpose)</p>

<p>Here are the comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not all parameters will be added, only the first three</li>
<li>The parameters are out of order, overcomplicating things. Is it due to something? Should I be careful about it?</li>
<li>There is duplication (i.e., parsing from string)</li>
<li>Bad naming: what is <code>a</code>, <code>b</code>, <code>c</code>?</li>
<li>There are no tests for it. No manual / javadoc either. Therefore, it&rsquo;s difficult to maintain</li>
<li><p>Difficult to test: a smell for bad design?</p>

<ul>
<li>How to test the adding by itself? The output is to the console, so we have to capture it (at GMaur we published this tool: <a href="https://github.com/GMaur/legacyutils">legacyUtils</a>)</li>
<li>How to test the parsing if there is no mock to be injected? Only via state tests, therefore &ldquo;end to end&rdquo; tests as it includes the adding</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Mixed concerns / responsibilities. Parsing the numbers and adding them are different concerns and should not be together</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<ul>
<li>No one was against it</li>
<li>We all agreed that is important to do it even in time-constrained environments</li>
<li>It is also important to review our code reviews to make the most of it. The article by <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=acc77a0fb2&amp;e=4a925444f9">J. B. Rainsberger</a> is quite useful for that</li>
<li>Even small codes can be bad and need to be reviewed (as the example)</li>
<li>Quick and dirty proof of concept do not mix well with code reviews</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pairing With Junior Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/03/pairing-with-junior-developers/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-03T23:40:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/03/pairing-with-junior-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading <a href="https://devmynd.com/blog/2015-1-pairing-with-junior-developers">this blog post</a>, here are my thoughts:</p>

<p><strong>WARNING</strong>: the post was about how to do it, these reflections are on a more philosophical level</p>

<p>This is a controversial topic, as:</p>

<ul>
<li>You cannot discern how much or little the other person knows more than you. I cannot find the reference anymore, but it was a to the tune of &ldquo;once the other person&rsquo;s level is higher than yours, you cannot know how much&rdquo;</li>
<li>There are different knowledge areas. Yours and theirs might overlap on some areas, but not completely. So they may be experts on an area that is not useful to the technology you&rsquo;re currently using.</li>
<li>Different people have different passions and motivators.</li>
</ul>


<p>When and where are you a junior and a senior?</p>

<ul>
<li>Does it depend on each job?</li>
<li>Is it on each product you work?</li>
<li>Is it on each team?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;when you join a new project you are starting from square one&rdquo;</p>

<p><cite> D. Hoover, A. Oshineye </cite> in the chapter <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch04.html#solution_id21">Sweep the floor</a>, <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/index.html">Apprenticeship patterns</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Related to the amount of senior people, is there only one senior per team?</p>

<ul>
<li>Can everybody be a senior? If we assert this is true, what about &ldquo;if everything matters, nothing matters&rdquo;. Does that mean that everyone is senior or there are different levels of seniority and we call &ldquo;the senior&rdquo; the one on the top of the list?</li>
<li>Who choses the senior within the team? Is it self-organized, self-chosen? Do the people chose one? Is a shared responsibility, as each one masters a (possibly different) subject?</li>
</ul>


<p>Food for thought.</p>

<p>What do you think about it?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bank Kata in Java]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/bank-kata-in-java/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T22:52:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/bank-kata-in-java</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/trikitrok">Manuel Rivero</a> and I did a subset of the <a href="https://github.com/sandromancuso/Bank-kata">bank kata</a>, proposed by <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a>.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve used java (mockito, hamcrest, junit), outside-in TDD. The code is spread among several sessions. We have not committed after each step, only at the end of the session.</p>

<p>The source code is on <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/bank-kata">github</a></p>

<p>You can read Manuel&rsquo;s take on the kata on <a href="http://garajeando.blogspot.com.es/2015/01/kata-bank-account-in-java.html">his blog</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
