<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pair-programming | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/pair-programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-04T08:56:36+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience Report: Test-driven Development Intensive, by Jason Gorman]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-12T20:13:45+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an experience report on <a href="http://twitter.com/@jasongorman">Jason Gorman</a>&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.codemanship.co.uk/tdd.html">Test-driven development intensive workshop</a>&rdquo; on the April 11th, 2015</p>

<p>I attended this training in the <a href="http://www.grenfell-housing.co.uk/">Greenfell housing &amp; training</a> in South Wimbledon, London SW19 1JZ. The training spanned from 10:00 to 17:00 with a half an hour for lunch plus three or four 10-15 minute pauses. (7 - ,5 - 4 * 12/60 = ~5.7hours = 5 hours 45 minutes)</p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>There were 23 of us, including me. We spent some half hour introducing ourselves before the training started. I remember about a tester that came to the workshop &ldquo;wanting to know more about this testing methodology&rdquo;. Jason&rsquo;s answer was priceless: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry but you came to the wrong place: this is not about testing&rdquo;.
</p>

<p>At 10:00 sharp, he started a set of slides explaining what TDD is about, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>productivity:

<ul>
<li>no company is willing to give you a &ldquo;get out of jail free&rdquo; card to get out of the productivity zone</li>
<li>a drop in the productivity, at least for the first weeks</li>
<li>you have to find a time slot in your schedule to practice TDD, otherwise it&rsquo;s like learning to swim while crossing the Atlantic Ocean</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You have to feel uncomfortable not doing TDD</li>
<li>triangulation:

<ul>
<li>how each problem is different</li>
<li>you can only learn it by doing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>TDD styles:

<ul>
<li>Chicago style by Kent Beck. Reference book would be &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">TDD by example</a>&rdquo;</li>
<li>London school or Mockist style by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce. Reference book would be <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">&ldquo;Growing object oriented software, guided by tests</a>&#8221;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>13 good habits for a sustainable test-driven development way</li>
<li>The basic TDD cycle:

<ul>
<li>an executable specification, encoded in a failing test</li>
<li>pass the test in the simplest way</li>
<li>refactor</li>
<li>(talking with another attendee, he described to me a new TDD phase called redesign. Maybe another post will explain this in deeper detail level)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Some ideas about <a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org/rules/simple.html">Simple design, simple development, simplicity</a> (<a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org">XP</a>)</li>
<li>Shown a wrong example of mixing assertions (state) and verifications (interactions)</li>
<li>More than one reason to go wrong makes the code non-trivial anymore. Non-trivial code requires tests</li>
<li>You want to see the test failing for the right reason: remove / finish code that does not compile, fix null pointers, array out of bounds exceptions, etc. See it fail with &ldquo;was <X> but expected <Y>&rdquo; or &ldquo;NoInteractionException&rdquo; (hamcrest error and mockito error, respectively; both java)</li>
<li>Duplication as a sign of design smell</li>
<li>Process of generalizing code: discover the need for patterns</li>
<li>The most difficult skill in TDD is refactoring [and design; note is mine]. The TDD cycle is very easy.

<ul>
<li>TDD is much more in demand than refactoring, even though the former includes the latter</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Refactor until you&rsquo;re happy with the code, until you stand by it</li>
</ul>


<h2>CRC Cards</h2>

<p>A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class-responsibility-collaboration_card">Class-responsibility-collaboration card</a> is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>top: class name</li>
<li>half left: responsibilities</li>
<li>half right: collaborations</li>
</ul>


<p>Notes from the slides:</p>

<ul>
<li>each then is an outcome

<ul>
<li>do not mix outcomes and implications. An example: after winning the lottery, the money should be transferred to my bank account and I can buy a yacht. The former is an outcome (change in state) and the latter an implication (a new action that is now enabled)</li>
<li>an outcome is mapped to an assertion, while a collaboration is mapped to an interaction (verify in mockito)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Given / When / Then is not enough to implement an executable specification. We need examples, detail</li>
<li>OO: send messages to distribute responsibility.

<ul>
<li>A Then is an unique responsibility</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Topmost object: no one connects with it</li>
<li>Put the work where the data is</li>
<li>Tell, don&rsquo;t ask <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> vs data driven design (tell a collaborator what to do vs ask for values and do the work yourself)</li>
<li>You want as few interactions as possible (related to the tell, don&rsquo;t ask)</li>
<li>More objects than outcomes is a bad thing (design smell) (?)</li>
<li>CRC is a very mechanical exercise, do not over think it</li>
<li>Describe outcomes as changes in OO (new, destroy, relationships, modify fields / state)</li>
<li>Continuous integration is not necessarily about shipping the code at each commit but having it shippable at each commit, as always having a product that is ready for its production phase</li>
</ul>


<h2>Exercises</h2>

<p>All exercises were done in pairs, always switching one half of the pair. He asked for someone in the pair to raise, especially if you were not a programmer (e.g., tester, manager)</p>

<h3>First exercise: Banking</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of transferring money from an account to another</p></blockquote>

<p>A chance to practice arrange, act, assert</p>

<p>Later, he did it some live coding to develop the same kata, practicing &ldquo;<a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/TDD-as-if-You-Meant-It">TDD as if you meant it</a>&rdquo; (<a href="https://twitter.com/keithb_b">Keith Braithwaite</a>&rsquo;s original idea). We discovered together the &ldquo;primitive obsession&rdquo; and &ldquo;feature envy&rdquo; smells. We tried doing as few decisions as possible.</p>

<h3>Second exercise: Fibonacci sequence generator</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of generating Fibonacci sequences, no shorter that 8 and no longer than 50</p></blockquote>

<p>A chance to practice baby steps.</p>

<p>My pair and I had the chance of discovering the importance of understanding correctly the requirements before writing a line of code. Also, I learned about the different ways of doing TDD. In this case, my pair executed the tests via a main (java class) and saw the failures on the console. When proposed to do it in the JUnit runner the IDE has, he said he preferred it in his own ways.</p>

<p>Jason did some live coding to show how he approached and triangulated this exercise.</p>

<p>I really liked some of what he said: I like to make the API correct from the first moment so I will ask questions that are correct but only check answers for things that I have already implemented. Example:</p>

<p>As the generated sequence can only have <code>8 &lt;= x &lt;= 50</code> elements, a list returning a single element would not be correct. So</p>

<pre><code class="java">//class FibonacciTests
@Test
public void theFirstElementIsOne(){
    assertThat(new FibonacciSequence().generate(8)[0], is(1));
}
</code></pre>

<h3>Third exercise: FizzBuzz</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of returning a string with all numbers less than 100 that are using the FizzBuzz pattern. This FizzBuzz pattern converts the divisors of 3 to &lsquo;fizz&rsquo;, divisors of 5 to &lsquo;buzz&rsquo; and divisors to both to &lsquo;fizzbuzz&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>I discovered that this FizzBuzz is a drinking game in the UK.</p>

<h3>Fourth exercise: CRC cards</h3>

<p>Before this exercise there was a short introduction on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class-responsibility-collaboration_card">Class-responsibility-collaboration card</a>, explained above</p>

<p>Following an example about a movie library, there were six user stories, described at high level, without acceptance criteria.</p>

<p>We had to create an acceptance criteria for this user story. Later create a set of CRC cards and finally partially implement said feature.</p>

<p>Very interesting exercise, such a pity that there wasn&rsquo;t more time to complete this exercise or see him doing it</p>

<h2>Knowledge pearls</h2>

<p>He dropped some knowledge pearls (that I&rsquo;m going to use myself):</p>

<pre><code>Q: When are you done with TDD?
A: When you can not think of more tests for your suite
</code></pre>

<pre><code>Q: What do we do after TDD?
A: (No answer)
Q: Starts with "T". Any idea?
A: Testing. Test for the purpose of testing, not TDD
</code></pre>

<p>Close concepts interested in responsibilities:</p>

<ul>
<li>Conceptual diagram and class diagram</li>
<li>Instance diagram</li>
<li>Knowledge map and tag cloud</li>
</ul>


<p>Regarding legacy code:</p>

<ul>
<li>Isolate big balls of mud into parts and test these as end-to-end. Also connected to isolating groups of nodes into the class graph</li>
<li>Understand what the code does, not the architecture</li>
<li>Do not use a mock to help you test legacy code, use it just as a design tool. (It might be a good idea to use it temporarily while you refactor, but remove it afterwards)</li>
<li>Tests with mocks double down on the design: if it is broken, it will be a drag more than help</li>
</ul>


<p>Test on the boundaries. Many times we test in the middle of the algorithm but forget the boundaries, where many special cases hide</p>

<p>The GOOS book is pronounced like the goose animal (&ldquo;/gús/&rdquo;) in English</p>

<p>He said he never copy pastes <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<ul>
<li>This is a two day workshop condensed on a single day. It shows. In my opinion, it would be better to do fewer exercises and dig deeper in them rather than try so many approaches / exercises</li>
<li>The CRC exercise was well thought and really massaged. It touches the right spots and makes you want to learn more about the subject</li>
<li>Promiscuously pairing is always a good idea, as you don&rsquo;t know what level have your attendees. Get stuck for the whole day with someone who has a (very) different knowledge level than you might spoil the workshop</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t see the benefit of doing the fizzbuzz kata after having done the Fibonacci sequence one</li>
<li>In my opinion, there were too many breaks. Doing a break in the morning (10-15 mins), lunch (30 mins) and afternoon (10-15 mins) is enough</li>
</ul>


<p>On a personal note:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is not enough to attend the workshop. You have to take notes and study them at home later. (Thanks <a href="http://spines.me">spines</a> for this lesson)</li>
<li>I really had a great time, learned a lot, even though I already know something about TDD</li>
<li>Met very interesting people</li>
<li>Would attend to the workshop again</li>
</ul>


<p>In general, I&rsquo;d like to thank Jason and the other attendees for making this workshop possible. I had a blast there.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>As described by <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TellDontAsk.html">Martin Fowler</a> and the <a href="https://pragprog.com/articles/tell-dont-ask">Pragmatic Bookshelf</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Copy pasting this post&rsquo;s structure resulted in a wrong title that had to be fixed. Maybe the extra effort of not copy pasting has a good ROI, as long as you do not copy paste by typing the text you&rsquo;re reading from somewhere else<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kata: Mars Rover in Clojure]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/kata-mars-rover-in-clojure/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-05T00:33:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/05/kata-mars-rover-in-clojure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday at the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/220773795/">clojure meetup</a> we<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> did the <a href="http://dallashackclub.com/rover">mars rover</a> in clojure and today I&rsquo;ve tried my hand at it again. Original, from the three of us <a href="https://github.com/jesusdiez/kata-rover-clojure">here</a> and my <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/kata-rover-clojure">results here</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jorgeavila_ss">Jorge Ávila</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/jdiezc">Jesús Díez</a> and I<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mob Programming String Calculator Kata]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T04:46:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we did a kata<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> using a projector the string calculator <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> using pair programming, TDD and some mob-programming for the last refactoring.</p>

<p>We used a projector (beamer) so everyone could see it. I tried to take really small baby steps but the adding part was done in ~6 cycles<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve all learnt about shotcuts, live user templates for the IDE <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>, TDD methodology, other ways of tackling the problem, how to refactor as a group, clean code, etc</p>

<p>These sessions are necessary to share some knowledge among the teammates and have another chance of doing code review, releasing some pressure from daily practices or bad abstractions / designs (that will be taken care of in the future)</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had such a great time, learning together, that would be a candidate for a weekly interaction.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mob_programming">Mob programming</a> is such an eye opening practice. It forces you to reconsider your previous dogma and to understand the others&#8217; positions. Wikipedia reads &ldquo;early use of phrase [&hellip;] was made in &lsquo;Extreme Programming Perspectives&rsquo;&rdquo; but this practice is practiced by some, such as <a href="https://twitter.com/carlosble">Carlos Blé</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a> among others; also at the <a href="http://www.softwarecraftsmanshipbarcelona.org/">Software Craftsmanship Barcelona</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/scbcn2013?src=hash">2013</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SCBCN14?src=hash">2014</a> and the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/socracan?src=hash">SoCra Canaries 2015</a></p>

<h2>One goal</h2>

<p>Our goal for this session was to practice TDD and baby steps, so the team can improve its ability on these skills.</p>

<p>In any case, my objective for the katas (or deliberate practice) is not to get there as fast as we can but to improve our automated routines. This can affect our daily performance, as it becomes natural. It is not about the getting to the destination but enjoying the path along the way. In this manner, you are not so hurried up about a slow train but enjoy the views across the window.</p>

<p>It was good that QA people in the team came to the session. He even participated with some tips / implementations during the refactors. Always fruitful to discuss (and learn) mixed skills (QA / dev) from the other side of the wall</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I still haven&rsquo;t mastered the recipe (algorithm) for knowing when it is a scaffold and when it&rsquo;s time to refactor using &ldquo;replace algorithm&rdquo;. For know, I just use the three (3) rule and a bit of gut feeling on the side. The bad thing is that this can not be easily taught to someone else. Just learnt by osmosis and practice.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>matching none of the styles explained in <a href="http://johannesbrodwall.com/2011/12/18/how-to-start-a-coding-dojo/">here</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>This is a very good beginner&rsquo;s kata, created by <a href="https://twitter.com/royosherove">Roy Osherove</a>. Can be found <a href="http://osherove.com/tdd-kata-1/">here</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>One piece of feedback I received is that I talk too much while coding, as these 6 cycles took us about 45 minutes, total<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>There are some for <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/live-templates.html">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4022367/what-is-the-eclipse-equivalent-of-intellij-live-templates">Eclipse</a> too<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Discussion: On Code Reviews]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/open-discussion-on-code-reviews/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-07T18:54:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/07/open-discussion-on-code-reviews</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a great conversation yesterday about code reviews.</p>

<p>The main idea was to discuss about it and share the ideas each one had. I didn&rsquo;t want it to turn into a masterclass (see <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch02.html#the_white_belt">the white belt</a>)</p>

<h2>Benefits</h2>

<p>These are the main benefits we saw in it:</p>

<ul>
<li>Increased trust</li>
<li>Learning from others, other approaches</li>
<li>Less defects, more quality</li>
<li>Increased <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">bus factor</a>, decreased information silos</li>
<li>Also:

<ul>
<li>Getting out of your comfort zone</li>
<li>Communicating more often (code style, edge cases, complaining, etc)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Pair programming</h2>

<p>Then we discussed about the topic of <a href="/blog/categories/code-review">code reviews</a> and <a href="/blog/categories/pair-programming/">pair programming</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>How do they mix</p>

<ul>
<li>Is the need for code review reduced when doing pair programming?</li>
<li>It is cheaper to catch defects when pairing than code review (e.g., less to modify, mental caches are hot, &hellip;), so why do code reviews? <a href="https://twitter.com/jbrains">J. B. Rainsberger</a> has an <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=acc77a0fb2&amp;e=4a925444f9">article</a> about it</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Does it give you the same benefits?</p>

<ul>
<li>I argued that it does, some of my colleagues argued against as one is &ldquo;while doing&rdquo; and the other is after.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Practice, Practice, Practice</h2>

<p>This is also a reference to a chapter by the same name (<a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch05.html#practice_comma_practice_comma_practice">here</a>)</p>

<p>We proposed this problem:</p>

<blockquote><p>Receive a list of numbers to a command-line (CLI) application and print their sum</p></blockquote>

<p>I wrote simple code listing and we reviewed it. The code is <a href="https://gist.github.com/alvarogarcia7/258faea12cb9375539fe">here as a gist</a></p>

<p>(Just in case, I wrote this listing with some defects / smells on purpose)</p>

<p>Here are the comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>Not all parameters will be added, only the first three</li>
<li>The parameters are out of order, overcomplicating things. Is it due to something? Should I be careful about it?</li>
<li>There is duplication (i.e., parsing from string)</li>
<li>Bad naming: what is <code>a</code>, <code>b</code>, <code>c</code>?</li>
<li>There are no tests for it. No manual / javadoc either. Therefore, it&rsquo;s difficult to maintain</li>
<li><p>Difficult to test: a smell for bad design?</p>

<ul>
<li>How to test the adding by itself? The output is to the console, so we have to capture it (at GMaur we published this tool: <a href="https://github.com/GMaur/legacyutils">legacyUtils</a>)</li>
<li>How to test the parsing if there is no mock to be injected? Only via state tests, therefore &ldquo;end to end&rdquo; tests as it includes the adding</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Mixed concerns / responsibilities. Parsing the numbers and adding them are different concerns and should not be together</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<ul>
<li>No one was against it</li>
<li>We all agreed that is important to do it even in time-constrained environments</li>
<li>It is also important to review our code reviews to make the most of it. The article by <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;id=acc77a0fb2&amp;e=4a925444f9">J. B. Rainsberger</a> is quite useful for that</li>
<li>Even small codes can be bad and need to be reviewed (as the example)</li>
<li>Quick and dirty proof of concept do not mix well with code reviews</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pairing With Junior Developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/03/pairing-with-junior-developers/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-03T23:40:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/03/pairing-with-junior-developers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading <a href="https://devmynd.com/blog/2015-1-pairing-with-junior-developers">this blog post</a>, here are my thoughts:</p>

<p><strong>WARNING</strong>: the post was about how to do it, these reflections are on a more philosophical level</p>

<p>This is a controversial topic, as:</p>

<ul>
<li>You cannot discern how much or little the other person knows more than you. I cannot find the reference anymore, but it was a to the tune of &ldquo;once the other person&rsquo;s level is higher than yours, you cannot know how much&rdquo;</li>
<li>There are different knowledge areas. Yours and theirs might overlap on some areas, but not completely. So they may be experts on an area that is not useful to the technology you&rsquo;re currently using.</li>
<li>Different people have different passions and motivators.</li>
</ul>


<p>When and where are you a junior and a senior?</p>

<ul>
<li>Does it depend on each job?</li>
<li>Is it on each product you work?</li>
<li>Is it on each team?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;when you join a new project you are starting from square one&rdquo;</p>

<p><cite> D. Hoover, A. Oshineye </cite> in the chapter <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch04.html#solution_id21">Sweep the floor</a>, <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/index.html">Apprenticeship patterns</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Related to the amount of senior people, is there only one senior per team?</p>

<ul>
<li>Can everybody be a senior? If we assert this is true, what about &ldquo;if everything matters, nothing matters&rdquo;. Does that mean that everyone is senior or there are different levels of seniority and we call &ldquo;the senior&rdquo; the one on the top of the list?</li>
<li>Who choses the senior within the team? Is it self-organized, self-chosen? Do the people chose one? Is a shared responsibility, as each one masters a (possibly different) subject?</li>
</ul>


<p>Food for thought.</p>

<p>What do you think about it?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
