<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pair-programming | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/pair-programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-15T14:11:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in October 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-01T13:25:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://elm-lang.org/blog/blazing-fast-html">this article</a> explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.</p>

<p>Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki</p>

<h2>Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://cryto.net/~joepie91/blog/2015/07/19/why-you-should-never-ever-ever-use-mongodb/">this article</a> stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg</p>

<p>Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid</p>

<h2>Do you really get classloaders?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/rebel-labs-tutorial-do-you-really-get-classloaders/">this video</a> by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</p>

<p>My notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>the classloading is lazy: the resources are not loaded until they are mentioned</li>
<li>every classloader has a parent</li>
<li>every class has a classloader associated with it</li>
<li>every object has a class associated with it</li>
<li>classloading delegation: the parent is consulted before loading a class. if it has it, it will load it. If not, I will delegate it</li>
</ul>


<p>There is also <a href="http://www.javaworld.com/article/2074396/core-java/javaone-2011--do-you-really-get-classloaders-.html">this article</a> on the same video</p>

<p>Tags: jevgeny-kabanov, classloader, java,</p>

<h2>Truth table</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truth_table">the wikipedia article</a> about the truth table and the 16 possible binary boolean operators:</p>

<ul>
<li>Contradiction</li>
<li>NOR</li>
<li>Converse nonimplication</li>
<li>Negation (of p)</li>
<li>Material nonimplication</li>
<li>Negation (of q)</li>
<li>XOR (exclusive disjunction)</li>
<li>NAND</li>
<li>AND (conjunction)</li>
<li>XNOR (biconditional)</li>
<li>Projection (of p)</li>
<li>Implication</li>
<li>Projection (of q)</li>
<li>Converse implication</li>
<li>OR (disjunction)</li>
<li>Tautology</li>
</ul>


<h2>7 lines of code, 3 minutes: Implement a programming language from scratch</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/implementing-a-programming-language/">this article</a> by Matt Might about the benefits of implementing a language (from scratch but on top of another existing language used as framework). Chooses lambda calculus as the desired DSL</p>

<p>Tags: matt-might, lambda-calculus, racket, domain-specific-language</p>

<h2>Turing completeness</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness">this wikipedia article</a> (both main and discussion) about this subject.</p>

<p>It has sounded strange to me the reference to S-expressions:</p>

<blockquote><p>Data languages
The notion of Turing-completeness does not apply to languages such as XML, HTML, JSON, YAML and S-expressions because they are typically used to represent structured data, not describe computation [&hellip;]</p></blockquote>

<p>If data (S-expression) is represented as the same format as code (e.g., Lisp&rsquo;s S-expression) and the latter is used to represent a computation, shouldn&rsquo;t be &ldquo;data languages that also are used as computation languages&rdquo; excluded from that list?</p>

<p>As a side note, Lisp is Turing Complete (see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness#Examples">Turing Complete#Examples</a>)</p>

<h2>The Prize Is Won; The Simplest Universal Turing Machine Is Proved</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.wolfram.com/2007/10/24/the-prize-is-won-the-simplest-universal-turing-machine-is-proved/?year=2007&amp;monthnum=10">this article</a> by Stephen Wolfram about the proof of a Turing Machine 2,3 being universal by Alex Smith.</p>

<p>Tags: stephen-wolfram, turing-machine, universal-turing-machine, proof, paper, alex-smith</p>

<h2>Making a successful commitment in each Sprint</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://succeeding-with-agile.blogspot.com/2015/07/making-successful-commitment-in-each.html">this article</a> by Nikolaos Raptis on committing to work in each sprint.</p>

<p>Tags: nikolaos-raptis, sprint, agile, commitment</p>

<h2>No increment operator (++) in Ruby?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3717519/no-increment-operator-in-ruby">this stackoverflow</a> question about the lack of post-increment operator (i++) in Ruby:</p>

<blockquote><p>++ and &ndash; are NOT reserved operator in Ruby.</p>

<p>Mailing list from <a href="http://blade.nagaokaut.ac.jp/cgi-bin/scat.rb/ruby/ruby-talk/2710">Yukihiro Matsumoto aka matz</a></p></blockquote>

<h2>Code is Data, Data is Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blogs.mulesoft.com/dev/news-dev/code-is-data-data-is-code/">this article</a> by James Donelan on the equivalence of code and data in homoiconic languages, including Clojure.</p>

<p>The article talks about homoiconicity, manually creating Abstract Syntax Trees (AST) out of data and the macro environment. Also, compares the difference between macros and functions.</p>

<p>Tags: code=data, data=code, james-donelan, clojure, homoiconicity, abstract-syntax-tree, ast, macro, function</p>

<h2>Agile in Practice: Test Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGaNkTahrIw">this video</a> introducing TDD by the Agile Academy. Explains its motivations and the basic cyclical fashion.</p>

<p>Tags: agile-academy, video, tdd, introduction</p>

<h2>Agile in Practice: Pair Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ET3Q6zNK3Io">this video</a> by Agile Academy on practicing pair programming. Explains the destination and how to get there.</p>

<p>Tags: agile-academy, pair-programming, video, introduction</p>

<h2>A low cost approach to working on side projects</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://practicingruby.com/articles/low-cost-approach-to-side-projects">this article</a> by Gregory Brown on how to apply the MVP and Lean Startup principles to side projects (a.k.a. pet projects). Try to start with a brainstorming session of all the features you want your product to have, then prioritise, picking the most important ones.</p>

<p>Most projects' needs can be solved with a minimal version, in the form of a script that took half an hour to develop.</p>

<p>Tags: gregory-brown, mvp, lean-startup, script, proof-of-concept, priority, backlog, side-project, pet-project, low-cost, cost-reduction</p>

<h2>Extreme Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kFM2Vcu-BRo">this video</a> by STAR Videos on the basic principles behind Extreme Programming and how to use it to improve software quality</p>

<p>Tags: star-videos, extreme-programming, xp, software-quality</p>

<h2>Disruptor: High performance alternative to bounded queues for exchanging data between concurrent threads</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://lmax-exchange.github.io/disruptor/files/Disruptor-1.0.pdf">this white paper</a> describing the disruptor framework: a way of exchanging data between concurrent threads.</p>

<p>It uses a ring buffer and other techniques to eliminate write contention, reduce read contention and produces good results. It was developed for a financial exchange environment but it&rsquo;s general purpose.</p>

<p>Tags: martin-thompson, dave-farley, michael-barker, patricia-gee, andrew-stewart, trisha-gee, disruptor, contention, framework, concurrency, parallelism, white-paper, comparison, arrayblockingqueue, concurrentlinkedqueue, doug-lea, benchmark, lmax, low-level-optimization, optimization</p>

<h2>Dissecting the Disruptor: What&rsquo;s so special about a ring buffer?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2011/06/dissecting-disruptor-whats-so-special.html">this article</a> about the ring buffer data structure. A FIFO data structure where elements get overwritten to reduce pressure on the garbage collector. Every message gets sent to every consumer.</p>

<p>Tags: patricia-gee, trisha-gee, disruptor, ring-buffer, data-structure</p>

<h2>The Dependency Inversion Principle</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.objectmentor.com/resources/articles/dip.pdf">this paper</a> about the Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) written Robert C. Martin.</p>

<p>It explains the theory, philosophy behind it. Also, creates an example with a copy buffer and different output locations</p>

<p>Tags: robert-martin, dependency-inversion-principle, dip, example, comparison, object-oriented, principle, solid, design-principle</p>

<h2>DIP in the Wild</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/dipInTheWild.html">this article</a> about the Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) written by Brett L. Schuchert.</p>

<p>It is explained non-canonical representations of this principle, how in other cases he has solved it and conclusions of using it day to day.</p>

<p>Tags: brett-l.-schuchert, dependency-inversion-principle, dip, example, object-oriented, solid, design-principle</p>

<h2>The New New Product Development Game</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hbr.org/1986/01/the-new-new-product-development-game">this paper</a> about the holistic approach to product development, considered seminal for Scrum and other Agile methodologies. Written by Hirotaka Takeuchi and Ikujiro Nonaka</p>

<p>In it, they describe how teams are distributed, the responsibilities for each one, and the degrees of freedom.</p>

<p>Cites the six basic characteristics:</p>

<ul>
<li>built-in instability</li>
<li>self-organizing project teams</li>
<li>overlapping development phases</li>
<li>multilearning</li>
<li>subtle control</li>
<li>organizational transfer of learning</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: hirotaka-takeuchi, ikujiro-nonaka, scrum, agile, product-development, management, 1986</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in July 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/self-study-in-july-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-30T23:08:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/self-study-in-july-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post</p>

<h2>Clojure made simple</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VSdnJDO-xdg">this talk</a> by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy">Easy made simple</a></p>

<ul>
<li>polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter</li>
</ul>


<h2>Productive pair programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/07/productive-pair-programming/">this article</a> about pair programming, using the driver &amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Building Automated REST APIs with Python</h2>

<p>Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jeffknupp/building-automated-rest-apis-with-python">these slides</a> about it</p>

<h2>Backwards Compatibility Testing For Your Clojure Project</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jenkster.com/2014/02/backwards-compatibility-testing-your-clojure-project.html">this article</a> on making leiningen test the application on several clojure versions. Written by Kris Jenkins.</p>

<h2>Succeeding with Automated Integration Tests</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://jeremydmiller.com/2015/06/25/succeeding_with_integration_testing/">this article</a> by Jeremy Miller on integration testing and how to succeed with it. Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Choose the Quickest, Useful Feedback Mechanism, even if that means testing the backend and frontend separately</li>
<li>Prefer white-box than black-box testing</li>
<li>Use quick tests, that can be run locally in an easy fashion</li>
<li>Do not share databases, as they introduce risks of flaky tests</li>
</ul>


<h2>Applied DDD in a Java EE 7 and Open Source World</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9D_-7E7Mrzw">this video</a> by Edson Yanaga in the Java One, about DDD using Java EE 7, JSFs and lambdas on top of glassfish</p>

<h2>Integrated tests are a scam</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read, again, <a href="http://blog.thecodewhisperer.com/2010/10/16/integrated-tests-are-a-scam/">this article</a> by J. B. Rainsberger on integrated tests and why not to use them. From a numerical / combinatorics point of view.</p>

<h2>Functional Programming should be your #1 priority for 2015</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@jugoncalves/functional-programming-should-be-your-1-priority-for-2015-47dd4641d6b9">this introduction</a> to functional programming by Ju Gonçalves. Explains some functional concepts, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>First-Class Functions</li>
<li>High-Order Functions</li>
<li>Pure Functions</li>
<li>Closures</li>
<li>Immutable State</li>
</ul>


<p>Also recommends a few books on the subject (e.g., SICP, HTDP).</p>

<h2>A Tutorial Introduction to the Lambda Calculus</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.inf.fu-berlin.de/lehre/WS03/alpi/lambda.pdf">this paper</a>, an introduction to the lambda calculus. Haven&rsquo;t done the exercises. Written by Raúl Rojas</p>

<h2>20 common mistakes when doing Test-Driven Development</h2>

<p>I had thought of converting all of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=svpino%20%23tdd%20mistake&amp;src=typd">his tweets</a> into a blog post, but he has already done this for us: I&rsquo;ve read a <a href="https://blog.svpino.com/2015/05/29/20-common-mistakes-when-doing-test-driven-development">list of common mistakes</a> when doing TDD by <a href="https://twitter.com/svpino">Santiago Pino</a></p>

<h2>Reducing coupling</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the article by Martin Fowler <a href="http://martinfowler.com/ieeeSoftware/coupling.pdf">Reducing Coupling</a> in the IEEE SOFTWARE July/August 2001</p>

<h2>Comparing Java Mock Frameworks – Part 2: Creating Mock Objects</h2>

<p><a href="https://softwareinabottle.wordpress.com/2010/10/06/comparing-java-mock-frameworks-part-2-creating-mock-objects/">List of mock frameworks for java</a>. Have only read the jMock, mockito and jMockit part.</p>

<h2> Software Craftsmanship book review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://meaganwaller.com/software-craftsmanship-book-review/">this review</a> for a book that is already pending in my book list: Software Craftsmanship by Pete McBreen.</p>

<p>The review has been written by Megan Waller, an (ex-)apprentice at 8th Light.</p>

<h2>Fundamental concepts in programming languages</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~crary/819-f09/Strachey67.pdf">this paper</a> containing the contents for lectures in Computer Programming in the year 1967. Written by Christopher Strachey.</p>

<p>Note: I&rsquo;ve also seen this paper recommended in the repo <a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love/tree/master/plt">Papers We Love > plt</a> (Programming Language Theory)</p>

<h2>What is reification?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.angelikalanger.com/GenericsFAQ/FAQSections/TechnicalDetails.html#FAQ101A">this FAQ</a> on reification by Angelika Langer</p>

<h2>Type erasure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wikipedia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_erasure">page on type erasure</a></p>

<h2>How to make an IntelliJ IDEA plugin in less than 30 minutes</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://bjorn.tipling.com/how-to-make-an-intellij-idea-plugin-in-30-minutes">this article</a> on creating new IntelliJ IDEA plugin, by Bjorn Tipling</p>

<h2>How to Write Clean, Testable Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched, again, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XcT4yYu_TTs">this video</a> by Miško Hevery. Discusses what are the characteristics of tested and untested code, how to get from one to the other. Discusses techniques for testing code. At the end, there are questions but they cannot be heard (lack of microphone), so it is harder to follow.</p>

<h2>How to Find a Mentor</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/letters-to-my-mother/how-to-find-a-mentor-27fb978a8f1">this opinion</a> on the importance of role models and mentors. The difference between them and a personal experience. Written by Joanne Wilson</p>

<h2>Type theory</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wiki page on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_theory">type theory</a></p>

<p>Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;type systems [&hellip;] language feature used to reduce bugs&rdquo;</li>
<li>two types: Church&rsquo;s typed λ-calculi and Martin-Löf&rsquo;s intuitionistic type theory.</li>
<li>notation:

<ul>
<li>typing judgement: <code>M : A</code>. Term <code>M</code> has type <code>A</code></li>
<li>example: <code>nat</code> may be a type</li>
<li><code>2 : nat</code>, like in Scala</li>
<li>function: &ldquo;arrow&rdquo;</li>
<li>apply function to argument: no parenthesis</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>conversion rule: rule for rewriting terms

<ul>
<li>reduction rule: conversion rule that only works in one direction</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>normal form: a form that cannot be further reduced</li>
<li>element: all closed elements that can be reduced to the same normal form</li>
<li>closed term: a term without parameters. Opposite is an open term</li>
<li>convertibility: property of terms, both open and closed. Said to be convertible if two terms can be reduced to the same term

<ul>
<li>warning: x + 1 and 1 + x are not convertible because they are in normal form and not the same</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Type system</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wiki page on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_system">type system</a></p>

<p>Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;The depth of type constraints and the manner of their evaluation affect the typing of the language&rdquo;</li>
<li>Type polymorphism</li>
<li>{compile time, runtime} x {manually annotated, inferred}</li>
<li>&ldquo;A program associates each value with at least one particular type, but it also can occur that one value is associated with many subtypes.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Classification of types:

<ul>
<li>data type – a type of a value</li>
<li>class – a type of an object</li>
<li>kind – a type of a type, or metatype</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>the type inference might be undecidable (for more complex type inference)</li>
<li>&ldquo;Strong typing offers more safety, but cannot guarantee complete type safety.&rdquo; An example is the division by zero, altough some languages may declare a dependent type &ldquo;non-zero numbers&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h2>The 3 things you should know about hashCode()</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://eclipsesource.com/blogs/2012/09/04/the-3-things-you-should-know-about-hashcode/">this article</a> on the hashCode() method in java, written by Ralf Sternberg.</p>

<h2>Reduce Complexity with Variants</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/reduce-complexity-with-variants">this article</a> on variants in clojure by Eric Normand</p>

<h2>What is new in SQL:2011</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.sigmod.org/publications/sigmod-record/1203/pdfs/10.industry.zemke.pdf">this white paper</a> on the new features in SQL 2011. Written by Fred Zemke</p>

<h2>5 Error Tracking Tools Java Developers Should Know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javacodegeeks.com/2014/09/5-error-tracking-tools-java-developers-should-know.html">this article</a> about tracking tools for java written by Alex Zhitnitsky, featuring:</p>

<ul>
<li>Raygun</li>
<li>Sentry</li>
<li>Takipi</li>
<li>Airbrake</li>
<li>StackHunter</li>
<li>[Bonus] ABRT</li>
<li>Comments cite <a href="http://squash.io">Squash</a> (server written in ruby, java client available) and <a href="http://rollbar.com">Rollbar</a> (home says supports android but not says anything about java)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Data clump</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DataClump.html">this article</a> on the bliki, by Martin Fowler</p>

<h2>NP-Complete problems</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://webdiis.unizar.es/asignaturas/TC/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/L15_NPcompletos.pdf">these slides</a> by Prof. Elvira Mayordomo about NP-Complete problems, how to reduce them to other problems and practical applications. (In Spanish)</p>

<h2>Removal of sun.misc.Unsafe in Java 9 - A disaster in the making</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.dripstat.com/removal-of-sun-misc-unsafe-a-disaster-in-the-making/">this article</a> about the removal of this Unsafe class in Java 9, by the DripStat team</p>

<h2>How To Write Directly to a Memory Locations In Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://robaustin.wikidot.com/how-to-write-to-direct-memory-locations-in-java">this guide</a> on how to write directly to a memory position in java, by Rob Austin</p>

<h2>Interesting uses of sun.misc.Unsafe</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://bytescrolls.blogspot.com.es/2011/04/interesting-uses-of-sunmiscunsafe.html">this article</a> by Haris A.L.</p>

<h2>Introduction to the theory of np-completeness</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.site.uottawa.ca/~lucia/courses/4105-02/np.pdf">these notes / slides</a> to the introductory course of NP-completeness, by Prof Lucia Moura</p>

<h2>JS Code Kata: Linked List</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/yitznewton/js-code-kata-linked-list">these slides</a> on the kata linked list, by Yitz Schaffer. The slide #13 talks about the transformations:</p>

<ul>
<li>refactor: change form without changing behavior</li>
<li>transform: change behavior while changing form as little as possible</li>
</ul>


<p>Also about the Transformation Priority Premise (TPP) (also in this month)</p>

<h2>The Transformation Priority Premise</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read, again, <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2013/05/27/TheTransformationPriorityPremise.html">this article</a> by Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)</p>

<h2>Data structures</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the wiki page for</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SPQR_tree">SPQR tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_search_tree">BSR tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red%E2%80%93black_tree">Red black tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judy_array">Judy array</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Also, The <a href="http://bigocheatsheet.com/">Big-O notation complexity cheatsheet</a></p>

<h2>On benchmarks: Numbers every programmer should know and their impact on benchmarks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hype-free.blogspot.com/2014/03/on-benchmarks.html">this post</a> on doing back-of-the-envelope calculations on publicly available benchmarks, written by Attila-Mihaly Balazs</p>

<h2>Top Java IDE Keyboard Shortcuts for Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA &amp; NetBeans</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/top-java-ide-keyboard-shortcuts-for-eclipse-intellij-idea-netbeans/">these slides</a> on the topic of keyboard shortcuts for java IDEs, written by Oleg Šelajev</p>

<h2>The hacker’s summer training guide – part 1</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.paymill.com/hackers-training-guide-1">this post</a> by Paymill, that suggests which new languages to learn this summer: rust, go, elixir, ocaml, scala, livescript.</p>

<h2>Applications built extremely right</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://apiumtech.com/blog/applications-build-with-outsourcing/">this post</a> with a list of candidates for building nice products, written by Xavi Hidalgo.</p>

<h2>Agile project seed. Infrastructure by default.</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://apiumtech.com/blog/seed-de-proyecto-agile-infraestructura-por-defecto/">this post</a> on an agile seed project. Reminded me of the 12-factor app</p>

<h2>What an agile developer should know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.apiumtech.com/blog/lo-que-un-desarrollador-agile-deberia-saber/">this post</a> by Xavi Hidalgo</p>

<h2>Bad Apples that can destroy a team</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve listened to <a href="http://www.scrum-master-toolbox.com/2015/03/podcast/dominic-krimmer-describes-the-types-of-bad-apples-that-can-destroy-a-team/">this podcast</a> about the bad apples in a team. Presented by Vasco Duarte and Dominic Krimmer as the main speaker</p>

<h2>How Scala compares with 20 other programming languages according to Reddit analysis</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.typesafe.com/blog/how-scala-compares-20-programming-languages-reddit-analysis">this analysis</a> of the language comparison, written by Oliver White</p>

<h2>Javascript patterns book review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2047-javascript-patterns-by-stoyan-stefanov.htm">this review</a> by Ben Nadel on the book Javascript Patterns, by Stoyan Stefanov</p>

<h2>Monogamous TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/04/25/MonogamousTDD.html">this article</a> on the fundamentalism of TDD, written by Robert C Martin</p>

<h2>Encapsulating LocalStorage Access In AngularJS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2861-encapsulating-localstorage-access-in-angularjs.htm">this article</a> on why encapsulate the access to the localStorage, written by Ben Nadel</p>

<h2>Anatomy of a zero-knowledge web application</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://clipperz.is/blog/2007/08/24/anatomy_zero_knowledge_web_application/">this article</a> on a zero-knowledge web application, by the clipperz team</p>

<h2>Refactorización de Código Legado Clase Maestra</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VBgCKKevhyI">this video</a> about refactoring a legacy code in C#, by Danijel Arsenovski</p>

<h2>Taming Javaagents</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/shelajev/taming-javaagents-bcn-jug-2015">these slides</a>, again, from a conference I went to a few months ago about java agents. Written by Oleg Šelajev.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/shelajev/ResourceLeakAgent">This</a> is the repository containing the memory leak agent he talks about</p>

<h2>Mathematics for Computer Science, Lecture 1</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched by <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/math_for_comp_science_mit/lessons/Lecture1/">the first recitation</a> in <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/math_for_comp_science_mit/index.php">this course</a>, offered by MIT Open Course Ware (OCW). Recited by Tom Leighton</p>

<h2>Programming Abstractions: Lecture 7</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/programming_abstractions_stanford/lessons/Lecture7/">this lecture</a> by Julie Zelensky about the comparison operator, recursion and a live coding session calculating the most ocurring anagram word in a file.</p>

<p>She uses small outputs to check the correctness of her programs to get short feedback cycles, even if they are manual.</p>

<h2>5 Ways To Launch a JMeter Test without Using the JMeter GUI</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blazemeter.com/blog/5-ways-launch-jmeter-test-without-using-jmeter-gui">this guide</a> on using jmeter without a GUI, by Dmitri Tikhanski</p>

<h2>Clojure unraveled, chapter 5</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the <a href="http://funcool.github.io/clojurescript-unraveled/#language-advanced-topics">fifth chapter</a>, on the topics of Transducers, Transients, Metadata, Macros, Core protocols. Written by Andrey Antukh and Alejandro Gómez</p>

<h2>A guide to the Basics of Data Structures</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/data-structures-basics/">this guide</a> to data structures, covering the stack, the queue, the heap, the tree and the hashmap. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>Government Abandonware</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://techblog.bozho.net/government-abandonware/">this post</a> on abandoned, public software that is not opensource. Dubbed by the author as &ldquo;Government Abandonware&rdquo;. Written by Bozhidar Bozhanov</p>

<h2>The Art of Incremental Stream Processing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mth.io/talks/streams/">these slides</a> on incremental stream processing. The examples are in haskell and scala. Written by Mark Hibberd</p>

<h2>Reader as Link Author</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hapgood.us/2015/07/22/follow-up-reader-as-link-author/">this insight</a> into federated wikis by Mike Caulfield</p>

<h2>Kafkapocalypse: a postmortem on our service outage</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.parsely.com/post/1738/kafkapocalypse/">this post-mortem analysis</a> of the service outage at parse.ly, by Andrew Montalenti</p>

<h2>Loving a Log-Oriented Architecture</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.parsely.com/post/1550/kreps-logs/">this post</a> on experiences using the log-based architecture, by Andrew Montalenti. Cites the books <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Logs-Stream-Processing-Integration/dp/1491909382">I Heart Logs</a>,  and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290343">Big Data: Principles and best practices of scalable realtime data systems</a> the essay <a href="http://engineering.linkedin.com/distributed-systems/log-what-every-software-engineer-should-know-about-real-time-datas-unifying">The Log</a></p>

<h2>A guide to Algorithmic Complexity</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/algorithmic-complexity">this guide</a> to algorithmic complexity, explaining Big-Oh notation (Big-Oh, Big-Theta, Big-Omega), with examples. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>A guide to Recursion</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/recursion">this guide</a> to recursion explaining the gist of it. Examples include the Fibonacci sequence and the Hanoi Towers problem. Later, an introduction to the chaos theory and fractals. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>Bootstrapped ClojureScript FAQ</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/clojure/clojurescript/wiki/Bootstrapped-ClojureScript-FAQ">this FAQ</a> related to bootstrapping clojurescript</p>

<h2>Applying property-based testing on my binary search tree implementation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://garajeando.blogspot.com/2015/07/applying-property-based-testing-on-my.html">this article</a>, written by Manuel Rivero, on applying test-check (a property-based testing framework, similar to quickcheck) to a Binary Search Tree (BST) he did.</p>

<h2>Do Extraterrestrials Use Functional Programming?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://yowconference.com.au/slides/yowlambdajam2013/Chakravarty-Extraterrestrials-Keynote.pdf">these slides</a>, an introduction to lambda calculus, the Turing machine and the Halting Problem. Later, continues to describe ways of solving problems in a functional way. Also performance and optimizations; monads as well. Written by Manuel M T Chakravarty</p>

<h2>WIP Limits</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://theagileist.wordpress.com/2015/06/15/wip-limits/">this post</a> by Tomas Rybing</p>

<h2>Applied capacity planning</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://theagileist.wordpress.com/2015/07/27/applied-capacity-planning/">this post</a> by Tomas Rybing.</p>

<h2>Don’t Get Attached to Programming Languages</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mikecavaliere.com/dont-get-attached-programming-languages">this post</a> by Mike Cavaliere</p>

<h2>The Top 5 Skills of Rock Star Software Engineers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://softwareplusplus.com/2015/06/24/the-top-5-skills-of-rock-star-software-engineers/">this post</a> by Cory Berg</p>

<h2>5 Reasons to Use Protocol Buffers Instead of JSON For Your Next Service</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codeclimate.com/blog/2014/06/05/choose-protocol-buffers/">this article</a> on Protocol Buffers, written by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Data Serialization Formats</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://gist.github.com/joshsz/11299196">this comparison</a> between MsgPack, JSON, Protocol Buffers, by Josh Szmajda.</p>

<h2>Protocol Buffer Basics: Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/javatutorial">this introduction</a> to Protocol Buffers in Java, by Google</p>

<h2>RESTful Considered Harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/restful-considered-harmful?oid=top_title">this article</a>, commenting downsides to using JSON / RESTful APIs, written by Tomasz Nurkiewicz</p>

<h2>“Considered Harmful” Essays Considered Harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://meyerweb.com/eric/comment/chech.html">this post</a>, by Eric Meyer, on why &ldquo;Considered Harmful&rdquo; are harmful as well.</p>

<h2>Keep Lambdas Cohesive</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.agiledeveloper.com/2015/07/keep-lambdas-cohesive.html">this post</a> with recommendations on keeping the java lambdas cohesive. Written by Venkat Subramaniam</p>

<h2>The Joy of Flying Robots with Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty9QDqV-_Ak">this video</a> by Carin Meier at the OSCON 2013 about communicating with robots in Clojure</p>

<h2>How to Learn TDD Without Getting Overwhelmed</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.justinweiss.com/blog/2014/06/02/how-to-learn-tdd-without-getting-overwhelmed/">this article</a> on learning TDD, by Justin Weiss</p>

<h2>Kata - the Only Way to Learn TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.peterprovost.org/blog/2012/05/02/kata-the-only-way-to-learn-tdd/">this article</a> on learning TDD, by Peter Provost</p>

<h2>Koan: Past Perfect</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thecodelesscode.com/case/180">this koan</a>, past perfect, reflecting on the people who prefer the past over the present. Who think that the past was simpler than currently is.</p>

<h2>Koan: Future Imperfect</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thecodelesscode.com/case/181">this koan</a>, continuation from past perfect.</p>

<h2>Why “Agile” and especially Scrum are terrible</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://michaelochurch.wordpress.com/2015/06/06/why-agile-and-especially-scrum-are-terrible/">this article</a> on downsides of Agile and Scrum, written by Michael Church.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience Report: Test-driven Development Intensive, by Jason Gorman]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-12T18:13:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an experience report on <a href="http://twitter.com/@jasongorman">Jason Gorman</a>&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.codemanship.co.uk/tdd.html">Test-driven development intensive workshop</a>&rdquo; on the April 11th, 2015</p>

<p>I attended this training in the <a href="http://www.grenfell-housing.co.uk/">Greenfell housing &amp; training</a> in South Wimbledon, London SW19 1JZ. The training spanned from 10:00 to 17:00 with a half an hour for lunch plus three or four 10-15 minute pauses. (7 - ,5 - 4 * 12/60 = ~5.7hours = 5 hours 45 minutes)</p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>There were 23 of us, including me. We spent some half hour introducing ourselves before the training started. I remember about a tester that came to the workshop &ldquo;wanting to know more about this testing methodology&rdquo;. Jason&rsquo;s answer was priceless: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry but you came to the wrong place: this is not about testing&rdquo;.
</p>

<p>At 10:00 sharp, he started a set of slides explaining what TDD is about, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>productivity:

<ul>
<li>no company is willing to give you a &ldquo;get out of jail free&rdquo; card to get out of the productivity zone</li>
<li>a drop in the productivity, at least for the first weeks</li>
<li>you have to find a time slot in your schedule to practice TDD, otherwise it&rsquo;s like learning to swim while crossing the Atlantic Ocean</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You have to feel uncomfortable not doing TDD</li>
<li>triangulation:

<ul>
<li>how each problem is different</li>
<li>you can only learn it by doing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>TDD styles:

<ul>
<li>Chicago style by Kent Beck. Reference book would be &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">TDD by example</a>&rdquo;</li>
<li>London school or Mockist style by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce. Reference book would be <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">&ldquo;Growing object oriented software, guided by tests</a>"</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>13 good habits for a sustainable test-driven development way</li>
<li>The basic TDD cycle:

<ul>
<li>an executable specification, encoded in a failing test</li>
<li>pass the test in the simplest way</li>
<li>refactor</li>
<li>(talking with another attendee, he described to me a new TDD phase called redesign. Maybe another post will explain this in deeper detail level)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Some ideas about <a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org/rules/simple.html">Simple design, simple development, simplicity</a> (<a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org">XP</a>)</li>
<li>Shown a wrong example of mixing assertions (state) and verifications (interactions)</li>
<li>More than one reason to go wrong makes the code non-trivial anymore. Non-trivial code requires tests</li>
<li>You want to see the test failing for the right reason: remove / finish code that does not compile, fix null pointers, array out of bounds exceptions, etc. See it fail with &ldquo;was <X> but expected <Y>&rdquo; or &ldquo;NoInteractionException&rdquo; (hamcrest error and mockito error, respectively; both java)</li>
<li>Duplication as a sign of design smell</li>
<li>Process of generalizing code: discover the need for patterns</li>
<li>The most difficult skill in TDD is refactoring [and design; note is mine]. The TDD cycle is very easy.

<ul>
<li>TDD is much more in demand than refactoring, even though the former includes the latter</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Refactor until you&rsquo;re happy with the code, until you stand by it</li>
</ul>


<h2>CRC Cards</h2>

<p>A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class-responsibility-collaboration_card">Class-responsibility-collaboration card</a> is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>top: class name</li>
<li>half left: responsibilities</li>
<li>half right: collaborations</li>
</ul>


<p>Notes from the slides:</p>

<ul>
<li>each then is an outcome

<ul>
<li>do not mix outcomes and implications. An example: after winning the lottery, the money should be transferred to my bank account and I can buy a yacht. The former is an outcome (change in state) and the latter an implication (a new action that is now enabled)</li>
<li>an outcome is mapped to an assertion, while a collaboration is mapped to an interaction (verify in mockito)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Given / When / Then is not enough to implement an executable specification. We need examples, detail</li>
<li>OO: send messages to distribute responsibility.

<ul>
<li>A Then is an unique responsibility</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Topmost object: no one connects with it</li>
<li>Put the work where the data is</li>
<li>Tell, don&rsquo;t ask <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> vs data driven design (tell a collaborator what to do vs ask for values and do the work yourself)</li>
<li>You want as few interactions as possible (related to the tell, don&rsquo;t ask)</li>
<li>More objects than outcomes is a bad thing (design smell) (?)</li>
<li>CRC is a very mechanical exercise, do not over think it</li>
<li>Describe outcomes as changes in OO (new, destroy, relationships, modify fields / state)</li>
<li>Continuous integration is not necessarily about shipping the code at each commit but having it shippable at each commit, as always having a product that is ready for its production phase</li>
</ul>


<h2>Exercises</h2>

<p>All exercises were done in pairs, always switching one half of the pair. He asked for someone in the pair to raise, especially if you were not a programmer (e.g., tester, manager)</p>

<h3>First exercise: Banking</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of transferring money from an account to another</p></blockquote>

<p>A chance to practice arrange, act, assert</p>

<p>Later, he did it some live coding to develop the same kata, practicing &ldquo;<a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/TDD-as-if-You-Meant-It">TDD as if you meant it</a>&rdquo; (<a href="https://twitter.com/keithb_b">Keith Braithwaite</a>&rsquo;s original idea). We discovered together the &ldquo;primitive obsession&rdquo; and &ldquo;feature envy&rdquo; smells. We tried doing as few decisions as possible.</p>

<h3>Second exercise: Fibonacci sequence generator</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of generating Fibonacci sequences, no shorter that 8 and no longer than 50</p></blockquote>

<p>A chance to practice baby steps.</p>

<p>My pair and I had the chance of discovering the importance of understanding correctly the requirements before writing a line of code. Also, I learned about the different ways of doing TDD. In this case, my pair executed the tests via a main (java class) and saw the failures on the console. When proposed to do it in the JUnit runner the IDE has, he said he preferred it in his own ways.</p>

<p>Jason did some live coding to show how he approached and triangulated this exercise.</p>

<p>I really liked some of what he said: I like to make the API correct from the first moment so I will ask questions that are correct but only check answers for things that I have already implemented. Example:</p>

<p>As the generated sequence can only have <code>8 &lt;= x &lt;= 50</code> elements, a list returning a single element would not be correct. So</p>

<pre><code class="java">//class FibonacciTests
@Test
public void theFirstElementIsOne(){
    assertThat(new FibonacciSequence().generate(8)[0], is(1));
}
</code></pre>

<h3>Third exercise: FizzBuzz</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of returning a string with all numbers less than 100 that are using the FizzBuzz pattern. This FizzBuzz pattern converts the divisors of 3 to &lsquo;fizz&rsquo;, divisors of 5 to &lsquo;buzz&rsquo; and divisors to both to &lsquo;fizzbuzz&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>I discovered that this FizzBuzz is a drinking game in the UK.</p>

<h3>Fourth exercise: CRC cards</h3>

<p>Before this exercise there was a short introduction on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class-responsibility-collaboration_card">Class-responsibility-collaboration card</a>, explained above</p>

<p>Following an example about a movie library, there were six user stories, described at high level, without acceptance criteria.</p>

<p>We had to create an acceptance criteria for this user story. Later create a set of CRC cards and finally partially implement said feature.</p>

<p>Very interesting exercise, such a pity that there wasn&rsquo;t more time to complete this exercise or see him doing it</p>

<h2>Knowledge pearls</h2>

<p>He dropped some knowledge pearls (that I&rsquo;m going to use myself):</p>

<pre><code>Q: When are you done with TDD?
A: When you can not think of more tests for your suite
</code></pre>

<pre><code>Q: What do we do after TDD?
A: (No answer)
Q: Starts with "T". Any idea?
A: Testing. Test for the purpose of testing, not TDD
</code></pre>

<p>Close concepts interested in responsibilities:</p>

<ul>
<li>Conceptual diagram and class diagram</li>
<li>Instance diagram</li>
<li>Knowledge map and tag cloud</li>
</ul>


<p>Regarding legacy code:</p>

<ul>
<li>Isolate big balls of mud into parts and test these as end-to-end. Also connected to isolating groups of nodes into the class graph</li>
<li>Understand what the code does, not the architecture</li>
<li>Do not use a mock to help you test legacy code, use it just as a design tool. (It might be a good idea to use it temporarily while you refactor, but remove it afterwards)</li>
<li>Tests with mocks double down on the design: if it is broken, it will be a drag more than help</li>
</ul>


<p>Test on the boundaries. Many times we test in the middle of the algorithm but forget the boundaries, where many special cases hide</p>

<p>The GOOS book is pronounced like the goose animal (&ldquo;/gús/&rdquo;) in English</p>

<p>He said he never copy pastes <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<ul>
<li>This is a two day workshop condensed on a single day. It shows. In my opinion, it would be better to do fewer exercises and dig deeper in them rather than try so many approaches / exercises</li>
<li>The CRC exercise was well thought and really massaged. It touches the right spots and makes you want to learn more about the subject</li>
<li>Promiscuously pairing is always a good idea, as you don&rsquo;t know what level have your attendees. Get stuck for the whole day with someone who has a (very) different knowledge level than you might spoil the workshop</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t see the benefit of doing the fizzbuzz kata after having done the Fibonacci sequence one</li>
<li>In my opinion, there were too many breaks. Doing a break in the morning (10-15 mins), lunch (30 mins) and afternoon (10-15 mins) is enough</li>
</ul>


<p>On a personal note:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is not enough to attend the workshop. You have to take notes and study them at home later. (Thanks <a href="http://spines.me">spines</a> for this lesson)</li>
<li>I really had a great time, learned a lot, even though I already know something about TDD</li>
<li>Met very interesting people</li>
<li>Would attend to the workshop again</li>
</ul>


<p>In general, I&rsquo;d like to thank Jason and the other attendees for making this workshop possible. I had a blast there.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>As described by <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TellDontAsk.html">Martin Fowler</a> and the <a href="https://pragprog.com/articles/tell-dont-ask">Pragmatic Bookshelf</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Copy pasting this post&rsquo;s structure resulted in a wrong title that had to be fixed. Maybe the extra effort of not copy pasting has a good ROI, as long as you do not copy paste by typing the text you&rsquo;re reading from somewhere else<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kata: Mars Rover in Clojure]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/04/kata-mars-rover-in-clojure/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-04T23:33:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/04/kata-mars-rover-in-clojure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday at the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/220773795/">clojure meetup</a> we<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> did the <a href="http://dallashackclub.com/rover">mars rover</a> in clojure and today I&rsquo;ve tried my hand at it again. Original, from the three of us <a href="https://github.com/jesusdiez/kata-rover-clojure">here</a> and my <a href="https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/kata-rover-clojure">results here</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/jorgeavila_ss">Jorge Ávila</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/jdiezc">Jesús Díez</a> and I<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mob Programming String Calculator Kata]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-03T03:46:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/03/mob-programming-string-calculator-kata</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we did a kata<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> using a projector the string calculator <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> using pair programming, TDD and some mob-programming for the last refactoring.</p>

<p>We used a projector (beamer) so everyone could see it. I tried to take really small baby steps but the adding part was done in ~6 cycles<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve all learnt about shotcuts, live user templates for the IDE <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>, TDD methodology, other ways of tackling the problem, how to refactor as a group, clean code, etc</p>

<p>These sessions are necessary to share some knowledge among the teammates and have another chance of doing code review, releasing some pressure from daily practices or bad abstractions / designs (that will be taken care of in the future)</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had such a great time, learning together, that would be a candidate for a weekly interaction.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mob_programming">Mob programming</a> is such an eye opening practice. It forces you to reconsider your previous dogma and to understand the others' positions. Wikipedia reads &ldquo;early use of phrase [&hellip;] was made in &lsquo;Extreme Programming Perspectives&rsquo;&rdquo; but this practice is practiced by some, such as <a href="https://twitter.com/carlosble">Carlos Blé</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sandromancuso">Sandro Mancuso</a> among others; also at the <a href="http://www.softwarecraftsmanshipbarcelona.org/">Software Craftsmanship Barcelona</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/scbcn2013?src=hash">2013</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SCBCN14?src=hash">2014</a> and the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/socracan?src=hash">SoCra Canaries 2015</a></p>

<h2>One goal</h2>

<p>Our goal for this session was to practice TDD and baby steps, so the team can improve its ability on these skills.</p>

<p>In any case, my objective for the katas (or deliberate practice) is not to get there as fast as we can but to improve our automated routines. This can affect our daily performance, as it becomes natural. It is not about the getting to the destination but enjoying the path along the way. In this manner, you are not so hurried up about a slow train but enjoy the views across the window.</p>

<p>It was good that QA people in the team came to the session. He even participated with some tips / implementations during the refactors. Always fruitful to discuss (and learn) mixed skills (QA / dev) from the other side of the wall</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I still haven&rsquo;t mastered the recipe (algorithm) for knowing when it is a scaffold and when it&rsquo;s time to refactor using &ldquo;replace algorithm&rdquo;. For know, I just use the three (3) rule and a bit of gut feeling on the side. The bad thing is that this can not be easily taught to someone else. Just learnt by osmosis and practice.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>matching none of the styles explained in <a href="http://johannesbrodwall.com/2011/12/18/how-to-start-a-coding-dojo/">here</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>This is a very good beginner&rsquo;s kata, created by <a href="https://twitter.com/royosherove">Roy Osherove</a>. Can be found <a href="http://osherove.com/tdd-kata-1/">here</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>One piece of feedback I received is that I talk too much while coding, as these 6 cycles took us about 45 minutes, total<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>There are some for <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/help/live-templates.html">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4022367/what-is-the-eclipse-equivalent-of-intellij-live-templates">Eclipse</a> too<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
