<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>analogy on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/analogy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in analogy on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/analogy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/01/self-study-september-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/01/self-study-september-2019/</guid>
      <description>Profiling Memory Allocations In iOS With Instruments Describes a technique for profiling memory allocations
Tags: memory-management, memory-allocation, tool, technique, ios, matt-eaton
Id: 237dd71a-dc50-11e9-b201-0242ac110003 Read: Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:13:56 +0000
Programming as translation  Converting the real world into digital abstractions requires distillation. And, like literary translators, developers must understand their biases.
 Tags: alvaro-videla, old_sound, analogy, metaphor, quote, umberto-eco
Id: a2c0f458-dc50-11e9-95d7-0242ac110003 Read: Sat, 21 Sep 2019 09:17:29 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>How I ended up paying $150 for a single 60GB download from Amazon Glacier I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Marko Karppinen that explains how a mistake in understanding the pricing model of AWS Glacier cost 150$ instead of the expected 0.86$
 When cloud providers use uncommon and/or unpredictable pricing models, even your informed hunch about the cost can be off by several orders of magnitude, like the price differential between an iPad and a Ferrari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftsmanship analogy</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/27/craftsmanship-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 00:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/27/craftsmanship-analogy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve found this set of tweets about the craftsmanship analogy by Sarah Mei:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: Chapter 4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/26/practical-object-oriented-design-in-ruby-chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 22:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/26/practical-object-oriented-design-in-ruby-chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve read the fourth chapter from the Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby, by Sandi Metz.
These are the concepts and links brought up during the discussion:
 The craftsmanship analogy, as exposed in these tweets Difference between function and method What vs How (also present in the GOOS)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in July 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post
Clojure made simple I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk Easy made simple
 polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter  Productive pair programming I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about pair programming, using the driver &amp;amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé
Building Automated REST APIs with Python Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: Software is eating the world</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 21:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Erik Meijer
My notes   Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly
  The hacker way
 code always wins vs manager always wins source: http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter/    we&amp;rsquo;re doing maths =&amp;gt; we&amp;rsquo;re building a proof
  reinforcement learning
 agent is the company    related to &amp;ldquo;build, measure, learn&amp;rdquo; by Eric Ries (the lean startup)
  Feedback systems  Open (no) feedback system, such as timed sprinklers Closed feedback system Output only system  Why everything is software  Examples of everything is software Software is eating the world Even hardware is modeled as software  Modeling as a Finite State Machine (FSM)  There&amp;rsquo;s memory in the feedback loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian of the Source</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/the-guardian-of-the-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 22:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/17/the-guardian-of-the-source/</guid>
      <description>Overheard today at the office, while they were discussing the approval of a pull request:
 [Pull request reviewer] - I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, can&amp;rsquo;t approve this: I don&amp;rsquo;t really agree with this design. Isn&amp;rsquo;t there an alternative for this?
[Pull request author] - [redacted], of course you don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;re the guardian of the source
[PR reviewer] - Well, sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m a bit picky about introducing bad code into our codebase.
 This has made me think about Gandalf blocking the path of Balrog Demon, shouting &amp;ldquo;[you shall not pass][you-shall-not-pass-meme]&amp;rdquo; while on top of the bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
