<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>talk on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in talk on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>Advice for white men I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cate Huston about how advice affects different people.
 But here are some things to consider:
 Advice on failure is different for people who are judged on performance rather than potential. Advice on saying no is different for people who aren’t appreciated for doing work for the collective… but who are punished if they don’t. Advice on negotiation is different for people who are perceived negatively when they do negotiate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: Software is eating the world</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 21:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Erik Meijer
My notes   Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly
  The hacker way
 code always wins vs manager always wins source: http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter/    we&amp;rsquo;re doing maths =&amp;gt; we&amp;rsquo;re building a proof
  reinforcement learning
 agent is the company    related to &amp;ldquo;build, measure, learn&amp;rdquo; by Eric Ries (the lean startup)
  Feedback systems  Open (no) feedback system, such as timed sprinklers Closed feedback system Output only system  Why everything is software  Examples of everything is software Software is eating the world Even hardware is modeled as software  Modeling as a Finite State Machine (FSM)  There&amp;rsquo;s memory in the feedback loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in May 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015 into a single post
Programmer passion considered harmful I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.
Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by Ken Auer
Improve your development environments with virtualization I have seen this video: Improve your development environments with virtualization by Luke Sneeringer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Nothing is something</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 07:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/</guid>
      <description>I have seen this video: [Nothing is something][video] by [Sandi Metz][sandimetz], as I saw it recommended [here][recommendation]
In the video, she talks programming in this fashion: (it is a stack, not an unordered list)
 Abstraction seeking Message centric Condition Averse Smalltalk Infected   Not here to change the language but change you
 This is a pattern I&amp;rsquo;ve also heard from [Alvaro Videla][old_sound], where he said that other, more powerful languages can change your mind and help you bring some of those concepts to your own language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: Simplicity matters</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/18/talk-simplicity-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 14:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/18/talk-simplicity-matters/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this video by Rich Hickey: &amp;ldquo;Simplicity matters&amp;rdquo;, taken from Manuel Rivero&amp;rsquo;s google plus&#39; site
here are my notes:
 the software is the elephant do more, do it differently, do it better complexity of the elephant is going to dominate what you can do your ability to reason about your program is critical design is about pulling things apart become familiar by learning, trying &amp;ldquo;We can be creating the exact same programs out of significantly simpler components&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: &#39;Is TDD Dead? Of course not! But what´s all the fuzz about then?&#39; by Emily Bache</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/talk-is-tdd-dead-of-course-not-by-emily-bache/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 15:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/talk-is-tdd-dead-of-course-not-by-emily-bache/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just seen this talk: Is TDD dead? Of course not! But what´s all the fuzz about then? by Emily Bache
My notes   deliberate vs accidental learning (around minute 19)
  do not be an evangelist for tdd but rather &amp;ldquo;come learn tdd, come at a dojo with us!&amp;rdquo;
  points to Dan North&amp;rsquo;s talk (at the same foo café)
  points to her book - The Coding Dojo Handbook</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
