<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maintenance on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/maintenance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maintenance on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/maintenance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters  In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing safe(r) bash scripts</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/13/writing-safe-bash-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 07:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/13/writing-safe-bash-scripts/</guid>
      <description>After writing more and more bash scripts for a client, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write down my thoughts about it.
This assumes you have some knowledge about bash, as it is not intended as a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial.
Why bash scripts?  Bash is present in almost every unix/linux-based stack, now some Windows as well. An exception is the &amp;lsquo;alpine&amp;rsquo; docker images, which have a smaller, lighter shell (more on that later) Everything that you can automate, you can do from bash.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
