<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>practice on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in practice on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB
Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable
Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000
Jepsen: Aerospike I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies
Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos
Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding all pending work in progress (WIP) in your workspace</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/find-all-pending-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 06:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/find-all-pending-work/</guid>
      <description>It is a good practice to push your local work at the end of the day. Be it for increasing the bus factor (more people have the code), be it for reducing the lifespan of the branches (less time without integrating) or just enabling visibility (your teammates to see what has been developed). If you&amp;rsquo;re using Continuous Integration (CI) or Continuous Delivery (CD), this is even more often
You can even do it more often: for example before going to lunch, before a meeting, before a demo, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Being A Developer After 40 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:
 Forget The Hype Choose Your Galaxy Wisely Learn About Software History Keep on Learning Teach Workplaces Suck Know Your Worth Send The Elevator Down LLVM  He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
