<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/app/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;diversitymediocrityillusion&#34;&gt;DiversityMediocrityIllusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DiversityMediocrityIllusion.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-cryptic-github-comments-mean&#34;&gt;What do cryptic Github comments mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/what-do-cryptic-github-comments-mean-9c1912bcc0a4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: github, pull-request, alex-beregszaszi, abbreviation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-erreurs-à-éviter-en-tant-que-développeur-freelance&#34;&gt;6 erreurs à éviter en tant que développeur freelance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@adrienjoly/enseignements-apr%C3%A8s-1-an-d-erreurs-en-tant-que-d%C3%A9veloppeur-freelance-916f855efd9b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (in French) by Adrien Joly on the mistakes freelancers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do when working with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrien-joly, freelance, list, mistake, french&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-methodology-s-promise-seems-to-fall-short-in-the-face-of-reality&#34;&gt;Agile Methodology’s Promise Seems To Fall Short in the Face of Reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@pagalvin/agile-methodology-s-promise-seems-to-fall-short-in-the-face-of-reality-b16d3e775dbe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on an experience by Paul Galvin on some failing agile implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: paul-galvin, agile, reality, agility, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-sharing-other-people-s-feelings-can-make-you-sick&#34;&gt;How sharing other people’s feelings can make you sick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg23030732-900-how-sharing-other-peoples-feelings-can-make-you-sick/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Emma Young on how being empathic to others can make you sick on their own illness. How illness can be socially transmitted, by loved ones or even by strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How algorithms (that display news) can affect your own well-being and how this is reduced by using compassion instead of empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borders on the difference of empathy vs compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: emma-young, empathy, compassion, feeling, team-management, vent-free-zone, sickness, illness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aws-lambda-for-beginners&#34;&gt;AWS Lambda for Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/aws-lambda-for-beginners&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mashooq Badar on an introduction to AWS Lambdas, where the basics are covered until getting a Lambda service in production. Using Python or Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mashooq-badar, serverless, aws, aws-lambda, lambda, python, java, devops, serverless-architecture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-logging-with-the-javascript-console&#34;&gt;Advanced Logging with the JavaScript Console&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://egghead.io/series/js-console-for-power-users&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this course&lt;/a&gt; by Mykola Bilokonsky at egghead.io.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, he covers the following methods on the console:&lt;/p&gt;
console.log
console.warn
console.error
console.info
console.debug

&lt;p&gt;The amount of parameters does not matter, it will put a space in between. printing an object will print its values&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;console.log with the C&amp;rsquo;s printf syntax, as long as the first parameter is a string&lt;/p&gt;
  %o for an object
  %c for CSS
console.group / groupCollapsed / groupEnd

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mykola-bilokonsky, logging, javascript, console, egghead, course&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-work-is-what-determines-your-future-spend-one-hour-per-day-doing-these-5-things-and-your-life-will-change-forever&#34;&gt;After work, is what determines your future! Spend one hour per day doing these 5 things and your life will change forever!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/after-work-what-determines-your-future-spend-one-hour-sundaram&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kalyana Sundaram on the activities we do at night, after a day&amp;rsquo;s work and how they influence our learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kalyana-sundaram, after-work, career, career-management, learning, lifelong-learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expert-resumé-driven-development&#34;&gt;Expert Resumé Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/tra/expert-resum-driven-development&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tariq Ali, where he explains the Resume-Driven Development, as a subset of the Principal-Agent Problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal (management) hires an Agent (a developer) to build a program and
allow the Agent to choose the tech stack. But the Agent&amp;rsquo;s interest (making his resumé
more impressive) can be orthogonal to the Principal&amp;rsquo;s interest (producing a great
product by using the &amp;ldquo;right tool&amp;rdquo; for the job). If the Principal allows the Agent to
do as he wish, then the Agent will do as he wishes, thereby leading to the Agent to
prosper and the Principal to suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gartner.com/technology/research/methodologies/hype-cycle.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gartner Hype Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tariq-ali, resume-driven-development, hype, cycle, hype-cycle, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resume-driven-development&#34;&gt;Resume Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2014/10/resume-driven-development.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Mike Loukides about the problem of finding a technical person based on CVs and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_the_instrument&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Law of the instrument&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] the inability of a technical team to specify what they really want
 (a developer with good programming taste and instincts), and
 instead hiring someone who has a particular skill or credential [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: law-instrument, mike-loukides, cv, career, resume-driven-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-britain-banned-mobile-apps&#34;&gt;Why Britain banned mobile apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://govinsider.asia/smart-gov/why-britain-banned-mobile-apps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with Ben Terrett, former design chief at the UK Government Digital Services (GDS), that explains why they prefer webapps rather than native (mobile) apps: it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of cost, having to maintain and update so many mobile versions, versus a single one for the webapp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also talks about user research and productagile teams inside the GDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview is written by Joshua Chambers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joshua-chambers, ben-terrett, gds, webapp, mobile-app, native-app, product-team, agile, government, uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-tech-interviews-suck-the-only-4-questions-that-matter&#34;&gt;Most Tech Interviews Suck — The Only 4 Questions That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/lightspeed-venture-partners/most-tech-interviews-suck-the-only-4-questions-that-matter-1a71181ef4d4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why the majority of technical interviews could be improved, asking four questions instead of following other practices. By Aaron Batalion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: aaron-batalion, tech-interview, hiring, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen&#34;&gt;Why Socrates UK is not just a conference for software craftsmen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codurance.com/2016/06/07/why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Giulia Mantuano on the SoCraTes UK 2016 conference, where she gave a talk on the importance of design in our environment, where we craft beautiful interfaces in our programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: socrates, socrates-uk, socrates-uk-2016, giulia-mantuano, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;360-million-reasons-to-destroy-all-passwords&#34;&gt;360 million reasons to destroy all passwords&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/360-million-reasons-to-destroy-all-passwords-9a100b2b5001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson about the insecurity of passwords, both managed by vaults (like LastPass) or remembered ones. They all are susceptible to being discovered, leaked or shared to other sites / accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author suggests to use passwordless login, which sends a link to your email account, which allows you to log in to the application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: passwordless, lastpass, vault, password-vault, quincy-larson, hack, leak, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brutally-honest-rejection-letter-by-an-hr&#34;&gt;A Brutally Honest Rejection Letter by an HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-coffeelicious/a-brutally-honest-rejection-letter-by-an-hr-493164bc5205&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this parody letter&lt;/a&gt; by Nish Rao, on the real reasons so HR uses these templates for rejecting candidates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nish-rao, parody, rejection-letter, hr, human-resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;passwords-are-obsolete&#34;&gt;Passwords are Obsolete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ninjudd/passwords-are-obsolete-9ed56d483eb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Justin Balthrop on how to set up a passwordless system and how is that related to the Heartbleed bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: passwordless, justin-balthrop, heartbleed, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;server-side-swift-vs-the-other-guys-2-speed&#34;&gt;Server Side Swift vs. The Other Guys — 2: Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@qutheory/server-side-swift-vs-the-other-guys-2-speed-ca65b2f79505&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comparison&lt;/a&gt; of languages and frameworks (Vapor (Swift), Ruby on Rails (Ruby), Laravel (PHP), Lumen (PHP), Express (JavaScript), Django (Python), Flask (Python), Spring (Java), Nancy (C#), Go (Pure Go, no framework)) and to benchmark Plaintext, JSON, Random SQLite Fetch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, qutheory, speed, swift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;compilers-as-assistants&#34;&gt;Compilers as Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org/blog/compilers-as-assistants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Evan Czaplicki on seeing the compiler as an assistant to your work, instead of an adversary. Of how the compiler should give the most useful errors and warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also explains what features have been removed from the Elm language in 0.16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: compiler, assistant, adversary, enemy, elm, elm-compiler, evan-czaplicki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;craftsmanship-design-and-code&#34;&gt;Craftsmanship, design, and code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/craftsmanship-design-and-code-6d93eba3e7fe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Z. White about the relation between design and code and what craftsmanship is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests learning more about the counterpart (design vs code), to better understand the activity of creating software as a whole. For developers, suggests a few activities to improve (e.g., read better code, write unit tests, analyze code). Cites that the only way of measuring progress is comparing where you are today compared to some time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: craftsmanship, jonathan-white, design, code, improving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-programmer-s-oath&#34;&gt;The Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Oath&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2015/11/18/TheProgrammersOath.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this oath&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: oath, programmer, craft, manifesto, robert-martin, uncle-bob&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intel-x86s-hide-another-cpu-that-can-take-over-your-machine-you-can-t-audit-it&#34;&gt;Intel x86s hide another CPU that can take over your machine (you can&amp;rsquo;t audit it)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://boingboing.net/2016/06/15/intel-x86-processors-ship-with.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Damien Zammit on the Intel Management Engine (ME), a hardware system that is embedded in the newer Intel chipsets. Its function is to provide low-level management services. ME (like Active Management Technology [AMT] in the past), provides great services, but has access to any memory location and to the TCP/IP stack, without any control from the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The firmware is currently checked before booting, but it is highly-valuable as a security risk, as it has full access to the physical hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: security, damien-zammit, intel-management-engine, active-management-technology, me, amt, tcp-ip, backdoor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-doesn-t-require-talent-or-even-passion&#34;&gt;Programming Doesn’t Require Talent or Even Passion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@WordcorpGlobal/programming-doesnt-require-talent-or-even-passion-11422270e1e4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of examples of why programming doesn&amp;rsquo;t require talent or passion, by Tony You&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: talent, passion, list, programming, tony-you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-from-to&#34;&gt;Getting from ⭐️⭐️ to ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/getting-from-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-to-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-c65cc3bb7cb1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Basecamp increased their ratings at the App Store: notify the user about new features and, in that modal, ask them to review the app or dismiss. By Dylan Ginsburg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: review, user-engagement, rating, basecamp, dylan-ginsburg, app-store, app&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-and-all-that-comes-with-it&#34;&gt;Software and all that comes with it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyrd.com/2011/fromthefront/sgfgw/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;driving-your-dba-crazy-in-3-easy-steps&#34;&gt;Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyrd.com/2011/ddd-day-it/shzym&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ddd, model, entity, aggregate, team-management, dba, agile, ubiquitous-language, alberto-brandolini, bus-factor, slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shorter-feedback-is-not-always-bett&#34;&gt;Shorter Feedback is not Always Bett&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.com/notes/kent-beck/shorter-feedback-is-not-always-bett/1097086386990891&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this note&lt;/a&gt; from Kent Beck on why shorter feedback loops might not always be better. I.e., why some processes take time to set in and results are not observable until that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  kent-beck, feedback-loops, open-question, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-regla-del-triple-check-para-ir-a-eventos&#34;&gt;La Regla del Triple Check para ir a eventos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bonillaware.com/regla-triple-check-para-ir-a-eventos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla about a rule to help you decide attendance to events, in Spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rule, time-management, david-bonilla, event, spanish, triple-check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-interview-with-charles-wetherell&#34;&gt;An interview with Charles Wetherell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://demin.ws/blog/english/2012/08/25/interview-with-charles-wetherell/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; by Alexander Demin about the interviewee&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;Etudes for Programmers&amp;rdquo;. In it, they talk about the origin of the études, the author&amp;rsquo;s research interests and activities. Also about the book (written in 1978) and how computer science has changed since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about three things a programmer should know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ability to do formal mathematics. The level necessary to understand Hopcroft and Ullman combined with a little graph theory is enough. Discrete mathematics is essential; calculus is only necessary for folks working in special application areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ability to write clearly in their native language. Dijkstra said that if a person couldn’t write their own language, they couldn’t write a correct program. (Well, that’s what I hope Dijkstra said!). Writing programs is essentially the same as writing a non-fiction essay. If you can’t make the step-by-step connections clearly in your own language, why would we think you could in C, for example?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that a program is primarily for communication with humans, not computers. When you write a program, the computer will do whatever you say. You must convince the humans who read the program that what you have asked the computer to do is the correct thing to do. Remember, the computer doesn’t care about correctness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to the last question means that programs should always have the form of paragraphs of comments that describe the intention of the program followed by paragraphs of code that implement that intention. All of the formatting should be designed to make readers as able as possible to read the code easily; the compiler doesn’t care. In particular, follow conventions of mathematics and your native language, not those you found in some random language manual. Write the comments first and then write the code, not the other way around. If you don’t know what you want to achieve and why, any code you write is, by definition, incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: charles-wetherell, alexander-demin, interview, book, etude, etudes-for-programmers, practice, ability, skill, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-javascript-maybe&#34;&gt;How to fix Javascript… maybe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@wob/how-to-fix-javascript-maybe-8857819bfa16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Drew Hamlett about the lack of style guide for javascript and how this affects the adoption of the language and the sprout of similar libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests the creation of a standard style guide for javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: drew-hamlett, javascript, style-guide, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;isomorphic-javascript-devbeat-master-class&#34;&gt;Isomorphic JavaScript: #DevBeat Master Class&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/spikebrehm/a-28174727&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by Spike Brehm on Isomorphic JavaScript and why it&amp;rsquo;s important: initial pageload and speed, reducing effort and duplication, SEO (crawlability).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: isomorphic-javascript, isomorphism, javascript, seo, crawler, frontend, app, application, fat-client, fat-server, thin-client, thin-server, ria-spike-brehm, slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-sourcing-our-docker-images&#34;&gt;Open-sourcing our docker images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.modulus.io/open-sourcing-our-docker-images&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brandon Cannaday about the Docker images that they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: docker, brandon-annaday, open-ource, image, container, modulus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-up-in-an-open-source-world&#34;&gt;growing up in an open source world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://fiveisprime.me/2015/02/18/growing-up-in-open-source/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Hernandez where he explains that fixing the style guide can limit your creativity and how the software is written in enterprise and open-source environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about how developers grow when exposed to different style guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: style-guide, matt-hernandez, creativity, dreyfus-model, enterprise, open-source, programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanlon-s-razor-and-working-with-young-engineers&#34;&gt;Hanlon&amp;rsquo;s Razor and working with young engineers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://fiveisprime.me/2013/07/27/young-engineers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Hernandez on the importance of understanding (and empathising) towards others&amp;rsquo; positions and worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the Hanlon Razor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  hanlon-razor, empathy, team-management, ignorance, malice, matt-hernandez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro-to-sails-js&#34;&gt;Intro to sails.js&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GK-tFvpIR7c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;, an introduction to the sails.js framework: a realtime nodejs server for creating REST APIs, inspired by Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sailsjs, ruby-on-rails, ror, framework, video, introduction, mvc, rest-api, realtime, nodejs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;node-js-and-hapi-creating-a-rest-api&#34;&gt;Node.js and hapi - creating a rest api&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.modulus.io/nodejs-and-hapi-create-rest-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about creating a REST API using &lt;a href=&#34;http://hapijs.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hapi&lt;/a&gt;, a nodejs framework. Written by Matt Hernandez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matt-hernandez, rest-api, nodejs, hapi, framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-pokedex-org-a-progressive-webapp-for-pokémon-fans&#34;&gt;Introducing Pokedex.org: a progressive webapp for Pokémon fans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketjavascript.com/blog/2015/11/23/introducing-pokedex-org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nolan Lawson about the challenge of having a 60 fps application on a mobile device, making it offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses Angular 2, javascript 7, PouchDB as well as LocalForage for storage. All processing on WebWorkers, except for DOM manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angular-2, javascript-7, angular, javascript, pouchdb, localforage, cloudant, 60fps, mobile, app, offline-first, offline, pokemon, api, nolan-lawson, web-worker, flip-technique, css, progressive, pokedex, svgomg, frontend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lambdaconf-2015-how-to-learn-haskell-in-less-than-5-years-chris-allen&#34;&gt;LambdaConf 2015 - How to Learn Haskell in Less Than 5 Years Chris Allen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bg9ccYzMbxc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Allen on how to learn haskell, what are some common pitfalls while learning it and how learning and teaching (it) are different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks about his (with a coauthor) book, focused on not reducing the readers that make it to the end and, finally, increasing the amount of haskell users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;https://yow.eventer.com/yow-2014-1222/stop-treading-water-learning-to-learn-by-edward-kmett-1750&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; by Kmett.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chris-allen, haskell, learning-to-learn, meta-learning, lambda-conf, talk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extreme-continuous-delivery-at-unruly&#34;&gt;Extreme Continuous Delivery - at Unruly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xpdays.de/2014/downloads/002-extreme-continuous-delivery-at-unruly/cd_javaone.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; about how the company Unruly does continuous delivery (CD), maximizing business value, minimizing time to market (TTM). Also describes how they do deployments and how to organize teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References: Extreme Programming Explained (Beck), Continuous Delivery (Humble &amp;amp; Farley)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: silo, team-management, culture, continuous-delivery, tdd, nagdd, shared-infrastructure, acceptance-testing, module-testing, conway-law, cross-pollination, continuous-investment, slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-chat-applications-and-robots-for-skype&#34;&gt;Building chat applications and robots for Skype&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensourcehacker.com/2013/03/28/building-chat-applications-and-robots-for-skype/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on building robots for skype. By Mikko Ohtamaa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: skype, robot, bot, mikko-ohtamaa, slack, integration, api&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-never-wrote-down-our-company-values&#34;&gt;Why I never wrote down our company values&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/why-i-never-wrote-down-our-company-values-8143520497e8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mikael Cho on the subject of having company values, preaching or writing them down. Also, what happens when hard times come, regarding your values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mikael-cho, value, company-value, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-protocol-design&#34;&gt;Interview with Jesper Louis Andersen about Erlang, Haskell, OCaml, Go, Idris, the JVM, software and protocol design &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this interview (&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial/interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-b0de06440fbd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial/interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-5628fe591295&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;) to Jesper Louis Andersen, interviewed by Federico Carrone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part is about a comparison of languages, what/why he uses them, and protocol design. The second is more about the Erlang language, the BEAM VM, and some experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: federico-carrone, erlang, interview, jesper-andersen, jesper-louis-andersen, haskell, ocaml, go, idris, the-jvm, protocol-design, software-design, language, functional-programming, protocol, land-of-lisp, northern-war&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress&#34;&gt;Migrating to Hugo From Octopress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://nathanleclaire.com/blog/2014/12/22/migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Nathan LeClaire on migrating the blog from Octopress to Hugo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: static-site-generator, hugo, go, octopress, ruby, jekyll, nathan-leclaire, migration, blog, meta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dynamic-static-site-generators-strategies&#34;&gt;Dynamic Static Site Generators strategies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://timnash.co.uk/dynamic-static-site-generators-strategies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining what are static site generators, and an example with Jekyll. By Tim Nash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tim-nash, static-site-generator, jekyll, strategy, explanation, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog-like-a-confused-hacker&#34;&gt;Blog like a confused hacker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://timnash.co.uk/using-wordpress-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Nash on what tools he recomends for static site generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tim-nash, static-site-generator, jekyll, hide, strategy, explanation, comparison, sublime, wordpress, amazon-s3, cdn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resolving-the-frontend-backend-api-design-conflict&#34;&gt;Resolving the Frontend/Backend API Design Conflict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://launchany.com/resolving-the-frontendbackend-api-design-conflict/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains the &amp;ldquo;Backend for Frontend&amp;rdquo; (BFF) pattern, for solving the different needs of data depending on each device / client. By James Higginbotham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: james-higginbotham, bff, pattern, backend-for-frontend, api, soa, microservice, frontend, backend, architecture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-we-forget-to-write-the-tests&#34;&gt;What If We Forget To Write The Tests?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;amp;id=f70f14b644&amp;amp;e=4a925444f9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by J. B. Rainsberger on the trust issues related to starting to use a new methodology (TDD in this case) and how to see what impacts it might have in your day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, tdd, motivation, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-microservices-the-unix-philosophy-and-the-richardson-maturity-model-a-practical-perspective&#34;&gt;API microservices, the Unix philosophy, and the Richardson Maturity Model - a practical perspective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@chrstphrhrt/microservices-the-unix-philosophy-and-the-richardson-maturity-model-425abed44826&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Hart on why startups and companies alike should be careful when choosing th latest technology and how this applies to microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: microservice, chris-hart, startup, analysis, company, technical-debt, bounded-context, ddd, rest-api&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;effective-programming&#34;&gt;Effective programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sebas5384/effective-programming-d7e5bb2f3b80&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sebastian Ferrari on the importance of clean code, systems thinking and functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifies the important difference between effectiveness and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links to this talk by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/OqEeIG8aPPk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Russ Ackoff&lt;/a&gt;. States the difference between &amp;ldquo;the right thing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the thing right&amp;rdquo;, by Drucker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: drucker, thing-right, right-thing, sebastian-ferrari, system-thinking, russ-ackoff, video, ted, difference, clean-code, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-how-to-learn&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@thejameskyle/learning-how-to-learn-7f04d6f42c1e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Kyle about the &amp;ldquo;how to learn&amp;rdquo; as one important skill for programmers and how having the solution at a few keystrokes limits / handicaps this ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: programmer, learn-to-learn, james-kyle, stack-overflow, skill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-some-functional-programmers-criticize-design-patterns-in-oop-languages-as-a-sign-of-language-deficiency-while-monad-is-also-a-design-pattern&#34;&gt;Why do some functional programmers criticize design patterns in OOP languages as a sign of language deficiency, while Monad is also a design pattern?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Why-do-some-functional-programmers-criticize-design-patterns-in-OOP-languages-as-a-sign-of-language-deficiency-while-Monad-is-also-a-design-pattern/answer/Edward-Kmett?srid=hVnO&amp;amp;share=12410d1e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this answer&lt;/a&gt; by Edward Kmett comparing the design patterns in OOP to the design patterns in functional languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: functional-language, object-oriented-language, edward-kmett, oop, pattern, monad, interface, quora, answer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-we-even-debate-refactoring-with-stakeholders&#34;&gt;Should We Even Debate Refactoring With Stakeholders?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;amp;id=215f7f649b&amp;amp;e=4a925444f9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by J. B. Rainsberger on the power balance between stakeholders and programmers and how it can be inclined to a &amp;lsquo;more trust&amp;rsquo; / &amp;lsquo;less trust&amp;rsquo; by following some actions. The analogy is to a trade you cannot understand, therefore you have to hope that the taken decisions are in your best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, refactor, business-need, communication, stakeholder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eternal-struggle-between-business-and-programmers&#34;&gt;The Eternal Struggle Between Business and Programmers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.thecodewhisperer.com/permalink/the-eternal-struggle-between-business-and-programmers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by J. B. Rainsberger on the discussion between business (&amp;lsquo;we want more features, now&amp;rsquo;) and the programmers (&amp;lsquo;we want more refactoring, now&amp;rsquo;). Concludes that both players need each other, in a symbiotic fashion, to keep their jobs at the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He suggests that Scrum cannot work without the XP practices and that we need to refactor aggressively after having finished our initial design, to keep the costs down. In fact, agreeing with both parts in this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References one of his own videos, at Oredev&amp;rsquo;13, &amp;ldquo;Fundamental Theorem of Agile Software Development&amp;rdquo;, where he describes the relationship between accidental / essential complexity in the cost of a feature, attributing most of it to accidental (&amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;re not good at our jobs&amp;rsquo;) and describing the need for more design / refactor after the initial design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, refactor, business-need, design, oredev, talk, agile, xp, scrum, software-development, accidental-complexity, essential-complexity, mythical-man-month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turning-code-to-cash-how-to-make-money-as-a-web-developer-and-live-to-tell-the-tale&#34;&gt;Turning code to cash — How to make money as a Web Developer and live to tell the tale.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kurtrohlandt/turning-code-to-cash-how-to-make-money-as-a-web-developer-and-live-to-tell-the-tale-f5eedc557b3e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Kurt Rohlandt with a list of items to check while dealing with clients as a freelancer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing is simple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your skill set — and let your client know it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be clear about what they are buying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to use the best tool for the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To your client you’re more than just a developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign off your jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: freelancer, kurt-rohlandt, list, tip, client&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>