<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/myth/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/myth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nodejs-logging-made-right-https-itnext-io-nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itnext.io/nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NodeJS logging made right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters-https-nicepage-com-doc-article-20348-web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nicepage.com/doc/article/20348/web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 2, we will talk about website builders that are lagging behind the trends and slowing down the Web Design evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 3, you will learn how to create modern web designs quickly and easily in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has walk through the different design phases, techniques; both in press (printed) design as in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some web builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the concept of the web 3.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element overlapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking the limitations of Bootstrap-like Grids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States the different needs for webmasters and designers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Designers need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing table constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property Panel for elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Windows and Mac OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Webmasters need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean HTML and CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile device support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress and Joomla support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building websites online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website builders are lagging behind the rapidly changing Web Design world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of web design tools has involved several transitions. However, progress has stopped. There are numerous signs that the new transition must happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are separate markets for web designers and webmasters. Popular website builders do not support the main features of Web Design 3.0: free positioning, modern grids, and layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, web-design, print-design, web-builder, creativity, metaphor, grid-layout, bootstrap, flexibility, design, web-3.0, web-design-3.0, web-2.0, progression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5101ce2e-3f5e-11e9-83d9-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:49:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gotify-a-self-hosted-push-notifications-service-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19347848&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19347848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gotify – a self-hosted push-notifications service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gotify, self-hosted, notification, notification-service, android, open-source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e839c82a-4367-11e9-b34d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:08:36 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-speak-like-a-leader-not-like-an-engineer-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19349676&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links and resources for speaking like a leader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leader, engineer, comparison, change, public-speaking, speak, speaking, career-management, career-change, professional-growth, resource:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1a478fc8-4368-11e9-b657-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:10:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;archivebox-open-source-self-hosted-web-archive-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19346985&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19346985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ArchiveBox: Open-source self-hosted web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools for archiving purposes. Has links to other sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpolarized.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://getpolarized.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: burtonator, web-archive, polarized, warch, warc, personal-knowledge-base&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4168161c-436e-11e9-aa0d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:54:03 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-as-a-freelancer-what-s-the-best-app-to-track-finances-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19450331&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19450331&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: As a freelancer, what&amp;rsquo;s the best app to track finances?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes tools for finance for freelancers. Stresses the importance of time wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, money-management, freelance, tool, ask-hn, hackernews, finance, time-wealth, money-wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b74a6696-4c83-11e9-99bd-0242ac110005
Read: Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:20:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned-in-my-first-year-as-a-solo-founder-https-tik-dev-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tik.dev/lessons-learned&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What I Learned in My First Year as a Solo Founder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learnings by a solo founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits of having a side project or side hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: side-hustle, side-business, learning, reflection, solo-founder, founder, revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f0dee42c-5142-11e9-9444-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:19:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-tests-not-too-many-mostly-integration-https-kentcdodds-com-blog-write-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kentcdodds.com/blog/write-tests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Write tests. Not too many. Mostly integration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paraphrasing of some advice for healthy eating: &amp;lsquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rsquo; (Pollan)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I find myself saving time when I put time in to write tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too many: you get diminishing returns on your tests as the coverage increases [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly integration: as you move up the pyramid, the confidence quotient of each form of testing increases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests strike a great balance on the trade-offs between confidence and speed/expense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: unit-test, testing, test-pyramid, healthy-testing, advice, integration-test, quote, kent-c-dodds, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d148d774-5144-11e9-94d8-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:32:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-rules-for-eating-https-www-webmd-com-food-recipes-news-20090323-7-rules-for-eating&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/food-recipes/news/20090323/7-rules-for-eating&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7 Rules for Eating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this reference article, Michael Pollan explains his seven rules for eating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything your great grandmother wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recognize as food. &amp;ldquo;When you pick up that box of portable yogurt tubes, or eat something with 15 ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce, ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What are those things doing there?&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t eat anything with more than five ingredients, or ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay out of the middle of the supermarket; shop on the perimeter of the store. Real food tends to be on the outer edge of the store near the loading docks, where it can be replaced with fresh foods when it goes bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that won&amp;rsquo;t eventually rot. &amp;ldquo;There are exceptions &amp;ndash; honey &amp;ndash; but as a rule, things like Twinkies that never go bad aren&amp;rsquo;t food,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not just what you eat but how you eat. &amp;ldquo;Always leave the table a little hungry,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Many cultures have rules that you stop eating before you are full. In Japan, they say eat until you are four-fifths full. Islamic culture has a similar rule, and in German culture they say, &amp;lsquo;Tie off the sack before it&amp;rsquo;s full.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Families traditionally ate together, around a table and not a TV, at regular meal times. It&amp;rsquo;s a good tradition. Enjoy meals with the people you love. &amp;ldquo;Remember when eating between meals felt wrong?&amp;rdquo; Pollan asks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t buy food where you buy your gasoline. In the U.S., 20% of food is eaten in the car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, four myths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food is a delivery vehicle for nutrients. What really matters isn&amp;rsquo;t broccoli but its fiber and antioxidants. If we get that right, we get our diet right. Foods kind of get in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need experts to tell us how to eat. Nutrients are invisible and mysterious. &amp;ldquo;It is a little like religion,&amp;rdquo; Pollan said. &amp;ldquo;If a powerful entity is invisible, you need a priesthood to mediate your relation with food.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole point of eating is to maintain and promote bodily health. &amp;ldquo;You are either improving or ruining your health when you eat &amp;ndash; that is a very American idea,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;But there are many other reasons to eat food: pleasure, social community, identity, and ritual. Health is not the only thing going on on our plates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are evil foods and good foods. &amp;ldquo;At any given time there is an evil nutrient we try to drive like Satan from the food supply &amp;ndash; first it was saturated fats, then it was trans fat,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Then there is the evil nutrient&amp;rsquo;s doppelganger, the blessed nutrient. If we get enough of that we, will be healthy and maybe live forever. It&amp;rsquo;s funny through history how the good and bad guys keep changing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can all be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: healthy-eating, michael-pollan, rule, advice, myth, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 30ece1fc-5145-11e9-87de-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:35:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-https-blog-usejournal-com-lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.usejournal.com/lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lean Testing or Why Unit Tests are Worse than You Think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article puts testing in an economic perspective. Calls it lean testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also references/paraphrases Michael Pollan&amp;rsquo;s Rules for eating ().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creates a testing trophy, a figure to explain the best testing pattern, replacing the testing pyramid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains return on investment (ROI) on tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;integration tests provide the best balance of cost, speed and confidence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests lie somewhere between unit tests and end-to-end tests so they provide the best balance. Therefore, they have the highest ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea is to just not mock so much&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: economic-perspective, lean-testing, testing-trophy, testing-pyramid, return-on-investment, roi, critical-path, testing, unit-test, anti-architecture, architecture, maintenance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: efe85d00-5147-11e9-87ce-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:55:02 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-user-programming-https-www-inkandswitch-com-end-user-programming-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inkandswitch.com/end-user-programming.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;End-user programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the writer explains some of the end-user modifications to programs. Examples include: adding download capabilities to instagram, generating backups for files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, applications (especially mobile) are tightly sealed, not allowing modification or extension. Even FOSS (free, open source software), modification implies the learning curve / entry barrier of having to setup, compile, debug the original program and modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives the example of the UNIX command line, as a programming environment. One that provides (one of) the best REPL examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characterizes spreadsheets as ad-hoc databases, programs; mostly created by domain experts (aka subject matter experts), than professional software engineers. Take into account that these hats are non-exclusive: a domain expert can also be a professional software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author tries to coin the term &amp;ldquo;end-user programming&amp;rdquo; to differentiate it from programming by professional software developers, who try to build general-purpose apps, to be used by thousands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means, that a professional software developer can be an &amp;ldquo;end-user programmer&amp;rdquo;, when creating solutions for themselves (limited user group), rather than for the general public. Maybe those one-off scripts that we create, are some kind of end-user programs. This is described in the article as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks of the chasm the user has to cross in order to customize the behaviour of their software. This is related to working in a framework or a library, in the sense of &amp;lsquo;who keeps the control&amp;rsquo;. In an UNIX, filesystem environment, you keep the control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References &amp;ldquo;citizen developers&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three qualities for end-user programming: embodiment, living systems, and in-place toolchains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment: it requires the programmer hold many abstractions in their mind. Related to abstract reasoning. Mentions that many end-users don&amp;rsquo;t have these abstractions in their mind, but are capable of abstract reasoning in their own domains of expertise. Mentions that via visual representations onscreen, we can help the end-user. An example: preview formula results in a spreadsheet; highlight the cells in a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment means, broadly, making elements of the programming experience more concrete and visual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living systems: interaction with them. Refers to shortening the feedback cycle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Live programming gives the programmer immediate feedback on the behavior of a program as it is edited, replacing the edit compile-debug cycle with a fluid programming experience.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But only short feedback loops, but also to change the system behaviour from within, such as the LISP compiler reading and compiling the source code from inside a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-place tool chains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user should be able to edit their programs without installing additional tools or programs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a Unix shell script is just a series of commands saved into a text file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning that the user is already accustomed to issuing those commands. A script is just grouping those commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives examples of end-user programming success stories: spreadsheets, SQL, browser dev tools,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: end-user-programming, programming, extensibility, open-closed-principle, ocp, mofication, user, extension, unix, repl, spreadsheet, reflection, theory, history, review, sql, dev-tools, chasm, abstraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4490792a-514b-11e9-9861-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:18:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-https-medium-com-web-development-why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@web.development/why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why developers consider Agile development to be nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article explains how Agile development is apt and indicated for short-term software development, especially for contracting or consulting companies, where the client is external to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why it does not make as much sense in products/services where there is a leapfrog solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t give the customer what they ask for; understand them, and revolutionize their world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leapfrog-solution, google, agile, agile-development, comparison, project-management, client, consulting, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9035ea3c-514f-11e9-9676-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:49:37 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-bother-with-what-three-words-https-shkspr-mobi-blog-2019-03-why-bother-with-what-three-words&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/03/why-bother-with-what-three-words/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why bother with What Three Words?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the author questions why using a closed protocol for translating geo-coordinates to words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author complains that it is masquerading a for-profit, closed algorithm as an open standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, that the GPS locations are drifting very quickly in some places, therefore the translated address changes, but the local address (e.g., 1 Wall Street), does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gps-drift, australia, open-standard, closed-standard, for-profit, protocol, open, closed, what-three-words, w3w, i18n, startup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 960e6750-5202-11e9-bb40-0242ac110008
Read: Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:11:07 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-hey-you-should-stop-using-texts-for-two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/hey-stop-using-texts-two-factor-authentication/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-d-never-work-for-google-twitter-or-facebook&#34;&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://naildrivin5.com/blog/2011/08/01/why-i-wont-work-for-google-twitter-facebook.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-copeland, google, twitter, facebook, job-satisfaction, commitment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-thinking-needs-to-think-bigger&#34;&gt;Design Thinking Needs To Think Bigger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcodesign.com/90112320/design-thinking-needs-to-think-bigger&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by STEVE VASSALLO on systems thinking and design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes a system a system rather than just a collection of parts is that the components are interconnected and interdependent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: steve-vassallo, design-thinking, system-thinking, mental-model, emergence-point, leverage-point, iceberg-model&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cobol-is-everywhere-who-will-maintain-it&#34;&gt;COBOL Is Everywhere. Who Will Maintain It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewstack.io/cobol-everywhere-will-maintain/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel explaining the state of the COBOL systems at some banks and the difficulty of finding young COBOL programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-cassel, cobol, youth, team-management, hiring, bank, java, mainframe, legacy-system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-too-busy-you-need-a-shultz-hour&#34;&gt;You’re Too Busy. You Need a ‘Shultz Hour.’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/18/opinion/youre-too-busy-you-need-a-shultz-hour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Leonhardt, about the Shultz Hour: time set aside to not be busy, so you can set aside the tactical topics and focus on the strategic topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You waste years by not being able to waste hours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amos Tversky  (as Michael Lewis describes in his THE UNDOING PROJECT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-leonhardt, busyness, time-management, shultz-hour, connectedness, social-media, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;avoid-these-35-habits-that-lead-to-unmaintainable-code&#34;&gt;Avoid these 35 habits that lead to unmaintainable code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/avoid-35-habits-lead-unmaintainable-code-christian-maioli-mackeprang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about habits that make writing software more difficult:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saying “I’ll fix it later”, and never doing it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insisting on a one-liner solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making pointless optimizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convincing yourself that styling issues are not that important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweeping things under the rug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using names that don’t add information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring proven best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abandoning plans too early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insisting on a plan that has little chance of working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on your own all the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refusing to write bad code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blaming others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not sharing with your team what you’ve learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being too slow on giving feedback to managers/clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not using Google enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overvaluing your personal style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a personal attachment to your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not knowing how to optimize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the wrong tool for the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not bothering with mastering your tools and IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring error messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Romanticizing your developer toolkit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardcoding values instead of making them configurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinventing the wheel all the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blindly copy/pasting code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not taking the time to learn how things really work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having excessive confidence in your own code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not thinking about the trade-offs of each design, solution, or library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not getting help when you’re stuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing tests to pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disregarding performance testing for critical cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not checking that your build works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing large changes late, or leaving after making a large push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disowning code you wrote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring the nonfunctional requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christian-maioli-mackeprang, maintanability, code, listicle, habit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-a-first-class-language-at-last&#34;&gt;JavaScript — A First-Class Language At Last&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/javascript-first-class-language-atlast-tom-goldenberg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Goldenberg defending javascript, citing sources on why it is a first-class language,
the amount of job offers, and the state of the art in NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-goldenberg, javascript, java, comparison, first-class, language, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-8-hour-workday-doesn-t-work&#34;&gt;Why the 8-Hour Workday Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/why-8-hour-workday-doesnt-work-dr-travis-bradberry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; defending the removal of the 8-hour workday, preferring the division of time in slots.
In the article, 52 minutes of highly focused work then 17 minutes of rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key idea is the work-rest, no matter how big those slots are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives tips on how to separate both, some other tips for improving your performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Travis Bradberry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, pomodoro-technique, travis-bradberry, time, workday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-and-how-to-steer-back-toward-the-light-https-medium-freecodecamp-com-the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-2a31ff7a4cd2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-2a31ff7a4cd2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The dark side of extreme productivity, and how to steer back toward the light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Beau Carnes on how productivity can have a downside, how it can affect your healthy lifestyle.
Explains effective vs efficient, productivity, silent retreat, prayer or meditation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is not to prioritize what’s on your schedule, but to schedule your priorities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Covey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: beau-carnes, productivity, quote, stephen-covey, sustainable-pace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dejé-de-leer&#34;&gt;Dejé de leer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://culto.latercera.com/2017/03/15/deje-de-leer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Catalina Bu on the tsundoku and how to read more. (In Spanish)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: catalina-bu, tsundoku, reading, time-management, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacked-in-translation-from-subtitles-to-complete-takeover&#34;&gt;Hacked in Translation – from Subtitles to Complete Takeover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.checkpoint.com/2017/05/23/hacked-in-translation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about a vector to getting to user&amp;rsquo;s machines through the video player, using subtitle files.
by Check Point Research Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: check-point-research-team, security, vulnerability, vector, attack, subtitle, video-player&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-teamwork-myths-to-tackle-at-your-office&#34;&gt;8 Teamwork Myths To Tackle At Your Office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/8-teamwork-myths-to-tackle-at-your-office&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Leah Ryder on remote work myths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leah-ryder, productivity, myth, remote, remote-work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-elm-is-the-future-of-front-end-development&#34;&gt;Why I think Elm is the Future of Front End Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rgoomar/why-i-think-elm-is-the-future-of-front-end-development-21e9b091fa05&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rishi Goomar comparing reactredux to elm, comparing javascript to elm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rishi-goomar, comparison, elm, javascript, react, redux, javascript-fatigue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;los-viejos-programadores-nunca-mueren-y-silicon-valley-se-está-dando-cuenta-de-ello&#34;&gt;Los viejos programadores nunca mueren, y Silicon Valley se está dando cuenta de ello&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.xataka.com/empresas-y-economia/los-viejos-programadores-nunca-mueren-y-silicon-valley-se-esta-dando-cuenta-de-ello&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Pastor on the age of the programmers in Silicon Valley. In Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, javier-pastor, age, programmer, career-manager, silicon-valley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-tensorflow-powered-ing-api-client&#34;&gt;Creating a TensorFlow-powered ING API client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@donflopez/cracking-the-ing-api-with-tensorflow-9681ae7dc249&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Francisco López on how he has implemented a small bot to click the virtual keyboard and connect to the bank website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ing-direct, francisco-lopez, bot, opencv, tensorflow, machine-learning, python, banking, open-banking-data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&#34;&gt;Be a good mentor, not a dickhead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Edaqa Mortoray about traits of a mentor. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/mortoray/be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://dev.to/mortoray/be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: edaqa-mortoray, mentor, trait, skill, mentorship, apprentice, apprenticeship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-bharry-2017-05-24-the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/bharry/2017/05/24/the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The largest Git repo on the planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by  Brian Harry on how Microsoft manages one of its big repositories. Explains how they have virtualized the git folder and the git workspace at Microsoft using gvfs. Explains how they have performed the improvements necessary to make it useful and usable to programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have support for clients, but what about Linux?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  brian-harry, microsoft, continous-delivery, linux, windows, gvfs, repository, monorepo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!--
## Gerald Weinberg on Bugs, Errors, and Software Quality

I&#39;ve listened to [this interview][bug-error-weinberg] with Gerald Weinberg where he first talks about software quality, defining a fault, failure, a boo-boo, a blunder (below). Then, they move on to the cost of quality, experiences in his project &#39;Mercury&#39; (a man in orbit; his contribution was on the software side). Says it&#39;s one of his first projects where a person&#39;s life was directly related to a piece of software.

Fault: wrong operation in code
Failure: user&#39;s experience caused by a fault
Boo-boo: a one-off, small failure. Usually shrugged as a small defect
Blunder: a one-off, big failure. Can kill a career

About the cost of software, he mentions that many managers are not willing to pay the price of almost defect-free software and that this level of quality is not required in every project. This idea is similar to the one &#39;Testing every part is akin to reading every letter on the newspaper: one parts are more important than other&#39;.

This interview talks about similar topics than &#39;Why programs fail&#39;, especially about the definition.

At the end of the interview, he talks about team-based software development (~XP) and an anecdote about a company he was consulting with: follow the process or pay the defects out of your own pocket. One of them, accepted paying for defects, until he made a big mistake. Accepted training the rest of the employees into his very precise methods and became very valuable to the company.

Tags: podcast, gerald-weinberg, quality, interview, manager, software-quality, definition, fault, failure, boo-boo, blunder, project-mercury

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;!--
## Microservice Practitioners with Austin Gunter and Richard Li

I&#39;ve listened to [this podcast][us-practitioners] at Software Engineering Daily with Austin Gunter and Richard Li. In it, they talk about how they have organized the conference &#39;Microservice Practicitioners&#39;: how to find speakers, the vibes of the conference, etc.

Tags: austin-gunter, richard-li, organize-a-conference, conference, microservice, microservice-practitioners, podcast, software-engineering-daily

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34;&gt;10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/derickbailey/10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this listicle&lt;/a&gt; of docker myths. By Derick Bailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bored-people-quit&#34;&gt;Bored People Quit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://randsinrepose.com/archives/bored-people-quit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-lopp, boredness, team-management, people, career, tech-lead, quote&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volver&#34;&gt;¿Volver?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raulavila.com/2017/01/volver/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;donkey-code&#34;&gt;Donkey code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://einarwh.wordpress.com/2017/01/21/donkey-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: einar-host, donkey-code, ddd, domain-driven-development, domain, abstraction, missing-abstraction, business-logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men&#34;&gt;10 Habits That Change Boys Into Men&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men-b103c47d47e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on why some men are still boys (e.g., expectations from society) and what can boys do to turn into men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, psychology, learning, evolution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-command-line-utilities&#34;&gt;My favorite command-line utilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/macbook-my-command-line-utilities-f8a121c3b019#.3hpq7suhj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Vitaly Belman in which he explains his curated list of utilities for the terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: vitaly-belman, terminal, cli, application, utility, tig, git&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-common-mistakes-of-the-first-time-tech-lead&#34;&gt;Three Common Mistakes of the First Time Tech Lead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/three-common-mistakes-first-time-tech-lead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Kua, in which he explains what are the anti-patterns (or mistakes) of a tech lead. They do not only apply to first timers, but more experienced ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially like a comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take all blame and give all credit: I ensure I always take the blame from the stakeholders when something is broken but when they praise, I say its all my teams efforts and I am just guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/by/ravensnowbird/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ravensnowbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: patrick-kua, tech-lead, leadership, team-management, mistake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimental-versioning&#34;&gt;Sentimental Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sentimentalversioning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (unknown author) on alternatives to semver (semantic versioning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: semver, semantic-versioning, sentimental-versioning, humor, parody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devoxx-2015-how-to-become-a-java-champion&#34;&gt;Devoxx 2015: How to Become a Java Champion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http//www.youtube.com/watch?v=otMc_3Dz3hU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Arun Gupta in which he explains what is a Java champion and how to become one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, arun-gupta, java-champion, devoxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-become-a-champion-programmer&#34;&gt;How Can I Become a Champion Programmer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaspecialists.eu/archive/Issue227.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Heinz M. Kabutz on how to become a java champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: heinz-kabutz, java-champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-using-scala-as-a-better-java&#34;&gt;The myth of using Scala as a better Java&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedscala.com/blog/2017/myth-of-scala-as-better-java/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Denis Kalinin disproving &amp;lsquo;Java as a better Scala&amp;rsquo;. He covers dependency injection, database access, serialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scala, java, comparison, orm, denis-kalinin, macwire, dependency-injection, serialization, database, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y&#34;&gt;The eigenvector of &amp;ldquo;Why we moved from language X to language Y&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://erikbern.com/2017/03/15/the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Erik Bern on the statistical analysis (based on people writing blog posts) of moving from language X to language Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can help predict which languages will be more prevalent in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eigenvector, statistic, erik-bern, language, programming-language, java, c, cplusplus, go, python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;facebook-s-code-quality-problem&#34;&gt;Facebook’s code quality problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.darkcoding.net/software/facebooks-code-quality-problem/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Graham King on the problems that Facebook is facing, at the code level, and how they solve some of them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: graham-king, facebook, quality, architecture, code-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-key-lesson-from-our-serverless-migration&#34;&gt;The key lesson from our serverless migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=abe09ce689751513abf6f095f&amp;amp;id=6ecb59a937&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gojko Adzic on serverless, a kind of lessons learned. Explains that their system can take 50% more users at 50% of the original cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains three ways of authenticating users: use IAM users, use Cognito, pre-sign URLs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lessons-learned, gojko-adzic, serverless, paas, platform-as-a-service, retrospective, money, total-cost-of-ownership, tco,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-automation-goes-horribly-wrong&#34;&gt;When automation goes horribly wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Gojko Adzic on a story of a manual process that was automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it focused too much on replacing humans instead of assisting them, MiDAS actually made it more difficult for clerks to access the data they needed for review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of the framework vs library discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in frameworks you relinquish the control, putting your code into the allocated holes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using the automated system, you can only check the claim at a certain spot, where the system lets you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system and the framework have been designed to take control of the situation. Both successful at what they do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gojko-adzic, automation, framework, library, framework-vs-library, comparison, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-store-my-1-s-and-0-s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy&#34;&gt;How I Store My 1’s and 0’s: ZFS  Bargain HP Microserver = JOY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mocko.org.uk/b/2012/06/17/how-i-store-my-1s-and-0s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Alex stores his backups, using a microserver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: backup, microserver, raid, zfs, backup-strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-policy&#34;&gt;Meeting policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/ueno/meeting-policy-9b04593d1b28&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by the Ueno team on how they handle meetings. Interesting that they require manager approval for meetings over a certain threshold (more than four people or more than half an hour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ueno, meeting-policy, meeting, approval&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-random-numbers&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Random Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/a-brief-history-of-random-numbers-9498737f5b6c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carl Tashian on how random numbers have evolved (from dice to pseudo random number generator and random number generators). Explain how some companies that need true randomness (e.g., certificates company) generate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: carl-tashian, dice, random-number, randomness, prng, pseudo-random-number-generator, random-number-generator, number-generator, true-random-number-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word&#34;&gt;Unlock honest feedback with this one word&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word-dcaf3839e7ee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Claire Lew, in which she suggests to ask for &amp;lsquo;advice&amp;rsquo; instead of asking for &amp;lsquo;feedback&amp;rsquo; as a way of getting more honest and better responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: claire-lew, advice, feedback, feedback-process, improvement&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliberate-practice-what-it-is-and-why-you-need-it&#34;&gt;Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four essential components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailored (practice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetion
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language&#34;&gt;10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jooq.org/2016/03/31/10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list of features&lt;/a&gt; that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language. By Lukas Eder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: list, lukas-eder, kotlin, java, comparison, language, jooq&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-built-uber-engineering-s-highest-query-per-second-service-using-go&#34;&gt;How we built Uber engineering&amp;rsquo;s highest query per second service using Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.uber.com/go-geofence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kai Wei on a microservice they&amp;rsquo;ve built using Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the reasons for choosing that algorithm for geofencing, the performance they&amp;rsquo;re achieving, and the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uber, go, microservice, performance, geofence, geofencing, rps, go-memory-model, kai-wei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service&#34;&gt;Unwinding Uber&amp;rsquo;s Most Efficient Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@buckhx/unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service-406413c5871d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Buck Heroux commenting on the decisions of Uber for building the geofencing microservice (above read).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the different alternatives for algorithms in this problem space and has implemented them in go. Provides a benchmark for comparing those, including a profiling session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: s2, quadtree, rtree, brute-force, geofence, geofencing, uber, comment, buck-heroux, go, read-on-read, meta-read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawful-hacking-and-continuing-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Lawful Hacking and Continuing Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/03/lawful_hacking_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on the stance the FBI is taking in regards to vulnerabilities discovered in Apple&amp;rsquo;s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, apple, security, fbi, vulnerability, exploit, law, hacking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-life-learning&#34;&gt;A Side Project Helped Jumpstart My Career — Life Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/life-learning/a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-7cd6f8e9b07f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dave Gerhardt on how making a side project happen affected his life and his skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons for doing it include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It forces you to figure stuff out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way to learn is by doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gets your brain working on something other than your job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to create your own network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are the CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: long-life-learning, continuous-learning, side-project, dave-gerhardt, drift, professional-development, personal-development, business, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-jekyll-tricks&#34;&gt;Fun Jekyll Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.madebymarket.com/blog/dev/fun-jekyll-tricks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Knapp where he explains some tips and tricks of jekyll (in which octopress is based on): speed, deployment, subcategories inside the blog, _data, _includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brian-knapp, jekyll, octopress, tip-and-trick, improvement, subcategory, meta, automation, deployment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-ola-que-llega&#34;&gt;La ola que llega&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=f8a8ee92cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla, where he explains (in Spanish) the &amp;lsquo;contractor&amp;rsquo; phenomenon arriving to Spain, 2-3 years after being in other countries and the effects that this could have both for workers and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bonilista, david-bonilla, contractor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-razones-por-las-que-este-sábado-deberías-ir-a-un-code-retreat&#34;&gt;10 razones por las que este sábado deberías ir a un code retreat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://francho.org/2015/11/10/10-razones-para-ir-a-un-coderetreat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of reasons for attending a code retreat, by Francho Joven, who I met in the Global Day Of Code Retreat (GDCR) &amp;lsquo;15 in Zaragoza&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: francho-joven, list, zaragoza, code-retreat, gdcr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meaningful-work-through-passion-not-genius&#34;&gt;Meaningful Work through Passion, not Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIYUMwxKFzo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; on the importance of hard work and how it can be mistaken as genious. By Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: malcolm-gladwell, passion, genius, work, time-management, productivity, career, mastery-autonomy-purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name&#34;&gt;How to ask your wife for permission to spend $250,000 on a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Stockphoto.com/how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name-c27a3c2852e1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jon Yau on how they started StockPhoto.com, buying a $250,000 domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: startup, domain, stockphoto, jon-yau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong&#34;&gt;Sorry, developer bootcamps: I was wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@dillonforrest/sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong-ea37fcc5572c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dillon Forrest on the topic of developer bootcamps. Explains why developers should not be threatened by recent graduates of these programs and describes how people pursuing these programs usually are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bootcamp, developer-bootcamp, dev-bootcamp, dillon-forrest, intelligence, risk-appetite, resilience, self-investment, entrepreneurship, growth-trajectory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jvm-and-java-garbage-collection&#34;&gt;The JVM and Java Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoJr5QQYsl8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this webcast&lt;/a&gt; about how the JVM garbage collection works. By Michael W Williams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-williams, oracle, webcast, jvm, garbage-collection, gc,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;files-are-hard&#34;&gt;Files Are Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/file-consistency/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why software that writes on files is difficult, based on the different filesystems that are below, and the operating system. Written by Dan Luu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses software product to find bugs in filesystems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: filesystem, file, dan-luu, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusión-inquebrantable&#34;&gt;Contrata a un fracasado con ilusión inquebrantable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contunegocio.es/tecnologia/contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusion-inquebrantable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alberto Mena (in Spanish) on what are the qualities that define a good programmer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;illusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-mena, spanish, team-management, success, developer, quality, developer-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-react&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t react&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.avdi.org/2016/04/14/dont-react/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Avdi Grimm on how the action vs reaction attitude. Why to prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: action, reaction, social-media, avdi-grimm, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34;&gt;FTP is so 90&amp;rsquo;s. Let&amp;rsquo;s deploy via Git instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderwall.com/p/xczkaq/ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to deploy using git. By Kerrick Long&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kerrick-long, git, deployment, webapp, application, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-vs-career-10-key-differences-you-need-to-understand&#34;&gt;Job vs Career: 10 Key Differences You Need To Understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/job-vs-career&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what differentiates a job from a career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, infographic, job-vs-career, comparison, job, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-secret-to-employee-motivation&#34;&gt;The Secret To Employee Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/secret-employee-motivation-infographic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what motivates employess: mastery, autonomy and purpose. A direct reference to Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The puzzle of motivation&amp;rdquo; TED talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, motivation, employee, infographic, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-puzzle-of-motivation&#34;&gt;The puzzle of motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Pink on what motivates us: intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about the gap that exists between what science knows and what businesses propose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ted, ted-talk, video, dan-pink, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count&#34;&gt;Applying a ceiling to the bug count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techblog.king.com/applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, written by Susanna Berg, on how King has reduced the amount of bugs in their backlog using an agile technique, measuring and setting a limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: susanna-berg, king, agile, bug, bug-count, defect, defect-count, per-malmen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34;&gt;Coming up in 2016: Spring Framework 4.3 &amp;amp; 5.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://spring.io/blog/2015/08/03/coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this announcement&lt;/a&gt; of Spring&amp;rsquo;s new release, 5.0, which will require java 8 and will turn most of the features into the reactive programming paradigm. By Juergen Hoeller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: juergen-hoeller, spring, reactive-programming, release, announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die&#34;&gt;Why offices are where work goes to die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swizec.com/blog/why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die/swizec/6695&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Swizec Teller explaining the downsides of working in an office as compared to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: swizec-teller, remote, home-office, office, comparison, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Passionate Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bm2yogi/the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer-76a41d457304&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Ibarra on what are the implications of being a passionate developer, how it affects your tasks and what are the factors to a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-ibarra, passion, development, job, motivation, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mossack-fonseca-breach-wordpress-revolution-slider-plugin-possible-cause&#34;&gt;Mossack Fonseca Breach – WordPress Revolution Slider Plugin Possible Cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2016/04/mossack-fonseca-breach-vulnerable-slider-revolution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Maunder, which describes an hypothesis on how the Mossack Fonseca breach could have happened. Also describes and shows how to breach a Wordpress installation with a vulnerable Revolution Slider plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mark-maunder, security, breach, mossack-fonseca-breach, mossack-fonseca, hypothesis, attack, plugin, revolution-slider, wordpress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tim-urban-inside-the-mind-of-a-master-procrastinator&#34;&gt;Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; from Tim Urban on how the procrastinator&amp;rsquo;s mind works, exemplified by his own career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: procrastinator, procrastination, mind, time-management, tim-urban&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pep-20-the-zen-of-python&#34;&gt;PEP 20 &amp;ndash; The Zen of Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the PEP20&lt;/a&gt;, the zen of python, with special attention to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: pep-20, pep, python, zen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Why I switched from Octopress 2 to Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Franklin Chen on the change he made on the static site generator (SSG) he used. He considered hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo. Was decided between hakyll and hugo for their speed but, finally, decided to use hugo for their bigger community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: franklin-chen, comparison, ssg, static-site-generator, hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo, change, speed, statically-typed, dynamically-typed, golang, performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-incremental-regeneration-in-jekyll-3-0-is-such-a-big-deal&#34;&gt;Why incremental regeneration in Jekyll 3.0 is such a big deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/11/04/jekyll-30-released-incremental-regeneration-rocks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Johnson on one of the new features that jekyll 3.0 brings: incremental generation. How this can speed up the generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-johnson, incremental-generation, speed, performance, octopress-2, octopress-3, jekyll-3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-s3-travis-ci-oh-boy&#34;&gt;Hugo, S3, Travis CI, oh boy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://continuousfailure.com/post/s3_blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Scherger on how to set up a specific stack for developing and deploying a static site blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alan-scherger, static-site-generator, ssg, travis, hugo, s3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-your-blog-to-github-pages-automatically-using-hugo-and-travis&#34;&gt;Deploy your blog to github pages automatically using Hugo and Travis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcoedo.com/post/hugo-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Roman Coedo on how to deploy a hugo blog to github pages, using travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: roman-coedo, travis, hugo, github, github-pages, ssg, static-site-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;improve-octopress-with-advanced-tweaks-tips&#34;&gt;Improve Octopress with Advanced Tweaks &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.narga.net/improve-octopress-advanced-tweaks-tips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tips on how to improve the octopress (2) installation. By Nguyễn Đình Quân.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nguyen-dinh-quan, octopress-2, tip, tweak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;laboratorios&#34;&gt;Laboratorios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2014/11/12/laboratorios/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla, about laboratories to use a percentage of company time to investigate, innovate, learn and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, team-management, time-management, innovation, strategy, improvement, kaizen, laboratory, craftsmanship, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isn-t&#34;&gt;What Refactoring is, and what it isn’t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swreflections.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isnt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Bird, where he splits some practices into refactoring and not refactoring. Draws the line between these two different activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also cites scratch refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jim-bird, scratch-refactoring, refactoring, martin-fowler, kent-beck, definition, quote, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitfalls-of-unlimited-vacations&#34;&gt;Pitfalls of Unlimited Vacations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/archive/2016/02/18/unlimited-vaction-pitfalls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Phil Haack on the github, travis and netflix policies about unlimited vacations and the effects they have on the employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about minimum vacation periods, (paternity) paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: phil-haack, unlimited-vacation, holiday, vacation, team-management, burnout, github, travis, netflix, policy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultura-corporativa&#34;&gt;Cultura Corporativa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2011/02/06/cultura-corporativa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla about the corporate culture, and how &amp;ldquo;hanging a highly interchangeable sentence on a wall&amp;rdquo; does not represent it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, corporate culture, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code&#34;&gt;What It’s Really Like to Learn to Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sandjar/what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code-53f6d9156a32&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains firsthand how it is to learn programming for a novice student,even with a strong financial background and having completed a university degree. By Sandjar Kozubaev&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sandjar-kozubaev, learning, programming, student, firsthand, coding, story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>