<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>repository on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/repository/</link>
    <description>Recent content in repository on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 10:03:01 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/repository/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python 3 Boilerplate for Non-Productive environments (e.g., Kata, Study)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/28/python-3-boilerplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 10:03:01 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/28/python-3-boilerplate/</guid>
      <description>I have created a Python 3 boilerplate for non-productive environments. It can be found here: https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/python-boilerplate
Main features Its main features are:
 It can be run locally (local python) or in a docker container (official docker image) It has a Makefile with the most common commands to drive the project. Also, other makefiles in this folder Batteries included: mypy, pytest, pre-commit. Permissive license: MIT. The updated version is here Currently, it is using python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2023</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/01/01/self-study-january-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2023/01/01/self-study-january-2023/</guid>
      <description>Show HN: I built Haystack – your own google for scattered workplace knowledge https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34218724
Tags: tool, index, note, knowledge-base, haystack, privacy, neural-network, imported, hacker-news
Id: 0fb5be84-8b37-11ed-b09f-0242ac110003 Read: Mon Jan 2 15:14:13 2023
Extending Python with Rust Tags: binding, rust, ffi, foreign-function-interface, tool, rumpy, tool
Id: 232ad576-8b37-11ed-bc27-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:20:44 +0000
Why CVE-2022-3602 was not detected by fuzz testing So recently a very hyped memory corruption security vulnerability was discovered in the OpenSSL punycode parser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.
Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning
Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool: Building a local pipeline</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Motivation At a client, one of the projects has a long building process and the tests are mostly slow, so I use a local building pipeline, an example of the Pipes and Filters pattern.
This allows for executing manually only the fast unit tests, then automatically (no user intervention, no time spent) executing the rest of them before pushing. In case the latter fails, it is possible to do git push -f to the pipeline without corrupting the central repository (origin) history, possibly disturbing others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the GitHub repositories</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/08/navigating-the-github-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 07:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/08/navigating-the-github-repositories/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve reorganized my github repositories, especially the katas and the simple sessions.
Katas All of them can be found in this search
Separated by language:
 Java Clojure Javascript Haskell Ruby  To the best of my knowledge, all repositories follow a similar pattern:
 Contain the keyword &amp;lsquo;kata&amp;rsquo; Contain the language Contain a description of the exercise  An example: palindromes-searcher-kata-haskell
Simple sessions A simple session is a lapse of time working with the language to solve a problem, but not big enough to deserve a repository of its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session and Dojo: Beginning Clojure</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/brown-bag-session-and-dojo-beginning-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 01:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/05/brown-bag-session-and-dojo-beginning-clojure/</guid>
      <description>At a client, today I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated a brown-bag session introducing the Clojure language to a group of java programmers.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started hands-on, live coding on a REPL. To make things easier, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a maven project that imports the clojure jar and lets you obtain dependencies from clojars. The repo is here. This repo wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been possible without the clojure maven plugin, written by Mark Derricutt.
I&amp;rsquo;ve more or less followed this guide</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven module Base for cucumber in java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 07:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve built a small maven module, to be used directly with cucumber. You can fork the repository here
This is the setup I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed for the meetup &amp;ldquo;BDD Cucumber kata (gherkin + code)&amp;quot;. Will see if this code is successfully used by the ~40 participants in a couple of weeks
(Quote from the README.md):
This maven project has been possible due to Thomas Sundberg and this post
Should you want to, there&amp;rsquo;s a tweet to thank him the effort: [tweet intent here](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippets Stash</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/24/code-snippets-stash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 20:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/24/code-snippets-stash/</guid>
      <description>Following a team member&amp;rsquo;s recommendation, I recently started a repository to save all my useful snippets.
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that the examples should be designed guided by tests or at least to have a working example exercised by tests. Also, that I should not reinvent the wheel and use as many open source libraries as possible, reducing the amount of code I have to write myself.
Ideally, every snippet should be a maven project (where applicable) and be imported as a small library, therefore being able to reuse the functionality incrementally across projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
