<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>c on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in c on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>Scientific glassblower continues century-old campus tradition (2021) the story of a glassblower dedicated to producing specialized hardware for a university
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40549209
Tags: hackernews, imported, dredmorbius, glassblower, university, hardware, profession, glass
Id: e07b0ed2-185b-4cf7-bdbe-a134c555d797 Read: Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:26:29 +0000
Half a century of SQL https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40561440
Tags: hackernews, imported, pseudolus, sql, programming-language, anniversary, birthday
Id: f971c65c-8034-47c1-b2f5-24358c2de7b4 Read: Mon, 03 Jun 2024 11:04:06 +0000
Entropy, a CLI that scans files to find high entropy lines (might be secrets) https://news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Native C Library in Android</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2021/05/02/native-c-library-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 03:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2021/05/02/native-c-library-android/</guid>
      <description>For a client, we needed to integrate a pure C library into an android application.
The library is written in C (not C++), the application in Kotlin.
Context We have created an Android application, that is using a native C library. This library provides an upgrade in performance over using a JVM library.
For this particular example, we&amp;rsquo;re showcasing how to integrate libsodium, but this can be expanded to any other library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</guid>
      <description>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.
Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery
Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &amp;ldquo;Call me maybe&amp;rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
