<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/robert-martin/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/robert-martin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;until-the-end-of-the-internet&#34;&gt;Until the End of the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/until-the-end-of-the-internet-405d55fde60f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-agile-principles-can-fund-your-start-up&#34;&gt;How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/how-agile-principles-can-fund-your-start-up&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one. This works both ways: for buying and for selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests using a base plus the amount of sales in the last year * a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  jurgen-appelo, investment, startup, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-fell-in-love-with-a-programming-language&#34;&gt;How I fell in love with a programming language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/how-i-fell-in-love-with-a-programming-language-8933d5e749ed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Kim on the feelings of love and comfort he feels when he&amp;rsquo;s programming in Kotlin, for Android. Tells the story of DHH and the love of Ruby as a similar one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-kim, dhh, ruby, love-of-language, kotlin, android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-writing-for-the-busy-programmer&#34;&gt;Book writing for the busy programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://gigasquidsoftware.com/blog/2016/06/19/book-writing-for-the-busy-programmer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carin Meier on what tools she found useful for writing, editing and publishing a science fiction book she was writing for her daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tool, pandoc, carin-meier, book, book-writing, book-editing, book-publishing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-two-and-three-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;one-, two-, and three-factor authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://pciguru.wordpress.com/2010/05/01/one-two-and-three-factor-authentication/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Hall, that explains the factors in multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jeff-hall, ofa, 2fa, mfa, one-factor-authentication, two-factor-authentication, multi-factor-authentication, pci-guru, security, authentication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling-agile-a-law-and-two-paradoxes&#34;&gt;Scaling Agile: A Law And Two Paradoxes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://asprotunity.com/blog/scaling-agile-a-law-and-two-paradoxes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Giovanni Asproni about agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamental law of scaling: Scaling up amplifies the bad and makes the good more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First paradox of scaling: Most projects are scaled up because they don’t fulfill the prerequisites for scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second paradox of scaling: Projects fulfilling the prerequisites for scaling have a lesser need to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;quote&gt;Giovanni Asproni&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also goes on to explain ten prerequisites for scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scaled-agile, agile, giovanni-asproni, paradox, law&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carta-abierta-a-ese-empresario-que-no-encuentra-talento&#34;&gt;Carta abierta a ese empresario que no encuentra talento&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/espanol/carta-abierta-a-ese-empresario-que-no-encuentra-talento-669e28e4a89b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ignacio Segura reacting to a previous article about job offer and demand. Ignacio explains how the job market can be modeled and how workers have found ways of selling their time to the best price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ignacio-segura, analogy, job-offer, job, job-market, economy, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;david-dill-why-online-voting-is-a-danger-to-democracy&#34;&gt;David Dill: Why Online Voting Is a Danger to Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.stanford.edu/news/david-dill-why-online-voting-danger-democracy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to David Dill on why the online voting is not a good idea and we should stick to paper as the golden rule for voting processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how difficult is to convince people of the technical limitations and the massive incentive it would be to hack into election systems / services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, david-dill, online-voting, limitation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;clojure-gazette-tdd-in-clojure-on-android&#34;&gt;Clojure Gazette - TDD in Clojure on Android&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us4.campaign-archive2.com/?u=a33b5228d1b5bf2e0c68a83f4&amp;amp;id=7023cf0a33&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Alexander Yakushev, about his Google Summer of Code and the project he is currently working on: Clojure-android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, clojure-gazette, alexander-yakushev, google-summer-of-code, gsoc, clojure, tdd, android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-will-github-be-in-5-years&#34;&gt;What Will GitHub Be in 5 years?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/ben/what-will-github-be-in-5-years&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that describes the current state of Github business and the possible solutions in the upcoming five years. By Ben Halpern&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ben-halpern, github, economy, startup, investment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serverless-architectures&#34;&gt;Serverless Architectures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/serverless.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this evolving article&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Roberts on what is and is not Serverless: [mobile] backend as a service or function as a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Converts some n-tier applications into serverless ones, expliciting that this is only a way of doing it, not necessarily the way he would do it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: faas, baas, mbass, function-as-a-service, backend-as-a-service, mobile-backend-as-a-service, serverless, evolving-article, mike-roberts, lambda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-co-vs-small-co-job-vs-career-stability&#34;&gt;Big co. vs small co. &amp;amp; job vs. career stability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catehuston.com/blog/2016/06/02/job-vs-career-stability/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cate Huston on the career and job stability that big companies and small companies can offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job security means that you know you will keep getting a paycheck from $company. Career security means that you know you can get another job, and develop yourself and your career in the way that is meaningful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: job-security, cate-huston, big-company, small-company, career-security, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;copy-paste-code&#34;&gt;Copy. Paste. Code?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.devmastery.com/copy-paste-code-6ed9bb841cd4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Sourour on the different point of view of solving questions in coding many years ago compared to nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explores the concept of copy pasting code without understanding it, explaining that the endgame is writing good code that works and is easy to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: copy-paste, bill-sourour, clean-code, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-so-many-developers-hate-recruiters&#34;&gt;Why so many developers hate recruiters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-tech-recruiter-red-pill-967dd492560c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson on how recruiters for the IT sector work and how to work with them for your best possible outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career, professional-career, recruitment, recruiter, agent, hiring, quincy-larson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-time-someone-posts-one-of-these-coding-is-over-essays-on-medium-they-undo-a-good-chunk-of&#34;&gt;Every time someone posts one of these “coding is over” essays on Medium, they undo a good chunk of…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@quincylarson/every-time-someone-posts-one-of-these-coding-is-over-essay-on-medium-they-undo-a-good-chunk-of-b7989849390b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson on why we should not tell others about their choosing of learning programming, and every time we do, some doors close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: answer, learn-coding, related-to-article, quincy-larson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;29-behaviors-that-will-make-you-an-unstoppable-programmer&#34;&gt;29 Behaviors That Will Make You An Unstoppable Programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kenmazaika/29-behaviors-that-will-make-you-an-unstoppable-programmer-8778941d80f7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tricks to become a be a better programmer. By Ken Mazaika&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Google very aggressively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain an obnoxious amount of stick-to-itiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that micro-decisions matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that most major decisions don’t matter that much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always use the right tool for the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand that code is cheap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate technologies based on all their merits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say “I don’t know.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always analyze the clues found in error messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the difference between a premature optimization and a show-stopping optimization that NEEDS to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take responsibility for your mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a power-user of your development tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know how to use Vim (at least a little bit).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never accept freelance work in an unfamiliar technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t count the number of hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absorb massive criticism with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair program with people with more experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always code review your own work first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize that the hard part of freelancing isn’t writing the code. It’s everything else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and resolve bigger issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into large open source projects to bring your features to life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip a lot of meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know when it’s time to give back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be capable of writing bad code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let other people know that you’re working late without being a jerk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act as a leader, not a boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go play foosball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Move fast and break things.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ken-mazaika, list, unbeateable-programmer, unstoppable-programmer, efficiency, 10x, tip-and-trick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;como-melhorar-seus-códigos-usando-object-calisthenics-portuguese&#34;&gt;Como melhorar seus códigos usando Object Calisthenics (Portuguese)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/coderockr-way/como-melhorar-seus-c%C3%B3digos-usando-object-calisthenics-444daf3e2e06&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about object calisthenics, with an example in PHP. By Elton Minetto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: object-calisthenics, elton-minetto, php, portuguese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-this-story-without-distraction-can-you&#34;&gt;Read This Story Without Distraction (Can You?)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/01/fashion/monotasking-drop-everything-and-read-this-story.html?action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=Fashion%20%26%20Style&amp;amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;amp;region=Marginalia&amp;amp;pgtype=article&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Verena von Pfetten on the effects on multitasking in our daily lives. Also comments on the movement of monotasking or unitasking, which is the opposite of multitasking: doing one thing at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underlines the benefits of monotasking and how this is related to mindfulness and psychological benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: multitasking, monotasking, unitasking, verena-von-pfetten, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debuggers-are-a-wasteful-timesink&#34;&gt;Debuggers are a wasteful Timesink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artima.com/weblogs/viewpost.jsp?thread=23476&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C. Martin on why we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use debuggers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uncle-bob, robert-martin, debugger, tdd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;taming-the-steamroller-how-to-communicate-compassionately-with-non-native-english-speakers&#34;&gt;Taming the steamroller: how to communicate compassionately with non-native English speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mollyclare/taming-the-steamroller-how-to-communicate-compassionately-with-non-native-english-speakers-d95d8d1845a0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Molly Clare Wilson on tips on how native English speakers can simplify their communication so it is easier for non-native speakers to understand them. Provides guidelines for situations involving &amp;lsquo;speaking and presenting&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;meetings&amp;rsquo;, written form &amp;lsquo;email, text, chat&amp;rsquo; and about correction each others English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: molly-wilson, english, communication, native, non-native, guideline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blue-no-yellow&#34;&gt;Blue. No! Yellow!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/05/21/BlueNoYellow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with Robert C. Martin on the productivity increases that different languages provide to the programmer. He says that no language can provide an effect as big as binary to assembler and that we&amp;rsquo;re currently searching the Holy Grail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-martin, uncle-bob, language, comparison, assembler, binary, clojure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-time-development-teams-chose-their-own-working-environments&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Time Development Teams Chose Their Own Working Environments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codemanship.co.uk/parlezuml/blog/?postid=1383&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Gorman on how takes the decision of working environments and why having other options are financially available. How developers should be in charge of their own working environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: office, working-environment, jason-gorman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-my-1-200-hackintosh&#34;&gt;Building My $1,200 Hackintosh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/building-my-1-200-hackintosh-49a1a186241e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to build a powerful hackintosh. By Mike Rundle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mike-rundle, hackintosh, macintosh, mac, computer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-practical-guide-to-becoming-a-professional-web-developer&#34;&gt;The Practical Guide to Becoming a Professional Web Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-practical-guide-to-becoming-a-professional-web-developer-2f255bc25c90&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Sourour on how to become a web developer. Explains all kind of resources, from learning javascript, deciding on being a frontend of backend developer, which language to choose, how to find a job, getting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bill-sourour, guide, career, beginner, developer, web, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hiring-is-so-hard-in-tech&#34;&gt;Why Hiring is So Hard in Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/why-hiring-is-so-hard-in-tech-c462c3230017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Elliot on how to tackle job interviews, both from the side of the employer and the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-elliot, job-interview, employee, employer, cv, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-node-js-with-brigadier-fluffykins-part-ii-events-eventemitter-and-the-event-loop&#34;&gt;Learn Node.js with Brigadier Fluffykins Part II: Events, EventEmitter and the Event Loop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/learn-node-js-with-brigadier-fluffykins-part-ii-events-eventemitter-the-event-loop-6d4c139694fb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Masha Diminsky on the architecture of javascript and nodejs. Explains the event-driven architecture, the events and the event loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: masha-diminsky, bus, nodejs, javascript, bus, event-loop, event&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-in-6-seconds-how-to-write-a-résumé-that-employers-will-actually-read&#34;&gt;You in 6 seconds: how to write a résumé that employers will actually read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/you-in-6-seconds-how-to-write-a-r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9-that-employers-will-actually-read-fd7757740802&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that suggests how to customize your cv for maximum engagement from interviewers / head hunters and to make the most of the 6 seconds they (allegedly) spend looking at your cv. Also explains some techniques for preparing the interview, about the cover letter, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: quincy-larson, cv, resume, career, professional-career, ats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starbucks-does-not-use-two-phase-commit&#34;&gt;Starbucks Does Not Use Two-Phase Commit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/ramblings/18_starbucks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gregor Hohpe explaining how Starbucks is modeled in terms of asynchronous interactions and the actions for exception handling: write-off, retry, compensating action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also mentions Conversation pattern and Correlation ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gregor-hohpe, conversation-pattern, correlation-id, analogy, asynchronous, exception-handling, write-off, retry, compensating-action&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;diversitymediocrityillusion&#34;&gt;DiversityMediocrityIllusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DiversityMediocrityIllusion.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-cryptic-github-comments-mean&#34;&gt;What do cryptic Github comments mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/what-do-cryptic-github-comments-mean-9c1912bcc0a4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: github, pull-request, alex-beregszaszi, abbreviation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-erreurs-à-éviter-en-tant-que-développeur-freelance&#34;&gt;6 erreurs à éviter en tant que développeur freelance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@adrienjoly/enseignements-apr%C3%A8s-1-an-d-erreurs-en-tant-que-d%C3%A9veloppeur-freelance-916f855efd9b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (in French) by Adrien Joly on the mistakes freelancers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do when working with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrien-joly, freelance, list, mistake, french&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-methodology-s-promise-seems-to-fall-short-in-the-face-of-reality&#34;&gt;Agile Methodology’s Promise Seems To Fall Short in the Face of Reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@pagalvin/agile-methodology-s-promise-seems-to-fall-short-in-the-face-of-reality-b16d3e775dbe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on an experience by Paul Galvin on some failing agile implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: paul-galvin, agile, reality, agility, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-sharing-other-people-s-feelings-can-make-you-sick&#34;&gt;How sharing other people’s feelings can make you sick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg23030732-900-how-sharing-other-peoples-feelings-can-make-you-sick/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Emma Young on how being empathic to others can make you sick on their own illness. How illness can be socially transmitted, by loved ones or even by strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How algorithms (that display news) can affect your own well-being and how this is reduced by using compassion instead of empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borders on the difference of empathy vs compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: emma-young, empathy, compassion, feeling, team-management, vent-free-zone, sickness, illness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aws-lambda-for-beginners&#34;&gt;AWS Lambda for Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/aws-lambda-for-beginners&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mashooq Badar on an introduction to AWS Lambdas, where the basics are covered until getting a Lambda service in production. Using Python or Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mashooq-badar, serverless, aws, aws-lambda, lambda, python, java, devops, serverless-architecture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-logging-with-the-javascript-console&#34;&gt;Advanced Logging with the JavaScript Console&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://egghead.io/series/js-console-for-power-users&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this course&lt;/a&gt; by Mykola Bilokonsky at egghead.io.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, he covers the following methods on the console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;warn&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;info&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;debug&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of parameters does not matter, it will put a space in between. printing an object will print its values&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;console.log with the C&amp;rsquo;s printf syntax, as long as the first parameter is a string&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;object&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;groupCollapsed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;groupEnd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mykola-bilokonsky, logging, javascript, console, egghead, course&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-work-is-what-determines-your-future-spend-one-hour-per-day-doing-these-5-things-and-your-life-will-change-forever&#34;&gt;After work, is what determines your future! Spend one hour per day doing these 5 things and your life will change forever!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/after-work-what-determines-your-future-spend-one-hour-sundaram&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kalyana Sundaram on the activities we do at night, after a day&amp;rsquo;s work and how they influence our learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kalyana-sundaram, after-work, career, career-management, learning, lifelong-learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expert-resumé-driven-development&#34;&gt;Expert Resumé Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/tra/expert-resum-driven-development&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tariq Ali, where he explains the Resume-Driven Development, as a subset of the Principal-Agent Problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal (management) hires an Agent (a developer) to build a program and
allow the Agent to choose the tech stack. But the Agent&amp;rsquo;s interest (making his resumé
more impressive) can be orthogonal to the Principal&amp;rsquo;s interest (producing a great
product by using the &amp;ldquo;right tool&amp;rdquo; for the job). If the Principal allows the Agent to
do as he wish, then the Agent will do as he wishes, thereby leading to the Agent to
prosper and the Principal to suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gartner.com/technology/research/methodologies/hype-cycle.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gartner Hype Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tariq-ali, resume-driven-development, hype, cycle, hype-cycle, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resume-driven-development&#34;&gt;Resume Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2014/10/resume-driven-development.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Mike Loukides about the problem of finding a technical person based on CVs and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_the_instrument&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Law of the instrument&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] the inability of a technical team to specify what they really want
 (a developer with good programming taste and instincts), and
 instead hiring someone who has a particular skill or credential [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: law-instrument, mike-loukides, cv, career, resume-driven-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-britain-banned-mobile-apps&#34;&gt;Why Britain banned mobile apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://govinsider.asia/smart-gov/why-britain-banned-mobile-apps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with Ben Terrett, former design chief at the UK Government Digital Services (GDS), that explains why they prefer webapps rather than native (mobile) apps: it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of cost, having to maintain and update so many mobile versions, versus a single one for the webapp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also talks about user research and productagile teams inside the GDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview is written by Joshua Chambers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joshua-chambers, ben-terrett, gds, webapp, mobile-app, native-app, product-team, agile, government, uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-tech-interviews-suck-the-only-4-questions-that-matter&#34;&gt;Most Tech Interviews Suck — The Only 4 Questions That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/lightspeed-venture-partners/most-tech-interviews-suck-the-only-4-questions-that-matter-1a71181ef4d4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why the majority of technical interviews could be improved, asking four questions instead of following other practices. By Aaron Batalion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: aaron-batalion, tech-interview, hiring, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen&#34;&gt;Why Socrates UK is not just a conference for software craftsmen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codurance.com/2016/06/07/why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Giulia Mantuano on the SoCraTes UK 2016 conference, where she gave a talk on the importance of design in our environment, where we craft beautiful interfaces in our programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: socrates, socrates-uk, socrates-uk-2016, giulia-mantuano, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;360-million-reasons-to-destroy-all-passwords&#34;&gt;360 million reasons to destroy all passwords&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/360-million-reasons-to-destroy-all-passwords-9a100b2b5001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson about the insecurity of passwords, both managed by vaults (like LastPass) or remembered ones. They all are susceptible to being discovered, leaked or shared to other sites / accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author suggests to use passwordless login, which sends a link to your email account, which allows you to log in to the application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: passwordless, lastpass, vault, password-vault, quincy-larson, hack, leak, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brutally-honest-rejection-letter-by-an-hr&#34;&gt;A Brutally Honest Rejection Letter by an HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-coffeelicious/a-brutally-honest-rejection-letter-by-an-hr-493164bc5205&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this parody letter&lt;/a&gt; by Nish Rao, on the real reasons so HR uses these templates for rejecting candidates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nish-rao, parody, rejection-letter, hr, human-resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;passwords-are-obsolete&#34;&gt;Passwords are Obsolete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ninjudd/passwords-are-obsolete-9ed56d483eb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Justin Balthrop on how to set up a passwordless system and how is that related to the Heartbleed bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: passwordless, justin-balthrop, heartbleed, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;server-side-swift-vs-the-other-guys-2-speed&#34;&gt;Server Side Swift vs. The Other Guys — 2: Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@qutheory/server-side-swift-vs-the-other-guys-2-speed-ca65b2f79505&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comparison&lt;/a&gt; of languages and frameworks (Vapor (Swift), Ruby on Rails (Ruby), Laravel (PHP), Lumen (PHP), Express (JavaScript), Django (Python), Flask (Python), Spring (Java), Nancy (C#), Go (Pure Go, no framework)) and to benchmark Plaintext, JSON, Random SQLite Fetch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, qutheory, speed, swift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;compilers-as-assistants&#34;&gt;Compilers as Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org/blog/compilers-as-assistants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Evan Czaplicki on seeing the compiler as an assistant to your work, instead of an adversary. Of how the compiler should give the most useful errors and warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also explains what features have been removed from the Elm language in 0.16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: compiler, assistant, adversary, enemy, elm, elm-compiler, evan-czaplicki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;craftsmanship-design-and-code&#34;&gt;Craftsmanship, design, and code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/craftsmanship-design-and-code-6d93eba3e7fe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Z. White about the relation between design and code and what craftsmanship is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests learning more about the counterpart (design vs code), to better understand the activity of creating software as a whole. For developers, suggests a few activities to improve (e.g., read better code, write unit tests, analyze code). Cites that the only way of measuring progress is comparing where you are today compared to some time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: craftsmanship, jonathan-white, design, code, improving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-programmer-s-oath&#34;&gt;The Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Oath&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2015/11/18/TheProgrammersOath.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this oath&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: oath, programmer, craft, manifesto, robert-martin, uncle-bob&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intel-x86s-hide-another-cpu-that-can-take-over-your-machine-you-can-t-audit-it&#34;&gt;Intel x86s hide another CPU that can take over your machine (you can&amp;rsquo;t audit it)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://boingboing.net/2016/06/15/intel-x86-processors-ship-with.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Damien Zammit on the Intel Management Engine (ME), a hardware system that is embedded in the newer Intel chipsets. Its function is to provide low-level management services. ME (like Active Management Technology [AMT] in the past), provides great services, but has access to any memory location and to the TCP/IP stack, without any control from the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The firmware is currently checked before booting, but it is highly-valuable as a security risk, as it has full access to the physical hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: security, damien-zammit, intel-management-engine, active-management-technology, me, amt, tcp-ip, backdoor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-doesn-t-require-talent-or-even-passion&#34;&gt;Programming Doesn’t Require Talent or Even Passion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@WordcorpGlobal/programming-doesnt-require-talent-or-even-passion-11422270e1e4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of examples of why programming doesn&amp;rsquo;t require talent or passion, by Tony You&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: talent, passion, list, programming, tony-you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-from-to&#34;&gt;Getting from ⭐️⭐️ to ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/getting-from-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-to-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-c65cc3bb7cb1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Basecamp increased their ratings at the App Store: notify the user about new features and, in that modal, ask them to review the app or dismiss. By Dylan Ginsburg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: review, user-engagement, rating, basecamp, dylan-ginsburg, app-store, app&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard&#34;&gt;Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@benedictfritz/learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard-40a4cf3104f4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;becodeweek-by-yeray-darias&#34;&gt;BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this category of posts&lt;/a&gt; by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;becodeweek-by-yeray-darias-1&#34;&gt;BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this category of posts&lt;/a&gt; by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracer-bullets&#34;&gt;Tracer Bullets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TracerBullets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; about tracer bullets, an analogy from the military warfare to a software project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serves the purpose of adjusting the aim of the cannon to better reach the target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: analogy, metaphor, warfare, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cohesion-the-cornerstone-of-software-design&#34;&gt;Cohesion - the cornerstone of software design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codurance.com/2016/03/03/cohesion-cornerstone-software-design/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sandro Mancuso on the topic of cohesion. Describes the 7 types of cohesion, as described in Structured Design&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, from worst to best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coincidental cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procedural cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicational/informational cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequential cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and about Design-Level Cohesion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coincidental relation (R1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditional relation (R2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterative relation (R3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication relation (R4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequential relation (R5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional (R6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cohesion, codurance, edward-yourdon, larry-constantine, list, sandro-mancuso, software-design, design-level-cohesion, smc-cohesion, dlc-cohesion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;etsy-cto-q-a-we-need-software-engineers-not-developers&#34;&gt;Etsy CTO Q&amp;amp;A: We Need Software Engineers, Not Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/etsy-cto-qa-need-software-engineers-not-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with John Allspaw, where they explain the onboarding experience for new hires at Etsy, the DevOps philosophy and the need for engineering skills, more than developer skills. This can be exemplified in the need to know more, defining the boundaries of your job and finding the right tool for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: devops, interview, q-and-a, john-allspaw, etsy, onboarding, hire, team-management, deploy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequency-reduces-difficulty&#34;&gt;Frequency Reduces Difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/FrequencyReducesDifficulty.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Martin Fowler on why we should repeat things that are difficult for us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfectioning the technique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internalizing the details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easing its automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-fowler, automation, process, perfection, internalizing, technique, detail, process-theory, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lambdas-are-confusing&#34;&gt;Lambdas are confusing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video where Coman Hamilton from JAXenter interviews Dr. Heinz Kabutz about Java&amp;rsquo;s lambda syntax. Cites the problem with exceptions, generics, method overloading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: java, lambda, coman-hamilton, jaxenter, heinz-kabutz, problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-full-stack-developer-en-2016&#34;&gt;El full-stack developer en 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.developerdepueblo.com/development/full-stack-developer-2016/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jose Ignacio Andrés about the job descriptions of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El principal valor de un full-stack es poder simplificar el trabajo a los demás miembros del equipo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My translation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main value of a full-stack developer is to be able to simplify other teammates&amp;rsquo; work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: teamwork, teammate, fullstack, simplification, work, team-management, jose andres&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-a-software-craftsman&#34;&gt;I am a software craftsman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dirv.me/i-am-a-software-craftsman/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Irvine about calling yourself a craftsman or not. He says that if you adhere to their values, you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: craftsmanship, label, daniel-irvine, craftsman, group-belonging&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-programming-languages-in-a-post-linnaean-age&#34;&gt;Teaching Programming Languages in a Post-Linnaean Age&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Papers/Published/sk-teach-pl-post-linnaean/paper.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; by Shriram Krishnamurthi where he explains the need for books like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plai.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PLAI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lack of paradigms in new languages, and its separation (or lack of)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design of languages cheaper and cheaper these days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rigor level in publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inductive and deductive learning
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;post-Linnaean&lt;/code&gt; refers to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Linnaeus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Carl Linnaeus&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is known as the father of modern taxonomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: inductive-learning, deductive-learning, dsl, domain-specific-language, type-soundness, continuation-style, garbage-collection, reactive-programming, scheme, plai, teaching, programming-language, shriram-krishnamurthi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lazy-ruby&#34;&gt;Lazy Ruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sonnym.github.io/2014/04/05/lazy-ruby/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by sonnym about using ruby&amp;rsquo;s lazy (non-strict) features, detailing an example with Fibonacci&amp;rsquo;s sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: laziness, strictness, non-strictness, ruby, fibonacci, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jessica-livingston&#34;&gt;Jessica Livingston&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/jessica.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this essay&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Graham about his co-founder at the Y-combinator: Jessica Livingston. She was considered the Social Radar at YC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essay also talks about the non-existent separation between working hours and not and about her implication and personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jessica-livingston, paul-graham, y-combinator, feminism, yc, essay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1&#34;&gt;Four Laws Of Software Economics (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@RichMironov/four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1-e162aa0ea9e5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rich Mironov on why the development team will never be big enough (because of economics, because there are more things to be done than time to do them, so we have to prioritize them) and about the communication problems between the dev team and the client(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also talks about the general personality of clients and devs and task prioritization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: exclusive-or, magical-thinking, tnstaafl, management, agile, team, capacity, death-march, estj, intp, software-economics, product-strategy, law-of-ruthless-prioritization, law, rich-mironov, slack, myers-briggs-type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-should-take-a-codecation&#34;&gt;You Should Take A Codecation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://robots.thoughtbot.com/you-should-take-a-codecation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Orenstein explaining what is a codecation and what he&amp;rsquo;s done in the two codecations he&amp;rsquo;s taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: codecation, ben-orenstein, vacation, holiday, coding, shipping, in-company&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;giving-up-on-tdd&#34;&gt;Giving Up on TDD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://iansommerville.com/systems-software-and-technology/giving-up-on-test-first-development/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ian Sommerville about the problems he&amp;rsquo;s found while doing TDD, mainly about design, but also about being conservative in the amount of tests you allow yourself to break while refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdd, ian-sommerville, refactoring, problem, design-problem, design, giving-up-tdd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;giving-up-on-tdd-answer&#34;&gt;Giving Up on TDD - answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/03/19/GivingUpOnTDD.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C. Martin on the common issues for people adopting TDD:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fragile Test Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Design Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Testable Design Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Magic Bullet Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is an answer to another by Ian Sommerville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdd, uncle-bob, robert-martin, adoption, ian-sommerville, fragile-test-problem, giving-up-tdd, design-problem, testable-design-problem, magic-bullet-problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;seek-out-jobs-with-fast-learning-cycles&#34;&gt;Seek out jobs with fast learning cycles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sarahtavel/seek-out-jobs-with-fast-learning-cycles-f923c8d8a4be#.7bxx65a4x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sarah Tavel on learning on the job and how fast these learning cycles can happen at companies at different stages of maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you’re thinking of changing jobs, or taking your first, my advice: find a place with a fast learning cycle, and a steep learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: learning, job, hypothesis, sarah-tavel, learning-cycle, maturity-level, learning-process, product-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-code-vs-implementation-patterns&#34;&gt;Clean Code Vs. Implementation Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.xebia.com/clean-code-vs-implementation-patterns/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comparison&lt;/a&gt; of Clean Code vs Implementation Pattern books, by Vincent Partington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, the author explains the differences in style in both books, and how they compare to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clean-code, implementation-patterns, comparison, book-review, book-comparison, vincent-partington&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stuck-in-traffic-vlog-103-new-spammer-techniques&#34;&gt;Stuck in Traffic vlog #103 - New Spammer Techniques&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.peerlyst.com/posts/stuck-in-traffic-vlog-103-new-spammer-techniques-j-wolfgang-goerlich&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this vlog entry&lt;/a&gt; on machines fighting machines (exemplified with the spam producing and filtering) and how some spammers are trying more direct techniques focusing on higher-value targets, sometimes even handcrafting messages and modifying them every few units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wolfgang-goerlich, spam, vlog, spammer, machine-learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;becoming-a-finisher&#34;&gt;Becoming A Finisher&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://christopherdbui.com/becoming-a-finisher/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher Bui where he explains that projects that are too ambitious stall your productivity and make you lose your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christopher-bui, pomodoro, time-management, productivity, motivation, ambition, paul-graham, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanging-around-with-red-black-tree-implementations-the-beginnings&#34;&gt;Hanging around with red-black tree implementations: the beginnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fraixed.es/post/hanging-around-red-black-trees-implementations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ivan Fraixedes where he details the progress of implementing a red-black tree, and also his motivation for doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ivan-fraixedes, red-black-tree, abstract-data-structure, adt, deliberate-practice, pet-project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-tools-for-faster-blogging-in-octopress&#34;&gt;Some Tools for Faster Blogging in Octopress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://dgmstuart.github.io/blog/2015/03/27/some-tools-for-faster-blogging-in-octopress/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for tips and tricks on how to blog faster with octopress. Written by Duncan Stuart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: duncan-stuart, blog, improvement, meta, octopress, tip-and-trick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-veil-of-ignorance&#34;&gt;The veil of ignorance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrmrs.io/writing/2016/03/23/the-veil-of-ignorance/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Adam Morse on how not being on the top of the skills performance can affect your design and your user experience. Also, references the concept of &amp;ldquo;The Veil of Ignorance&amp;rdquo;, a concept by John Rawls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-rawls, veil-of-ignorance, user-experience, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-smile-again-recovering-from-the-paralysis-of-burnout&#34;&gt;To Smile Again &amp;ndash; Recovering from the paralysis of burnout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/to-smile-again-ae0ba9f2198c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jamis Buck on his story of burnout, what symptoms had on him and how he got out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: burnout, jamis-buck, psychology, productivity, personal, story, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-email-could-startup-slack-change-the-way-you-work&#34;&gt;Beyond email: could startup Slack change the way you work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/mar/25/slack-butterfield-emoji-chat-nasa-harvard-silicon-valley&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on Slack&amp;rsquo;s office culture, with their diversity, policies and values after a high people growth in a short period of time. By Jemima Kiss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: culture, office-culture, slack, jemima-kiss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slack-work-this-way&#34;&gt;Slack: Work This Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@iaintait/slack-work-this-way-9221284472dd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, a response to my above read, about the office culture at Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: iain-tait, response, slack, office-culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bem-101&#34;&gt;BEM 101&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/bem-101/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this introduction&lt;/a&gt; to a CSS style called Block, Element, Modifier methodology (BEM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a block is a top-level abstraction of a new component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Child items, or elements, can be placed inside and these are denoted by two underscores following the name of the block [&amp;hellip;].
modifiers can manipulate the block so that we can theme or style that particular component without inflicting changes on a completely unrelated module. This is done by appending two hyphens to the name of the block [&amp;hellip;].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Joe Richardson, Robin Rendle et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joe-richardson, robin-rendle, bem, css, css-methodology, introduction, css-architecture, sass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Structured Design: Fundamentals of a Discipline of Computer Program and Systems Design by Yourdon and Constantine.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blazing-fast-html-virtual-dom-in-elm&#34;&gt;Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org/blog/blazing-fast-html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-should-never-ever-ever-use-mongodb&#34;&gt;Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://cryto.net/~joepie91/blog/2015/07/19/why-you-should-never-ever-ever-use-mongodb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-really-get-classloaders&#34;&gt;Do you really get classloaders?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/rebel-labs-tutorial-do-you-really-get-classloaders/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the classloading is lazy: the resources are not loaded until they are mentioned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every classloader has a parent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every class has a classloader associated with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every object has a class associated with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;classloading delegation: the parent is consulted before loading a class. if it has it, it will load it. If not, I will delegate it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaworld.com/article/2074396/core-java/javaone-2011--do-you-really-get-classloaders-.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on the same video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jevgeny-kabanov, classloader, java,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth-table&#34;&gt;Truth table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truth_table&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; about the truth table and the 16 possible binary boolean operators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contradiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NOR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converse nonimplication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negation (of p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Material nonimplication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negation (of q)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XOR (exclusive disjunction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAND&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND (conjunction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XNOR (biconditional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projection (of p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projection (of q)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converse implication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR (disjunction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tautology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-lines-of-code-3-minutes-implement-a-programming-language-from-scratch&#34;&gt;7 lines of code, 3 minutes: Implement a programming language from scratch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://matt.might.net/articles/implementing-a-programming-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Might about the benefits of implementing a language (from scratch but on top of another existing language used as framework). Chooses lambda calculus as the desired DSL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matt-might, lambda-calculus, racket, domain-specific-language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turing-completeness&#34;&gt;Turing completeness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; (both main and discussion) about this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has sounded strange to me the reference to S-expressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data languages
The notion of Turing-completeness does not apply to languages such as XML, HTML, JSON, YAML and S-expressions because they are typically used to represent structured data, not describe computation [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If data (S-expression) is represented as the same format as code (e.g., Lisp&amp;rsquo;s S-expression) and the latter is used to represent a computation, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;ldquo;data languages that also are used as computation languages&amp;rdquo; excluded from that list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, Lisp is Turing Complete (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness#Examples&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Turing Complete#Examples&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prize-is-won-the-simplest-universal-turing-machine-is-proved&#34;&gt;The Prize Is Won; The Simplest Universal Turing Machine Is Proved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wolfram.com/2007/10/24/the-prize-is-won-the-simplest-universal-turing-machine-is-proved/?year=2007&amp;amp;monthnum=10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Wolfram about the proof of a Turing Machine 2,3 being universal by Alex Smith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: stephen-wolfram, turing-machine, universal-turing-machine, proof, paper, alex-smith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-a-successful-commitment-in-each-sprint&#34;&gt;Making a successful commitment in each Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://succeeding-with-agile.blogspot.com/2015/07/making-successful-commitment-in-each.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nikolaos Raptis on committing to work in each sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nikolaos-raptis, sprint, agile, commitment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-increment-operator-in-ruby&#34;&gt;No increment operator (++) in Ruby?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3717519/no-increment-operator-in-ruby&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; question about the lack of post-increment operator (i++) in Ruby:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++ and &amp;ndash; are NOT reserved operator in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mailing list from &lt;a href=&#34;http://blade.nagaokaut.ac.jp/cgi-bin/scat.rb/ruby/ruby-talk/2710&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yukihiro Matsumoto aka matz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-is-data-data-is-code&#34;&gt;Code is Data, Data is Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.mulesoft.com/dev/news-dev/code-is-data-data-is-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Donelan on the equivalence of code and data in homoiconic languages, including Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article talks about homoiconicity, manually creating Abstract Syntax Trees (AST) out of data and the macro environment. Also, compares the difference between macros and functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: code=data, data=code, james-donelan, clojure, homoiconicity, abstract-syntax-tree, ast, macro, function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-in-practice-test-driven-development&#34;&gt;Agile in Practice: Test Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGaNkTahrIw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; introducing TDD by the Agile Academy. Explains its motivations and the basic cyclical fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: agile-academy, video, tdd, introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-in-practice-pair-programming&#34;&gt;Agile in Practice: Pair Programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ET3Q6zNK3Io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Agile Academy on practicing pair programming. Explains the destination and how to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: agile-academy, pair-programming, video, introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-low-cost-approach-to-working-on-side-projects&#34;&gt;A low cost approach to working on side projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://practicingruby.com/articles/low-cost-approach-to-side-projects&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gregory Brown on how to apply the MVP and Lean Startup principles to side projects (a.k.a. pet projects). Try to start with a brainstorming session of all the features you want your product to have, then prioritise, picking the most important ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most projects&amp;rsquo; needs can be solved with a minimal version, in the form of a script that took half an hour to develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gregory-brown, mvp, lean-startup, script, proof-of-concept, priority, backlog, side-project, pet-project, low-cost, cost-reduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extreme-programming&#34;&gt;Extreme Programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kFM2Vcu-BRo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by STAR Videos on the basic principles behind Extreme Programming and how to use it to improve software quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: star-videos, extreme-programming, xp, software-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disruptor-high-performance-alternative-to-bounded-queues-for-exchanging-data-between-concurrent-threads&#34;&gt;Disruptor: High performance alternative to bounded queues for exchanging data between concurrent threads&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lmax-exchange.github.io/disruptor/files/Disruptor-1.0.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this white paper&lt;/a&gt; describing the disruptor framework: a way of exchanging data between concurrent threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses a ring buffer and other techniques to eliminate write contention, reduce read contention and produces good results. It was developed for a financial exchange environment but it&amp;rsquo;s general purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-thompson, dave-farley, michael-barker, patricia-gee, andrew-stewart, trisha-gee, disruptor, contention, framework, concurrency, parallelism, white-paper, comparison, arrayblockingqueue, concurrentlinkedqueue, doug-lea, benchmark, lmax, low-level-optimization, optimization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dissecting-the-disruptor-what-s-so-special-about-a-ring-buffer&#34;&gt;Dissecting the Disruptor: What&amp;rsquo;s so special about a ring buffer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2011/06/dissecting-disruptor-whats-so-special.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the ring buffer data structure. A FIFO data structure where elements get overwritten to reduce pressure on the garbage collector. Every message gets sent to every consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: patricia-gee, trisha-gee, disruptor, ring-buffer, data-structure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dependency-inversion-principle&#34;&gt;The Dependency Inversion Principle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.objectmentor.com/resources/articles/dip.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about the Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) written Robert C. Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It explains the theory, philosophy behind it. Also, creates an example with a copy buffer and different output locations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-martin, dependency-inversion-principle, dip, example, comparison, object-oriented, principle, solid, design-principle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dip-in-the-wild&#34;&gt;DIP in the Wild&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/dipInTheWild.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) written by Brett L. Schuchert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is explained non-canonical representations of this principle, how in other cases he has solved it and conclusions of using it day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brett-l.-schuchert, dependency-inversion-principle, dip, example, object-oriented, solid, design-principle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-new-product-development-game&#34;&gt;The New New Product Development Game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/1986/01/the-new-new-product-development-game&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about the holistic approach to product development, considered seminal for Scrum and other Agile methodologies. Written by Hirotaka Takeuchi and Ikujiro Nonaka&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, they describe how teams are distributed, the responsibilities for each one, and the degrees of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the six basic characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built-in instability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-organizing project teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overlapping development phases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multilearning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subtle control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organizational transfer of learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: hirotaka-takeuchi, ikujiro-nonaka, scrum, agile, product-development, management, 1986&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>