<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Q3 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Q3 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Bushido, the soul of Japan; Nitobe; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 1); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy My Story, Al Maktoum; non-technical  My Story, Al Maktoum  This important collection of anecdotes and reminiscences from Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum is published to mark the occasion of his fifty years in public service, which began with his appointment as Dubai’s Minister of Defence in 1968.
These stories tell of the vision behind Dubai’s meteoric growth from a small and bustling trading port to an international metropolis at the heart of global business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles Book of Transformation; Dalai Lama  Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book on philosophy and ethics. This book contains an analysis of the relationship between the personality, intelligence and happiness.
Tries to describe what &amp;lsquo;virtues&amp;rsquo; are, that they belong in a continuum of acts, aand the good term is always in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 the senior software developer; Copeland, with the aprendices reading club Scandal in Bohemia, a; Doyle: a short novel by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, mentioning Irene Adler and the king of Bohemia Getting things done, &amp;hellip;; Allen (+): A book on productivity, where Allen explains his method of GTD and how to apply it. Explains what has worked and not worked for him in his many years of consulting and coaching clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/books-read-in-2016q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/books-read-in-2016q3/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Pocket Guide by Chromatic Notes to a Software Team Leader (1st Edition), by Roy Osherove  Non-technical:
 The Zero Marginal Cost Society: The Internet of Things, the Collaborative Commons, and the Eclipse of Capitalism, by Jeremy Rifkin Snow Crash, by Neal Stephenson La guerra no tiene rostro de mujer, by Svetlana Aleksiévich  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Talking with Tech Leads: From Novices to Practitioners by Patrick Kua  Books I want to finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/books-read-in-2015q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/books-read-in-2015q3/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 The Craftsman by Richard Sennett. Posts under the tag the-craftsman Software Craftsmanship: The New Imperative by Pete McBreen. Posts under the tag software-craftsmanship-book Lisp Hackers by Vsevolod Dyomkin The Passionate Programmer: Creating a Remarkable Career in Software Development by Chad Fowler.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Haskell Programming, By Chris Allen and Julie Moronuki. This book is still in progress and I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing it Functional Programming Patterns in Scala and Clojure by Michael Bevilacqua-Linn Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt  Books I want to finish:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
