<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>decision-making on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/decision-making/</link>
    <description>Recent content in decision-making on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/decision-making/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/01/self-study-may-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/01/self-study-may-2019/</guid>
      <description>The Problem of Thinking Too Much An example of what happens when you think too much. The paralysis that comes from it
Tags: persi-diaconis, stanford, stated-meeting-report, barry-mazur, spin-a-penny, decision-making, decision
Id: e14aba08-7add-11e9-9e23-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 20 May 2019 09:01:39 +0000
Personal web archives; a report Creating a personal web archive, based on the tools they created.
a browser extension for storing web pages, a web archive server hosting such snapshots, a(nother) browser extension to query such archives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/01/self-study-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/01/self-study-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>How the Clipboard Works, Part 1 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Matt Burrough, on how the clipboard works on windows.
Explains how the API works and how the different formats and priorities are organized so the new application can decide which format to accept.
Tags: windows, clipboard, matt-burrough, format, copy-paste
Top developers can have a life outside coding I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Belen Albeza on how top coders don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend all their time programming or with activities related to programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</guid>
      <description>Should Engineers Design? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cap Watkins where he explains the relationship between designers and programmers and how to get the latter involved in the design / UX / UI process.
Tags: cap-watkins, design, ux, ui, exchange, cross-functional
The Sliding Scale of Giving a Fuck I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cap Watkins where he explains that different topics have a different importance to each one of us: this topic might be very important for someone else, ergo, it makes mores sense to evaluate their option more carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
