<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>formulation on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/formulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in formulation on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:44:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/formulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brownish Greenfield Gilded Rose Kata</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/brownish-greenfield-gilded-rose-kata-formulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/brownish-greenfield-gilded-rose-kata-formulation/</guid>
      <description>(This formulation has been copied and adapted from Bobby Johnson and Terry Hughes&amp;rsquo;s repository)
Formulation Hi and welcome to team Gilded Rose. As you know, we are a small inn with a prime location in a prominent city ran by a friendly innkeeper named Allison. We also buy and sell only the finest goods.
Unfortunately, our goods are constantly degrading in quality as they approach their sell by date. We have a system in place that updates our inventory for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kata formulation: Find the comments</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/01/kata-formulation-find-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 08:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/01/kata-formulation-find-comments/</guid>
      <description>Little Johnny is inspecting a PHP source code that contains comments. These comments contains words that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand, as it written in another language.
Rules and constraints The source code in the PHP files does not need to be correct.
A comment (a subset of PHP comments) is defined as:
 A line containing C-style comment delimiter, except when it is within a string  // hello C-style is a valid comment echo &amp;quot;//&amp;quot;; is not a comment echo &#39;//&#39;; is not a comment   A line containing Perl-style comment delimiter, except when it is within a string  # hello Perl-style is a valid comment echo &amp;quot;#&amp;quot;; is not a comment echo &#39;#&#39;; is not a comment   There are no multi-line comments  /* .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
