<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>legacy on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/legacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in legacy on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/legacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote: Characterization tests</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/quote-characterization-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/quote-characterization-tests/</guid>
      <description>In Working effectively with legacy code, Michael Feathers talks a type of tests to define or characterize the current behavior of the legacy system:
 In nearly every legacy system, what the system does is more important than what it is supposed to do.
A characterization test is a test that characterizes the actual behavior of a piece of code. [&amp;hellip;] The test document the actual current behavior of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session: refactoring legacy code</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/brownbag-session-refactoring-legacy-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 13:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/brownbag-session-refactoring-legacy-code/</guid>
      <description>Today I have done a brown bag session about refactoring legacy code. It includes:
 legacy code definition. There is no agreement about this in the team. the legacy code change algorithm (source is Feathers, Working effectively with legacy code). Plus an example about it. working with legacy code experience with it.  The slides are available here (PDF format)
We also did a practical session, whose experience report is here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
