<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Q2 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Q2 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Skunk Works; Rich; own-it, non-technical  Skunk Works This book describes Ben R. Rich&amp;rsquo;s adventure of creating the F-117A, the stealth plane with a triangular shape.
Describes how he won a bet against legendary plane designer Clarence &amp;lsquo;Kelly&amp;rsquo; Johnson. How he got the 25 cents from his old mentor and friend.
Later, the book reviews Kelly&amp;rsquo;s history as the manager of Skunk Works, how it works, the principles (Kelly&amp;rsquo;s 14 rules), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein; own-it, finance, non-technical Candide; Voltaire; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Simple path to wealth, the; Collins; own-it, non-technical, finance Lagom; Brantmark; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Comment revivre par le jeune; Lützner; own-it, non-technical Educación financiera avanzada desde cero; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance Pensiones públicas, la esclavitud de nuestra época; Hernández; non-technical, own-it, finance On the shortness of life; Séneca; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Código del dinero, el; Samsó; own-it, non-technical, finance Más cosas sobre la bolsa; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance  4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein Candide; Voltaire Came across this book as the source for the term &amp;lsquo;Panglossian&amp;rsquo; or extreme optimist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Quien se ha llevado mi queso; Johnson; own-it, guillem One minute manager, the; Blanchard; own-it, non-technical, guillem En defensa de los ociosos; Stevenson; non-technical, own-it Ladybird Book of Mindfulness, the (Ladybirds for Grown-Ups); Hazeley, Morris; non-technical Art of the start, the; Kawasaki; own-it, non-technical, guillem Getting started with NoFap; non-technical Emotional intelligence; Goleman; non-technical  Quien se ha llevado mi queso I&amp;rsquo;ve read this fable explaining the little story of two mice and two lilliputians that end up without any cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</guid>
      <description>(I&amp;rsquo;ve changed how I organize my books. More, here (TODO))
Finished:
 Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern; non-technical. A quick introduction to Bertrand Russell, his life and his way of thinking and seeing the world. Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell; non-technical. A first-person view of the events during the Spanish Civil War (1936-1939), seen from the perspective of a British citizen that went there voluntarily. Explains the internal fracture of the left political parties and the fracture of the Spanish society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change, 2nd Edition by Kent Beck and Cynthia Andres, again. Building Microservices, Designing Fine-Grained Systems, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Reinventing Organizations by Frederic Laloux. Blog posts under the tag reinventing-organizations  Non-technical:
 L&amp;rsquo;acabadora, by Michela Murgia Disrupted: My Misadventure in the Start-Up Bubble by Dan Lyons  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/books-read-in-2015q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/books-read-in-2015q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q2 on 2015:
 Flow by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi. Blog posts under the tag flow Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce. Blog posts under the tag goos. Read in the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. TDD in Java, by Viktor Farcic and Alex García. I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed this book.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 The Well-Grounded Java Developer by Benjamin J.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
