<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>function on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/function/</link>
    <description>Recent content in function on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/function/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>Lessons in Agile: Six Months at Pivotal I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Maryam Labib where she explains what she has learned in the last 6 months at Pivotal: how to pair program, how to TDD and some good practices to be a better developer.
Tags: maryam-labib, pivotal, career, professional-career, tdd, pair-programming, team, lessons-learned, experience
Hacking verbal communication systems I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Ryan Alexander on what kind of systems humans use to communicate and how to improve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure and the macro and</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/08/clojure-and-the-macro-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 17:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/08/clojure-and-the-macro-and/</guid>
      <description>While on the REPL, I tried this:
simple.core=&amp;gt; (reduce and true [true]) CompilerException java.lang.RuntimeException: Can&amp;#39;t take value of a macro: #&amp;#39;clojure.core/and, compiling:(form-init7116694665186998245.clj:1:1) Reading the clojuredocs for and, you can find this:
 Note add is a macro, so you cannot apply it. For example, there is a vector of some Boolean values [true true false true], which you want to test to see if they are all true. The code below will not work:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
