<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/microservice-practitioners/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/microservice-practitioners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!--
## Gerald Weinberg on Bugs, Errors, and Software Quality

I&#39;ve listened to [this interview][bug-error-weinberg] with Gerald Weinberg where he first talks about software quality, defining a fault, failure, a boo-boo, a blunder (below). Then, they move on to the cost of quality, experiences in his project &#39;Mercury&#39; (a man in orbit; his contribution was on the software side). Says it&#39;s one of his first projects where a person&#39;s life was directly related to a piece of software.

Fault: wrong operation in code
Failure: user&#39;s experience caused by a fault
Boo-boo: a one-off, small failure. Usually shrugged as a small defect
Blunder: a one-off, big failure. Can kill a career

About the cost of software, he mentions that many managers are not willing to pay the price of almost defect-free software and that this level of quality is not required in every project. This idea is similar to the one &#39;Testing every part is akin to reading every letter on the newspaper: one parts are more important than other&#39;.

This interview talks about similar topics than &#39;Why programs fail&#39;, especially about the definition.

At the end of the interview, he talks about team-based software development (~XP) and an anecdote about a company he was consulting with: follow the process or pay the defects out of your own pocket. One of them, accepted paying for defects, until he made a big mistake. Accepted training the rest of the employees into his very precise methods and became very valuable to the company.

Tags: podcast, gerald-weinberg, quality, interview, manager, software-quality, definition, fault, failure, boo-boo, blunder, project-mercury

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;!--
## Microservice Practitioners with Austin Gunter and Richard Li

I&#39;ve listened to [this podcast][us-practitioners] at Software Engineering Daily with Austin Gunter and Richard Li. In it, they talk about how they have organized the conference &#39;Microservice Practicitioners&#39;: how to find speakers, the vibes of the conference, etc.

Tags: austin-gunter, richard-li, organize-a-conference, conference, microservice, microservice-practitioners, podcast, software-engineering-daily

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34;&gt;10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/derickbailey/10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this listicle&lt;/a&gt; of docker myths. By Derick Bailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bored-people-quit&#34;&gt;Bored People Quit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://randsinrepose.com/archives/bored-people-quit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-lopp, boredness, team-management, people, career, tech-lead, quote&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>