<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spanish on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/spanish/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spanish on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/spanish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB
Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable
Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000
Jepsen: Aerospike I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies
Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos
Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.
Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning
Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>Lessons in Agile: Six Months at Pivotal I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Maryam Labib where she explains what she has learned in the last 6 months at Pivotal: how to pair program, how to TDD and some good practices to be a better developer.
Tags: maryam-labib, pivotal, career, professional-career, tdd, pair-programming, team, lessons-learned, experience
Hacking verbal communication systems I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Ryan Alexander on what kind of systems humans use to communicate and how to improve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Diseño Ágil con TDD (Spanish)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book Diseño Ágil con TDD (Spanish) by Carlos Blé from cover to cover, when previously I had only read the theoretical parts (Part I and Chapter 12 in Part II).
It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that this is the first TDD book in Spanish (I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any book in Spanish predating this one - also backed by the author; published in January 2010) and, as such, there are some translations that could be improved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
