<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 12 rules for life; Peterson; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  12 rules for life The book contains some rules, some principles to remove doubt and uncertainty from life.
There are plenty of mentions to the Bible, although I consider the book to the secular in its contents.
There are few personal stories on the book (e.g., about his daughter Mikhaila Peterson), which makes it readable and enjoyable. The philosophy behind it is sometimes not-politically-correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Bushido, the soul of Japan; Nitobe; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Skunk Works; Rich; own-it, non-technical  Skunk Works This book describes Ben R. Rich&amp;rsquo;s adventure of creating the F-117A, the stealth plane with a triangular shape.
Describes how he won a bet against legendary plane designer Clarence &amp;lsquo;Kelly&amp;rsquo; Johnson. How he got the 25 cents from his old mentor and friend.
Later, the book reviews Kelly&amp;rsquo;s history as the manager of Skunk Works, how it works, the principles (Kelly&amp;rsquo;s 14 rules), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live test from the MMA</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/04/04/live-article-mma-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 10:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/04/04/live-article-mma-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is an article written, live, from the MMA in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 3); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy Confidence Hacks: 99 small actions to massively boost your confidence; Davenport; own-it, non-technical Tots estimem l&amp;rsquo;Emma; Burgas; non-technical  Confidence Hacks This is a self help book to boost your confidence.
It covers several areas of your life, that could erode your confidence:
 Relationships Social Life Career Appearance Self-Improvement Body Language Thinking Fun and Adventure Finances  How to read and apply it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2020</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/02/01/self-study-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/02/01/self-study-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>localdots — HTTPS domains for localhost localdots combines Caddy and smallstep/certificates with automated configuration and hot reload.
Generates SSL/TLS certificates automatically Reloads Caddy automatically with every change
Tags: https, tls, ssl, caddy, certificate, ssl-certificate, development, dev, environment, local, localhost
Id: 851bde02-2e14-11ea-9ec6-0242ac11000d Read: Fri, 03 Jan 2020 10:33:45 +0000
Write Your Own Compiler Link to create a new compiler, for the T3X language.
 less than 150 pages of comprehensible code and straight-forward prose</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
