<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2020/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Read this quarter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 rules for life; Peterson; own-it, non-technical, philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-rules-for-life&#34;&gt;12 rules for life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book contains some rules, some principles to remove doubt and uncertainty from life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of mentions to the Bible, although I consider the book to the secular in its contents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few personal stories on the book (e.g., about his daughter Mikhaila Peterson), which makes it readable and enjoyable. The philosophy behind it is sometimes not-politically-correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of the rules, he has a setup of &amp;ldquo;introduction - main - conclusion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From wikipedia &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12_Rules_for_Life&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;0&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is divided into chapters with each title representing one of the following twelve specific rules for life as explained through an essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stand up straight with your shoulders back&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Treat yourself like you are someone you are responsible for helping&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Make friends with people who want the best for you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Compare yourself with who you were yesterday, not with who someone else is today&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do not let your children do anything that makes you dislike them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Set your house in perfect order before you criticize the world&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pursue what is meaningful (not what is expedient)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tell the truth — or, at least, don’t lie&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Assume that the person you are listening to might know something you don’t&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be precise in your speech&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do not bother children when they are skate-boarding&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Pet a cat when you encounter one on the street&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read this quarter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bushido, the soul of Japan; Nitobe; own-it, non-technical, philosophy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Read this quarter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skunk Works; Rich; own-it, non-technical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;skunk-works&#34;&gt;Skunk Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book describes Ben R. Rich&amp;rsquo;s adventure of creating the F-117A, the stealth plane with a triangular shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes how he won a bet against legendary plane designer Clarence &amp;lsquo;Kelly&amp;rsquo; Johnson. How he got the 25 cents from his old mentor and friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, the book reviews Kelly&amp;rsquo;s history as the manager of Skunk Works, how it works, the principles (Kelly&amp;rsquo;s 14 rules), etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, he retrospects on his own career, and the principles on which Skunk Works has thrived on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kelly-s-14-rules-practices&#34;&gt;Kelly&amp;rsquo;s 14 Rules &amp;amp; Practices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Kelly Johnson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Skunk Works® manager must be delegated practically complete control of his program in all aspects. He should report to a division president or higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strong but small project offices must be provided both by the military and industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number of people having any connection with the project must be restricted in an almost vicious manner. Use a small number of good people (10% to 25% compared to the so-called normal systems).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A very simple drawing and drawing release system with great flexibility for making changes must be provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There must be a minimum number of reports required, but important work must be recorded thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There must be a monthly cost review covering not only what has been spent and committed but also projected costs to the conclusion of the program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contractor must be delegated and must assume more than normal responsibility to get good vendor bids for subcontract on the project. Commercial bid procedures are very often better than military ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inspection system as currently used by the Skunk Works, which has been approved by both the Air Force and Navy, meets the intent of existing military requirements and should be used on new projects. Push more basic inspection responsibility back to subcontractors and vendors. Don&amp;rsquo;t duplicate so much inspection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contractor must be delegated the authority to test his final product in flight. He can and must test it in the initial stages. If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, he rapidly loses his competency to design other vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The specifications applying to the hardware must be agreed to well in advance of contracting. The Skunk Works practice of having a specification section stating clearly which important military specification items will not knowingly be complied with and reasons therefore is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funding a program must be timely so that the contractor doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to keep running to the bank to support government projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There must be mutual trust between the military project organization and the contractor, the very close cooperation and liaison on a day-to-day basis. This cuts down misunderstanding and correspondence to an absolute minimum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access by outsiders to the project and its personnel must be strictly controlled by appropriate security measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because only a few people will be used in engineering and most other areas, ways must be provided to reward good performance by pay not based on the number of personnel supervised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lockheedmartin.com/en-us/who-we-are/business-areas/aeronautics/skunkworks/kelly-14-rules.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.lockheedmartin.com/en-us/who-we-are/business-areas/aeronautics/skunkworks/kelly-14-rules.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live test from the MMA</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/04/04/live-article-mma-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 10:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/04/04/live-article-mma-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an article written, live, from the MMA in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Read this quarter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tao of Séneca (vol 3); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confidence Hacks: 99 small actions to massively boost your confidence; Davenport; own-it, non-technical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tots estimem l&amp;rsquo;Emma; Burgas; non-technical&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;confidence-hacks&#34;&gt;Confidence Hacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a self help book to boost your confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It covers several areas of your life, that could erode your confidence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Career&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appearance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-Improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Body Language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun and Adventure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to read and apply it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a review, here&amp;rsquo;s how I suggest you use this book to help boost your confidence:
* Read through the entire book once, making notes about any the life areas where you need to work on your confidence.
* Go back through the book again to review those specific life areas you want to work on and the ideas and Action Steps suggested.
* Select the most troublesome area of low confidence to work on first, and determine very specific actions based on the suggestions outlined in the book to work on over the next four to six weeks.
* Determine the time of day you&amp;rsquo;ll work on those actions and a specific trigger or cue to remind yourself to perform the action.
* Expect to feel uncomfortable and resistant for the first few weeks. Try to manage your discomfort by reminding yourself it will diminish over time.
* Seek out accountability and support from a friend or family member by telling them about your confidence work.
* Acknowledge your small daily actions and reward yourself immediately after you take the action with something that makes you feel good.
* Track your feelings of confidence weekly as you work on these actions by scoring yourself from one being very low confidence. Give yourself a baseline score before you begin taking the actions.
* Repeat this process for any additional areas of low confidence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excerpt From: Barrie Davenport. “Confidence Hacks: 99 Small Actions to Massively Boost Your Confidence.” iBooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>