<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/yes-people/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/yes-people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-the-uuid-https-segment-com-blog-a-brief-history-of-the-uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-uuid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Brief History of the UUID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rick Branson on the history of UUID.
Describes the history of uid, uuid, early computing (both networked and not networked) and their own implementation of a uuid library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uuid, uid, flake, snowflake, ksuid, go, golang, rick-branson, library, implementation-history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-data-more-data-https-blog-cloudflare-com-more-data-more-data&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/more-data-more-data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More data, more data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how cloudflare manages its logs. By Hunter Blanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: log, cloudflare, comparison, what-worked, what-did-not-work, kafka, citusdb, sre, site-reliability-engineering, analytics, hunter-blanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no-https-hbr-org-2017-06-help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/06/help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Help Your Team Stop Overcommitting by Empowering Them to Say No&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that describes how important is to say no to some ideas or projects so you can say yes to others.
In other words, how prioritizing is important as time and energy (i.e., resources) are not infinite and must be allocated accordingly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: diana-kander, hbr, harvard-business-review, priority, energy, resources, time, pet-project, yes-people, no-people, yes-culture, no-culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology-http-ben-evans-com-benedictevans-2017-5-24-not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2017/5/24/not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Not even wrong - ways to dismiss technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how technology can be seen as toys before it is developed to the point where it can be expanded and used for other purposes than the one expected / designed for. By Benedict Evans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benedict-evans, technology, prediction, usage, invention, philosophy, wolfgang-pauli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-we-have-a-better-option-here-https-softwaremill-com-do-we-have-better-option-here&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwaremill.com/do-we-have-better-option-here/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Do we have a better Option here?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article comparing &lt;code&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Optional&lt;/code&gt; as types that can contain a value, but maybe not. By Michał Chmielarz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michal-chmielarz, option, optional, vavr, javaslang, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-the-keyboard-faster-than-the-mouse-http-danluu-com-keyboard-v-mouse&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/keyboard-v-mouse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Is the keyboard faster than the mouse?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan Luu comparing the use of the mouse and the use of the keyboard and their speeds.
He groups existing literature on the topic plus some experiments he has done himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentions the amount of myths related to this, based on old and non-accurate research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-luu, keyboard, comparison, mouse, human-interaction-device, hid, interaction, user-experience, interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-crypto-anarchist-manifesto-http-groups-csail-mit-edu-mac-classes-6-805-articles-crypto-cypherpunks-may-crypto-manifesto-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/mac/classes/6.805/articles/crypto/cypherpunks/may-crypto-manifesto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Timothy C. May forecasting the development of a new market based on cryptography and secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same that barbed wire transformed property in the West, is the analogy he uses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: timothy-may, anarchy, encryption, market, forecast, crypto-anarchism, public-key-encryption, zero-knowledge-proof, cryptography&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>