<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/leadership/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-create-reality-https-www-mrmoneymustache-com-2019-02-27-how-to-create-reality&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2019/02/27/how-to-create-reality/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Create Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, it is explained how to create a (different) reality in the mind of your target (users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin with the End in Mind – and Start by Painting a Beautiful Picture of that end  destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the technique at the core of the world’s best marketing and negotiation strategies, and it works so well because it short circuits the human brain into making everyone – including you – see things in the desired way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a simple picture of a very clear end destination that automatically got people’s imagination running and filling in their own details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: communication, people-management, leadership, marketing, pete-adeney, mr-money-mustache, paint-the-picture, technique&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: add12910-3b3f-11e9-8a1b-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:00:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;red-flags-in-software-developer-job-descriptions-https-joecmarshall-com-posts-job-description-red-flags&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Red Flags in Software Developer Job Descriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains some red flags the author has detected while reading job offers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress Developer - Degree + 10 years experience required: refers to the exageration of needed qualifications for jobs that do not require it, apparently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP Contractor - 2 Months: refers to the short-term mentality of jobs, and the environment that it creates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Stage Emmployee / Technical Co-founder / Person to Make My Thing: refers to how cheap ideas are and how important (to developers) execution is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies: Coldfusion + jQuery: refers to old/out of fashion technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: job-offer, pattern, joe-marshall, old-technology, fashionable, short-term, long-term, mentality, hiring, recruiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3841f764-3b40-11e9-9d75-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:04:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-be-productive-with-big-existing-code-base-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19254008&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19254008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to be productive with big existing code base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this HN discussion, there are some pearls regarding working with big, legacy codebases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it the way they did doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they did it wrong. A reference to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Chesterton%27s_fence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reference to Working Effectively With Legacy Code, by Feathers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 1. Assess how much of the code is actually understood. Is there any record of the &amp;gt; design decisions, the edge cases, the debugging process, the paths that weren&amp;rsquo;t taken? Who knows the most about the codebase and how it got to be how it is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 2. What&amp;rsquo;s the current specification? Don&amp;rsquo;t look at the stack, look at input and output cases. How well does the code meet the spec? Where is it failing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 3. Before you change anything you need to know what the change process is. You &amp;gt; probably do already know this, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to find out whether there are &amp;gt; any demarcations of responsibility, even if they&amp;rsquo;re only informal and unstated areas of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 4. When you have all that, you can start working on the code with some knowledge of the context you - and the code - are operating in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 5. If code works, don&amp;rsquo;t rewrite or refactor for style without a very very good &amp;gt; reason. And don&amp;rsquo;t do it unless you can change all the &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; code at once. Otherwise &amp;gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a mess of incompatible idioms that make future changes hard to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 6. Write your own docs as you go. Best case is other people will benefit from reading them, worst case is you&amp;rsquo;ll remind yourself what you were doing six months from now - because you&amp;rsquo;ll have forgotten by then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reference to flamegraphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; The problem with the after-the-fact abstraction layer is that if the original team members are not available, you are likely not in possession of the whole theory of the software. Hence it is not likely you can in the beginning choose the right abstractions. Endquote. This is a reference to &amp;ldquo;Programming as theory building&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; Get it into a state that will support current business goals and roadmap while protecting current business value and users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: the quotes are copied directly from the discussion page and are property of the original commentators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wewlc, michael-feathers, hackernews, yc, legacy-code, theory-building, quote, chesterton-fence, working-effectively-with-legacy-code, programming-as-theory-building&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0eb0ef62-3b41-11e9-863a-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:10:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nodejs-logging-made-right-https-itnext-io-nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itnext.io/nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NodeJS logging made right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters-https-nicepage-com-doc-article-20348-web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nicepage.com/doc/article/20348/web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 2, we will talk about website builders that are lagging behind the trends and slowing down the Web Design evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 3, you will learn how to create modern web designs quickly and easily in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has walk through the different design phases, techniques; both in press (printed) design as in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some web builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the concept of the web 3.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element overlapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking the limitations of Bootstrap-like Grids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States the different needs for webmasters and designers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Designers need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing table constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property Panel for elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Windows and Mac OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Webmasters need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean HTML and CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile device support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress and Joomla support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building websites online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website builders are lagging behind the rapidly changing Web Design world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of web design tools has involved several transitions. However, progress has stopped. There are numerous signs that the new transition must happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are separate markets for web designers and webmasters. Popular website builders do not support the main features of Web Design 3.0: free positioning, modern grids, and layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, web-design, print-design, web-builder, creativity, metaphor, grid-layout, bootstrap, flexibility, design, web-3.0, web-design-3.0, web-2.0, progression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5101ce2e-3f5e-11e9-83d9-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:49:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gotify-a-self-hosted-push-notifications-service-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19347848&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19347848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gotify – a self-hosted push-notifications service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gotify, self-hosted, notification, notification-service, android, open-source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e839c82a-4367-11e9-b34d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:08:36 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-speak-like-a-leader-not-like-an-engineer-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19349676&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links and resources for speaking like a leader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leader, engineer, comparison, change, public-speaking, speak, speaking, career-management, career-change, professional-growth, resource:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1a478fc8-4368-11e9-b657-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:10:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;archivebox-open-source-self-hosted-web-archive-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19346985&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19346985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ArchiveBox: Open-source self-hosted web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools for archiving purposes. Has links to other sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpolarized.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://getpolarized.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: burtonator, web-archive, polarized, warch, warc, personal-knowledge-base&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4168161c-436e-11e9-aa0d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:54:03 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-as-a-freelancer-what-s-the-best-app-to-track-finances-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19450331&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19450331&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: As a freelancer, what&amp;rsquo;s the best app to track finances?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes tools for finance for freelancers. Stresses the importance of time wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, money-management, freelance, tool, ask-hn, hackernews, finance, time-wealth, money-wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b74a6696-4c83-11e9-99bd-0242ac110005
Read: Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:20:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned-in-my-first-year-as-a-solo-founder-https-tik-dev-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tik.dev/lessons-learned&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What I Learned in My First Year as a Solo Founder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learnings by a solo founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits of having a side project or side hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: side-hustle, side-business, learning, reflection, solo-founder, founder, revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f0dee42c-5142-11e9-9444-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:19:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-tests-not-too-many-mostly-integration-https-kentcdodds-com-blog-write-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kentcdodds.com/blog/write-tests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Write tests. Not too many. Mostly integration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paraphrasing of some advice for healthy eating: &amp;lsquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rsquo; (Pollan)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I find myself saving time when I put time in to write tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too many: you get diminishing returns on your tests as the coverage increases [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly integration: as you move up the pyramid, the confidence quotient of each form of testing increases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests strike a great balance on the trade-offs between confidence and speed/expense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: unit-test, testing, test-pyramid, healthy-testing, advice, integration-test, quote, kent-c-dodds, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d148d774-5144-11e9-94d8-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:32:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-rules-for-eating-https-www-webmd-com-food-recipes-news-20090323-7-rules-for-eating&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/food-recipes/news/20090323/7-rules-for-eating&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7 Rules for Eating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this reference article, Michael Pollan explains his seven rules for eating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything your great grandmother wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recognize as food. &amp;ldquo;When you pick up that box of portable yogurt tubes, or eat something with 15 ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce, ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What are those things doing there?&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t eat anything with more than five ingredients, or ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay out of the middle of the supermarket; shop on the perimeter of the store. Real food tends to be on the outer edge of the store near the loading docks, where it can be replaced with fresh foods when it goes bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that won&amp;rsquo;t eventually rot. &amp;ldquo;There are exceptions &amp;ndash; honey &amp;ndash; but as a rule, things like Twinkies that never go bad aren&amp;rsquo;t food,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not just what you eat but how you eat. &amp;ldquo;Always leave the table a little hungry,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Many cultures have rules that you stop eating before you are full. In Japan, they say eat until you are four-fifths full. Islamic culture has a similar rule, and in German culture they say, &amp;lsquo;Tie off the sack before it&amp;rsquo;s full.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Families traditionally ate together, around a table and not a TV, at regular meal times. It&amp;rsquo;s a good tradition. Enjoy meals with the people you love. &amp;ldquo;Remember when eating between meals felt wrong?&amp;rdquo; Pollan asks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t buy food where you buy your gasoline. In the U.S., 20% of food is eaten in the car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, four myths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food is a delivery vehicle for nutrients. What really matters isn&amp;rsquo;t broccoli but its fiber and antioxidants. If we get that right, we get our diet right. Foods kind of get in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need experts to tell us how to eat. Nutrients are invisible and mysterious. &amp;ldquo;It is a little like religion,&amp;rdquo; Pollan said. &amp;ldquo;If a powerful entity is invisible, you need a priesthood to mediate your relation with food.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole point of eating is to maintain and promote bodily health. &amp;ldquo;You are either improving or ruining your health when you eat &amp;ndash; that is a very American idea,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;But there are many other reasons to eat food: pleasure, social community, identity, and ritual. Health is not the only thing going on on our plates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are evil foods and good foods. &amp;ldquo;At any given time there is an evil nutrient we try to drive like Satan from the food supply &amp;ndash; first it was saturated fats, then it was trans fat,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Then there is the evil nutrient&amp;rsquo;s doppelganger, the blessed nutrient. If we get enough of that we, will be healthy and maybe live forever. It&amp;rsquo;s funny through history how the good and bad guys keep changing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can all be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: healthy-eating, michael-pollan, rule, advice, myth, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 30ece1fc-5145-11e9-87de-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:35:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-https-blog-usejournal-com-lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.usejournal.com/lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lean Testing or Why Unit Tests are Worse than You Think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article puts testing in an economic perspective. Calls it lean testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also references/paraphrases Michael Pollan&amp;rsquo;s Rules for eating ().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creates a testing trophy, a figure to explain the best testing pattern, replacing the testing pyramid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains return on investment (ROI) on tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;integration tests provide the best balance of cost, speed and confidence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests lie somewhere between unit tests and end-to-end tests so they provide the best balance. Therefore, they have the highest ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea is to just not mock so much&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: economic-perspective, lean-testing, testing-trophy, testing-pyramid, return-on-investment, roi, critical-path, testing, unit-test, anti-architecture, architecture, maintenance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: efe85d00-5147-11e9-87ce-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:55:02 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-user-programming-https-www-inkandswitch-com-end-user-programming-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inkandswitch.com/end-user-programming.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;End-user programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the writer explains some of the end-user modifications to programs. Examples include: adding download capabilities to instagram, generating backups for files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, applications (especially mobile) are tightly sealed, not allowing modification or extension. Even FOSS (free, open source software), modification implies the learning curve / entry barrier of having to setup, compile, debug the original program and modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives the example of the UNIX command line, as a programming environment. One that provides (one of) the best REPL examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characterizes spreadsheets as ad-hoc databases, programs; mostly created by domain experts (aka subject matter experts), than professional software engineers. Take into account that these hats are non-exclusive: a domain expert can also be a professional software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author tries to coin the term &amp;ldquo;end-user programming&amp;rdquo; to differentiate it from programming by professional software developers, who try to build general-purpose apps, to be used by thousands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means, that a professional software developer can be an &amp;ldquo;end-user programmer&amp;rdquo;, when creating solutions for themselves (limited user group), rather than for the general public. Maybe those one-off scripts that we create, are some kind of end-user programs. This is described in the article as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks of the chasm the user has to cross in order to customize the behaviour of their software. This is related to working in a framework or a library, in the sense of &amp;lsquo;who keeps the control&amp;rsquo;. In an UNIX, filesystem environment, you keep the control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References &amp;ldquo;citizen developers&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three qualities for end-user programming: embodiment, living systems, and in-place toolchains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment: it requires the programmer hold many abstractions in their mind. Related to abstract reasoning. Mentions that many end-users don&amp;rsquo;t have these abstractions in their mind, but are capable of abstract reasoning in their own domains of expertise. Mentions that via visual representations onscreen, we can help the end-user. An example: preview formula results in a spreadsheet; highlight the cells in a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment means, broadly, making elements of the programming experience more concrete and visual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living systems: interaction with them. Refers to shortening the feedback cycle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Live programming gives the programmer immediate feedback on the behavior of a program as it is edited, replacing the edit compile-debug cycle with a fluid programming experience.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But only short feedback loops, but also to change the system behaviour from within, such as the LISP compiler reading and compiling the source code from inside a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-place tool chains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user should be able to edit their programs without installing additional tools or programs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a Unix shell script is just a series of commands saved into a text file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning that the user is already accustomed to issuing those commands. A script is just grouping those commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives examples of end-user programming success stories: spreadsheets, SQL, browser dev tools,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: end-user-programming, programming, extensibility, open-closed-principle, ocp, mofication, user, extension, unix, repl, spreadsheet, reflection, theory, history, review, sql, dev-tools, chasm, abstraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4490792a-514b-11e9-9861-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:18:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-https-medium-com-web-development-why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@web.development/why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why developers consider Agile development to be nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article explains how Agile development is apt and indicated for short-term software development, especially for contracting or consulting companies, where the client is external to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why it does not make as much sense in products/services where there is a leapfrog solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t give the customer what they ask for; understand them, and revolutionize their world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leapfrog-solution, google, agile, agile-development, comparison, project-management, client, consulting, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9035ea3c-514f-11e9-9676-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:49:37 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-bother-with-what-three-words-https-shkspr-mobi-blog-2019-03-why-bother-with-what-three-words&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/03/why-bother-with-what-three-words/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why bother with What Three Words?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the author questions why using a closed protocol for translating geo-coordinates to words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author complains that it is masquerading a for-profit, closed algorithm as an open standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, that the GPS locations are drifting very quickly in some places, therefore the translated address changes, but the local address (e.g., 1 Wall Street), does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gps-drift, australia, open-standard, closed-standard, for-profit, protocol, open, closed, what-three-words, w3w, i18n, startup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 960e6750-5202-11e9-bb40-0242ac110008
Read: Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:11:07 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-reason-why-the-spotify-model-is-broken&#34;&gt;The real reason why the Spotify model is broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://kernelmag.dailydot.com/issue-sections/staff-editorials/12136/spotify-royalty-payment-model/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-of-7-badass-developer-gets-a-rude-awakening&#34;&gt;[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, they wanted a professional problem solver who could jump in and deliver what the company needed, to meet THEIR customers&amp;rsquo; demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking for ways that I could add value to my employer outside of the code I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed my &amp;ldquo;soft skills&amp;rdquo;—my ability to communicate, learn quickly, and pass my knowledge on to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-sonmez, programmer, language-programmer, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-rules-to-live-by-when-you-work-in-an-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34;&gt;6 Rules To Live By When You Work In An Office But Have Remote Team Members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/6-mistakes-when-you-work-in-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Lauren Moon about how trello works remotely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value Individuals Over Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Impromptu Meetings At Someone’s Desk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If One Person Is On A Video Call, EVERYONE Is On A Video Call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication Is Asynchronous. Deal With It.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socializing Is Not Around A Watercooler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tools You’re Using Matter. A Lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, lauren-moon, listicle, trello, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;princeton-s-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34;&gt;Princeton’s Ad-Blocking Superweapon May Put an End to the Ad-Blocking Arms Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/princetons-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Koebler on the tool a university has written and published, that using computer vision, is able to detect sponsored content in native form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jason-koebler, computer-vision, ad, advertisement, ublock, adblock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hasta-pronto&#34;&gt;Hasta pronto…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javiergarzas.com/2016/07/hasta-pronto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Garzás, where he explains that he&amp;rsquo;ll stop blogging for a while and why&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javier-garzas, blog, personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-principles-of-clean-architecture&#34;&gt;The principles of Clean Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video about the clean architecture (with a client&amp;rsquo;s lunch and learn initiative). By Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the plugin is vulnerable to the plugged-in system, at the source code level&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate the detail from the general things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clean-architecture, uncle-bob, robert-martin, video, mvp, model-view-presenter, model-view-controller, mvc, quote, plugin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-languages-which-almost-became-css&#34;&gt;The Languages Which Almost Became CSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eager.io/blog/the-languages-which-almost-were-css/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zack Bloom on the origins of CSS and the languages to add representation to HTML pages / markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes the origins of these languages (e.g., RPP, PWP, CHSS, PSL, FOSI, DSSSL) and how the acceptance of CSS came to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was the technology which was easiest for a beginner to pick up which won, rather than those which were most powerful for an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt; Zack Bloom&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: css, html, history, zack-bloom, mosaic, violawww&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-not-going-to-believe-what-i-m-about-to-tell-you&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not going to believe what I&amp;rsquo;m about to tell you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/believe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Inman about how we process information from outside, especially when it conflicts with our beliefs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-inman, comic, oatmeal, belief&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-perfectly-unhappy&#34;&gt;How to be perfectly unhappy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/unhappy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Inman about the definition of happiness and how it affects the author&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-inman, oatmeal, happiness, comic, definition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spotify-engineering-culture-part-1&#34;&gt;Spotify Engineering Culture - part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/85490944&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; about the Spotify engineering culture: team organization, the terms they introduce and some general culture about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: team-management, people, spotify, henrik-kniberg, squad, chapter, guild, tribe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speak-like-a-leader&#34;&gt;Speak like a leader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bGBamfWasNQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TEDx Talk&lt;/a&gt; by Simon Lancaster in which he explains the importance of rhetoric in our speech. Explains 6 techniques for achieving better communication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three breathless sentences: &amp;ldquo;Mangia Bene, Ridi Spesso, ama molto&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ein Volk, ein Reich, ein Fuhrer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three repetitive sentences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three balancing statements: if we hear the statements as balanced, we imagine that the underlaying thinking is balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metaphor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exaggeration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: simon-lancaster, tedx, ted, quote, speech, leadership, communication&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volver&#34;&gt;¿Volver?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raulavila.com/2017/01/volver/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;donkey-code&#34;&gt;Donkey code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://einarwh.wordpress.com/2017/01/21/donkey-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: einar-host, donkey-code, ddd, domain-driven-development, domain, abstraction, missing-abstraction, business-logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men&#34;&gt;10 Habits That Change Boys Into Men&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men-b103c47d47e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on why some men are still boys (e.g., expectations from society) and what can boys do to turn into men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, psychology, learning, evolution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-command-line-utilities&#34;&gt;My favorite command-line utilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/macbook-my-command-line-utilities-f8a121c3b019#.3hpq7suhj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Vitaly Belman in which he explains his curated list of utilities for the terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: vitaly-belman, terminal, cli, application, utility, tig, git&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-common-mistakes-of-the-first-time-tech-lead&#34;&gt;Three Common Mistakes of the First Time Tech Lead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/three-common-mistakes-first-time-tech-lead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Kua, in which he explains what are the anti-patterns (or mistakes) of a tech lead. They do not only apply to first timers, but more experienced ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially like a comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take all blame and give all credit: I ensure I always take the blame from the stakeholders when something is broken but when they praise, I say its all my teams efforts and I am just guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/by/ravensnowbird/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ravensnowbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: patrick-kua, tech-lead, leadership, team-management, mistake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimental-versioning&#34;&gt;Sentimental Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sentimentalversioning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (unknown author) on alternatives to semver (semantic versioning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: semver, semantic-versioning, sentimental-versioning, humor, parody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devoxx-2015-how-to-become-a-java-champion&#34;&gt;Devoxx 2015: How to Become a Java Champion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http//www.youtube.com/watch?v=otMc_3Dz3hU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Arun Gupta in which he explains what is a Java champion and how to become one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, arun-gupta, java-champion, devoxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-become-a-champion-programmer&#34;&gt;How Can I Become a Champion Programmer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaspecialists.eu/archive/Issue227.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Heinz M. Kabutz on how to become a java champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: heinz-kabutz, java-champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-using-scala-as-a-better-java&#34;&gt;The myth of using Scala as a better Java&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedscala.com/blog/2017/myth-of-scala-as-better-java/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Denis Kalinin disproving &amp;lsquo;Java as a better Scala&amp;rsquo;. He covers dependency injection, database access, serialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scala, java, comparison, orm, denis-kalinin, macwire, dependency-injection, serialization, database, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y&#34;&gt;The eigenvector of &amp;ldquo;Why we moved from language X to language Y&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://erikbern.com/2017/03/15/the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Erik Bern on the statistical analysis (based on people writing blog posts) of moving from language X to language Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can help predict which languages will be more prevalent in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eigenvector, statistic, erik-bern, language, programming-language, java, c, cplusplus, go, python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;facebook-s-code-quality-problem&#34;&gt;Facebook’s code quality problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.darkcoding.net/software/facebooks-code-quality-problem/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Graham King on the problems that Facebook is facing, at the code level, and how they solve some of them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: graham-king, facebook, quality, architecture, code-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-key-lesson-from-our-serverless-migration&#34;&gt;The key lesson from our serverless migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=abe09ce689751513abf6f095f&amp;amp;id=6ecb59a937&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gojko Adzic on serverless, a kind of lessons learned. Explains that their system can take 50% more users at 50% of the original cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains three ways of authenticating users: use IAM users, use Cognito, pre-sign URLs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lessons-learned, gojko-adzic, serverless, paas, platform-as-a-service, retrospective, money, total-cost-of-ownership, tco,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-automation-goes-horribly-wrong&#34;&gt;When automation goes horribly wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Gojko Adzic on a story of a manual process that was automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it focused too much on replacing humans instead of assisting them, MiDAS actually made it more difficult for clerks to access the data they needed for review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of the framework vs library discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in frameworks you relinquish the control, putting your code into the allocated holes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using the automated system, you can only check the claim at a certain spot, where the system lets you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system and the framework have been designed to take control of the situation. Both successful at what they do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gojko-adzic, automation, framework, library, framework-vs-library, comparison, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-store-my-1-s-and-0-s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy&#34;&gt;How I Store My 1’s and 0’s: ZFS  Bargain HP Microserver = JOY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mocko.org.uk/b/2012/06/17/how-i-store-my-1s-and-0s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Alex stores his backups, using a microserver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: backup, microserver, raid, zfs, backup-strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-policy&#34;&gt;Meeting policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/ueno/meeting-policy-9b04593d1b28&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by the Ueno team on how they handle meetings. Interesting that they require manager approval for meetings over a certain threshold (more than four people or more than half an hour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ueno, meeting-policy, meeting, approval&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-random-numbers&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Random Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/a-brief-history-of-random-numbers-9498737f5b6c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carl Tashian on how random numbers have evolved (from dice to pseudo random number generator and random number generators). Explain how some companies that need true randomness (e.g., certificates company) generate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: carl-tashian, dice, random-number, randomness, prng, pseudo-random-number-generator, random-number-generator, number-generator, true-random-number-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word&#34;&gt;Unlock honest feedback with this one word&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word-dcaf3839e7ee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Claire Lew, in which she suggests to ask for &amp;lsquo;advice&amp;rsquo; instead of asking for &amp;lsquo;feedback&amp;rsquo; as a way of getting more honest and better responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: claire-lew, advice, feedback, feedback-process, improvement&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;translation-from-haskell-to-javascript-of-selected-portions-of-the-best-introduction-to-monads-i-ve-ever-read&#34;&gt;Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jcoglan.com/2011/03/05/translation-from-haskell-to-javascript-of-selected-portions-of-the-best-introduction-to-monads-ive-ever-read/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Coglan, introducing monads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About composability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;symmetric input and output types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guide to basic monadic functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function
bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form
unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is a monad? Well, it’s a design pattern. It says that whenever you have a class of functions that accept one type of thing and return another type of thing, there are two functions that can be applied across this class to make them composable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt; function that transforms any function so that accepts the same type as it returns, making it composable
There is a &lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; function that wraps a value in the type accepted by the composable functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I]t’s a very useful design pattern to be aware of because it helps you spot accidental complexity: code that isn’t dealing directly with the problem at hand, but which is dealing with glueing data types together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: monad, monad-explanation, haskell, javascript, james-coglan, bind, unit, lift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-could-have-invented-monads-and-maybe-you-already-have&#34;&gt;You Could Have Invented Monads! (And Maybe You Already Have.)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sigfpe.com/2006/08/you-could-have-invented-monads-and.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Piponi, in which he slowly introduces monads, using examples from everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-piponi, monad, monad-explanation, haskell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-one&#34;&gt;Monads, part one&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/21/monads-part-one/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes monads as a design pattern that &amp;ldquo;can sneak up on you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-two&#34;&gt;Monads, part two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/25/monads-part-two/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes monad examples in the C# code. Also describes what an &amp;lsquo;amplifier&amp;rsquo; is. I relate it to composing behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &amp;ldquo;amplifier&amp;rdquo; is something that increases the representational power of their &amp;ldquo;underlying&amp;rdquo; type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, amplifier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-three&#34;&gt;Monads, part three&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/28/monads-part-three/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes how to wrap a value in a monadic wrapper (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-four&#34;&gt;Monads, part four&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/04/monads-part-four/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the second function (&lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-five&#34;&gt;Monads, part five&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/07/monads-part-five/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the three laws, which are later compressed into two (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-six&#34;&gt;Monads, part six&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/11/monads-part-six/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the logical identity of applying the function inside a monad and outside a monad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-seven&#34;&gt;Monads, part seven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/14/monads-part-seven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he states the three laws of monads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying the construction function to a given instance of the monad produces a logically identical instance of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying a function to the result of the construction function on a value, and applying that function to the value directly, produces two logically identical instances of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying to a value a first function followed by applying to the result a second function, and applying to the original value a third function that is the composition of the first and second functions, produces two logically identical instances of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-eight&#34;&gt;Monads, part eight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/18/monads-part-eight/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes the monad terms he was using other, more common names (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-nine&#34;&gt;Monads, part nine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/21/monads-part-nine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he creates a &lt;code&gt;Tainted&lt;/code&gt; monad, which is basically a &lt;code&gt;Nullable&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Maybe&lt;/code&gt; monad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-ten&#34;&gt;Monads, part ten&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/25/monads-part-ten/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes &lt;code&gt;Where&lt;/code&gt; (as the query syntax form) using the &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt; signature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-eleven&#34;&gt;Monads, part eleven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/28/monads-part-eleven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes the &amp;ldquo;additive monad&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a zero value of every construction of the monadic type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a way to add two monads with the same underlying type together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The zero value is the identity of the add operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bind to apply any function to the zero produces the zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bind to apply the function &lt;code&gt;a=&amp;gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; to any &lt;code&gt;M&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; produces the zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, additive-monad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-twelve&#34;&gt;Monads, part twelve&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/04/02/monads-part-twelve/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains how the &lt;code&gt;SelectMany&lt;/code&gt; could be implemented (but it is not implemented in practice)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-thirteen&#34;&gt;Monads, part thirteen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/04/03/monads-part-thirteen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he suggests reading a similar article on the Task comonad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, comonad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks-monads-and-linq&#34;&gt;Tasks, Monads, and LINQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/pfxteam/2013/04/03/tasks-monads-and-linq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Toub in which he explains the comonad &lt;code&gt;Task&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comonad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] dual of a monad, a triple consisting of the type and two operators: &lt;code&gt;Extract&lt;/code&gt; (the flip of &lt;code&gt;Unit&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Return&lt;/code&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;Extend&lt;/code&gt; (the flip of &lt;code&gt;Bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comonad, monad, monad-explanation, stephen-toub, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-questions-every-unit-test-must-answer&#34;&gt;5 Questions Every Unit Test Must Answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/what-every-unit-test-needs-f6cd34d9836d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (titled as a listicle) by Eric Elliot about unit tests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are you testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should it do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the actual output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the expected output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can the test be reproduced?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-elliott, javascript, unit-test, test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-should-be-planning-for-2018-not-2017&#34;&gt;Why You Should be Planning for 2018, Not 2017.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/why-you-should-be-planning-for-2018-not-2017-7c8fea3e2e52&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on motivation, planning and designing your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] having the power to make choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The responsibility to choose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The results of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] hope reflects your perceptions regarding your capacity to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearly conceptualize goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop the specific strategies to reach those goals (i.e., pathways thinking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initiate and sustain the motivation for using those strategies (i.e., agency thinking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] motivation involves three components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the value you place on your goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your belief that specific behaviors will actually facilitate the outcomes you desire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your belief in your own ability to successfully execute the behaviors requisite to achieving your goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, motivation, life, planning, long-term-plans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-5-better&#34;&gt;Get 5% Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2016/03/five-percent-better/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, in which the author explains how compound interest does not only apply to investing and saving but also personal improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kaizen, personal-improvement, compound-interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hunter-s-thompson-s-letter-on-finding-your-purpose-and-living-a-meaningful-life&#34;&gt;Hunter S. Thompson’s Letter on Finding Your Purpose and Living a Meaningful Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2014/05/hunter-s-thompson-to-hume-logan/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; from Hunter S. Thompson to his friend Hume Logan, containing advice on living your own life: must find your own way, decide between floating or swimming to your goal and strive to be yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: hunter-thompson, hume-logan, advice, psychology, life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-japanese-philosophy-of-kaizen-offers-an-effective-manageable-way-to-achieve-long-term-goals&#34;&gt;The Japanese philosophy of Kaizen offers an effective, manageable way to achieve long-term goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/867711/the-japanese-philosophy-of-kaizen-offers-an-effective-manageable-way-to-achieve-long-term-goals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Oppong on kaizen, or continuous improvement, and how it applies like compound interest to your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kaizen, continous-improvement, thomas-oppong, compound-interest, life, psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-a-software-interview&#34;&gt;Preparing for a Software Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://42hire.com/preparing-for-a-software-interview-6d0392a3d72c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alvaro Videla on interviewing technical people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: recruitement, interviewing, interview, alvaro-videla&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-recursive-data-structures&#34;&gt;Why Recursive Data Structures?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raganwald.com/2016/12/27/recursive-data-structures.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this essay&lt;/a&gt; by Reginald “Raganwald” Braithwaite, on which he introduces the relationship between data structures and algorithms. Explains how the algorithm can be split into parts, following the data structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses a library containing a function called &lt;code&gt;multirec&lt;/code&gt; for recursion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackage.haskell.org/package/multirec&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a candidate&lt;/a&gt; library, in haskell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lazutkin.com/blog/2008/06/30/using-recursion-combinators-javascript/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;another candidate&lt;/a&gt; library, in javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: reginald-braithwaite, recursive-data-structure, quadtree, javascript, functional-programming, essay, data-structure, isomorphic, tree, multirec, linrec, tailrec, haskell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leading-by-example&#34;&gt;Leading by Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/leading-by-example/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on how the best leadership comes from doing, rather than telling how to do it. From being a leader rather than being a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests further reads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leadership, team-lead, leading-by-example, jeff-atwood, gerald-weinberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discipline-makes-strong-developers&#34;&gt;Discipline Makes Strong Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/discipline-makes-strong-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on a project sucess should not be attributed to a language or framework, but to the team&amp;rsquo;s and individuals&amp;rsquo; discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains how small projects require different levels of discipline than large projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leadership, discipline, nasa, code-complete, coding-horror, jeff-atwood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;effectively-integrating-into-software-development-teams&#34;&gt;Effectively Integrating Into Software Development Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dennisforbes.ca/index.php/2006/01/29/effectively-integrating-into-software-development-teams/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dennis Forbes about authority and discipline in a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One organization’s Enterprise solution is another organization’s short sighted mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: shiny, dennis-forbes, discipline, authority, psychology, politics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>