<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>The real reason why the Spotify model is broken I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify
Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty
[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:
 Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Coglan, introducing monads.
About composability:
 The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable
 or
 symmetric input and output types
 Guide to basic monadic functions:
 lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
