<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Jason-gorman | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/jason-gorman/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-08T10:15:55+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in December 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-02T07:50:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.skorks.com/2009/09/ruby-equality-and-object-comparison/">this article</a>, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:</p>

<ul>
<li>equal? is reference equality</li>
<li>== is value equality</li>
<li>eql? is value and type equality</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin</p>

<h2>Software Folklore</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/software-folklore">this PechaKucha</a> by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</p>

<p>Tags: folklore, chris-ford, analogy, computer-science, pechakucha, software-engineering, software-creation, law</p>

<h2>3 Things Java Programmers Can Steal from Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/3-things-java-can-steal-from-clojure">this article</a> by Eric Normand, where he explains 3 clojure things that can be applied to your day to day java:</p>

<ol>
<li>Persistent Data Structures</li>
<li>Software Transactional Memory</li>
<li>Extensible Data Notation</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: clojure, java, eric-normand, stm, edn</p>

<h2>2 Features of Clojure Editors Professionals Won&rsquo;t Do Without</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/clojure-editors">this article</a> by Eric Normand, where he explains the most necessary features for a clojure editor:</p>

<ol>
<li>REPL Integration</li>
<li>Structural Editing</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: clojure, java, eric-normand, stm, edn</p>

<h2>How to read more books</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://verraes.net/2012/12/how-to-read-more-books/">this article</a> by Mathias Verraes on tips to read more books:</p>

<ul>
<li>Negative things to stop doing</li>
<li>Positive things to start doing</li>
<li>Habits to form</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: mathias-verraes, reading, book</p>

<h2>Effective Learning Strategies for Programmers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://akaptur.com/blog/2015/10/10/effective-learning-strategies-for-programmers/">this article</a> by Allison Kaptur on fixed vs growth mindset and the need for having the latter for being a programmer.</p>

<p>Especially interesting is the provided example of the confusion in the documentation, that can hinder productivity</p>

<p>(Note: this entry is also present in this same month)</p>

<p>Tags: allison-kaptur, fixed-mindset, growth-mindset, research, learning-strategy, recurse-center, carol-dweck, mindset</p>

<h2>Code a fully-functional web app in 14 days… - Challenge Accepted</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@OggimusPrime/code-a-fully-functional-web-app-in-14-days-e247f536772d">this experience report</a> on how Ryan Haase and Benjamin Hoffman built an MVP in 14 days. They describe their stack choices, gotchas and key points.</p>

<p>Tags: ryan-haase, benjamin-hoffman, mvp, angular, firebase, challenge</p>

<h2>Writing-Clear-Code, Not-Clever-Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve-read <a href="https://medium.com/@mikesherov/writing-clear-code-not-clever-code-d6b90353a3c5">this-article</a> by-Mike-Sherov-where-he-explains-the-reflection-he-did-since-his-team-members-were-asking-too-much-about-his-code. His-conclusion-was-to-stop-reducing-the-size-of-the-code-to-improve-readability.</p>

<p>Tags: mike-sherov, clean-code,clear-code, clever-code, reflection, team, code</p>

<h2>En vez de “un Scrum por proyecto” mejor un “Scrum por equipo”</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javiergarzas.com/2015/12/alejate-del-concepto-proyecto-si-quieres-usar-bien-scrum-22-adaptar-scrum-segun-cada-proyecto.html">this article</a> where Javier Garzás explains scrum by teams or by projects and why the former should be preferred (in Spanish).</p>

<p>Tags:  javier-garzas, scrum, project-management, team, agile</p>

<h2>Application gateways: an example in Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.obliquo.eu/post/134421923177/application-gateways-an-example-in-clojure">this example</a> that Cristobal Garcia prepared for me after asking for it at the local Barcelona Software Craftsmanship community (Many thanks!).</p>

<p>He describes what an application gateway is, giving an example in clojure. In this case, the application gateway is used to cache and forward/deny requests to another webservice.</p>

<p>Tags: cristobal-garcia, application-gateway, clojure, example, level-7-firewall, barcelona-software-craftsmanship, scbcn, gift</p>

<h2>Habits For Effective Refactoring</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=THw8t7ePlsc">this video</a> by Jason Gorman about techniques for effective and sustainable refactoring. Among them:</p>

<ul>
<li>check the tests, the coverage to make sure that the refactored code has a good safety net</li>
<li>set a refactoring goal: decide what you want to refactor at this time and when you&rsquo;ll be done</li>
<li>know your code smells</li>
<li>only refactor on green</li>
<li>use automated refactoring steps whenever possible: for the benefits of transactionability and undo are huge and the risk of messing it up decreases</li>
<li>commit after achieving the refactoring goal: allows to create a checkpoint to revert to</li>
<li>bottle the code smells for faster/better learning (in the commit message, he uses a hashtag for searching)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: jason-gorman, refactoring, video, technique, refactor, tutorial, code-smell</p>

<h2>Key to &ldquo;OEIS.org&rdquo; Poster, n. 15</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://oeisf.org/Poster15a_key.pdf">the 15th &ldquo;poster and its key&rdquo;</a> by the OEIS, published by N. J. A. Sloane.</p>

<p>Tags: sloane, oeis, poster-and-key, neil-sloane</p>

<h2>The Clojure Style Guide</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/clojure-style-guide">this style guide</a> to clojure, by Bozhidar Batsov</p>

<p>Tags: bozhidar-batsov, clojure, style-guide</p>

<h2>Marick&rsquo;s Midje information</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Writing-your-own-checkers">Custom checkers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Two-words-you-need-to-know">Domain concepts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Top-down-testing">Top-down testing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Nested-checkers">Nested checkers</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Clusterware 11gR2 – Setting up an Active/Passive failover configuration</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/xpsoluxdb/entry/clusterware_11gr2_setting_up_an_activepassive_failover_configuration">this how-to guide</a> by Gilles Haro on how to create an Active/Passive failover configuration for Oracle.</p>

<p>Tags: failover, high-availability, oracle, gilles-haro, active-passive, database</p>

<h2>Old stuff that rocks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://wincent.com/blog/old-stuff-that-rocks">this list</a> of old technologies that still rock, according to Greg Hurrell.</p>

<p>Tags: list, old-stuff, greg-hurrell</p>

<h2>Do not underestimate credentials leaks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/ChALkeR/notes/blob/master/Do-not-underestimate-credentials-leaks.md">this article</a> that describes how credentials are usually accidentally leaked and a guide on what to do about it. By Сковорода Никита Андреевич.</p>

<p>Tags: credential, leak, guide, how-to</p>

<h2>Clojure for the brave and true: chapter 8 - Writing Macros</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.braveclojure.com/writing-macros">this chapter</a> from Daniel Higginbotham about macros in clojure. In it, he explains common gotchas (e.g., double execution, variable capture), splicing, quoting and unquoting.</p>

<p>Tags: daniel-higginbotham, clojure, macro, chapter, quoting, unquoting, splicing</p>

<h2>The Telescoping Constructor (Anti)Pattern</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.captaindebug.com/2011/05/telescoping-constructor-antipattern.html#.ViF57eztmkp">this article</a> by Roger Hughes on the telescoping constructor, with the example in java. The discussion is whether to apply this or not and whether this is a pattern or an anti-pattern</p>

<p>Tags: roger-hughes, telescoping-constructor, java, pattern, antipattern</p>

<h2>Ruby for Newbies: Testing with Rspec</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby-for-newbies-testing-with-rspec--net-21297">this tutorial</a> on how to make write tests with RSpec in Ruby. Written by Andrew Burgess</p>

<p>Tags: andrew-burgess, ruby, rspec, test, tutorial</p>

<h2>Ruby dynamic method calling</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.khd.me/ruby/ruby-dynamic-method-calling/">this article</a> about dynamically calling methods and a benchmark on three ways of doing it in Ruby:</p>

<ul>
<li>call</li>
<li>send</li>
<li>eval</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: khell, metaprogramming, comparison, benchmark, ruby, evaluation, dynamic</p>

<h2>Becoming a CTO</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article <a href="https://medium.com/@juokaz/becoming-a-cto-337dc1a9c6ae"></a> by Juozas Kaziukėnas about the profile and the abilities of a CTO. Talks about the limiting factors for being one (e.g., stop programming, attend many meetings) and the type of work you are supposed to do (e.g., face business people, communicate the strategy, make yourself respectable).</p>

<p>Tags: juozas-kaziukenas, cto, career-change, technology, career, programmer, title, job</p>

<h2>4 Stages of Team Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=7NouiH2ZT8w">this video</a> by the Glenn Smith &ldquo;Growth Coach Houston&rdquo; about the four stages of team development: forming, norming, storming, performing and how to get through them.</p>

<p>Tags: tuckman, forming, norming, storming, performing, glenn-smith, video, team-management, team</p>

<h2>Time Hacking for College Students</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://goel.io/time-hacking/">this article</a> by Karan Goel about techniques for finding time for important things:</p>

<ul>
<li>prioritizing</li>
<li>waking up early</li>
<li>automate</li>
<li>keep learning</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: karan-goel, time-management, important-vs-urgent, prioritization</p>

<h2>Clojure at a Real Estate Portal</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pitheringabout.com/?p=1069">this article</a> by Jon Pither, where he does a post-mortem analysis of a real-estate project with a fixed deadline (TV ads) with around ten months of development time. They brought in an external company, JUXT, who with 6 seasoned developers were able to finish the project on time and on budget.</p>

<p>Their stack was:  Ring, Compojure, Bidi, and http-kit for our Clojure web-apps, mixing in Friend and Liberator.</p>

<p>Tags: ring, compojure, bidi, http-kit, clojure, fixed-deadline, project, success-story, post-mortem, jon-pither</p>

<h2>Musing on TDD, Impulsive Developers and Aesthetics</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article by Jon Pither on why TDD can be harmful sometimes:</p>

<ul>
<li>limits the amount of lateral thinking</li>
<li>forces a technology</li>
<li>limits the solution space given a fixed problem space</li>
<li>limits creativity and freedom when performing large / aggressive refactorings</li>
<li>sterile place</li>
</ul>


<p>while he agrees that can be useful sometimes:</p>

<ul>
<li>mostly in OOP</li>
<li>to keep you on the rails and focused</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: tdd, jon-pither, senior-developer, junior-developer, aesthetics, lateral-thinking</p>

<h2>Fred George On Programmer Anarchy</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/news/2012/02/programmer-anarchy">this article</a> by Roopesh Shenoy on a talk by Fred George: &ldquo;Programmer Anarchy&rdquo;, where programmers make business decisions based on business metrics set by clients, among other things.</p>

<p>Tags: roopesh-shenoy, fred-george, programmer-anarchy, analogy, anarchy, business-metric, client, agile, methodology</p>

<h2>Programmer Anarchy</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/fredgeorge/programmer-anarchy-chinese">these slides</a> by Fred George about programmer&rsquo;s anarchy. Commented in the article above</p>

<p>Tags: slide, fred-george, programmer-anarchy, analogy, anarchy, business-metric, client, agile, methodology</p>

<h2>What is Programmer Anarchy and does it have a future?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinjeeblog.com/2012/11/20/what-is-programmer-anarchy-and-does-it-have-a-future/">this article</a> by Martin Jee explaining what is programmer anarchy and how it compares to an agile team. Compares the division of labor structure in anarchist and agile teams, using Marxist terms.</p>

<p>He finishes saying that what is a powerful idea in this methodology is the taking of personal responsibilities by the programmers.</p>

<p>Tags: fred-george, programmer-anarchy, analogy, anarchy, martin-jee, agile, methodology</p>

<h2>Agile is the New Black</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/fredgeorge/agile-is-thenewblack">these slides</a> by Fred George where compares xp/agile development in 1999, 2006 and 2011.</p>

<p>Tags: fred-george, agile, methodology, comparison, slide</p>

<h2>Show How, Don&rsquo;t Tell What - A Management Style</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://2ndscale.com/rtomayko/2012/management-style">this article</a> by Ryan Tomayko about the management style they apply at github:</p>

<blockquote><p>instead of telling them what to do, show people how to plan, build, and ship product together.</p>

<p>I’ve never actually told anyone what to do here. In fact, I vehemently refuse to tell people what to do. Here are just a couple reasons why:</p>

<p>I don’t scale. If I tell someone what to do and they do it, then what? Do I have to tell them another thing to do? What happens when I have to decide what to do for 20 people?</p>

<p>Telling people what to do is lazy. Instead, try to convince them with argument. This is how humans interact when there’s no artificial authority structure and it works great. If you can’t convince people through argument then maybe you shouldn’t be doing it.</p></blockquote>

<p>about managers:</p>

<blockquote><p>It’s often cited that GitHub doesn’t have managers. In my opinion, a better way to describe the phenomenon would be to say that everyone at GitHub is a manager</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: ryan-tomayko, management, management-style, team-management, github</p>

<h2>Clojure for the brave and true: chapter 7 - Clojure Alchemy: Reading, Evaluation, and Macros</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.braveclojure.com/read-and-eval/">this chapter</a> from Daniel Higginbotham about the essential concepts for macros: the reader, the evaluator, their relative order and independence. How to use clojure to extend itself and an example: the thread (<code>-&gt;</code>) macro</p>

<p>Tags: daniel-higginbotham, clojure, macro, chapter, reader, evaluator</p>

<h2>Team Bus Factors: How to Reduce Them and How to Prevent Them</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://5whys.com/blog/team-bus-factors-how-to-reduce-them-and-how-to-prevent-them.html">this article</a> by Roy Osherove on the bus factor:</p>

<ul>
<li>what is it</li>
<li>how to reduce them</li>
<li>how to prevent them</li>
</ul>


<p>Also talks about examples of bus-factor people</p>

<p>Tags: bus-factor, roy-osherove, team-management, prevention, reduction, definition</p>

<h2>Hambre de programar</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@xav1uzz/hambre-de-programar-166aeae3b525">this article</a> (in Spanish) by Xavi Gost where he analyses the Barcelona Software Craftsmanship 2015: the events, the relationships and the passion that it has injected to attendees</p>

<p>Tags: xavi-gost, barcelona-software-craftsmanship, 2015, experience-report, scbcn15</p>

<h2>Software Craftsmanship Barcelona 2015</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.idealista.com/labs/blog/idealista/software-craftsmanship-barcelona-2015/">this analysis</a> of the Barcelona Software Craftsmanship 2015 by the Idealista R&amp;D team.</p>

<p>Tags: jaime-perera, barcelona-software-craftsmanship, 2015, idealista, experience-report, scbcn15</p>

<h2>JVMLS 2015 - Compilers are Databases</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48js0H6ooBY">this video</a> by Martin Odersky on why compilers resemble databases and explains how a functional compiler works on the inside.</p>

<p>Explains the notion of a Type, Reference, Symbol, Denotation (and Multi-Denotation) living in the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST)</p>

<p>Also explains the need for a reading compiler (e.g., for quick validation in the IDE), single-pass and multi-pass compiler.</p>

<p>They have built phases to transform the source code into bytecode, but to better use the cache locality, they programmatically mix phases using Java Reflection (metaprogramming) to traverse the tree (AST) once for these selected phases.</p>

<p>Tags: type, reference, symbol, denotation, abstract-syntax-tree, ast, compiler, functional-compiler, scalac, dotty, martin-odersky, analogy, database</p>

<h2>In Functional Programming, what is a functor?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2030863/in-functional-programming-what-is-a-functor/2031421#2031421">this answer</a> of what is a functor</p>

<p>Tags: stack-overflow, functor, answer, functional-programming</p>

<h2>Ten Habits of a Good Programmer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hintjens.com/blog:98">this list</a> of good habits of good programmers by Pieter Hintjens:</p>

<ol>
<li>If it works and is still useful, don&rsquo;t throw it out.</li>
<li>Never solve the same problem twice in parallel.</li>
<li>Solve the same problem often in serial.</li>
<li>Write code, and repeat, until you are fluent in your language.</li>
<li>Learn to use code generators.</li>
<li>Work with others.</li>
<li>Technology is a tool, not a tribal affiliation.</li>
<li>Aim for this cycle: learn, play, work, teach.</li>
<li>Get your edit-compile-run-fail cycles down to seconds.</li>
<li>If you need debuggers, you&rsquo;re doing it wrong.</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: pieter-hintjens, list, habit, good-programmer</p>

<h2>Beginning Clojure: Cursive</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://potetm.github.io/2015/10/04/beginning-clojure-cursive.html">this tutorial</a> on installing Cursive, IntelliJ Idea&rsquo;s plugin for working with Clojure. Written by Tim Pote</p>

<p>Tags: cursive, clojure, intellij-idea, plugin, tutorial, tim-pote</p>

<h2>#NodeJS : A quick optimization advice</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://top.fse.guru/nodejs-a-quick-optimization-advice-7353b820c92e">this article</a> on the limit for inlining for the NodeJS optimizing compiler (Crankshaft), that includes both source code and comments. Written Julien Crouzet</p>

<p>Tags: nodejs, comment, julien-crouzet, crankshaft, optimizer, inline, function-inline</p>

<h2>Specification Pattern</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Specification_pattern">this wikipedia</a> page on the specification pattern</p>

<p>Tags: eric-evans, martin-fowler, specification-pattern, pattern, design-pattern, dsl, domain-specific-language</p>

<h2>El recruiting está ROTO #Bonilista</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;id=539364dde4">this bonilista</a> where David Bonilla explains why the recruitment sector for technical people in Spain is broken. Article is in Spanish.</p>

<p>Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, recruitment, job, career</p>

<h2>BDDon’t: The practice and the tools</h2>

<p>​I&rsquo;ve  read <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/p2magazine/issue12/bdd-dont/">this article</a> by Kevin Dishman that explains what is BDD and how it I  usually used. Also the common downsides and what to do about it</p>

<p>Suggests using a faster tool, lower on the test pyramid that can bring the same business value at a lower cost</p>

<p>Tags: kevin-dishman, downside, test-pyramid, bdd, test, unit-test, functional-test, acceptance-test</p>

<h2>Cómo usan #Git en GitHub – #scbcn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://codely.tv/screencasts/como-usan-git-en-github/">this screencast</a> on the talk we organized yesterday about github.</p>

<p>Tags: javier-ferrer, codely-tv, codely, event, scbcn, alain-helaili, screencast</p>

<h2>Trying to speed up Binary Search</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://databasearchitects.blogspot.com.es/2015/09/trying-to-speed-up-binary-search.html">this article</a> on how the binary search is implemented and what other algorithms are possible to speed up the search in large datasets, especially common in databases.</p>

<p>Tags: optimization, branch-misprediction, clang, o3, gpp, c, database, binary-search, thomas-neumann</p>

<h2>Scrum 3.0 and Organization 4.0 - impressions from a great evening with Boris Gloger at ImmobilienScout24</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://www.ontheagilepath.net/2015/12/scrum-30-and-organization-40.html">this article</a> by  Sebastian Radics that compares the different ways of doing scrum: 1 2 3, most comments on other strategies or management methodologies like no estimates.</p>

<p>Compares the importance of focusing on the process or on the final product, the role of the scrum master, the role of the product owner, and the team itself.</p>

<p>Tags: management, agile, scrum, team-management, sebastian-radics, scrum30</p>

<h2>Trucos para trabajar con equipos remotos</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://thinkingwithyou.com/2015/11/trucos-para-trabajar-con-equipos-remotos/">this article</a> by Israel Alcázar (Spanish). Explains how this company organized their product development process. explains tools for working with a remote team.</p>

<p>give three pieces of advice for improving it, and further resources to read</p>

<p>Tags: remote, remote-first, isra-alcazar, israel-alcazar, team-management, advice</p>

<h2>Introducing new open-source tools for the Elixir community</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://engineering.pinterest.com/blog/introducing-new-open-source-tools-elixir-community">this article</a> by Steve Cohen that explains what the actor model is and what is the spirit of the elixir language: user friendlier syntax for erlang</p>

<p>They also explain that they have implemented and ad server and access control using elixir. For this matter, they rely on two tools that are now open source</p>

<p>Tags: elixir, microsecond, latency, erlang, actor-model, language-syntax, open-source, steve-cohen</p>

<h2>¿Cuánto pagas por tus herramientas de trabajo?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;id=12ed2d6eb0">this bonilista</a> about how much programmers invest in buying their tools (and honing them). By David Bonilla, in Spanish</p>

<p>Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, tool, investment</p>

<h2>Clojure at a Bank – Freeing the Rules</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pitheringabout.com/?p=830">this article</a> by Jon Pither about converting OO business rules into Clojure and using the homoiconicity for increasing the power: when code is data, the rules themselves become searchable (using a search engine), visualizable and analyzable. This wasn&rsquo;t possible before when code was not data.</p>

<p>They have also build further tools to analyze rules with larger sets of data, rather than unit tests, to see if they conflict among each other.</p>

<p>Tags: jon-pither, clojure, homoiconicity, code=data, data=code, rule, rule-engine, bank, business-rule, code-analysis</p>

<h2>Five reasons to learn Clojure and Emacs together</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pitheringabout.com/?p=849">this article</a> by Jon Pither advocating the learning of Clojure and Emacs at the same time. The main reasons are: liberation, change, support, simplicity, mass adoption.</p>

<p>Cites that being hard to learn a new editor is a good idea to separate those who are willing to invest the time in learning (both an editor and a new language) from those who don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Tags: clojure, emacs, jon-pither, learning, liberation, change, support, simplicity, mass-adoption</p>

<h2>Pull Requests Maintainers Won&rsquo;t Hate</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this <a href="https://www.booleanknot.com/blog/2013/09/07/pull-requests.html">list of tips</a> by James Reeves on improving the pull requests
Tags: pull-request, james-reeves, tip, list</p>

<h2>How to get rich in tech, guaranteed.</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://startupljackson.com/post/135800367395/how-to-get-rich-in-tech-guaranteed">this article</a> that describes what is a way to make good money and retire rich why working for a company.</p>

<p>It also explains about entering the startup market, what questions should be asked, what&rsquo;s your real value, what are the benefits of doing it, known limitations and other questions</p>

<p>Tags: startup, career, career-management, work, professional-career, value, money</p>

<h2>Modern Perl 4th edition, a review</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://perltricks.com/article/205/2015/12/21/Modern-Perl-4th-edition--a-review">this article</a> that explains how this new book covers the syntax, idioms and the rest of the Perl language.</p>

<p>In this 4th edition, parts of  the text have completely been rewritten, a New formatting applied to ease and improve the reading comprehension</p>

<p>Tags: book-review, review, david-farrell, perl, reedition, modern-perl</p>

<h2>8 Characteristics of Agile Software Developers</h2>

<p>​I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@pm_loop/8-characteristics-of-successful-agile-software-developers-ab2c43abb959">this article</a> that describes what characteristics are common in companies practicing an agile methodology, as revealed by a study (that even though it&rsquo;s not cited, can be tracked back to <a href="http://productdevelopmentsuccess.com/study">here</a>)</p>

<p>Suggests ideas for teams that change in a changing environment and what to do about it.</p>

<p>Written by Keela Robison.</p>

<p>Tags: keela-robison, agile, team-management</p>

<h2>This is why you never end up hiring good developers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://qz.com/258066/this-is-why-you-dont-hire-good-developers/">this article</a> that explains what to look for in a strong, stronger, strongest (software) developer</p>

<p>The main idea is to find a good person that fits the job, without inflicting pain in the team morale and can learn to perform the specific tasks in the future, as (paraprasing) the pool of people that know what you need is much smaller than the people who can learn it.</p>

<p>The article specifies what to look and not look for in a candidate.</p>

<p>Some quotes:</p>

<blockquote><p>grasp of complex topics and the ability to clearly communicate about them, which are the two jobs of the working engineer.</p>

<p>track record of learning new skills and applying them successfully</p>

<p>TL;DR:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Many interview techniques test skills that are at best irrelevant to real working life;</p></li>
<li><p>you want somebody who knows enough to do the job right now;</p></li>
<li><p>or somebody smart and motivated enough that they can learn the job quickly;</p></li>
<li><p>you want somebody who keeps getting better at what they do;</p></li>
<li><p>your interview should be a collaborative conversations, not a combative interrogation;</p></li>
<li><p>you also want somebody who you will enjoy working with;</p></li>
<li><p>it’s important to separate “enjoy working with” from “enjoy hanging out with;”</p></li>
<li><p>don’t hire assholes, no matter how good they are;</p></li>
<li><p>if your team isn’t diverse, your team is worse than it needed to be;</p></li>
<li><p>accept that hiring takes a really long time and is really, really hard.</p></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<h2>Effective Learning Strategies for Programmers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve (re-)read <a href="http://akaptur.com/blog/2015/10/10/effective-learning-strategies-for-programmers/">this article</a> by Allison Kaptur on fixed vs growth mindset and the need for having the latter for being a programmer.</p>

<p>The fixed mindset is present in the 10x-engineer, and the worshipping of heroes.</p>

<p>It also includes a recipe for changing from a fixed-mindset to a growth-mindset.</p>

<p>(Note: this entry is also present in this same month)</p>

<p>Tags: allison-kaptur, fixed-mindset, growth-mindset, research, learning-strategy, recurse-center, carol-dweck, mindset, 10x-engineer, impostor-syndrome</p>

<h2>Doctor! Please fix my agile!</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/59614769/Presentations/Doctor%20please%20fix%20my%20Agile.pdf">these slides</a> by Ville Törmälä on what is agile, organizational problems and the distinction between efficiency and effectiveness. Also talks about the distribution of time and the organization of the environment (what calls)</p>

<p>Tags: slide, agile, efficiency, effectiveness, tip, organization, ville-tormala, project-thinking, team-thinking</p>

<h2>“Wolf” narrative considered harmful (also biologically unlikely)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://laughingmeme.org/2014/09/02/wolf-narrative-considered-harmful-also-biologically-unlikely/">this article</a> that explains what the &ldquo;lone wolf&rdquo; archetype is, among programmers, and possible outcomings for those profiles. Written by Kellan Elliott-McCrea.</p>

<p>Describes some craftsmanship ideas for these roles, based on their proficiency with their tools, that will generate tools for the rest of the team and make the rest more effective. Also discusses the non-management advancement career.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, wolf, lone-wolf, archetype, programmer, programmer-analogy, profile, team-management, kellan-elliott-mccrea</p>

<h2>The Wolf - dictating their own terms</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/the-wolf/">this article</a> by Michael Lopp about the <code>wolf</code> position as a person or in a team. He describes their characteristics and his own experiences working with them.</p>

<p>Tags: management, wolf, team-management, analogy, michael-lopp</p>

<h2>Volkswagen and Cheating Software</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.schneier.com/crypto-gram/archives/2015/1015.html#1">this essay</a> by Bruce Schneier on cheating software, using as an example the Volkswagen case, but especially centered on software that is made do cheat in an undetectable fashion. Or that could be attributed to a programming mistake. The later, says the author, is so common that there could be already intentional or unintentional errors hiding cheating.</p>

<p>The author cites the Internet of Things of new opportunities for companies to use / produce cheating software and about a possible solution: transparency and oversight of the software that more and more reigns our lives.</p>

<p>Other (opinion) articles I&rsquo;ve read on the issue are:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/24/opinion/volkswagen-and-the-era-of-cheating-software.html">Volkswagen and the Era of Cheating Software</a> by Zeynep Tufekci</li>
<li><a href="http://fusion.net/story/202867/volkswagen-software-deception-ai/">Volkswagen isn’t the first company to use software to break the law and it won’t be the last</a> by Daniela Hernandez</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/future_tense/2015/09/volkswagen_s_cheating_emissions_software_and_the_threat_of_black_boxes.html">Harry Potter and the Mysterious Defeat Device</a> by James Grimmelmann</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: cryptogram, bruce Schneier, volkswagen, mistake, quality, transparency, oversight, iot, essay, cheating, cheating software</p>

<h2>Please, Java. Do Finally Support Multiline String Literals</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jooq.org/2015/12/29/please-java-do-finally-support-multiline-strings/">this article</a> explaining the need for multi-line string literal in java.</p>

<p>Tags: java, syntax, string, feature, multi-line string</p>

<h2>The Silver Bullet Syndrome</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wyd6J3yjcs">this talk</a> by Hadi Hariri about chasing the next silver bullet.</p>

<p>He explains this with javascript and nodejs, but it could be exemplified with other technologies / promises as well.</p>

<p>Note: ABC stands for:</p>

<ul>
<li>A = address</li>
<li>B = binding</li>
<li>C = contract</li>
</ul>


<p> Tags: hadi-hariri, silver-bullet, talk, devoxx</p>

<h2>Writing Clean Tests – Small Is Beautiful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.petrikainulainen.net/programming/testing/writing-clean-tests-small-is-beautiful/">this article</a> by Petri Kainulainen on writing BDD style tests with JUnit in java.</p>

<p>There is <a href="https://github.com/NitorCreations/CoreComponents/tree/master/junit-runners">a tool</a>, created by Nitor Creations that allows you to write nested classes in JUnit, allowing for test specialization.</p>

<p>Tags: junit, runner, bdd, test, nitor-creations, petri-kainulainen, tdd</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demand for TDD and Refactor]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/demand-for-tdd-and-refactor/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-25T11:28:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/demand-for-tdd-and-refactor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I went to the Jason Gorman&rsquo;s TDD workshop (experience report <a href="../../../../2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop">here</a>), he said something interesting regarding refactor and TDD:</p>

<blockquote><p>In job offers / advertisements, TDD is much more in demand than refactor. But the latter is included in the former as an integral part.</p>

<p>Jason Gorman</p></blockquote>

<p>I agree with the second thought: you cannot properly do TDD without refactoring, as it is an integral part; also the third phase.</p>

<p>For me, sometimes refactoring is the difference between code and &ldquo;Clean Code&rdquo; (as defined in the book by the same title). If I cannot find the (algorithmic) pattern for the software I&rsquo;m writing, I try to introduce scaffolds to keep investigating until I can find a viable, general solution (if the problem requires it.)</p>

<p>Even after doing the refactor <code>replace algorithm</code>, the code might not have the responsibilities in the right place, the methods might be long, value objects not extracted yet, etc. This is where further refactor is needed to introduce all those qualities in the piece of software.</p>

<p>I believe that we programmers have done a bad job of communicating with the rest of the organization what refactoring is about. It has nothing to do with beauty, style or design (in the visual sense) but is related to maintainability, coupling, defects and quality. Money, in the long run, as its objective is to make it cheaper to change in the future, a better investment and ROI. This is the common language that the rest of the company understands.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience Report: Test-driven Development Intensive, by Jason Gorman]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-12T18:13:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/12/jason-gorman-tdd-intensive-workshop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an experience report on <a href="http://twitter.com/@jasongorman">Jason Gorman</a>&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.codemanship.co.uk/tdd.html">Test-driven development intensive workshop</a>&rdquo; on the April 11th, 2015</p>

<p>I attended this training in the <a href="http://www.grenfell-housing.co.uk/">Greenfell housing &amp; training</a> in South Wimbledon, London SW19 1JZ. The training spanned from 10:00 to 17:00 with a half an hour for lunch plus three or four 10-15 minute pauses. (7 - ,5 - 4 * 12/60 = ~5.7hours = 5 hours 45 minutes)</p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>There were 23 of us, including me. We spent some half hour introducing ourselves before the training started. I remember about a tester that came to the workshop &ldquo;wanting to know more about this testing methodology&rdquo;. Jason&rsquo;s answer was priceless: &ldquo;I&rsquo;m sorry but you came to the wrong place: this is not about testing&rdquo;.
</p>

<p>At 10:00 sharp, he started a set of slides explaining what TDD is about, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>productivity:

<ul>
<li>no company is willing to give you a &ldquo;get out of jail free&rdquo; card to get out of the productivity zone</li>
<li>a drop in the productivity, at least for the first weeks</li>
<li>you have to find a time slot in your schedule to practice TDD, otherwise it&rsquo;s like learning to swim while crossing the Atlantic Ocean</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You have to feel uncomfortable not doing TDD</li>
<li>triangulation:

<ul>
<li>how each problem is different</li>
<li>you can only learn it by doing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>TDD styles:

<ul>
<li>Chicago style by Kent Beck. Reference book would be &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">TDD by example</a>&rdquo;</li>
<li>London school or Mockist style by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce. Reference book would be <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">&ldquo;Growing object oriented software, guided by tests</a>"</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>13 good habits for a sustainable test-driven development way</li>
<li>The basic TDD cycle:

<ul>
<li>an executable specification, encoded in a failing test</li>
<li>pass the test in the simplest way</li>
<li>refactor</li>
<li>(talking with another attendee, he described to me a new TDD phase called redesign. Maybe another post will explain this in deeper detail level)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Some ideas about <a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org/rules/simple.html">Simple design, simple development, simplicity</a> (<a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org">XP</a>)</li>
<li>Shown a wrong example of mixing assertions (state) and verifications (interactions)</li>
<li>More than one reason to go wrong makes the code non-trivial anymore. Non-trivial code requires tests</li>
<li>You want to see the test failing for the right reason: remove / finish code that does not compile, fix null pointers, array out of bounds exceptions, etc. See it fail with &ldquo;was <X> but expected <Y>&rdquo; or &ldquo;NoInteractionException&rdquo; (hamcrest error and mockito error, respectively; both java)</li>
<li>Duplication as a sign of design smell</li>
<li>Process of generalizing code: discover the need for patterns</li>
<li>The most difficult skill in TDD is refactoring [and design; note is mine]. The TDD cycle is very easy.

<ul>
<li>TDD is much more in demand than refactoring, even though the former includes the latter</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Refactor until you&rsquo;re happy with the code, until you stand by it</li>
</ul>


<h2>CRC Cards</h2>

<p>A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class-responsibility-collaboration_card">Class-responsibility-collaboration card</a> is as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>top: class name</li>
<li>half left: responsibilities</li>
<li>half right: collaborations</li>
</ul>


<p>Notes from the slides:</p>

<ul>
<li>each then is an outcome

<ul>
<li>do not mix outcomes and implications. An example: after winning the lottery, the money should be transferred to my bank account and I can buy a yacht. The former is an outcome (change in state) and the latter an implication (a new action that is now enabled)</li>
<li>an outcome is mapped to an assertion, while a collaboration is mapped to an interaction (verify in mockito)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Given / When / Then is not enough to implement an executable specification. We need examples, detail</li>
<li>OO: send messages to distribute responsibility.

<ul>
<li>A Then is an unique responsibility</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Topmost object: no one connects with it</li>
<li>Put the work where the data is</li>
<li>Tell, don&rsquo;t ask <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> vs data driven design (tell a collaborator what to do vs ask for values and do the work yourself)</li>
<li>You want as few interactions as possible (related to the tell, don&rsquo;t ask)</li>
<li>More objects than outcomes is a bad thing (design smell) (?)</li>
<li>CRC is a very mechanical exercise, do not over think it</li>
<li>Describe outcomes as changes in OO (new, destroy, relationships, modify fields / state)</li>
<li>Continuous integration is not necessarily about shipping the code at each commit but having it shippable at each commit, as always having a product that is ready for its production phase</li>
</ul>


<h2>Exercises</h2>

<p>All exercises were done in pairs, always switching one half of the pair. He asked for someone in the pair to raise, especially if you were not a programmer (e.g., tester, manager)</p>

<h3>First exercise: Banking</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of transferring money from an account to another</p></blockquote>

<p>A chance to practice arrange, act, assert</p>

<p>Later, he did it some live coding to develop the same kata, practicing &ldquo;<a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/TDD-as-if-You-Meant-It">TDD as if you meant it</a>&rdquo; (<a href="https://twitter.com/keithb_b">Keith Braithwaite</a>&rsquo;s original idea). We discovered together the &ldquo;primitive obsession&rdquo; and &ldquo;feature envy&rdquo; smells. We tried doing as few decisions as possible.</p>

<h3>Second exercise: Fibonacci sequence generator</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of generating Fibonacci sequences, no shorter that 8 and no longer than 50</p></blockquote>

<p>A chance to practice baby steps.</p>

<p>My pair and I had the chance of discovering the importance of understanding correctly the requirements before writing a line of code. Also, I learned about the different ways of doing TDD. In this case, my pair executed the tests via a main (java class) and saw the failures on the console. When proposed to do it in the JUnit runner the IDE has, he said he preferred it in his own ways.</p>

<p>Jason did some live coding to show how he approached and triangulated this exercise.</p>

<p>I really liked some of what he said: I like to make the API correct from the first moment so I will ask questions that are correct but only check answers for things that I have already implemented. Example:</p>

<p>As the generated sequence can only have <code>8 &lt;= x &lt;= 50</code> elements, a list returning a single element would not be correct. So</p>

<pre><code class="java">//class FibonacciTests
@Test
public void theFirstElementIsOne(){
    assertThat(new FibonacciSequence().generate(8)[0], is(1));
}
</code></pre>

<h3>Third exercise: FizzBuzz</h3>

<blockquote><p>Write a program that is capable of returning a string with all numbers less than 100 that are using the FizzBuzz pattern. This FizzBuzz pattern converts the divisors of 3 to &lsquo;fizz&rsquo;, divisors of 5 to &lsquo;buzz&rsquo; and divisors to both to &lsquo;fizzbuzz&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>I discovered that this FizzBuzz is a drinking game in the UK.</p>

<h3>Fourth exercise: CRC cards</h3>

<p>Before this exercise there was a short introduction on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Class-responsibility-collaboration_card">Class-responsibility-collaboration card</a>, explained above</p>

<p>Following an example about a movie library, there were six user stories, described at high level, without acceptance criteria.</p>

<p>We had to create an acceptance criteria for this user story. Later create a set of CRC cards and finally partially implement said feature.</p>

<p>Very interesting exercise, such a pity that there wasn&rsquo;t more time to complete this exercise or see him doing it</p>

<h2>Knowledge pearls</h2>

<p>He dropped some knowledge pearls (that I&rsquo;m going to use myself):</p>

<pre><code>Q: When are you done with TDD?
A: When you can not think of more tests for your suite
</code></pre>

<pre><code>Q: What do we do after TDD?
A: (No answer)
Q: Starts with "T". Any idea?
A: Testing. Test for the purpose of testing, not TDD
</code></pre>

<p>Close concepts interested in responsibilities:</p>

<ul>
<li>Conceptual diagram and class diagram</li>
<li>Instance diagram</li>
<li>Knowledge map and tag cloud</li>
</ul>


<p>Regarding legacy code:</p>

<ul>
<li>Isolate big balls of mud into parts and test these as end-to-end. Also connected to isolating groups of nodes into the class graph</li>
<li>Understand what the code does, not the architecture</li>
<li>Do not use a mock to help you test legacy code, use it just as a design tool. (It might be a good idea to use it temporarily while you refactor, but remove it afterwards)</li>
<li>Tests with mocks double down on the design: if it is broken, it will be a drag more than help</li>
</ul>


<p>Test on the boundaries. Many times we test in the middle of the algorithm but forget the boundaries, where many special cases hide</p>

<p>The GOOS book is pronounced like the goose animal (&ldquo;/gús/&rdquo;) in English</p>

<p>He said he never copy pastes <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup>.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<ul>
<li>This is a two day workshop condensed on a single day. It shows. In my opinion, it would be better to do fewer exercises and dig deeper in them rather than try so many approaches / exercises</li>
<li>The CRC exercise was well thought and really massaged. It touches the right spots and makes you want to learn more about the subject</li>
<li>Promiscuously pairing is always a good idea, as you don&rsquo;t know what level have your attendees. Get stuck for the whole day with someone who has a (very) different knowledge level than you might spoil the workshop</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t see the benefit of doing the fizzbuzz kata after having done the Fibonacci sequence one</li>
<li>In my opinion, there were too many breaks. Doing a break in the morning (10-15 mins), lunch (30 mins) and afternoon (10-15 mins) is enough</li>
</ul>


<p>On a personal note:</p>

<ul>
<li>It is not enough to attend the workshop. You have to take notes and study them at home later. (Thanks <a href="http://spines.me">spines</a> for this lesson)</li>
<li>I really had a great time, learned a lot, even though I already know something about TDD</li>
<li>Met very interesting people</li>
<li>Would attend to the workshop again</li>
</ul>


<p>In general, I&rsquo;d like to thank Jason and the other attendees for making this workshop possible. I had a blast there.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>As described by <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/TellDontAsk.html">Martin Fowler</a> and the <a href="https://pragprog.com/articles/tell-dont-ask">Pragmatic Bookshelf</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Copy pasting this post&rsquo;s structure resulted in a wrong title that had to be fixed. Maybe the extra effort of not copy pasting has a good ROI, as long as you do not copy paste by typing the text you&rsquo;re reading from somewhere else<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
