<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>haskell on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/haskell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in haskell on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/haskell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/06/01/self-study-june-2024/</guid>
      <description>Scientific glassblower continues century-old campus tradition (2021) the story of a glassblower dedicated to producing specialized hardware for a university
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40549209
Tags: hackernews, imported, dredmorbius, glassblower, university, hardware, profession, glass
Id: e07b0ed2-185b-4cf7-bdbe-a134c555d797 Read: Sat, 01 Jun 2024 21:26:29 +0000
Half a century of SQL https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40561440
Tags: hackernews, imported, pseudolus, sql, programming-language, anniversary, birthday
Id: f971c65c-8034-47c1-b2f5-24358c2de7b4 Read: Mon, 03 Jun 2024 11:04:06 +0000
Entropy, a CLI that scans files to find high entropy lines (might be secrets) https://news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Coglan, introducing monads.
About composability:
 The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable
 or
 symmetric input and output types
 Guide to basic monadic functions:
 lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A common misunderstanding about `reduce`</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/14/a-common-misunderstanding-about-reduce/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 18:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/14/a-common-misunderstanding-about-reduce/</guid>
      <description>Misconception I&amp;rsquo;ve read in several places that reduce reduces an array1 of values to a single one. The main characteristic of this function is not to reduce to a &amp;lsquo;smaller element&amp;rsquo; / &amp;lsquo;single element&amp;rsquo;, but to have access to the accumulated results and the elements, one by one. Quoting Mozilla Developer Network&amp;rsquo;s (MDN) Javascript reference:
 The reduce() method applies a function against an accumulator and each value of the array (from left-to-right) to reduce it to a single value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>Advice for white men I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cate Huston about how advice affects different people.
 But here are some things to consider:
 Advice on failure is different for people who are judged on performance rather than potential. Advice on saying no is different for people who aren’t appreciated for doing work for the collective… but who are punished if they don’t. Advice on negotiation is different for people who are perceived negatively when they do negotiate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</guid>
      <description>Should Engineers Design? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cap Watkins where he explains the relationship between designers and programmers and how to get the latter involved in the design / UX / UI process.
Tags: cap-watkins, design, ux, ui, exchange, cross-functional
The Sliding Scale of Giving a Fuck I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cap Watkins where he explains that different topics have a different importance to each one of us: this topic might be very important for someone else, ergo, it makes mores sense to evaluate their option more carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</guid>
      <description>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.
Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery
Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &amp;ldquo;Call me maybe&amp;rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The language was prepared for that</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-language-was-prepared-for-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-language-was-prepared-for-that/</guid>
      <description>Many times I&amp;rsquo;ve written this function:
public boolean between(int lowerBound, int n, int upperBound){ return lowerBound &amp;lt;= n &amp;amp;&amp;amp; n &amp;lt;= upperBound; } It may depend on the case, whether it is [], [), (] or (), to use mathematical terms.
When the two comparisons are the same ([] and ()), there is duplication in the comparisons.
Investigating a little bit on this in clojure, I&amp;rsquo;ve found this function:
&amp;lt;= And its clojuredocs: Returns non-nil if nums are in monotonically non-decreasing order, otherwise false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in May 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015 into a single post
Programmer passion considered harmful I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.
Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by Ken Auer
Improve your development environments with virtualization I have seen this video: Improve your development environments with virtualization by Luke Sneeringer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
