<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>script on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/script/</link>
    <description>Recent content in script on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/script/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing safe(r) bash scripts</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/13/writing-safe-bash-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 07:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/13/writing-safe-bash-scripts/</guid>
      <description>After writing more and more bash scripts for a client, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write down my thoughts about it.
This assumes you have some knowledge about bash, as it is not intended as a beginner&amp;rsquo;s tutorial.
Why bash scripts?  Bash is present in almost every unix/linux-based stack, now some Windows as well. An exception is the &amp;lsquo;alpine&amp;rsquo; docker images, which have a smaller, lighter shell (more on that later) Everything that you can automate, you can do from bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying titles in a Trello Board</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/modifying-titles-in-a-trello-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/modifying-titles-in-a-trello-board/</guid>
      <description>A teammate and I have created a small tool to modify the titles of the trello card in a trello board.
Technical description It works by applying a function to the existing title (because we wanted to remove a prefix from the existing title).
The modification is done, not through the API, but simulating user interaction:
 Click to edit the card Input the new title Save  The full code is available here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
