<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>java on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in java on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/12/01/self-study-december-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/12/01/self-study-december-2022/</guid>
      <description>CCache: a fast c/c++ compiler cache Related to 027d6f8a-714e-11ed-869a-0242ac110003
Tags: tool, cache, compilation-cache, optimization, speedup, c, cpp, c++, gcc, clang
Id: f2423a38-714d-11ed-92b4-0242ac110003 Read: Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:58:30 +0000
CATS: OpenAPI fuzzing and test generation tool Tags: cats, tool, openapi, fuzz-testing, test-tool, java, endava, eoin-woods
Id: 08b0cdb0-714f-11ed-a45c-0242ac110003 Read: Thu, 01 Dec 2022 08:06:18 +0000
I&amp;rsquo;ve fuzzed a small part of the GitHub API. Here are my findings. Using CATS to fuzz part of the Github API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/08/01/self-study-august-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/08/01/self-study-august-2022/</guid>
      <description>A Tutorial on Portable Makefiles (2017) https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32303193
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a4860376-c1a0-11ed-ae57-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 07:43:01 2022
Software engineering books https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32305997
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a23a4924-c1a0-11ed-a585-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 13:57:25 2022
Show HN: Emery – Personal productivity workspace https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32312413
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a6dab644-c1a0-11ed-b024-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 21:42:53 2022
Minify your container https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32334741
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a94d30aa-c1a0-11ed-bb01-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Aug 3 17:42:44 2022
Against Discipline https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32340703</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/07/01/self-study-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>How I use reveal.js This author explains how they use reveal.js.
The online editor (slides.com).
The author uses plain html for storing the slides.
Tags: slide, slideshare, reveal-js, reveal, presentation, slide-deck, michael-mccune
Id: 41e287b4-ae15-11e9-9e8a-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 07:16:33 +0000
All your digital life on a single timeline, stored locally Keep your digital life under your control
Tags: backup, local-data, encryption, control
Id: 4d115f64-ae17-11e9-bf0e-0242ac110003 Read: Wed, 24 Jul 2019 13:31:11 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a component that includes randomness</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/15/testing-component-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 09:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/15/testing-component-randomness/</guid>
      <description>Context We have been tasked with designing a component to generate secrets for two-factor authentication (2FA), to ensure that the you also own that other &amp;lsquo;channel&amp;rsquo;.
It has to be secure enough to pass to verify a user, meaning no other user should be able to impersonating another one by guessing the secret.
Solution A first solution that he have implemented is to provide a 6-digit pin code.
The solution (in java) is straightforward: get a Random to generate ints for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.
Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning
Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing options for parametrized testing in javascript</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/26/comparing-options-for-parametrized-testing-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 15:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/26/comparing-options-for-parametrized-testing-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>We explore how to use parametrized tests (example in java, example in c#)
The tests are written using mocha syntax: describe, it. Using chai for expectations: assert.
Note: the example used below (adding to an array) is simple enough to be understood by everybody, without having to explain the domain. The real tests can have a more complicated environment or domain. This is just an example.
Using a custom syntax This is just an example of some possible syntax, not using any (currently) existing framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>DiversityMediocrityIllusion I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Martin Fowler (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.
Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.
Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki
What do cryptic Github comments mean? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Being A Developer After 40 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:
 Forget The Hype Choose Your Galaxy Wisely Learn About Software History Keep on Learning Teach Workplaces Suck Know Your Worth Send The Elevator Down LLVM  He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/11/02/self-study-in-november-2015/</guid>
      <description>Call me maybe: RabbitMQ I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Kyle Kingsbury on using RabbitMQ as a lock service. It investigates and gives a counterexample of using it for this purpose.
Uses Knossos to do the testing and surfaces a problem with it. Explains specific problems on locking: at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery
Note: References Jepsen (I guess an inside joke to the song &amp;ldquo;Call me maybe&amp;rdquo; by Carly Rae Jepsen) for at-most-once and at-least-once message delivery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Tips &amp; Gotchas</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/07/java-tips-gotchas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/07/java-tips-gotchas/</guid>
      <description>JVM default encoding as UTF-8 Make the JVM use UTF-8 character encoding by default
Set up the system property JAVA_TOOL_OPTIONS to -Dfile.encoding=UTF8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding dojo: Palindromes</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/19/coding-dojo-palindromes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 11:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/19/coding-dojo-palindromes/</guid>
      <description>At a client, today I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated a coding dojo on palindrome searching.
I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared a github repository for the java solutions. In this repository, the tag start-here has the prepared pom with dependencies.
We have paired to work on the kata but none of my teammate&amp;rsquo;s solutions are available (at the moment), but mine is at the master branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding dojo: Goldbach Conjecture</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/17/coding-dojo-goldbach-conjecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 23:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/17/coding-dojo-goldbach-conjecture/</guid>
      <description>At the Barcelona Software Craftsmanship meetup, today I&amp;rsquo;ve facilitated a coding dojo on the Goldbach Conjecture. The problem was prepared by Manuel Rivero.
The meetup event is here and there are plenty of solutions prepared by the pairs:
 Java C# Haskell PHP Java PHP Haskell  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The language was prepared for that</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-language-was-prepared-for-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-language-was-prepared-for-that/</guid>
      <description>Many times I&amp;rsquo;ve written this function:
public boolean between(int lowerBound, int n, int upperBound){ return lowerBound &amp;lt;= n &amp;amp;&amp;amp; n &amp;lt;= upperBound; } It may depend on the case, whether it is [], [), (] or (), to use mathematical terms.
When the two comparisons are the same ([] and ()), there is duplication in the comparisons.
Investigating a little bit on this in clojure, I&amp;rsquo;ve found this function:
&amp;lt;= And its clojuredocs: Returns non-nil if nums are in monotonically non-decreasing order, otherwise false.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple return values in a Mockito Stub</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/07/multiple-values-in-a-mockito-stub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 11:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/07/multiple-values-in-a-mockito-stub/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked today how to return multiple return values from a Mockito Spy, effectively using the spy as a Stub, as well.
package com.example.spike; import static org.hamcrest.MatcherAssert.assertThat; import static org.hamcrest.Matchers.is; import static org.mockito.Mockito.spy; import static org.mockito.Mockito.when; import org.junit.Test; import org.mockito.Spy; public class DifferentReturnValues { @Spy private Spike1 spike1 = new Spike1(); @Test public void spike1() { spike1 = spy(spike1); when(spike1.getBool()).thenReturn(false, true); assertThat(spike1.getBool(), is(false)); assertThat(spike1.getBool(), is(true)); assertThat(spike1.getBool(), is(true)); assertThat(spike1.getBool(), is(true)); } private class Spike1 { public boolean getBool() { return true; } } } The key line is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool to Find Duplicate values in Constants</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/tool-to-find-duplicate-values-in-constants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 13:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/tool-to-find-duplicate-values-in-constants/</guid>
      <description>Imagine having this java class:
private static class RepeatedConstants { public static final String A = &amp;#34;A&amp;#34;; public static final String A_1 = A; public static final String A_2 = &amp;#34;A&amp;#34;; public static final Integer _3 = 3; public static final Integer THREE = 3; } I wanted to remove the repeated values in the constants, in an automatic way, because the file was big (&amp;gt; 4000 constants). A way of doing this is basing the differences on the values, directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Testing with Java 8 Lambdas</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/exploring-testing-with-java-8-lambdas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 13:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/exploring-testing-with-java-8-lambdas/</guid>
      <description>At a client, we were testing a simple feature, but the resulting tests had much subtle repetition:
(source code is here)
@Test public void log_when_sending_greeting_letters() { sut.send(mock(GreetingLetter.class)); verify(logger).sentGreetingLetter(); } @Test public void log_when_sending_love_letters() { sut.send(mock(LoveLetter.class)); verify(logger).sentLoveLetter(); } and the production code:
public class MailSender { private final EventLogger eventLogger; public MailSender (final EventLogger eventLogger) { this.eventLogger = eventLogger; } public void send (final GreetingLetter letter) { // more business logic 	eventLogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What defines a dependency</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/what-defines-a-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 07:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/what-defines-a-dependency/</guid>
      <description>A friend and I were arguing about this code (fragment):
public void register (final String userName) { try { registeredUsers.add(new User(userName)); } catch (AlreadyRegisteredUserException e) { resultListener.alreadyRegistered(userName); } } I would have said that resultListener is a dependency as, first, it was injected by the constructor, second, it is necessary for the execution (negative case).
He suggested that:
 being injected through the constructor is usually what happens with dependencies, but does not make it one (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in July 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post
Clojure made simple I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk Easy made simple
 polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter  Productive pair programming I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about pair programming, using the driver &amp;amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé
Building Automated REST APIs with Python Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotations and Aspects in Java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/21/annotations-and-aspects-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 07:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/21/annotations-and-aspects-in-java/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a sample project with an annotation and an aspect to intercept it and decorate it.
The code provides a way of doing try|catch, specifying an exception to be caught.
The source code is available here
In the process This has taken me approximately one hour to prepare the spike and half more to refactor and massage a bit.
If you want to see the raw details, the refactor has been committed step by step (the spike hasn&amp;rsquo;t).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven module Base for cucumber in java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 07:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve built a small maven module, to be used directly with cucumber. You can fork the repository here
This is the setup I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed for the meetup &amp;ldquo;BDD Cucumber kata (gherkin + code)&amp;quot;. Will see if this code is successfully used by the ~40 participants in a couple of weeks
(Quote from the README.md):
This maven project has been possible due to Thomas Sundberg and this post
Should you want to, there&amp;rsquo;s a tweet to thank him the effort: [tweet intent here](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown-bag session: maven</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/06/brown-bag-session-maven/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 22:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/06/brown-bag-session-maven/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we did a training about the maven tool. One of the team members explained to us some topics including:
 lifecycles profiles and how to create one  slowTests for integration tests (this client only) downloadJavadoc downloadSources   convention over configuration scopes of the dependencies (test, runtime, compile, provided) tricks about the tool:  order of the dependencies (especially junit, hamcrest)   plugins and how to build one destination folders  target, classes, test-classes, etc    Note: this post was created a posteriori, with the original date</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kata: persistent linked list</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/23/kata-persistent-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 23:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/23/kata-persistent-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just written a new kata, about a persistent linked list.
It is using the same project as for the linked list kata.
For now, only the add, contains and size methods are implemented.
If you have any comments or code review, please let me know</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your First Language</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language/</guid>
      <description>After reading (in a specific order - below) part of the patterns in Apprenticeship Patterns, I stumbled upon the &amp;ldquo;Your First Language&amp;rdquo;
First of all, the illustration with the baby reading a Java book is priceless.
Having said that, I came to the realization that you might not know a paradigm but just an implementation (e.g., you don&amp;rsquo;t know about Object-Oriented programming but just about Java), in the same fashion as you could not know about LISPs but only about an implementation, such as clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank kata in java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/bank-kata-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 22:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/22/bank-kata-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Manuel Rivero and I did a subset of the bank kata, proposed by Sandro Mancuso.
We&amp;rsquo;ve used java (mockito, hamcrest, junit), outside-in TDD. The code is spread among several sessions. We have not committed after each step, only at the end of the session.
The source code is on github
You can read Manuel&amp;rsquo;s take on the kata on his blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kata: Reverse Polish Notation in java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/kata-reverse-polish-notation-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 03:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/kata-reverse-polish-notation-in-java/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a RPN string calculator in java, using TDD with these: mockito, hamcrest, junit
It&amp;rsquo;s close to the String Calculator kata, by Roy Osherove. This RPN is using mocks (so more difficult than the String calculator)
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to practice &amp;ldquo;Your tests are dragging you down&amp;rdquo; by J.B Rainsberger (mainly, to use something to write on). This behavior is also explained in the book Dirigido por tests (Spanish) by Carlos Blé.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kata: prime factors</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/kata-prime-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 21:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/kata-prime-factors/</guid>
      <description>I just did the prime factors kata, in java using TDD. Results: https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/primeFactors
Code review, comments, pull requests are more than welcome
Source: http://craftsmanship.sv.cmu.edu/katas/prime-factors-kata
Source: http://butunclebob.com/ArticleS.UncleBob.ThePrimeFactorsKata</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
