<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retrospective on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/retrospective/</link>
    <description>Recent content in retrospective on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/retrospective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD Meetup Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 05:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we organized a TDD meetup at the FIB - Barcelona School of Informatics UPC, within Barcelona Software Craftsmanship sponsored by the Junior Empresa d&amp;rsquo;Informàtica. The meetup started at 9:00 until 18:00, with a one-hour pause in the middle.
Where  Please make sure the meetup space (e.g., classroom, meeting room) is available and ready to be used at least 15 minutes before the meetup starts The organizer and the event host should be there in advance to prepare the physical environment (chairs, wifi, beamer, etc) as well as mentally: getting comfortable with the space, loading the presentation, prepare the speaker notes, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing BDD at a client</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/09/implementing-bdd-at-a-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 22:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/09/implementing-bdd-at-a-client/</guid>
      <description>This was a low-hanging fruit as a team member who specialises in QA complained about testing in the last moment during the last sprint&amp;rsquo;s retrospective.
Did the grunt job of connecting the dots and configuring the maven project (using jbehave). Also, got the inspiration from a tutorial.
Announced it only as it was in place and QA approved of it
This grunt job clicked with Sweep the floor
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how the sprint goes and what are the pain points during this sprint</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
