<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/self-study-aggregation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/self-study-aggregation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-reason-why-the-spotify-model-is-broken&#34;&gt;The real reason why the Spotify model is broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://kernelmag.dailydot.com/issue-sections/staff-editorials/12136/spotify-royalty-payment-model/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-of-7-badass-developer-gets-a-rude-awakening&#34;&gt;[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, they wanted a professional problem solver who could jump in and deliver what the company needed, to meet THEIR customers&amp;rsquo; demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking for ways that I could add value to my employer outside of the code I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed my &amp;ldquo;soft skills&amp;rdquo;—my ability to communicate, learn quickly, and pass my knowledge on to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-sonmez, programmer, language-programmer, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-rules-to-live-by-when-you-work-in-an-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34;&gt;6 Rules To Live By When You Work In An Office But Have Remote Team Members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/6-mistakes-when-you-work-in-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Lauren Moon about how trello works remotely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value Individuals Over Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Impromptu Meetings At Someone’s Desk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If One Person Is On A Video Call, EVERYONE Is On A Video Call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication Is Asynchronous. Deal With It.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socializing Is Not Around A Watercooler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tools You’re Using Matter. A Lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, lauren-moon, listicle, trello, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;princeton-s-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34;&gt;Princeton’s Ad-Blocking Superweapon May Put an End to the Ad-Blocking Arms Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/princetons-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Koebler on the tool a university has written and published, that using computer vision, is able to detect sponsored content in native form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jason-koebler, computer-vision, ad, advertisement, ublock, adblock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hasta-pronto&#34;&gt;Hasta pronto…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javiergarzas.com/2016/07/hasta-pronto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Garzás, where he explains that he&amp;rsquo;ll stop blogging for a while and why&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javier-garzas, blog, personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-principles-of-clean-architecture&#34;&gt;The principles of Clean Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video about the clean architecture (with a client&amp;rsquo;s lunch and learn initiative). By Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the plugin is vulnerable to the plugged-in system, at the source code level&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate the detail from the general things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clean-architecture, uncle-bob, robert-martin, video, mvp, model-view-presenter, model-view-controller, mvc, quote, plugin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-languages-which-almost-became-css&#34;&gt;The Languages Which Almost Became CSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eager.io/blog/the-languages-which-almost-were-css/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zack Bloom on the origins of CSS and the languages to add representation to HTML pages / markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes the origins of these languages (e.g., RPP, PWP, CHSS, PSL, FOSI, DSSSL) and how the acceptance of CSS came to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was the technology which was easiest for a beginner to pick up which won, rather than those which were most powerful for an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt; Zack Bloom&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: css, html, history, zack-bloom, mosaic, violawww&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!--
## Gerald Weinberg on Bugs, Errors, and Software Quality

I&#39;ve listened to [this interview][bug-error-weinberg] with Gerald Weinberg where he first talks about software quality, defining a fault, failure, a boo-boo, a blunder (below). Then, they move on to the cost of quality, experiences in his project &#39;Mercury&#39; (a man in orbit; his contribution was on the software side). Says it&#39;s one of his first projects where a person&#39;s life was directly related to a piece of software.

Fault: wrong operation in code
Failure: user&#39;s experience caused by a fault
Boo-boo: a one-off, small failure. Usually shrugged as a small defect
Blunder: a one-off, big failure. Can kill a career

About the cost of software, he mentions that many managers are not willing to pay the price of almost defect-free software and that this level of quality is not required in every project. This idea is similar to the one &#39;Testing every part is akin to reading every letter on the newspaper: one parts are more important than other&#39;.

This interview talks about similar topics than &#39;Why programs fail&#39;, especially about the definition.

At the end of the interview, he talks about team-based software development (~XP) and an anecdote about a company he was consulting with: follow the process or pay the defects out of your own pocket. One of them, accepted paying for defects, until he made a big mistake. Accepted training the rest of the employees into his very precise methods and became very valuable to the company.

Tags: podcast, gerald-weinberg, quality, interview, manager, software-quality, definition, fault, failure, boo-boo, blunder, project-mercury

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;!--
## Microservice Practitioners with Austin Gunter and Richard Li

I&#39;ve listened to [this podcast][us-practitioners] at Software Engineering Daily with Austin Gunter and Richard Li. In it, they talk about how they have organized the conference &#39;Microservice Practicitioners&#39;: how to find speakers, the vibes of the conference, etc.

Tags: austin-gunter, richard-li, organize-a-conference, conference, microservice, microservice-practitioners, podcast, software-engineering-daily

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34;&gt;10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/derickbailey/10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this listicle&lt;/a&gt; of docker myths. By Derick Bailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bored-people-quit&#34;&gt;Bored People Quit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://randsinrepose.com/archives/bored-people-quit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-lopp, boredness, team-management, people, career, tech-lead, quote&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volver&#34;&gt;¿Volver?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raulavila.com/2017/01/volver/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;donkey-code&#34;&gt;Donkey code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://einarwh.wordpress.com/2017/01/21/donkey-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: einar-host, donkey-code, ddd, domain-driven-development, domain, abstraction, missing-abstraction, business-logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men&#34;&gt;10 Habits That Change Boys Into Men&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men-b103c47d47e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on why some men are still boys (e.g., expectations from society) and what can boys do to turn into men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, psychology, learning, evolution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-command-line-utilities&#34;&gt;My favorite command-line utilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/macbook-my-command-line-utilities-f8a121c3b019#.3hpq7suhj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Vitaly Belman in which he explains his curated list of utilities for the terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: vitaly-belman, terminal, cli, application, utility, tig, git&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-common-mistakes-of-the-first-time-tech-lead&#34;&gt;Three Common Mistakes of the First Time Tech Lead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/three-common-mistakes-first-time-tech-lead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Kua, in which he explains what are the anti-patterns (or mistakes) of a tech lead. They do not only apply to first timers, but more experienced ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially like a comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take all blame and give all credit: I ensure I always take the blame from the stakeholders when something is broken but when they praise, I say its all my teams efforts and I am just guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/by/ravensnowbird/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ravensnowbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: patrick-kua, tech-lead, leadership, team-management, mistake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimental-versioning&#34;&gt;Sentimental Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sentimentalversioning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (unknown author) on alternatives to semver (semantic versioning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: semver, semantic-versioning, sentimental-versioning, humor, parody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devoxx-2015-how-to-become-a-java-champion&#34;&gt;Devoxx 2015: How to Become a Java Champion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http//www.youtube.com/watch?v=otMc_3Dz3hU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Arun Gupta in which he explains what is a Java champion and how to become one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, arun-gupta, java-champion, devoxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-become-a-champion-programmer&#34;&gt;How Can I Become a Champion Programmer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaspecialists.eu/archive/Issue227.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Heinz M. Kabutz on how to become a java champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: heinz-kabutz, java-champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-using-scala-as-a-better-java&#34;&gt;The myth of using Scala as a better Java&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://appliedscala.com/blog/2017/myth-of-scala-as-better-java/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Denis Kalinin disproving &amp;lsquo;Java as a better Scala&amp;rsquo;. He covers dependency injection, database access, serialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scala, java, comparison, orm, denis-kalinin, macwire, dependency-injection, serialization, database, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y&#34;&gt;The eigenvector of &amp;ldquo;Why we moved from language X to language Y&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://erikbern.com/2017/03/15/the-eigenvector-of-why-we-moved-from-language-x-to-language-y.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Erik Bern on the statistical analysis (based on people writing blog posts) of moving from language X to language Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can help predict which languages will be more prevalent in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eigenvector, statistic, erik-bern, language, programming-language, java, c, cplusplus, go, python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;facebook-s-code-quality-problem&#34;&gt;Facebook’s code quality problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.darkcoding.net/software/facebooks-code-quality-problem/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Graham King on the problems that Facebook is facing, at the code level, and how they solve some of them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: graham-king, facebook, quality, architecture, code-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-key-lesson-from-our-serverless-migration&#34;&gt;The key lesson from our serverless migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=abe09ce689751513abf6f095f&amp;amp;id=6ecb59a937&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gojko Adzic on serverless, a kind of lessons learned. Explains that their system can take 50% more users at 50% of the original cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains three ways of authenticating users: use IAM users, use Cognito, pre-sign URLs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lessons-learned, gojko-adzic, serverless, paas, platform-as-a-service, retrospective, money, total-cost-of-ownership, tco,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-automation-goes-horribly-wrong&#34;&gt;When automation goes horribly wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Gojko Adzic on a story of a manual process that was automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it focused too much on replacing humans instead of assisting them, MiDAS actually made it more difficult for clerks to access the data they needed for review&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of the framework vs library discussion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in frameworks you relinquish the control, putting your code into the allocated holes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using the automated system, you can only check the claim at a certain spot, where the system lets you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system and the framework have been designed to take control of the situation. Both successful at what they do&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gojko-adzic, automation, framework, library, framework-vs-library, comparison, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-store-my-1-s-and-0-s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy&#34;&gt;How I Store My 1’s and 0’s: ZFS  Bargain HP Microserver = JOY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mocko.org.uk/b/2012/06/17/how-i-store-my-1s-and-0s-zfs-bargain-hp-microserver-joy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Alex stores his backups, using a microserver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: backup, microserver, raid, zfs, backup-strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meeting-policy&#34;&gt;Meeting policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/ueno/meeting-policy-9b04593d1b28&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by the Ueno team on how they handle meetings. Interesting that they require manager approval for meetings over a certain threshold (more than four people or more than half an hour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ueno, meeting-policy, meeting, approval&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-random-numbers&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Random Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/a-brief-history-of-random-numbers-9498737f5b6c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carl Tashian on how random numbers have evolved (from dice to pseudo random number generator and random number generators). Explain how some companies that need true randomness (e.g., certificates company) generate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: carl-tashian, dice, random-number, randomness, prng, pseudo-random-number-generator, random-number-generator, number-generator, true-random-number-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word&#34;&gt;Unlock honest feedback with this one word&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/unlock-honest-feedback-with-this-one-word-dcaf3839e7ee&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Claire Lew, in which she suggests to ask for &amp;lsquo;advice&amp;rsquo; instead of asking for &amp;lsquo;feedback&amp;rsquo; as a way of getting more honest and better responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: claire-lew, advice, feedback, feedback-process, improvement&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whatsapp-security-vulnerability&#34;&gt;WhatsApp Security Vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2017/01/whatsapp_securi.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;encrypted-email-service-once-used-by-edward-snowden-relaunches&#34;&gt;Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2017/01/20/encrypted-email-service-once-used-by-edward-snowden-to-relaunch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lavabit, kim-zetter, privacy, encryption, email, mail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-when-you-mix-java-with-a-1960-ibm-mainframe&#34;&gt;What Happens When You Mix Java with a 1960 IBM Mainframe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/happens-use-java-1960-ibm-mainframe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel about the legacy infrastructure of hardware that the U.S. government agencies have. How old mainframes are still useful to web applications and how these mainframes can communicate with more modern systems, through APIs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mainframe, david-cassel, marianne-bellotti, legacy-hardware, legacy-software, legacy-system, legacy, api&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;systems-we-love-how-the-past-informs-our-present&#34;&gt;Systems We Love: How the Past Informs Our Present&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/systems-we-love/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this experience report&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel about the conference &amp;ldquo;Systems we love&amp;rdquo;: a mix of papers we love and systems that happened at San Francisco in December 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-cassel, systems-we-love, papers-we-love, system, conference, experience-report, joyent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-agonizing-death-of-an-astronaut&#34;&gt;The agonizing death of an astronaut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.javaslang.io/the-agonizing-death-of-an-astronaut/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Dietrich on why the implementation of the &lt;code&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; in Javaslang seems to be broken but, in fact, follows the rules of the monads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains why &lt;code&gt;map&lt;/code&gt; should be used for non-changing contexts and &lt;code&gt;flatmap&lt;/code&gt; should be used for changing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: daniel-dietrich, monad, option, haskell, optional, maybe, scala, javaslang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-reverse-engineered-16k-apps-here-s-what-we-found&#34;&gt;We reverse engineered 16k apps, here’s what we found&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/we-reverse-engineered-16k-apps-heres-what-we-found-51bdf3b456bb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Fallible team, in which they describe the analysis of apps. They discovered 2500 apps with key and secret on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] whenever you hardcode any API key/token in the app, think hard if you really need to hardcode this, understand the API usage and the read/write scope of the tokens before putting it in the apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: analysis, security, app, key, token, api, fallible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oh-the-emails-you-ll-get&#34;&gt;Oh, the emails you’ll get&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2006/11/09/oh-the-emails-youll-get/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Joel Spolsky, in which he explains how some companies focus on some metrics for measuring performance, how difficult it is to measure performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joel-spolsky, performance, management, consulting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2002-07-15-measurement&#34;&gt;2002/07/15 - Measurement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/07/15/20020715/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Joel Spolsky where he explains how measuring performance is difficult, according to  Robert D. Austin in his book Measuring and Managing Performance in Organizations. He gives some examples of that, mainly about paying out bonuses for performance reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joel-spolsky, robert-austin, measuring-performance, managing-performance, book, knowledge-worker, bonus, pay, performance, organization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-purpose-of-life-is-not-happiness-it-s-usefulness&#34;&gt;The Purpose Of Life Is Not Happiness: It’s Usefulness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://dariusforoux.com/happiness-usefulness/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Darius Foroux on what the purpose of life is about: making a difference (even if small) in what you leave behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: psychology, purpose-of-life, usefulness, happiness, darius-foroux&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-user-interfaces&#34;&gt;The Future of User Interfaces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://brandur.org/interfaces&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brandur on how interfaces are becoming more and more bloated, slow and ridden with animations. All of that is targeted to the beginner user, rather than the proficient one. He suggests some ideas on finding inspiration from the terminal applications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brandur, interface, interface-design, ux, ui&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-increasing-frustration-with-clojure&#34;&gt;My Increasing Frustration With Clojure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ashtonkemerling.com/blog/2016/06/11/my-increasing-frustration-with-clojure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ashton Kemerling on the problems he has found working professionally with Clojure and some possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clojure, language, ashton-kemerling, functional-programming, problem, frustration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-without-if&#34;&gt;Java Without If&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ashtonkemerling.com/blog/2017/01/26/java-without-if/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ashton Kemerling on how he is using a library called &amp;lsquo;lambda&amp;rsquo;, which brings some of the functional programming features to Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lambda, library, ashton-kemerling, functional-programming, java, palatable, john-napier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-ten-pull-request-review-mistakes&#34;&gt;Top ten pull request review mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.scottnonnenberg.com/top-ten-pull-request-review-mistakes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Scott Nonnenberg on the most common mistakes while doing a code review in the context of a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scott-nonnenberg, pull-request, code-review, github, diff, listicle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shutting-down-simplicity-itself&#34;&gt;Shutting down Simplicity Itself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://daviddawson.me/blog/2017/02/04/simplicity-itself-shutdown.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Dawson on why he&amp;rsquo;s shutting down his consultancy company, Simplicity Itself, which was mainly focused on microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-dawson, simplicity-itself, shut-down, company, consulting, post-mortem, postmortem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turn-off-your-cellphone&#34;&gt;Turn Off Your Cellphone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://brandur.org/fragments/turn-off-your-cellphone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brandur on how to get more done by unplugging the notifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brandur, time-management, interruption, phone, notification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dark-standup&#34;&gt;The Dark Standup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://18f.gsa.gov/2017/01/19/the-dark-standup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Brouilette on the steps they took to reduce the amount of hours worked. It started with a few extra questions during the daily standup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What didn’t you do today because you stopped working on time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will the impact be on tomorrow because of it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much more time would you have needed to get everything done today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will you do with those hours tonight instead?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and what they realized after a two-week experiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The costs of context switching are much higher than we realized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We were spending a lot of time doing things that were urgent but not important, or that didn’t need to have been urgent at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We needed to be a lot more ruthless about saying “No.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some Operations roles are legitimately shorthanded, some of us just needed to impose a little order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOMO WIP (unnecessary work one takes on because one fears missing something) is a real problem, especially as regards to Slack and meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We worked better in the time we had to work, knowing it was finite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work-life balance improves both work and life. People literally slept better when limiting after-hours exposure to Slack and email. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dark-standup, quote, limited-time, overtime, team-management, experiment, question, alan-brouilette&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-means-to-be-a-remote-first-company&#34;&gt;What it Means to be a Remote-First Company&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stackoverflow.blog/code-for-a-living/what-it-means-to-be-a-remote-first-company&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Alyssa Mazzina on what Stack Overflow does to keep its remote employees happy, how they are a remote-first company and small practicalities like tools, holiday gifts and stipends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alyssa-mazzina, team-management, remote, remote-work, stack-overflow, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-s-not-so-secret-new-os&#34;&gt;Google’s not-so-secret new OS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techspecs.blog/blog/2017/2/14/googles-not-so-secret-new-os&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; describing the state of Google&amp;rsquo;s new operating system, Fuchsia or Andromeda (the final name is not final yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: google, os, operating-system, daniel-matte, fuchsia, andromeda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-secrets-of-people-who-finish-their-workweeks-on-thursday&#34;&gt;Four Secrets Of People Who Finish Their Workweeks On Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/3068122/work-smart/four-secrets-of-people-who-finish-their-workweeks-on-thursday&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Kat Boogaard that includes four tips to finish your week early:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Schedule Intentionally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Focus On Priorities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Tune Out Distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Find Shortcuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kat-boogaard, time-management, eisenhower-productivity-matrix, urgent-vs-important, important-vs-urgent, urgent, important, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflecting-on-one-very-very-strange-year-at-uber&#34;&gt;Reflecting On One Very, Very Strange Year At Uber&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.susanjfowler.com/blog/2017/2/19/reflecting-on-one-very-strange-year-at-uber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Susan J Fowler on some bad HR practices at Uber and how they are part of the reason their low percentage of women (3%) in the engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sexism, uber, susan-fowler, hr, human-resources, women, work-environment, review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ni-dioses-ni-reyes-sólo-el-hombre&#34;&gt;Ni dioses ni reyes. Sólo el hombre.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=860ccae5e2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish) by David Bonilla on which he talks about the God Mode and how that is implemented in different applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also liked this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los desarrolladores sólo somos herreros que forjan ceros y unos. Construimos herramientas para satisfacer necesidades de nuestros usuarios, sin que eso nos haga mejores que ellos o nos dé el derecho de supervisar y juzgar sus actos. A la hora de diseñar nuevos sistemas y funcionalidades, lo único que nunca deberíamos olvidar es que no somos dioses ni reyes, sólo hombres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rough translation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, developers, we are only blacksmiths of the digital era. We build tools to satisfy our user&amp;rsquo;s need, without that fact making us better than they are or without the right to overview what they do or to judge their acts. When designing new systems and features, the only thing we must never forget is that we are neither gods nor kings, just humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;las-tres-erres&#34;&gt;Las tres erres&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article (in Spanish) by David Bonilla in which he explains three necessary factors when considering a job offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referentes: es imposible conocer a toda la plantilla de una empresa, pero si conoces a dos o tres empleados clave, podrás hacerte una idea de cómo será el equipo que te vas a encontrar. La gente prefiere trabajar con compañeros que compartan su ética y valores. Yo conocía a casi toda la plantilla de Comalatech tras haber coincidido con unos y otros en distintos eventos… y aún hay gente que se pregunta para qué sirve ir a conferencias técnicas si en Internet “se puede encontrar todo”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referencias: es complicado, pero en el día a día una persona puede ser completamente diferente a la imagen que proyecta públicamente. Me ha pasado. Por eso es importante contar con referencias, terceras personas –antiguos empleados, clientes o proveedores- con las que haya trabajado. Los españoles no solemos pedirlas, pero para los anglosajones son un requisito imprescindible. En el caso de Comala, conseguí las mejores de la mejor fuente posible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retos: los profesionales trabajamos por dinero, pero a partir de cierto nivel de salario, podemos permitirnos el lujo de elegir un trabajo u otro según otros factores. En mi caso, siempre he priorizado por encima de todo el potencial de aprendizaje y, en ese sentido, Comalatech no tenía rival.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: referent, reference, challenge, david-bonilla, bonilista, change-job, job-offer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;translation-from-haskell-to-javascript-of-selected-portions-of-the-best-introduction-to-monads-i-ve-ever-read&#34;&gt;Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jcoglan.com/2011/03/05/translation-from-haskell-to-javascript-of-selected-portions-of-the-best-introduction-to-monads-ive-ever-read/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Coglan, introducing monads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About composability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;symmetric input and output types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guide to basic monadic functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function
bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form
unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is a monad? Well, it’s a design pattern. It says that whenever you have a class of functions that accept one type of thing and return another type of thing, there are two functions that can be applied across this class to make them composable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt; function that transforms any function so that accepts the same type as it returns, making it composable
There is a &lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; function that wraps a value in the type accepted by the composable functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I]t’s a very useful design pattern to be aware of because it helps you spot accidental complexity: code that isn’t dealing directly with the problem at hand, but which is dealing with glueing data types together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: monad, monad-explanation, haskell, javascript, james-coglan, bind, unit, lift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-could-have-invented-monads-and-maybe-you-already-have&#34;&gt;You Could Have Invented Monads! (And Maybe You Already Have.)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sigfpe.com/2006/08/you-could-have-invented-monads-and.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Piponi, in which he slowly introduces monads, using examples from everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-piponi, monad, monad-explanation, haskell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-one&#34;&gt;Monads, part one&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/21/monads-part-one/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes monads as a design pattern that &amp;ldquo;can sneak up on you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-two&#34;&gt;Monads, part two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/25/monads-part-two/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes monad examples in the C# code. Also describes what an &amp;lsquo;amplifier&amp;rsquo; is. I relate it to composing behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &amp;ldquo;amplifier&amp;rdquo; is something that increases the representational power of their &amp;ldquo;underlying&amp;rdquo; type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, amplifier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-three&#34;&gt;Monads, part three&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/28/monads-part-three/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes how to wrap a value in a monadic wrapper (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-four&#34;&gt;Monads, part four&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/04/monads-part-four/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the second function (&lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-five&#34;&gt;Monads, part five&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/07/monads-part-five/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the three laws, which are later compressed into two (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-six&#34;&gt;Monads, part six&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/11/monads-part-six/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the logical identity of applying the function inside a monad and outside a monad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-seven&#34;&gt;Monads, part seven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/14/monads-part-seven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he states the three laws of monads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying the construction function to a given instance of the monad produces a logically identical instance of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying a function to the result of the construction function on a value, and applying that function to the value directly, produces two logically identical instances of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying to a value a first function followed by applying to the result a second function, and applying to the original value a third function that is the composition of the first and second functions, produces two logically identical instances of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-eight&#34;&gt;Monads, part eight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/18/monads-part-eight/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes the monad terms he was using other, more common names (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-nine&#34;&gt;Monads, part nine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/21/monads-part-nine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he creates a &lt;code&gt;Tainted&lt;/code&gt; monad, which is basically a &lt;code&gt;Nullable&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Maybe&lt;/code&gt; monad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-ten&#34;&gt;Monads, part ten&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/25/monads-part-ten/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes &lt;code&gt;Where&lt;/code&gt; (as the query syntax form) using the &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt; signature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-eleven&#34;&gt;Monads, part eleven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/28/monads-part-eleven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes the &amp;ldquo;additive monad&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a zero value of every construction of the monadic type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a way to add two monads with the same underlying type together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The zero value is the identity of the add operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bind to apply any function to the zero produces the zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bind to apply the function &lt;code&gt;a=&amp;gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; to any &lt;code&gt;M&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; produces the zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, additive-monad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-twelve&#34;&gt;Monads, part twelve&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/04/02/monads-part-twelve/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains how the &lt;code&gt;SelectMany&lt;/code&gt; could be implemented (but it is not implemented in practice)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-thirteen&#34;&gt;Monads, part thirteen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/04/03/monads-part-thirteen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he suggests reading a similar article on the Task comonad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, comonad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks-monads-and-linq&#34;&gt;Tasks, Monads, and LINQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/pfxteam/2013/04/03/tasks-monads-and-linq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Toub in which he explains the comonad &lt;code&gt;Task&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comonad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] dual of a monad, a triple consisting of the type and two operators: &lt;code&gt;Extract&lt;/code&gt; (the flip of &lt;code&gt;Unit&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Return&lt;/code&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;Extend&lt;/code&gt; (the flip of &lt;code&gt;Bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comonad, monad, monad-explanation, stephen-toub, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-questions-every-unit-test-must-answer&#34;&gt;5 Questions Every Unit Test Must Answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/what-every-unit-test-needs-f6cd34d9836d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (titled as a listicle) by Eric Elliot about unit tests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are you testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should it do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the actual output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the expected output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can the test be reproduced?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-elliott, javascript, unit-test, test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-should-be-planning-for-2018-not-2017&#34;&gt;Why You Should be Planning for 2018, Not 2017.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/why-you-should-be-planning-for-2018-not-2017-7c8fea3e2e52&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on motivation, planning and designing your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] having the power to make choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The responsibility to choose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The results of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] hope reflects your perceptions regarding your capacity to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearly conceptualize goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop the specific strategies to reach those goals (i.e., pathways thinking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initiate and sustain the motivation for using those strategies (i.e., agency thinking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] motivation involves three components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the value you place on your goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your belief that specific behaviors will actually facilitate the outcomes you desire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your belief in your own ability to successfully execute the behaviors requisite to achieving your goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, motivation, life, planning, long-term-plans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-5-better&#34;&gt;Get 5% Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2016/03/five-percent-better/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, in which the author explains how compound interest does not only apply to investing and saving but also personal improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kaizen, personal-improvement, compound-interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hunter-s-thompson-s-letter-on-finding-your-purpose-and-living-a-meaningful-life&#34;&gt;Hunter S. Thompson’s Letter on Finding Your Purpose and Living a Meaningful Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2014/05/hunter-s-thompson-to-hume-logan/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; from Hunter S. Thompson to his friend Hume Logan, containing advice on living your own life: must find your own way, decide between floating or swimming to your goal and strive to be yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: hunter-thompson, hume-logan, advice, psychology, life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-japanese-philosophy-of-kaizen-offers-an-effective-manageable-way-to-achieve-long-term-goals&#34;&gt;The Japanese philosophy of Kaizen offers an effective, manageable way to achieve long-term goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/867711/the-japanese-philosophy-of-kaizen-offers-an-effective-manageable-way-to-achieve-long-term-goals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Oppong on kaizen, or continuous improvement, and how it applies like compound interest to your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kaizen, continous-improvement, thomas-oppong, compound-interest, life, psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-a-software-interview&#34;&gt;Preparing for a Software Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://42hire.com/preparing-for-a-software-interview-6d0392a3d72c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alvaro Videla on interviewing technical people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: recruitement, interviewing, interview, alvaro-videla&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-recursive-data-structures&#34;&gt;Why Recursive Data Structures?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raganwald.com/2016/12/27/recursive-data-structures.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this essay&lt;/a&gt; by Reginald “Raganwald” Braithwaite, on which he introduces the relationship between data structures and algorithms. Explains how the algorithm can be split into parts, following the data structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses a library containing a function called &lt;code&gt;multirec&lt;/code&gt; for recursion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackage.haskell.org/package/multirec&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a candidate&lt;/a&gt; library, in haskell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lazutkin.com/blog/2008/06/30/using-recursion-combinators-javascript/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;another candidate&lt;/a&gt; library, in javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: reginald-braithwaite, recursive-data-structure, quadtree, javascript, functional-programming, essay, data-structure, isomorphic, tree, multirec, linrec, tailrec, haskell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leading-by-example&#34;&gt;Leading by Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/leading-by-example/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on how the best leadership comes from doing, rather than telling how to do it. From being a leader rather than being a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests further reads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leadership, team-lead, leading-by-example, jeff-atwood, gerald-weinberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discipline-makes-strong-developers&#34;&gt;Discipline Makes Strong Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/discipline-makes-strong-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on a project sucess should not be attributed to a language or framework, but to the team&amp;rsquo;s and individuals&amp;rsquo; discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains how small projects require different levels of discipline than large projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leadership, discipline, nasa, code-complete, coding-horror, jeff-atwood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;effectively-integrating-into-software-development-teams&#34;&gt;Effectively Integrating Into Software Development Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dennisforbes.ca/index.php/2006/01/29/effectively-integrating-into-software-development-teams/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dennis Forbes about authority and discipline in a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One organization’s Enterprise solution is another organization’s short sighted mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: shiny, dennis-forbes, discipline, authority, psychology, politics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-docker-fork-talk-of-a-split-is-now-on-the-table&#34;&gt;A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/docker-fork-talk-split-now-table/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&amp;rsquo; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-ode-to-boring-creating-open-and-stable-container-world&#34;&gt;An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine. Asks for some kind of Docker long-time support (LTS - like Ubuntu does, for example) and to create a boring environment so applications on top of the containers itself can thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference here is that application creators want some boring infrastructure because their product is the application on top, not the container themselves. Docker&amp;rsquo;s product, on the other hand, is the containers and the Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ode, bob-wise, devops, tool, request, kubernetes, docker-swarm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-npm-link&#34;&gt;How to use &amp;lsquo;npm link&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://tobyret.github.io/NPM-Link/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Toby Retallick about using npm link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: npm, tool, npm-link, toby-retallick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;valve-s-flat-management-structure-like-high-school&#34;&gt;Valve&amp;rsquo;s flat management structure &amp;lsquo;like high school&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.co.uk/article/valve-management-jeri-ellsworth&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Philippa Warr on the flat management hierarchy at Valve (a company cited as having some Teal practices) and its shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  philippa-warr, teal, teal-organization, valve, management, flat-hierarchy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hazards-of-going-on-autopilot&#34;&gt;The hazards of going on autopilot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/science/maria-konnikova/hazards-automation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Maria Konnikova on how pilots get distracted (their minds drift off) when not stimulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article introduces the idea of human-centric automation and letting the computer check what the human is doing (to tell when it is wrong), rather than the human what the computer is doing wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: maria-konnikova, automation, autopilot, complacency&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cobra-effect-that-is-disabling-paste-on-password-fields&#34;&gt;The “Cobra Effect” that is disabling paste on password fields&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.troyhunt.com/the-cobra-effect-that-is-disabling/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on disabling paste on password fields, how that forces using a weaker password. Also names the &amp;lsquo;Cobra Effect&amp;rsquo;. By Troy Hunt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: troy-hunt, copy-paste, paste, password-field, cobra-effect, disable-paste, usability, ux&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-course-smart-homes-are-targets-for-hackers&#34;&gt;Of course smart homes are targets for hackers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/45483.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Garrett on how the security of Internet of Things devices is as important as traditional devices and what rules should a consumer follow to decide whether a device is secure or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-garrett, security, internet-of-things, iot, hacker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-salaries-outcomes&#34;&gt;Open Salaries: Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.lunarlogic.io/2016/open-salaries-outcomes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Paweł Brodziński on how the open salaries has affected them in their company (Lunar Logic):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removing the bottleneck for salary reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;making more often and better the feedback process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;people more involved in running the company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: teal, company, salary, teal-organization, company-practice, open-salary, pawel-brodzinski&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-more-vote-for-functional-languages&#34;&gt;One more vote for functional languages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.simeonov.com/2013/03/04/one-more-vote-for-functional-languages/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Simeon Simeonov in which he describes how setting a watch expression can cause a side effect (e.g. VBA, Ruby).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: immutability, simeon-simeonov, watch-expression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fastest-way-to-learn-a-new-programming-language&#34;&gt;The fastest way to learn a new programming language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.simeonov.com/2013/02/11/the-fastest-way-to-learn-a-new-programming-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; the ways the author (Simeon Simeonov) goes while learning a new language:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curious George. During this phase, which usually lasts only a few hours and involves semi-random exploration of tutorials, reference manuals, blog posts and StackOverflow posts, I get my bearings straight, find analogies between the new language and ones I’m more familiar with and choose my initial tooling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mario Bros. -&amp;gt; Super Mario Bros. In this phase, which usually lasts several days, I try to bring the meta-patterns I’m comfortable working with from familiar environments (the sewers of New York) to the new environment (the Mushroom Kingdom). It involves diving head first into advanced language features and building various utilities that I find lacking in the environment, e.g., debugging tools, all in the context of early prototypes of whatever it is that I need to work on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bull in a china shop. This is the phase where my noble goal of bending the language to the way I solve problems meets the harsh reality of me being a neophyte in its intricacies. The observable attributes of this phase are lower velocity, increased use of expletives and more time on StackOverflow. The amount of time in this phase varies. The “Eureka!” moments are fun but overall it’s a dip in the experience curve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singin’ in the Rain. With newly acquired knowledge and improved language-specific testing/debugging skills, the bull gently transforms into Fred Astaire. Coding is a lot of fun again. It’s time to go to production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obi-Wan Kenobi. Over time, the interaction with the new language improves the meta-patterns I use for problem solving. I tend to use less and simpler code using natural language idioms as opposed to generalized utilities &amp;amp; abstractions. It’s like changing from using the Force to allowing the Force to do things through you. It takes a long time to get here. More often than not, I never do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also describes several (advanced) techniques that helped him better understand programming:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In C++ template, meta-programming [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Java, dynamic bytecode generation [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Python [&amp;hellip;] stateful decorators [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Ruby, metaprogramming  [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: simeon-simeonov, metaprogramming, ruby, decorator, python, bytecode-generation, java, cpp, learning-programming-language, programming-language, curious-georde, mario-bros, bull-in-a-china-shop, singing-in-the-rain, obi-wan-kenobi, eureka, learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-marvellously-mysterious-javascript-maybe-monad&#34;&gt;The marvellously mysterious javascript Maybe monad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://jrsinclair.com/articles/2016/marvellously-mysterious-javascript-maybe-monad/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Sinclair in which he tries to explain monads in javascript, explaining how promises work, then establishing the parallellism between a promise and a type of monad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: monad, javascript, promise, james-sinclair, analogy, functional-programming, monad-explanation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debug-trace&#34;&gt;Debug.Trace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read both &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackage.haskell.org/package/base-4.9.0.0/docs/Debug-Trace.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the source code for &lt;code&gt;Debug.Trace&lt;/code&gt;, a haskell module that contains functions to trace a program execution. It is interesting to see how a function performs side effects and its signature seems to be pure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main trick is to use &lt;code&gt;unsafePerformIO&lt;/code&gt;, which points to &lt;code&gt;unsafeDupablePerformIO&lt;/code&gt;, which performs a side effect on the Real World (&lt;code&gt;runRW#&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: haskell, debug, monitoring, source-code, real-world&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advice-for-white-men&#34;&gt;Advice for white men&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catehuston.com/blog/2016/01/28/advice-for-white-men/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cate Huston about how advice affects different people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here are some things to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on failure is different for people who are judged on performance rather than potential.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on saying no is different for people who aren’t appreciated for doing work for the collective… but who are punished if they don’t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on negotiation is different for people who are perceived negatively when they do negotiate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on choosing a new job is different for people who disproportionately experience harassment (it’s another factor to consider).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advice on raising your profile is different for people who are recognized for their advocacy more than their work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cate-huston, management, advice, psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-1-1s&#34;&gt;On 1:1s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catehuston.com/blog/2016/11/05/on-11s/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cate Huston about one-on-ones (1:1s), that includes how she handles and the purpose of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, 1:1s were about active relationship building, with a focus on the important-but-not urgent. But having built a relationships where we talked regularly and I listened, that created space for conversations to happen outside of the 1:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cate-huston, management, psychology, one-on-one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsoft-i-forgive-you&#34;&gt;Microsoft, I forgive you!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/microsoft-i-forgive-you-2fb6d6061a2c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH) on why Microsoft has changed and why the author has forgiven past beefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dhh, david-heinemeier-hansson, microsoft&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-writing-rambling-commit-messages&#34;&gt;Stop writing rambling commit messages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://stopwritingramblingcommitmessages.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this rant&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Pope on commit messages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rant, commit-message, tim-pope, commit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-note-about-git-commit-messages&#34;&gt;A Note About Git Commit Messages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://tbaggery.com/2008/04/19/a-note-about-git-commit-messages.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Pope on git commits and tools to normalize the text and apply the rules he describes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: commit-message, tim-pope, commit, tool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;purely-functional-i-o&#34;&gt;Purely Functional I/O&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infoq.com/presentations/io-functional-side-effects&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; by Runar Bjarnason on purely functional IO. In the first part, he introduces functional programming, referential transparency and functional IO. In the second part, he explains the types for IO and both the implementation in haskell and in scala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: runar-bjarnason, haskell, scala, talk, video, functional-programming, functional-io, io&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-signs-you-re-working-in-a-feature-factory&#34;&gt;12 Signs You’re Working in a Feature Factory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/12-signs-youre-working-in-a-feature-factory-44a5b938d6a2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this listicle&lt;/a&gt; by John Cutler on signs that a company is very centered in features rather than value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-cutler, feature, value, product-management, product-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-a-the-tao-of-monad&#34;&gt;3.a The Tao of Monad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schoolofhaskell.com/school/starting-with-haskell/basics-of-haskell/the-tao-of-monad&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bartosz Milewski explaining the Monad under another lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He draws some inspiration from Lao Tzu, in Tao Te Ching: TE as virtue, laziness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bartosz-milewski, monad, haskell, school-of-haskell, tao-te-ching, tao&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-engineers-design&#34;&gt;Should Engineers Design?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.capwatkins.com/should-engineers-design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cap Watkins where he explains the relationship between designers and programmers and how to get the latter involved in the design / UX / UI process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cap-watkins, design, ux, ui, exchange, cross-functional&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sliding-scale-of-giving-a-fuck&#34;&gt;The Sliding Scale of Giving a Fuck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.capwatkins.com/the-sliding-scale-of-giving-a-fuck&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cap Watkins where he explains that different topics have a different importance to each one of us: this topic might be very important for someone else, ergo, it makes mores sense to evaluate their option more carefully. When your importance level is not so high, you can take the other option easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cap-watkins, sliding-scale, decision-making, discussion, argument, convincing, people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuevos-retos&#34;&gt;Nuevos retos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modestosanjuan.com/nuevos-retos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Modesto San Juan about him leaving Codesai and joining a new adventure. In Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career-change, modesto-san-juan, codesai, carlos-ble, .net&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;muchas-gracias-modesto&#34;&gt;Muchas gracias Modesto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codesai.com/2016/10/muchas-gracias-modesto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, by Carlos Blé and the rest of the Codesai team, saying goodbye to Modesto San Juan, commenting on their experiences working with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career-change, modesto-san-juan, codesai, carlos-ble, .net&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-ticket-magpie&#34;&gt;Introducing…Ticket Magpie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thetestdoctor.wordpress.com/2016/10/11/introducing-ticket-magpie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Billing about the a honeypot application he has to teach about security and attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-hatanian, dan-billing, ticket-magpie, honeypot, security, attack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;destructuring-assignment&#34;&gt;Destructuring assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Operators/Destructuring_assignment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;destructuring assignment page&lt;/a&gt; at MDN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javascript, destructuring, mdn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-lessons-i-learned-from-doing-my-first-real-startup&#34;&gt;10 Lessons I Learned from Doing My First Real Startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://degoes.net/articles/precog-lessons-learned&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, a post-mortem analysis of his company, precog, with 10 items that he learned from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-de-goes, precog, post-mortem, startup, lessons-learned&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-being-nice-and-just-tell-the-fucking-truth-already&#34;&gt;Stop Being &amp;ldquo;Nice&amp;rdquo; and Just Tell the Fucking Truth Already&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://degoes.net/articles/be-nice-not-nice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about giving honest feedback vs being a nice guy. The author concludes that the former is, in fact, the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: feedback, honesty, comparison, john-de-goes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;haskell-s-type-classes-we-can-do-better&#34;&gt;Haskell&amp;rsquo;s Type Classes: We Can Do Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://degoes.net/articles/principled-typeclasses&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the abuse of newtype classes in haskell to overcome some language limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article has helped me understand better inheritance, in the sections orphans and laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also suggests that the compiler could check at compile time that the children impose more restrictive (more specific) laws than the parent, given that any children must comply with the inherited rules (liskov substitution principle)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: inheritance, liskov, lsp, solid, john-de-goes, functional-programming, haskell, type-classes,  newtype-clases, monoid, law&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-the-three-amigos&#34;&gt;Introducing the Three Amigos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrumalliance.org/community/articles/2013/2013-april/introducing-the-three-amigos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Thomas Hewitt about the Three Amigos meeting, to better define a feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ryan-hewitt, three-amigos, agile, meeting, process, scrum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-mac-is-for&#34;&gt;Apple just told the world it has no idea who the Mac is for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/charged-tech/apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-mac-is-for-722a2438389b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Owen Williams on the latest presentation by Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: owen-williams, mac, apple, strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sigil&#34;&gt;Sigil&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this page for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sigil_(computer_programming)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sigil&lt;/a&gt;, or the symbol attached to the variable. An example is the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; in Perl or the earmuffs in Clojure (&lt;code&gt;*out*&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sigil, wikipedia, example, computer-science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;list-of-languages-that-compile-to-js&#34;&gt;List of languages that compile to JS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jashkenas/coffeescript/wiki/List-of-languages-that-compile-to-JS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of programming languages that compile to JS. By Jeremy Ashkenas and the community&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jeremy-ashkenas, compilation, compiled-language, compiled-to-javascript, compiled-javascript, javascript&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-accountable-for-delivering-value&#34;&gt;Being accountable for delivering value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://niksilver.com/2017/01/17/accountable-for-value/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nik Silver on how the team should be accountable for delivering value, not accountable for delivering artifacts that produce value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: agile, management, nik-silver, accountability, team, value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-partial-value-from-partial-delivery&#34;&gt;Getting partial value from partial delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://niksilver.com/2015/10/20/partial-value-from-partial-delivery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nik Silver on how it is possible to be agile in an environment where the business is not agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, introduces the concept of &amp;lsquo;partial delivery&amp;rsquo;, meaning incomplete delivery from development to business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: delivery, partial-delivery, management, value, partial-value, change, walkawayability, change, nik-silver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hierarchy-of-opinion&#34;&gt;Hierarchy of opinion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://codurance.com/2017/01/16/hierarchy-of-opinion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mashooq Badar on what are opinions, how important they are and how them impact others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mashooq-badar, opinion, critical-thinking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/01/self-study-in-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 11:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/01/self-study-in-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-in-agile-six-months-at-pivotal&#34;&gt;Lessons in Agile: Six Months at Pivotal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/built-to-adapt/lessons-in-agile-six-months-at-pivotal-66b4c57386a4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Maryam Labib where she explains what she has learned in the last 6 months at Pivotal: how to pair program, how to TDD and some good practices to be a better developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: maryam-labib, pivotal, career, professional-career, tdd, pair-programming, team, lessons-learned, experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacking-verbal-communication-systems&#34;&gt;Hacking verbal communication systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/album/4045988/video/173255458&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Alexander on what kind of systems humans use to communicate and how to improve them. Explains the hand signals at Occupy movement (called (Occupy movement hand signals)[&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals]&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals]&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: conference, ryan-alexander, lead-dev, conf, hand-signals, occupy-movement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ni-titulitis-ni-cuñadismo-spanish&#34;&gt;Ni titulitis, ni cuñadismo (Spanish)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.koalite.com/2016/06/ni-titulitis-ni-cunadismo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the regulation or no regulation of the programmer trade, by Juan María Hernández&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: regulation, opinion, title, degree, university, juan-hernandez, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-semicolons-necessary-in-javascript&#34;&gt;Are Semicolons Necessary in JavaScript?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gsfbh17Ax9I&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Kyle Robinson Young on whether semicolons are necessary in javascript and why he purposely does not use them, to teach people how to do it. Suggests going for a month with the opposite way (write / don&amp;rsquo;t write) to see how it feels and take an informed decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javascript, semicolon, style, syntax, kyle-young&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;race-conditions-on-the-web&#34;&gt;Race conditions on the web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josipfranjkovic.com/blog/race-conditions-on-web&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Josip Franjković on the race conditions that can happen using REST APIs, related to eventual consistency matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eventual-consistency, josip-franjkovic, race-condition, rest-api, rest, web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nist-declares-the-age-of-sms-based-2-factor-authentication-over&#34;&gt;NIST declares the age of SMS-based 2-factor authentication over&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/25/nist-declares-the-age-of-sms-based-2-factor-authentication-over/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Devin Coldewey, where he explains that the US NIST has published a draft that suggests using SMS for two-factor authentication in a different way: check that they are real phones and not VoIP to reduce the tampering with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  devin-coldewey, 2fa, sms, nist, us-nist, security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-interviews-with-amazon&#34;&gt;My Interviews with Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesocietea.org/2016/07/my-interviews-with-amazon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Aaron Krauss, where he explains his experience interviewing with Amazon at Seattle. Explains the whole process and insights from some phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: aaron-krauss, amazon, interview-process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devops-students-learn-the-value-of-uptime-with-3-a-m-calls&#34;&gt;DevOps Students Learn the Value of Uptime With 3 a.m. Calls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linux.com/news/devops-students-learn-value-uptime-3-am-calls&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the practices related to &amp;ldquo;on call&amp;rdquo; at Holberton School and their students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sylvain-kalache, holberton-school, on-call, full-stack-developer, devops, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;constant-confusion-why-i-still-use-javascript-function-statements&#34;&gt;Constant confusion: why I still use JavaScript function statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/constant-confusion-why-i-still-use-javascript-function-statements-984ece0b72fd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains the comparison of declaring functions in javascript (ES2015 and above), with the short notation for a function. By Bill Sourour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the temporal dead zone (TDZ):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] JavaScript binds the declaration of “sayHelloTo” — reads it first, puts it at the top, and creates a space in memory to hold its value — but it doesn’t set “sayHelloTo” to anything until it reaches it during execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time between “sayHelloTo” being bound and “sayHelloTo” being initialized is called the temporal dead zone (TDZ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdz, temporal-dead-zone, bill-sourour, javascript, es2015, function, const, var, binding, lifecycle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;until-the-end-of-the-internet&#34;&gt;Until the End of the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/until-the-end-of-the-internet-405d55fde60f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-agile-principles-can-fund-your-start-up&#34;&gt;How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/how-agile-principles-can-fund-your-start-up&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one. This works both ways: for buying and for selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests using a base plus the amount of sales in the last year * a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  jurgen-appelo, investment, startup, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-fell-in-love-with-a-programming-language&#34;&gt;How I fell in love with a programming language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/how-i-fell-in-love-with-a-programming-language-8933d5e749ed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Kim on the feelings of love and comfort he feels when he&amp;rsquo;s programming in Kotlin, for Android. Tells the story of DHH and the love of Ruby as a similar one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-kim, dhh, ruby, love-of-language, kotlin, android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-writing-for-the-busy-programmer&#34;&gt;Book writing for the busy programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://gigasquidsoftware.com/blog/2016/06/19/book-writing-for-the-busy-programmer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carin Meier on what tools she found useful for writing, editing and publishing a science fiction book she was writing for her daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tool, pandoc, carin-meier, book, book-writing, book-editing, book-publishing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-two-and-three-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;one-, two-, and three-factor authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://pciguru.wordpress.com/2010/05/01/one-two-and-three-factor-authentication/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Hall, that explains the factors in multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jeff-hall, ofa, 2fa, mfa, one-factor-authentication, two-factor-authentication, multi-factor-authentication, pci-guru, security, authentication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling-agile-a-law-and-two-paradoxes&#34;&gt;Scaling Agile: A Law And Two Paradoxes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://asprotunity.com/blog/scaling-agile-a-law-and-two-paradoxes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Giovanni Asproni about agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamental law of scaling: Scaling up amplifies the bad and makes the good more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First paradox of scaling: Most projects are scaled up because they don’t fulfill the prerequisites for scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second paradox of scaling: Projects fulfilling the prerequisites for scaling have a lesser need to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;quote&gt;Giovanni Asproni&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also goes on to explain ten prerequisites for scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scaled-agile, agile, giovanni-asproni, paradox, law&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carta-abierta-a-ese-empresario-que-no-encuentra-talento&#34;&gt;Carta abierta a ese empresario que no encuentra talento&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/espanol/carta-abierta-a-ese-empresario-que-no-encuentra-talento-669e28e4a89b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ignacio Segura reacting to a previous article about job offer and demand. Ignacio explains how the job market can be modeled and how workers have found ways of selling their time to the best price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ignacio-segura, analogy, job-offer, job, job-market, economy, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;david-dill-why-online-voting-is-a-danger-to-democracy&#34;&gt;David Dill: Why Online Voting Is a Danger to Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.stanford.edu/news/david-dill-why-online-voting-danger-democracy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to David Dill on why the online voting is not a good idea and we should stick to paper as the golden rule for voting processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how difficult is to convince people of the technical limitations and the massive incentive it would be to hack into election systems / services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, david-dill, online-voting, limitation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;clojure-gazette-tdd-in-clojure-on-android&#34;&gt;Clojure Gazette - TDD in Clojure on Android&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us4.campaign-archive2.com/?u=a33b5228d1b5bf2e0c68a83f4&amp;amp;id=7023cf0a33&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Alexander Yakushev, about his Google Summer of Code and the project he is currently working on: Clojure-android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, clojure-gazette, alexander-yakushev, google-summer-of-code, gsoc, clojure, tdd, android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-will-github-be-in-5-years&#34;&gt;What Will GitHub Be in 5 years?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/ben/what-will-github-be-in-5-years&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that describes the current state of Github business and the possible solutions in the upcoming five years. By Ben Halpern&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ben-halpern, github, economy, startup, investment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serverless-architectures&#34;&gt;Serverless Architectures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/serverless.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this evolving article&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Roberts on what is and is not Serverless: [mobile] backend as a service or function as a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Converts some n-tier applications into serverless ones, expliciting that this is only a way of doing it, not necessarily the way he would do it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: faas, baas, mbass, function-as-a-service, backend-as-a-service, mobile-backend-as-a-service, serverless, evolving-article, mike-roberts, lambda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-co-vs-small-co-job-vs-career-stability&#34;&gt;Big co. vs small co. &amp;amp; job vs. career stability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catehuston.com/blog/2016/06/02/job-vs-career-stability/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cate Huston on the career and job stability that big companies and small companies can offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job security means that you know you will keep getting a paycheck from $company. Career security means that you know you can get another job, and develop yourself and your career in the way that is meaningful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: job-security, cate-huston, big-company, small-company, career-security, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;copy-paste-code&#34;&gt;Copy. Paste. Code?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.devmastery.com/copy-paste-code-6ed9bb841cd4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Sourour on the different point of view of solving questions in coding many years ago compared to nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explores the concept of copy pasting code without understanding it, explaining that the endgame is writing good code that works and is easy to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: copy-paste, bill-sourour, clean-code, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-so-many-developers-hate-recruiters&#34;&gt;Why so many developers hate recruiters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-tech-recruiter-red-pill-967dd492560c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson on how recruiters for the IT sector work and how to work with them for your best possible outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career, professional-career, recruitment, recruiter, agent, hiring, quincy-larson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-time-someone-posts-one-of-these-coding-is-over-essays-on-medium-they-undo-a-good-chunk-of&#34;&gt;Every time someone posts one of these “coding is over” essays on Medium, they undo a good chunk of…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@quincylarson/every-time-someone-posts-one-of-these-coding-is-over-essay-on-medium-they-undo-a-good-chunk-of-b7989849390b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson on why we should not tell others about their choosing of learning programming, and every time we do, some doors close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: answer, learn-coding, related-to-article, quincy-larson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;29-behaviors-that-will-make-you-an-unstoppable-programmer&#34;&gt;29 Behaviors That Will Make You An Unstoppable Programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kenmazaika/29-behaviors-that-will-make-you-an-unstoppable-programmer-8778941d80f7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tricks to become a be a better programmer. By Ken Mazaika&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Google very aggressively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain an obnoxious amount of stick-to-itiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that micro-decisions matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that most major decisions don’t matter that much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always use the right tool for the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand that code is cheap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate technologies based on all their merits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say “I don’t know.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always analyze the clues found in error messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the difference between a premature optimization and a show-stopping optimization that NEEDS to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take responsibility for your mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a power-user of your development tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know how to use Vim (at least a little bit).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never accept freelance work in an unfamiliar technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t count the number of hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absorb massive criticism with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair program with people with more experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always code review your own work first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize that the hard part of freelancing isn’t writing the code. It’s everything else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and resolve bigger issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into large open source projects to bring your features to life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip a lot of meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know when it’s time to give back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be capable of writing bad code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let other people know that you’re working late without being a jerk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act as a leader, not a boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go play foosball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Move fast and break things.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ken-mazaika, list, unbeateable-programmer, unstoppable-programmer, efficiency, 10x, tip-and-trick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;como-melhorar-seus-códigos-usando-object-calisthenics-portuguese&#34;&gt;Como melhorar seus códigos usando Object Calisthenics (Portuguese)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/coderockr-way/como-melhorar-seus-c%C3%B3digos-usando-object-calisthenics-444daf3e2e06&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about object calisthenics, with an example in PHP. By Elton Minetto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: object-calisthenics, elton-minetto, php, portuguese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-this-story-without-distraction-can-you&#34;&gt;Read This Story Without Distraction (Can You?)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/01/fashion/monotasking-drop-everything-and-read-this-story.html?action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=Fashion%20%26%20Style&amp;amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;amp;region=Marginalia&amp;amp;pgtype=article&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Verena von Pfetten on the effects on multitasking in our daily lives. Also comments on the movement of monotasking or unitasking, which is the opposite of multitasking: doing one thing at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underlines the benefits of monotasking and how this is related to mindfulness and psychological benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: multitasking, monotasking, unitasking, verena-von-pfetten, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debuggers-are-a-wasteful-timesink&#34;&gt;Debuggers are a wasteful Timesink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artima.com/weblogs/viewpost.jsp?thread=23476&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C. Martin on why we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use debuggers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uncle-bob, robert-martin, debugger, tdd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;taming-the-steamroller-how-to-communicate-compassionately-with-non-native-english-speakers&#34;&gt;Taming the steamroller: how to communicate compassionately with non-native English speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mollyclare/taming-the-steamroller-how-to-communicate-compassionately-with-non-native-english-speakers-d95d8d1845a0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Molly Clare Wilson on tips on how native English speakers can simplify their communication so it is easier for non-native speakers to understand them. Provides guidelines for situations involving &amp;lsquo;speaking and presenting&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;meetings&amp;rsquo;, written form &amp;lsquo;email, text, chat&amp;rsquo; and about correction each others English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: molly-wilson, english, communication, native, non-native, guideline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blue-no-yellow&#34;&gt;Blue. No! Yellow!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/05/21/BlueNoYellow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with Robert C. Martin on the productivity increases that different languages provide to the programmer. He says that no language can provide an effect as big as binary to assembler and that we&amp;rsquo;re currently searching the Holy Grail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-martin, uncle-bob, language, comparison, assembler, binary, clojure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-time-development-teams-chose-their-own-working-environments&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Time Development Teams Chose Their Own Working Environments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codemanship.co.uk/parlezuml/blog/?postid=1383&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Gorman on how takes the decision of working environments and why having other options are financially available. How developers should be in charge of their own working environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: office, working-environment, jason-gorman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-my-1-200-hackintosh&#34;&gt;Building My $1,200 Hackintosh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/building-my-1-200-hackintosh-49a1a186241e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to build a powerful hackintosh. By Mike Rundle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mike-rundle, hackintosh, macintosh, mac, computer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-practical-guide-to-becoming-a-professional-web-developer&#34;&gt;The Practical Guide to Becoming a Professional Web Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-practical-guide-to-becoming-a-professional-web-developer-2f255bc25c90&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Sourour on how to become a web developer. Explains all kind of resources, from learning javascript, deciding on being a frontend of backend developer, which language to choose, how to find a job, getting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bill-sourour, guide, career, beginner, developer, web, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hiring-is-so-hard-in-tech&#34;&gt;Why Hiring is So Hard in Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/why-hiring-is-so-hard-in-tech-c462c3230017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Elliot on how to tackle job interviews, both from the side of the employer and the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-elliot, job-interview, employee, employer, cv, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-node-js-with-brigadier-fluffykins-part-ii-events-eventemitter-and-the-event-loop&#34;&gt;Learn Node.js with Brigadier Fluffykins Part II: Events, EventEmitter and the Event Loop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/learn-node-js-with-brigadier-fluffykins-part-ii-events-eventemitter-the-event-loop-6d4c139694fb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Masha Diminsky on the architecture of javascript and nodejs. Explains the event-driven architecture, the events and the event loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: masha-diminsky, bus, nodejs, javascript, bus, event-loop, event&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-in-6-seconds-how-to-write-a-résumé-that-employers-will-actually-read&#34;&gt;You in 6 seconds: how to write a résumé that employers will actually read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/you-in-6-seconds-how-to-write-a-r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9-that-employers-will-actually-read-fd7757740802&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that suggests how to customize your cv for maximum engagement from interviewers / head hunters and to make the most of the 6 seconds they (allegedly) spend looking at your cv. Also explains some techniques for preparing the interview, about the cover letter, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: quincy-larson, cv, resume, career, professional-career, ats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starbucks-does-not-use-two-phase-commit&#34;&gt;Starbucks Does Not Use Two-Phase Commit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enterpriseintegrationpatterns.com/ramblings/18_starbucks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gregor Hohpe explaining how Starbucks is modeled in terms of asynchronous interactions and the actions for exception handling: write-off, retry, compensating action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also mentions Conversation pattern and Correlation ID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gregor-hohpe, conversation-pattern, correlation-id, analogy, asynchronous, exception-handling, write-off, retry, compensating-action&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;diversitymediocrityillusion&#34;&gt;DiversityMediocrityIllusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DiversityMediocrityIllusion.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; (on his bliki) about the diversity in conferences and the profession. How it is our job to incentive a positive feedback cycle that brings more diverse people into the workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how they do it in ThoughtWorks and how they have changed in the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-fowler, diversity, gender, workforce, conference, profession, bliki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-cryptic-github-comments-mean&#34;&gt;What do cryptic Github comments mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/what-do-cryptic-github-comments-mean-9c1912bcc0a4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Beregszaszi on the abbreviations used in Github comments and pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: github, pull-request, alex-beregszaszi, abbreviation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-erreurs-à-éviter-en-tant-que-développeur-freelance&#34;&gt;6 erreurs à éviter en tant que développeur freelance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@adrienjoly/enseignements-apr%C3%A8s-1-an-d-erreurs-en-tant-que-d%C3%A9veloppeur-freelance-916f855efd9b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (in French) by Adrien Joly on the mistakes freelancers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do when working with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrien-joly, freelance, list, mistake, french&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-methodology-s-promise-seems-to-fall-short-in-the-face-of-reality&#34;&gt;Agile Methodology’s Promise Seems To Fall Short in the Face of Reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@pagalvin/agile-methodology-s-promise-seems-to-fall-short-in-the-face-of-reality-b16d3e775dbe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on an experience by Paul Galvin on some failing agile implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: paul-galvin, agile, reality, agility, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-sharing-other-people-s-feelings-can-make-you-sick&#34;&gt;How sharing other people’s feelings can make you sick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newscientist.com/article/mg23030732-900-how-sharing-other-peoples-feelings-can-make-you-sick/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Emma Young on how being empathic to others can make you sick on their own illness. How illness can be socially transmitted, by loved ones or even by strangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How algorithms (that display news) can affect your own well-being and how this is reduced by using compassion instead of empathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Borders on the difference of empathy vs compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: emma-young, empathy, compassion, feeling, team-management, vent-free-zone, sickness, illness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aws-lambda-for-beginners&#34;&gt;AWS Lambda for Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/aws-lambda-for-beginners&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mashooq Badar on an introduction to AWS Lambdas, where the basics are covered until getting a Lambda service in production. Using Python or Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mashooq-badar, serverless, aws, aws-lambda, lambda, python, java, devops, serverless-architecture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-logging-with-the-javascript-console&#34;&gt;Advanced Logging with the JavaScript Console&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://egghead.io/series/js-console-for-power-users&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this course&lt;/a&gt; by Mykola Bilokonsky at egghead.io.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, he covers the following methods on the console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;warn&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;info&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;debug&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of parameters does not matter, it will put a space in between. printing an object will print its values&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;console.log with the C&amp;rsquo;s printf syntax, as long as the first parameter is a string&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;an&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;object&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34; data-lang=&#34;javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;groupCollapsed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;groupEnd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mykola-bilokonsky, logging, javascript, console, egghead, course&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-work-is-what-determines-your-future-spend-one-hour-per-day-doing-these-5-things-and-your-life-will-change-forever&#34;&gt;After work, is what determines your future! Spend one hour per day doing these 5 things and your life will change forever!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/after-work-what-determines-your-future-spend-one-hour-sundaram&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kalyana Sundaram on the activities we do at night, after a day&amp;rsquo;s work and how they influence our learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kalyana-sundaram, after-work, career, career-management, learning, lifelong-learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expert-resumé-driven-development&#34;&gt;Expert Resumé Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/tra/expert-resum-driven-development&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tariq Ali, where he explains the Resume-Driven Development, as a subset of the Principal-Agent Problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal (management) hires an Agent (a developer) to build a program and
allow the Agent to choose the tech stack. But the Agent&amp;rsquo;s interest (making his resumé
more impressive) can be orthogonal to the Principal&amp;rsquo;s interest (producing a great
product by using the &amp;ldquo;right tool&amp;rdquo; for the job). If the Principal allows the Agent to
do as he wish, then the Agent will do as he wishes, thereby leading to the Agent to
prosper and the Principal to suffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gartner.com/technology/research/methodologies/hype-cycle.jsp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gartner Hype Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tariq-ali, resume-driven-development, hype, cycle, hype-cycle, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resume-driven-development&#34;&gt;Resume Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2014/10/resume-driven-development.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Mike Loukides about the problem of finding a technical person based on CVs and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_the_instrument&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Law of the instrument&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] the inability of a technical team to specify what they really want
 (a developer with good programming taste and instincts), and
 instead hiring someone who has a particular skill or credential [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: law-instrument, mike-loukides, cv, career, resume-driven-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-britain-banned-mobile-apps&#34;&gt;Why Britain banned mobile apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://govinsider.asia/smart-gov/why-britain-banned-mobile-apps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with Ben Terrett, former design chief at the UK Government Digital Services (GDS), that explains why they prefer webapps rather than native (mobile) apps: it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of cost, having to maintain and update so many mobile versions, versus a single one for the webapp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also talks about user research and productagile teams inside the GDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview is written by Joshua Chambers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joshua-chambers, ben-terrett, gds, webapp, mobile-app, native-app, product-team, agile, government, uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-tech-interviews-suck-the-only-4-questions-that-matter&#34;&gt;Most Tech Interviews Suck — The Only 4 Questions That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/lightspeed-venture-partners/most-tech-interviews-suck-the-only-4-questions-that-matter-1a71181ef4d4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why the majority of technical interviews could be improved, asking four questions instead of following other practices. By Aaron Batalion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: aaron-batalion, tech-interview, hiring, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen&#34;&gt;Why Socrates UK is not just a conference for software craftsmen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codurance.com/2016/06/07/why-socrates-uk-is-not-just-a-conference-for-software-craftsmen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Giulia Mantuano on the SoCraTes UK 2016 conference, where she gave a talk on the importance of design in our environment, where we craft beautiful interfaces in our programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: socrates, socrates-uk, socrates-uk-2016, giulia-mantuano, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;360-million-reasons-to-destroy-all-passwords&#34;&gt;360 million reasons to destroy all passwords&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/360-million-reasons-to-destroy-all-passwords-9a100b2b5001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson about the insecurity of passwords, both managed by vaults (like LastPass) or remembered ones. They all are susceptible to being discovered, leaked or shared to other sites / accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author suggests to use passwordless login, which sends a link to your email account, which allows you to log in to the application&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: passwordless, lastpass, vault, password-vault, quincy-larson, hack, leak, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brutally-honest-rejection-letter-by-an-hr&#34;&gt;A Brutally Honest Rejection Letter by an HR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-coffeelicious/a-brutally-honest-rejection-letter-by-an-hr-493164bc5205&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this parody letter&lt;/a&gt; by Nish Rao, on the real reasons so HR uses these templates for rejecting candidates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nish-rao, parody, rejection-letter, hr, human-resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;passwords-are-obsolete&#34;&gt;Passwords are Obsolete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ninjudd/passwords-are-obsolete-9ed56d483eb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Justin Balthrop on how to set up a passwordless system and how is that related to the Heartbleed bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: passwordless, justin-balthrop, heartbleed, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;server-side-swift-vs-the-other-guys-2-speed&#34;&gt;Server Side Swift vs. The Other Guys — 2: Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@qutheory/server-side-swift-vs-the-other-guys-2-speed-ca65b2f79505&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comparison&lt;/a&gt; of languages and frameworks (Vapor (Swift), Ruby on Rails (Ruby), Laravel (PHP), Lumen (PHP), Express (JavaScript), Django (Python), Flask (Python), Spring (Java), Nancy (C#), Go (Pure Go, no framework)) and to benchmark Plaintext, JSON, Random SQLite Fetch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, qutheory, speed, swift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;compilers-as-assistants&#34;&gt;Compilers as Assistants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org/blog/compilers-as-assistants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Evan Czaplicki on seeing the compiler as an assistant to your work, instead of an adversary. Of how the compiler should give the most useful errors and warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also explains what features have been removed from the Elm language in 0.16.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: compiler, assistant, adversary, enemy, elm, elm-compiler, evan-czaplicki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;craftsmanship-design-and-code&#34;&gt;Craftsmanship, design, and code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/craftsmanship-design-and-code-6d93eba3e7fe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jonathan Z. White about the relation between design and code and what craftsmanship is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests learning more about the counterpart (design vs code), to better understand the activity of creating software as a whole. For developers, suggests a few activities to improve (e.g., read better code, write unit tests, analyze code). Cites that the only way of measuring progress is comparing where you are today compared to some time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: craftsmanship, jonathan-white, design, code, improving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-programmer-s-oath&#34;&gt;The Programmer&amp;rsquo;s Oath&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2015/11/18/TheProgrammersOath.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this oath&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: oath, programmer, craft, manifesto, robert-martin, uncle-bob&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intel-x86s-hide-another-cpu-that-can-take-over-your-machine-you-can-t-audit-it&#34;&gt;Intel x86s hide another CPU that can take over your machine (you can&amp;rsquo;t audit it)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://boingboing.net/2016/06/15/intel-x86-processors-ship-with.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Damien Zammit on the Intel Management Engine (ME), a hardware system that is embedded in the newer Intel chipsets. Its function is to provide low-level management services. ME (like Active Management Technology [AMT] in the past), provides great services, but has access to any memory location and to the TCP/IP stack, without any control from the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The firmware is currently checked before booting, but it is highly-valuable as a security risk, as it has full access to the physical hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: security, damien-zammit, intel-management-engine, active-management-technology, me, amt, tcp-ip, backdoor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-doesn-t-require-talent-or-even-passion&#34;&gt;Programming Doesn’t Require Talent or Even Passion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@WordcorpGlobal/programming-doesnt-require-talent-or-even-passion-11422270e1e4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of examples of why programming doesn&amp;rsquo;t require talent or passion, by Tony You&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: talent, passion, list, programming, tony-you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-from-to&#34;&gt;Getting from ⭐️⭐️ to ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/getting-from-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-to-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-%EF%B8%8F-c65cc3bb7cb1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on how Basecamp increased their ratings at the App Store: notify the user about new features and, in that modal, ask them to review the app or dismiss. By Dylan Ginsburg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: review, user-engagement, rating, basecamp, dylan-ginsburg, app-store, app&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-developer-after-40&#34;&gt;Being A Developer After 40&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/being-a-developer-after-40-3c5dd112210c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forget The Hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose Your Galaxy Wisely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn About Software History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep on Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workplaces Suck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know Your Worth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send The Elevator Down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take conscious decisions in your life. Be aware of your actions and their effect. Do not blush or be embarrased for changing your opinions. Say “I’m sorry” when required. Listen. Do not be a hotshot. Have integrity and self-respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommends these books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealers of Lightning by Michael A. Hiltzik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revolution in the Valley by Andy Hertzfeld&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar by Eric S. Raymond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Success of Open Source by Steven Weber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Old New Thing by Raymond Chen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mythical Man Month by Frederick P. Brooks Jr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peopleware by Tom DeMarco and Tim Lister&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Psychology of Software Programming by Gerald M. Weinberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facts and Fallacies of Software Engineering by Robert L. Glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Design of Everyday Things by Don Norman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly by Bertrand Meyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geekonomics by David Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrian-kosmaczewski, career, profession, age, galaxy, long-term, book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;firing-people&#34;&gt;Firing people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://zachholman.com/talk/firing-people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Holman on firing people at your current work, both from the perspective of the employee (fired), employer, coworker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains his personal experience of being fired from Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll know the difference between doing far and away your best work, and doing work that is still good, but just nominally better than what you’ve been doing. Once you catch yourself adjusting to that incremental progression… maybe it’s time to leave, to change things up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zach-holman, github, team-management, firing, coworker, employee, employer, job, relationship, next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-design-principles-for-developers&#34;&gt;10 design principles — for developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@nirbenita/the-10-design-heuristics-for-developers-1e70a9dc58a7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains what are the 10 design principles for programmers, as outlined by Jakob Nielsen. The article itself is by Nir Benita&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: design-principle, ux, jakob-nielsen, nir-benita, usability, testing, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two&#34;&gt;Design Patterns — Coming Full Circle, Part Two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two-ced2c69e4724#.x8ud7eeqm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains how design patterns can be observed and then discovered and shows a list of four patterns dot working with data, by flux.io. Article by Jen Carlile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: design-pattern, data, pattern, flux, flux-io, pattern-catalog, jen-carlile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days&#34;&gt;Why I’m Ending my Github Streak after 844 Days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@karan/why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days-80fd014dc8df&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Karan Goel on the mechanics of following a pattern, of an activity sliced in small parts (1 problem a day or half an hour) and how this can be counterproductive sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discusses ROI of this type of activity at the beginning of your career and later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: karan-goel, github, streak, python, code, everyday, practice, deliberate-practice, career, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs&#34;&gt;Good lessons learned from past jobs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kartones.net/post/good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Diego &amp;lsquo;Kartones&amp;rsquo; on a synopsis of his work experience, job by job and what he has learned on each job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: diego-kartones, job, professional-career, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;too-much-work-in-progress&#34;&gt;Too Much Work In Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://monospacedmonologues.com/post/144137568985/too-much-work-in-progress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Samir Talwar on factors that indicate work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wip, work-in-progress, list, samir-talwar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testdouble&#34;&gt;TestDouble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.martinfowler.com/bliki/TestDouble.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Martin Fowler describing the test doubles that Gerard Meszaros describes in xUnit Test Patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: test-double, martin-fowler, gerard-meszaros, stub, fake, mock, dummy, spy, xunit, junit, pattern, test-pattern&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it&#34;&gt;Scaling to 12 Million Concurrent Connections: How MigratoryData Did It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrotaru.wordpress.com/2013/10/10/scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mihai Rotaru on how MigratoryData scaled to 12 million concurrent connections in a 1U server. They explain what optimizations they did in order to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: migratorydata, mihai-rotaru, concurrent-connection, 1u-server, scalability, websocket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-what-you-love&#34;&gt;Do what you love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/do-what-you-love-jorge-diaz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jorge Diaz on doing what takes you out of your comfort zone, changing careers, and life-work in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/scott_dinsmore_how_to_find_work_you_love/transcript?language=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TED talk: How to find work you love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jorge-diaz, work, life, career, comfort-zone, scott-dinsmore, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app&#34;&gt;JHipster - The best way to breed a new app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/olbpetersson/jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by Ola Petersson, where he describes the architecture and contents of the jHipster, its pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jhipster, ola petersson, java, code-generation, code-generator, microservice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-going-to-coding-events-helped-me-get-an-awesome-job&#34;&gt;How going to coding events helped me get an awesome job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/networking-at-meet-ups-getting-hired-f0f7c4f4681a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gwendolyn Faraday on how to kickstart a career in web development, attending events, pairing and networking. That netted her some interviews to start programming for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: networking, gwendolyn-faraday, event, job, learn-to-code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maze-generation-algorithm-recap&#34;&gt;Maze Generation: Algorithm Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2011/2/7/maze-generation-algorithm-recap&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of maze-generation algorithms by Jamis Buck. Including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recursive backtracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eller’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kruskal’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prim’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recursive division algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aldous-Broder algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilson’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunt-and-Kill algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing Tree algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary Tree algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidewinder algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: recursive-backtracker,eller-algorithm,kruskal-algorithm,prim-algorithm,recursive-division-algorithm,aldous-broder-algorithm,wilson-algorithm,hunt-and-kill-algorithm,growing-tree-algorithm,binary-tree-algorithm,sidewinder-algorithm, jamis-buck, maze, maze-generation, algorithm, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-poverty-of-constraints&#34;&gt;The Poverty of Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2016/3/19/poverty-of-constraints.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jamis Buck on interpreting two Korean proverbs in the world of software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dutiful son comes from a poor home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A poor house has many children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: proverb, korea, philosophy, software, constraint, jamis-buck&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliberate-practice-what-it-is-and-why-you-need-it&#34;&gt;Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four essential components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailored (practice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetion
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language&#34;&gt;10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jooq.org/2016/03/31/10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list of features&lt;/a&gt; that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language. By Lukas Eder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: list, lukas-eder, kotlin, java, comparison, language, jooq&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-built-uber-engineering-s-highest-query-per-second-service-using-go&#34;&gt;How we built Uber engineering&amp;rsquo;s highest query per second service using Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.uber.com/go-geofence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kai Wei on a microservice they&amp;rsquo;ve built using Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the reasons for choosing that algorithm for geofencing, the performance they&amp;rsquo;re achieving, and the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uber, go, microservice, performance, geofence, geofencing, rps, go-memory-model, kai-wei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service&#34;&gt;Unwinding Uber&amp;rsquo;s Most Efficient Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@buckhx/unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service-406413c5871d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Buck Heroux commenting on the decisions of Uber for building the geofencing microservice (above read).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the different alternatives for algorithms in this problem space and has implemented them in go. Provides a benchmark for comparing those, including a profiling session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: s2, quadtree, rtree, brute-force, geofence, geofencing, uber, comment, buck-heroux, go, read-on-read, meta-read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawful-hacking-and-continuing-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Lawful Hacking and Continuing Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/03/lawful_hacking_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on the stance the FBI is taking in regards to vulnerabilities discovered in Apple&amp;rsquo;s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, apple, security, fbi, vulnerability, exploit, law, hacking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-life-learning&#34;&gt;A Side Project Helped Jumpstart My Career — Life Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/life-learning/a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-7cd6f8e9b07f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dave Gerhardt on how making a side project happen affected his life and his skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons for doing it include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It forces you to figure stuff out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way to learn is by doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gets your brain working on something other than your job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to create your own network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are the CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: long-life-learning, continuous-learning, side-project, dave-gerhardt, drift, professional-development, personal-development, business, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-jekyll-tricks&#34;&gt;Fun Jekyll Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.madebymarket.com/blog/dev/fun-jekyll-tricks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Knapp where he explains some tips and tricks of jekyll (in which octopress is based on): speed, deployment, subcategories inside the blog, _data, _includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brian-knapp, jekyll, octopress, tip-and-trick, improvement, subcategory, meta, automation, deployment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-ola-que-llega&#34;&gt;La ola que llega&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=f8a8ee92cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla, where he explains (in Spanish) the &amp;lsquo;contractor&amp;rsquo; phenomenon arriving to Spain, 2-3 years after being in other countries and the effects that this could have both for workers and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bonilista, david-bonilla, contractor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-razones-por-las-que-este-sábado-deberías-ir-a-un-code-retreat&#34;&gt;10 razones por las que este sábado deberías ir a un code retreat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://francho.org/2015/11/10/10-razones-para-ir-a-un-coderetreat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of reasons for attending a code retreat, by Francho Joven, who I met in the Global Day Of Code Retreat (GDCR) &amp;lsquo;15 in Zaragoza&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: francho-joven, list, zaragoza, code-retreat, gdcr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meaningful-work-through-passion-not-genius&#34;&gt;Meaningful Work through Passion, not Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIYUMwxKFzo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; on the importance of hard work and how it can be mistaken as genious. By Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: malcolm-gladwell, passion, genius, work, time-management, productivity, career, mastery-autonomy-purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name&#34;&gt;How to ask your wife for permission to spend $250,000 on a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Stockphoto.com/how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name-c27a3c2852e1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jon Yau on how they started StockPhoto.com, buying a $250,000 domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: startup, domain, stockphoto, jon-yau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong&#34;&gt;Sorry, developer bootcamps: I was wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@dillonforrest/sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong-ea37fcc5572c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dillon Forrest on the topic of developer bootcamps. Explains why developers should not be threatened by recent graduates of these programs and describes how people pursuing these programs usually are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bootcamp, developer-bootcamp, dev-bootcamp, dillon-forrest, intelligence, risk-appetite, resilience, self-investment, entrepreneurship, growth-trajectory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jvm-and-java-garbage-collection&#34;&gt;The JVM and Java Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoJr5QQYsl8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this webcast&lt;/a&gt; about how the JVM garbage collection works. By Michael W Williams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-williams, oracle, webcast, jvm, garbage-collection, gc,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;files-are-hard&#34;&gt;Files Are Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/file-consistency/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why software that writes on files is difficult, based on the different filesystems that are below, and the operating system. Written by Dan Luu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses software product to find bugs in filesystems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: filesystem, file, dan-luu, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusión-inquebrantable&#34;&gt;Contrata a un fracasado con ilusión inquebrantable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contunegocio.es/tecnologia/contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusion-inquebrantable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alberto Mena (in Spanish) on what are the qualities that define a good programmer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;illusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-mena, spanish, team-management, success, developer, quality, developer-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-react&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t react&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.avdi.org/2016/04/14/dont-react/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Avdi Grimm on how the action vs reaction attitude. Why to prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: action, reaction, social-media, avdi-grimm, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34;&gt;FTP is so 90&amp;rsquo;s. Let&amp;rsquo;s deploy via Git instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderwall.com/p/xczkaq/ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to deploy using git. By Kerrick Long&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kerrick-long, git, deployment, webapp, application, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-vs-career-10-key-differences-you-need-to-understand&#34;&gt;Job vs Career: 10 Key Differences You Need To Understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/job-vs-career&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what differentiates a job from a career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, infographic, job-vs-career, comparison, job, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-secret-to-employee-motivation&#34;&gt;The Secret To Employee Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/secret-employee-motivation-infographic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what motivates employess: mastery, autonomy and purpose. A direct reference to Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The puzzle of motivation&amp;rdquo; TED talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, motivation, employee, infographic, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-puzzle-of-motivation&#34;&gt;The puzzle of motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Pink on what motivates us: intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about the gap that exists between what science knows and what businesses propose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ted, ted-talk, video, dan-pink, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count&#34;&gt;Applying a ceiling to the bug count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techblog.king.com/applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, written by Susanna Berg, on how King has reduced the amount of bugs in their backlog using an agile technique, measuring and setting a limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: susanna-berg, king, agile, bug, bug-count, defect, defect-count, per-malmen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34;&gt;Coming up in 2016: Spring Framework 4.3 &amp;amp; 5.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://spring.io/blog/2015/08/03/coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this announcement&lt;/a&gt; of Spring&amp;rsquo;s new release, 5.0, which will require java 8 and will turn most of the features into the reactive programming paradigm. By Juergen Hoeller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: juergen-hoeller, spring, reactive-programming, release, announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die&#34;&gt;Why offices are where work goes to die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swizec.com/blog/why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die/swizec/6695&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Swizec Teller explaining the downsides of working in an office as compared to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: swizec-teller, remote, home-office, office, comparison, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Passionate Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bm2yogi/the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer-76a41d457304&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Ibarra on what are the implications of being a passionate developer, how it affects your tasks and what are the factors to a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-ibarra, passion, development, job, motivation, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mossack-fonseca-breach-wordpress-revolution-slider-plugin-possible-cause&#34;&gt;Mossack Fonseca Breach – WordPress Revolution Slider Plugin Possible Cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2016/04/mossack-fonseca-breach-vulnerable-slider-revolution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Maunder, which describes an hypothesis on how the Mossack Fonseca breach could have happened. Also describes and shows how to breach a Wordpress installation with a vulnerable Revolution Slider plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mark-maunder, security, breach, mossack-fonseca-breach, mossack-fonseca, hypothesis, attack, plugin, revolution-slider, wordpress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tim-urban-inside-the-mind-of-a-master-procrastinator&#34;&gt;Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; from Tim Urban on how the procrastinator&amp;rsquo;s mind works, exemplified by his own career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: procrastinator, procrastination, mind, time-management, tim-urban&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pep-20-the-zen-of-python&#34;&gt;PEP 20 &amp;ndash; The Zen of Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the PEP20&lt;/a&gt;, the zen of python, with special attention to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: pep-20, pep, python, zen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Why I switched from Octopress 2 to Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Franklin Chen on the change he made on the static site generator (SSG) he used. He considered hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo. Was decided between hakyll and hugo for their speed but, finally, decided to use hugo for their bigger community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: franklin-chen, comparison, ssg, static-site-generator, hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo, change, speed, statically-typed, dynamically-typed, golang, performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-incremental-regeneration-in-jekyll-3-0-is-such-a-big-deal&#34;&gt;Why incremental regeneration in Jekyll 3.0 is such a big deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/11/04/jekyll-30-released-incremental-regeneration-rocks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Johnson on one of the new features that jekyll 3.0 brings: incremental generation. How this can speed up the generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-johnson, incremental-generation, speed, performance, octopress-2, octopress-3, jekyll-3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-s3-travis-ci-oh-boy&#34;&gt;Hugo, S3, Travis CI, oh boy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://continuousfailure.com/post/s3_blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Scherger on how to set up a specific stack for developing and deploying a static site blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alan-scherger, static-site-generator, ssg, travis, hugo, s3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-your-blog-to-github-pages-automatically-using-hugo-and-travis&#34;&gt;Deploy your blog to github pages automatically using Hugo and Travis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcoedo.com/post/hugo-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Roman Coedo on how to deploy a hugo blog to github pages, using travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: roman-coedo, travis, hugo, github, github-pages, ssg, static-site-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;improve-octopress-with-advanced-tweaks-tips&#34;&gt;Improve Octopress with Advanced Tweaks &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.narga.net/improve-octopress-advanced-tweaks-tips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tips on how to improve the octopress (2) installation. By Nguyễn Đình Quân.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nguyen-dinh-quan, octopress-2, tip, tweak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;laboratorios&#34;&gt;Laboratorios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2014/11/12/laboratorios/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla, about laboratories to use a percentage of company time to investigate, innovate, learn and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, team-management, time-management, innovation, strategy, improvement, kaizen, laboratory, craftsmanship, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isn-t&#34;&gt;What Refactoring is, and what it isn’t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swreflections.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isnt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Bird, where he splits some practices into refactoring and not refactoring. Draws the line between these two different activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also cites scratch refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jim-bird, scratch-refactoring, refactoring, martin-fowler, kent-beck, definition, quote, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitfalls-of-unlimited-vacations&#34;&gt;Pitfalls of Unlimited Vacations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/archive/2016/02/18/unlimited-vaction-pitfalls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Phil Haack on the github, travis and netflix policies about unlimited vacations and the effects they have on the employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about minimum vacation periods, (paternity) paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: phil-haack, unlimited-vacation, holiday, vacation, team-management, burnout, github, travis, netflix, policy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultura-corporativa&#34;&gt;Cultura Corporativa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2011/02/06/cultura-corporativa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla about the corporate culture, and how &amp;ldquo;hanging a highly interchangeable sentence on a wall&amp;rdquo; does not represent it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, corporate culture, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code&#34;&gt;What It’s Really Like to Learn to Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sandjar/what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code-53f6d9156a32&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains firsthand how it is to learn programming for a novice student,even with a strong financial background and having completed a university degree. By Sandjar Kozubaev&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sandjar-kozubaev, learning, programming, student, firsthand, coding, story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard&#34;&gt;Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@benedictfritz/learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard-40a4cf3104f4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;becodeweek-by-yeray-darias&#34;&gt;BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this category of posts&lt;/a&gt; by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;becodeweek-by-yeray-darias-1&#34;&gt;BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this category of posts&lt;/a&gt; by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tracer-bullets&#34;&gt;Tracer Bullets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TracerBullets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; about tracer bullets, an analogy from the military warfare to a software project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serves the purpose of adjusting the aim of the cannon to better reach the target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: analogy, metaphor, warfare, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cohesion-the-cornerstone-of-software-design&#34;&gt;Cohesion - the cornerstone of software design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codurance.com/2016/03/03/cohesion-cornerstone-software-design/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sandro Mancuso on the topic of cohesion. Describes the 7 types of cohesion, as described in Structured Design&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, from worst to best:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coincidental cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logical cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Procedural cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicational/informational cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequential cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional cohesion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and about Design-Level Cohesion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coincidental relation (R1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditional relation (R2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterative relation (R3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication relation (R4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequential relation (R5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional (R6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cohesion, codurance, edward-yourdon, larry-constantine, list, sandro-mancuso, software-design, design-level-cohesion, smc-cohesion, dlc-cohesion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;etsy-cto-q-a-we-need-software-engineers-not-developers&#34;&gt;Etsy CTO Q&amp;amp;A: We Need Software Engineers, Not Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/etsy-cto-qa-need-software-engineers-not-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with John Allspaw, where they explain the onboarding experience for new hires at Etsy, the DevOps philosophy and the need for engineering skills, more than developer skills. This can be exemplified in the need to know more, defining the boundaries of your job and finding the right tool for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: devops, interview, q-and-a, john-allspaw, etsy, onboarding, hire, team-management, deploy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequency-reduces-difficulty&#34;&gt;Frequency Reduces Difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/FrequencyReducesDifficulty.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Martin Fowler on why we should repeat things that are difficult for us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfectioning the technique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internalizing the details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easing its automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-fowler, automation, process, perfection, internalizing, technique, detail, process-theory, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lambdas-are-confusing&#34;&gt;Lambdas are confusing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video where Coman Hamilton from JAXenter interviews Dr. Heinz Kabutz about Java&amp;rsquo;s lambda syntax. Cites the problem with exceptions, generics, method overloading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: java, lambda, coman-hamilton, jaxenter, heinz-kabutz, problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-full-stack-developer-en-2016&#34;&gt;El full-stack developer en 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.developerdepueblo.com/development/full-stack-developer-2016/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jose Ignacio Andrés about the job descriptions of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El principal valor de un full-stack es poder simplificar el trabajo a los demás miembros del equipo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My translation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main value of a full-stack developer is to be able to simplify other teammates&amp;rsquo; work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: teamwork, teammate, fullstack, simplification, work, team-management, jose andres&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-a-software-craftsman&#34;&gt;I am a software craftsman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dirv.me/i-am-a-software-craftsman/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Irvine about calling yourself a craftsman or not. He says that if you adhere to their values, you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: craftsmanship, label, daniel-irvine, craftsman, group-belonging&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching-programming-languages-in-a-post-linnaean-age&#34;&gt;Teaching Programming Languages in a Post-Linnaean Age&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Papers/Published/sk-teach-pl-post-linnaean/paper.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; by Shriram Krishnamurthi where he explains the need for books like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plai.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PLAI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lack of paradigms in new languages, and its separation (or lack of)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design of languages cheaper and cheaper these days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rigor level in publications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inductive and deductive learning
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;post-Linnaean&lt;/code&gt; refers to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Linnaeus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Carl Linnaeus&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is known as the father of modern taxonomy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: inductive-learning, deductive-learning, dsl, domain-specific-language, type-soundness, continuation-style, garbage-collection, reactive-programming, scheme, plai, teaching, programming-language, shriram-krishnamurthi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lazy-ruby&#34;&gt;Lazy Ruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sonnym.github.io/2014/04/05/lazy-ruby/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by sonnym about using ruby&amp;rsquo;s lazy (non-strict) features, detailing an example with Fibonacci&amp;rsquo;s sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: laziness, strictness, non-strictness, ruby, fibonacci, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jessica-livingston&#34;&gt;Jessica Livingston&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/jessica.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this essay&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Graham about his co-founder at the Y-combinator: Jessica Livingston. She was considered the Social Radar at YC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essay also talks about the non-existent separation between working hours and not and about her implication and personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jessica-livingston, paul-graham, y-combinator, feminism, yc, essay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1&#34;&gt;Four Laws Of Software Economics (Part 1)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@RichMironov/four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1-e162aa0ea9e5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rich Mironov on why the development team will never be big enough (because of economics, because there are more things to be done than time to do them, so we have to prioritize them) and about the communication problems between the dev team and the client(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also talks about the general personality of clients and devs and task prioritization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: exclusive-or, magical-thinking, tnstaafl, management, agile, team, capacity, death-march, estj, intp, software-economics, product-strategy, law-of-ruthless-prioritization, law, rich-mironov, slack, myers-briggs-type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-should-take-a-codecation&#34;&gt;You Should Take A Codecation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://robots.thoughtbot.com/you-should-take-a-codecation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Orenstein explaining what is a codecation and what he&amp;rsquo;s done in the two codecations he&amp;rsquo;s taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: codecation, ben-orenstein, vacation, holiday, coding, shipping, in-company&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;giving-up-on-tdd&#34;&gt;Giving Up on TDD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://iansommerville.com/systems-software-and-technology/giving-up-on-test-first-development/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ian Sommerville about the problems he&amp;rsquo;s found while doing TDD, mainly about design, but also about being conservative in the amount of tests you allow yourself to break while refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdd, ian-sommerville, refactoring, problem, design-problem, design, giving-up-tdd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;giving-up-on-tdd-answer&#34;&gt;Giving Up on TDD - answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/03/19/GivingUpOnTDD.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C. Martin on the common issues for people adopting TDD:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fragile Test Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Design Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Testable Design Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Magic Bullet Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is an answer to another by Ian Sommerville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdd, uncle-bob, robert-martin, adoption, ian-sommerville, fragile-test-problem, giving-up-tdd, design-problem, testable-design-problem, magic-bullet-problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;seek-out-jobs-with-fast-learning-cycles&#34;&gt;Seek out jobs with fast learning cycles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sarahtavel/seek-out-jobs-with-fast-learning-cycles-f923c8d8a4be#.7bxx65a4x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sarah Tavel on learning on the job and how fast these learning cycles can happen at companies at different stages of maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you’re thinking of changing jobs, or taking your first, my advice: find a place with a fast learning cycle, and a steep learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: learning, job, hypothesis, sarah-tavel, learning-cycle, maturity-level, learning-process, product-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;clean-code-vs-implementation-patterns&#34;&gt;Clean Code Vs. Implementation Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.xebia.com/clean-code-vs-implementation-patterns/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comparison&lt;/a&gt; of Clean Code vs Implementation Pattern books, by Vincent Partington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, the author explains the differences in style in both books, and how they compare to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clean-code, implementation-patterns, comparison, book-review, book-comparison, vincent-partington&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stuck-in-traffic-vlog-103-new-spammer-techniques&#34;&gt;Stuck in Traffic vlog #103 - New Spammer Techniques&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.peerlyst.com/posts/stuck-in-traffic-vlog-103-new-spammer-techniques-j-wolfgang-goerlich&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this vlog entry&lt;/a&gt; on machines fighting machines (exemplified with the spam producing and filtering) and how some spammers are trying more direct techniques focusing on higher-value targets, sometimes even handcrafting messages and modifying them every few units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wolfgang-goerlich, spam, vlog, spammer, machine-learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;becoming-a-finisher&#34;&gt;Becoming A Finisher&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://christopherdbui.com/becoming-a-finisher/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher Bui where he explains that projects that are too ambitious stall your productivity and make you lose your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christopher-bui, pomodoro, time-management, productivity, motivation, ambition, paul-graham, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanging-around-with-red-black-tree-implementations-the-beginnings&#34;&gt;Hanging around with red-black tree implementations: the beginnings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.fraixed.es/post/hanging-around-red-black-trees-implementations/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ivan Fraixedes where he details the progress of implementing a red-black tree, and also his motivation for doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ivan-fraixedes, red-black-tree, abstract-data-structure, adt, deliberate-practice, pet-project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-tools-for-faster-blogging-in-octopress&#34;&gt;Some Tools for Faster Blogging in Octopress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://dgmstuart.github.io/blog/2015/03/27/some-tools-for-faster-blogging-in-octopress/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for tips and tricks on how to blog faster with octopress. Written by Duncan Stuart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: duncan-stuart, blog, improvement, meta, octopress, tip-and-trick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-veil-of-ignorance&#34;&gt;The veil of ignorance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mrmrs.io/writing/2016/03/23/the-veil-of-ignorance/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Adam Morse on how not being on the top of the skills performance can affect your design and your user experience. Also, references the concept of &amp;ldquo;The Veil of Ignorance&amp;rdquo;, a concept by John Rawls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-rawls, veil-of-ignorance, user-experience, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-smile-again-recovering-from-the-paralysis-of-burnout&#34;&gt;To Smile Again &amp;ndash; Recovering from the paralysis of burnout&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/to-smile-again-ae0ba9f2198c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jamis Buck on his story of burnout, what symptoms had on him and how he got out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: burnout, jamis-buck, psychology, productivity, personal, story, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-email-could-startup-slack-change-the-way-you-work&#34;&gt;Beyond email: could startup Slack change the way you work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/mar/25/slack-butterfield-emoji-chat-nasa-harvard-silicon-valley&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on Slack&amp;rsquo;s office culture, with their diversity, policies and values after a high people growth in a short period of time. By Jemima Kiss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: culture, office-culture, slack, jemima-kiss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slack-work-this-way&#34;&gt;Slack: Work This Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@iaintait/slack-work-this-way-9221284472dd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, a response to my above read, about the office culture at Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: iain-tait, response, slack, office-culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bem-101&#34;&gt;BEM 101&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/bem-101/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this introduction&lt;/a&gt; to a CSS style called Block, Element, Modifier methodology (BEM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a block is a top-level abstraction of a new component&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Child items, or elements, can be placed inside and these are denoted by two underscores following the name of the block [&amp;hellip;].
modifiers can manipulate the block so that we can theme or style that particular component without inflicting changes on a completely unrelated module. This is done by appending two hyphens to the name of the block [&amp;hellip;].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Joe Richardson, Robin Rendle et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joe-richardson, robin-rendle, bem, css, css-methodology, introduction, css-architecture, sass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Structured Design: Fundamentals of a Discipline of Computer Program and Systems Design by Yourdon and Constantine.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>