<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/self-study-aggregation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/self-study-aggregation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-create-reality-https-www-mrmoneymustache-com-2019-02-27-how-to-create-reality&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2019/02/27/how-to-create-reality/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Create Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, it is explained how to create a (different) reality in the mind of your target (users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin with the End in Mind – and Start by Painting a Beautiful Picture of that end  destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the technique at the core of the world’s best marketing and negotiation strategies, and it works so well because it short circuits the human brain into making everyone – including you – see things in the desired way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a simple picture of a very clear end destination that automatically got people’s imagination running and filling in their own details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: communication, people-management, leadership, marketing, pete-adeney, mr-money-mustache, paint-the-picture, technique&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: add12910-3b3f-11e9-8a1b-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:00:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;red-flags-in-software-developer-job-descriptions-https-joecmarshall-com-posts-job-description-red-flags&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Red Flags in Software Developer Job Descriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains some red flags the author has detected while reading job offers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress Developer - Degree + 10 years experience required: refers to the exageration of needed qualifications for jobs that do not require it, apparently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP Contractor - 2 Months: refers to the short-term mentality of jobs, and the environment that it creates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Stage Emmployee / Technical Co-founder / Person to Make My Thing: refers to how cheap ideas are and how important (to developers) execution is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies: Coldfusion + jQuery: refers to old/out of fashion technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: job-offer, pattern, joe-marshall, old-technology, fashionable, short-term, long-term, mentality, hiring, recruiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3841f764-3b40-11e9-9d75-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:04:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-be-productive-with-big-existing-code-base-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19254008&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19254008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to be productive with big existing code base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this HN discussion, there are some pearls regarding working with big, legacy codebases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it the way they did doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they did it wrong. A reference to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Chesterton%27s_fence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reference to Working Effectively With Legacy Code, by Feathers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 1. Assess how much of the code is actually understood. Is there any record of the &amp;gt; design decisions, the edge cases, the debugging process, the paths that weren&amp;rsquo;t taken? Who knows the most about the codebase and how it got to be how it is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 2. What&amp;rsquo;s the current specification? Don&amp;rsquo;t look at the stack, look at input and output cases. How well does the code meet the spec? Where is it failing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 3. Before you change anything you need to know what the change process is. You &amp;gt; probably do already know this, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to find out whether there are &amp;gt; any demarcations of responsibility, even if they&amp;rsquo;re only informal and unstated areas of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 4. When you have all that, you can start working on the code with some knowledge of the context you - and the code - are operating in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 5. If code works, don&amp;rsquo;t rewrite or refactor for style without a very very good &amp;gt; reason. And don&amp;rsquo;t do it unless you can change all the &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; code at once. Otherwise &amp;gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a mess of incompatible idioms that make future changes hard to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 6. Write your own docs as you go. Best case is other people will benefit from reading them, worst case is you&amp;rsquo;ll remind yourself what you were doing six months from now - because you&amp;rsquo;ll have forgotten by then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reference to flamegraphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; The problem with the after-the-fact abstraction layer is that if the original team members are not available, you are likely not in possession of the whole theory of the software. Hence it is not likely you can in the beginning choose the right abstractions. Endquote. This is a reference to &amp;ldquo;Programming as theory building&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; Get it into a state that will support current business goals and roadmap while protecting current business value and users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: the quotes are copied directly from the discussion page and are property of the original commentators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wewlc, michael-feathers, hackernews, yc, legacy-code, theory-building, quote, chesterton-fence, working-effectively-with-legacy-code, programming-as-theory-building&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0eb0ef62-3b41-11e9-863a-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:10:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nodejs-logging-made-right-https-itnext-io-nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itnext.io/nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NodeJS logging made right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters-https-nicepage-com-doc-article-20348-web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nicepage.com/doc/article/20348/web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 2, we will talk about website builders that are lagging behind the trends and slowing down the Web Design evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 3, you will learn how to create modern web designs quickly and easily in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has walk through the different design phases, techniques; both in press (printed) design as in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some web builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the concept of the web 3.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element overlapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking the limitations of Bootstrap-like Grids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States the different needs for webmasters and designers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Designers need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing table constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property Panel for elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Windows and Mac OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Webmasters need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean HTML and CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile device support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress and Joomla support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building websites online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website builders are lagging behind the rapidly changing Web Design world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of web design tools has involved several transitions. However, progress has stopped. There are numerous signs that the new transition must happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are separate markets for web designers and webmasters. Popular website builders do not support the main features of Web Design 3.0: free positioning, modern grids, and layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, web-design, print-design, web-builder, creativity, metaphor, grid-layout, bootstrap, flexibility, design, web-3.0, web-design-3.0, web-2.0, progression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5101ce2e-3f5e-11e9-83d9-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:49:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gotify-a-self-hosted-push-notifications-service-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19347848&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19347848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gotify – a self-hosted push-notifications service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gotify, self-hosted, notification, notification-service, android, open-source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e839c82a-4367-11e9-b34d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:08:36 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-speak-like-a-leader-not-like-an-engineer-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19349676&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links and resources for speaking like a leader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leader, engineer, comparison, change, public-speaking, speak, speaking, career-management, career-change, professional-growth, resource:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1a478fc8-4368-11e9-b657-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:10:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;archivebox-open-source-self-hosted-web-archive-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19346985&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19346985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ArchiveBox: Open-source self-hosted web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools for archiving purposes. Has links to other sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpolarized.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://getpolarized.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: burtonator, web-archive, polarized, warch, warc, personal-knowledge-base&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4168161c-436e-11e9-aa0d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:54:03 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-as-a-freelancer-what-s-the-best-app-to-track-finances-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19450331&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19450331&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: As a freelancer, what&amp;rsquo;s the best app to track finances?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes tools for finance for freelancers. Stresses the importance of time wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, money-management, freelance, tool, ask-hn, hackernews, finance, time-wealth, money-wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b74a6696-4c83-11e9-99bd-0242ac110005
Read: Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:20:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned-in-my-first-year-as-a-solo-founder-https-tik-dev-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tik.dev/lessons-learned&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What I Learned in My First Year as a Solo Founder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learnings by a solo founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits of having a side project or side hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: side-hustle, side-business, learning, reflection, solo-founder, founder, revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f0dee42c-5142-11e9-9444-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:19:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-tests-not-too-many-mostly-integration-https-kentcdodds-com-blog-write-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kentcdodds.com/blog/write-tests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Write tests. Not too many. Mostly integration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paraphrasing of some advice for healthy eating: &amp;lsquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rsquo; (Pollan)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I find myself saving time when I put time in to write tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too many: you get diminishing returns on your tests as the coverage increases [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly integration: as you move up the pyramid, the confidence quotient of each form of testing increases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests strike a great balance on the trade-offs between confidence and speed/expense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: unit-test, testing, test-pyramid, healthy-testing, advice, integration-test, quote, kent-c-dodds, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d148d774-5144-11e9-94d8-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:32:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-rules-for-eating-https-www-webmd-com-food-recipes-news-20090323-7-rules-for-eating&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/food-recipes/news/20090323/7-rules-for-eating&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7 Rules for Eating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this reference article, Michael Pollan explains his seven rules for eating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything your great grandmother wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recognize as food. &amp;ldquo;When you pick up that box of portable yogurt tubes, or eat something with 15 ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce, ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What are those things doing there?&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t eat anything with more than five ingredients, or ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay out of the middle of the supermarket; shop on the perimeter of the store. Real food tends to be on the outer edge of the store near the loading docks, where it can be replaced with fresh foods when it goes bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that won&amp;rsquo;t eventually rot. &amp;ldquo;There are exceptions &amp;ndash; honey &amp;ndash; but as a rule, things like Twinkies that never go bad aren&amp;rsquo;t food,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not just what you eat but how you eat. &amp;ldquo;Always leave the table a little hungry,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Many cultures have rules that you stop eating before you are full. In Japan, they say eat until you are four-fifths full. Islamic culture has a similar rule, and in German culture they say, &amp;lsquo;Tie off the sack before it&amp;rsquo;s full.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Families traditionally ate together, around a table and not a TV, at regular meal times. It&amp;rsquo;s a good tradition. Enjoy meals with the people you love. &amp;ldquo;Remember when eating between meals felt wrong?&amp;rdquo; Pollan asks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t buy food where you buy your gasoline. In the U.S., 20% of food is eaten in the car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, four myths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food is a delivery vehicle for nutrients. What really matters isn&amp;rsquo;t broccoli but its fiber and antioxidants. If we get that right, we get our diet right. Foods kind of get in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need experts to tell us how to eat. Nutrients are invisible and mysterious. &amp;ldquo;It is a little like religion,&amp;rdquo; Pollan said. &amp;ldquo;If a powerful entity is invisible, you need a priesthood to mediate your relation with food.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole point of eating is to maintain and promote bodily health. &amp;ldquo;You are either improving or ruining your health when you eat &amp;ndash; that is a very American idea,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;But there are many other reasons to eat food: pleasure, social community, identity, and ritual. Health is not the only thing going on on our plates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are evil foods and good foods. &amp;ldquo;At any given time there is an evil nutrient we try to drive like Satan from the food supply &amp;ndash; first it was saturated fats, then it was trans fat,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Then there is the evil nutrient&amp;rsquo;s doppelganger, the blessed nutrient. If we get enough of that we, will be healthy and maybe live forever. It&amp;rsquo;s funny through history how the good and bad guys keep changing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can all be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: healthy-eating, michael-pollan, rule, advice, myth, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 30ece1fc-5145-11e9-87de-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:35:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-https-blog-usejournal-com-lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.usejournal.com/lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lean Testing or Why Unit Tests are Worse than You Think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article puts testing in an economic perspective. Calls it lean testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also references/paraphrases Michael Pollan&amp;rsquo;s Rules for eating ().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creates a testing trophy, a figure to explain the best testing pattern, replacing the testing pyramid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains return on investment (ROI) on tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;integration tests provide the best balance of cost, speed and confidence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests lie somewhere between unit tests and end-to-end tests so they provide the best balance. Therefore, they have the highest ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea is to just not mock so much&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: economic-perspective, lean-testing, testing-trophy, testing-pyramid, return-on-investment, roi, critical-path, testing, unit-test, anti-architecture, architecture, maintenance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: efe85d00-5147-11e9-87ce-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:55:02 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-user-programming-https-www-inkandswitch-com-end-user-programming-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inkandswitch.com/end-user-programming.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;End-user programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the writer explains some of the end-user modifications to programs. Examples include: adding download capabilities to instagram, generating backups for files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, applications (especially mobile) are tightly sealed, not allowing modification or extension. Even FOSS (free, open source software), modification implies the learning curve / entry barrier of having to setup, compile, debug the original program and modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives the example of the UNIX command line, as a programming environment. One that provides (one of) the best REPL examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characterizes spreadsheets as ad-hoc databases, programs; mostly created by domain experts (aka subject matter experts), than professional software engineers. Take into account that these hats are non-exclusive: a domain expert can also be a professional software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author tries to coin the term &amp;ldquo;end-user programming&amp;rdquo; to differentiate it from programming by professional software developers, who try to build general-purpose apps, to be used by thousands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means, that a professional software developer can be an &amp;ldquo;end-user programmer&amp;rdquo;, when creating solutions for themselves (limited user group), rather than for the general public. Maybe those one-off scripts that we create, are some kind of end-user programs. This is described in the article as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks of the chasm the user has to cross in order to customize the behaviour of their software. This is related to working in a framework or a library, in the sense of &amp;lsquo;who keeps the control&amp;rsquo;. In an UNIX, filesystem environment, you keep the control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References &amp;ldquo;citizen developers&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three qualities for end-user programming: embodiment, living systems, and in-place toolchains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment: it requires the programmer hold many abstractions in their mind. Related to abstract reasoning. Mentions that many end-users don&amp;rsquo;t have these abstractions in their mind, but are capable of abstract reasoning in their own domains of expertise. Mentions that via visual representations onscreen, we can help the end-user. An example: preview formula results in a spreadsheet; highlight the cells in a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment means, broadly, making elements of the programming experience more concrete and visual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living systems: interaction with them. Refers to shortening the feedback cycle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Live programming gives the programmer immediate feedback on the behavior of a program as it is edited, replacing the edit compile-debug cycle with a fluid programming experience.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But only short feedback loops, but also to change the system behaviour from within, such as the LISP compiler reading and compiling the source code from inside a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-place tool chains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user should be able to edit their programs without installing additional tools or programs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a Unix shell script is just a series of commands saved into a text file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning that the user is already accustomed to issuing those commands. A script is just grouping those commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives examples of end-user programming success stories: spreadsheets, SQL, browser dev tools,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: end-user-programming, programming, extensibility, open-closed-principle, ocp, mofication, user, extension, unix, repl, spreadsheet, reflection, theory, history, review, sql, dev-tools, chasm, abstraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4490792a-514b-11e9-9861-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:18:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-https-medium-com-web-development-why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@web.development/why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why developers consider Agile development to be nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article explains how Agile development is apt and indicated for short-term software development, especially for contracting or consulting companies, where the client is external to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why it does not make as much sense in products/services where there is a leapfrog solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t give the customer what they ask for; understand them, and revolutionize their world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leapfrog-solution, google, agile, agile-development, comparison, project-management, client, consulting, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9035ea3c-514f-11e9-9676-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:49:37 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-bother-with-what-three-words-https-shkspr-mobi-blog-2019-03-why-bother-with-what-three-words&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/03/why-bother-with-what-three-words/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why bother with What Three Words?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the author questions why using a closed protocol for translating geo-coordinates to words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author complains that it is masquerading a for-profit, closed algorithm as an open standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, that the GPS locations are drifting very quickly in some places, therefore the translated address changes, but the local address (e.g., 1 Wall Street), does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gps-drift, australia, open-standard, closed-standard, for-profit, protocol, open, closed, what-three-words, w3w, i18n, startup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 960e6750-5202-11e9-bb40-0242ac110008
Read: Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:11:07 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amazon-dynamodb-transactions-how-it-works-https-docs-aws-amazon-com-amazondynamodb-latest-developerguide-transaction-apis-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/transaction-apis.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002
Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jepsen-aerospike-https-aphyr-com-posts-324-call-me-maybe-aerospike&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aphyr.com/posts/324-call-me-maybe-aerospike&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jepsen: Aerospike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002
Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-critique-of-ansi-sql-isolation-levels-https-www-microsoft-com-en-us-research-wp-content-uploads-2016-02-tr-95-51-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tr-95-51.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Critique of ANSI SQL Isolation Levels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this paper that explains the ANSI SQL isolation levels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: non-repeatable, fuzzy-read, dirty-read, phantom, phantom-read, isolation, serializability, consistency, consistency, consistency-level, read-uncommitted, read-committed, repeatable-read, serializable, microsoft&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 01292b8c-263a-11e9-a7fe-0242ac110002
Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:56:58 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weak-consistency-a-generalized-theory-and-optimistic-implementations-for-distributed-transactions-http-pmg-csail-mit-edu-papers-adya-phd-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pmg.csail.mit.edu/papers/adya-phd.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Weak Consistency: A Generalized Theory and Optimistic Implementations for Distributed Transactions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extended paper on ACID properties for SQL databases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: liskov, atul-adya, stronger-serializable, consistency, consistency-level, isolation, database, sql-database, acid, transaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4a1c6f7a-263a-11e9-8e08-0242ac110002
Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:59:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-todo-el-mundo-sabe-o-debe-dar-feedback-https-softwareyotrasdesvirtudes-com-2018-11-26-no-todo-el-mundo-sabe-o-debe-dar-feedback&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwareyotrasdesvirtudes.com/2018/11/26/no-todo-el-mundo-sabe-o-debe-dar-feedback/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;No todo el mundo sabe o debe dar feedback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author explains why some feedback is dangerous: either the way of giving it, or the message, or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, she&amp;rsquo;s talking about the Commit Conf, but this is applicable to any situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para dar un buen feedback es importante:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primero: agradecer el esfuerzo por la charla.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Segundo: resaltar algo positivo de ella.  Seguro que algo cumple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tercero: decir cómo mejorarías un aspecto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Último: volver a dar las gracias o decir una frase buena que motive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dar un mal feedback es muy fácil:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primero: no leerte la descripción ni el nivel de la charla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Segundo: te cabreas porque no es lo esperado y dudabas entre esa y otra charla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tercero: dices lo que no te ha gustado sin rodeos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cuarto: además asumes cosas que no ha hecho y las escribes. Igual que yo he hecho en el Primero y Segundo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quinto: si además dices algo faltoso gana puntos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexto: Utilizas esa tónica destructiva en todos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: laura-lacarra, commit, commit-conf, feedback, good-feedback, honest-feedback, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 20d8145e-3a92-11e9-8023-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:18:10 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-deal-with-difficult-people-on-software-projects-https-people-neilon-software&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://people.neilon.software/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Deal with Difficult People on Software Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this guide on dealing with difficult people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many (48) personality types, including these types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product Managers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Managers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development Managers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality Assurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: people, people-management, personality-type, guide, neil-green&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 95554892-3a92-11e9-9bbf-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:21:25 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-disenchantment-http-tonsky-me-blog-disenchantment&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tonsky.me/blog/disenchantment/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software disenchantment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about somebody disenchanted with the current state of the art of software: slow, bloated, not better than 10 years ago, or faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nikita-prokopov, bloat, rant, disenchantment, tonsky, comparison, speed, software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0078d58a-3a93-11e9-8f23-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:24:25 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-values-and-principles-of-agile-software-development-https-www-slideshare-net-bradapp-the-values-and-principles-of-agile-software-development&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/bradapp/the-values-and-principles-of-agile-software-development&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Values and Principles of Agile Software Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the slides of this presentation by Brad Appleton, on Values, Principles, and Practices in an Agile environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of good quotes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brad-appleton, slideshare, slide, agile, practice, principle, value, xp, extreme-programming, quote, lean-software, lean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 42cdde80-3a93-11e9-814c-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:26:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;makefiles-como-dejar-de-memorizar-comandos-en-docker-developer-vago-https-jesuslc-com-2018-04-21-makefiles-como-dejar-de-memorizar-comandos-en-docker-developer-vago&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jesuslc.com/2018/04/21/makefiles-como-dejar-de-memorizar-comandos-en-docker-developer-vago/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Makefiles como dejar de memorizar comandos en docker – Developer Vago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered a new technique for Makefiles:\n\nUsing a common format (a DSL, in fact) to document the goal, then a new goal &amp;lsquo;help&amp;rsquo; to print that documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.PHONY: &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;
help: &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## Print this help.&lt;/span&gt;
  @grep -E &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;^[a-zA-Z_-]+:.*?## .*$$&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;MAKEFILE_LIST&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; awk &lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;BEGIN {FS = \&amp;quot;:.*?## \&amp;quot;}; {printf \&amp;quot;\033[36m%-20s\033[0m %s\n\&amp;quot;, $$1, $$2}&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when you run &lt;code&gt;make help&lt;/code&gt;, then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Print this help.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: makefile, jesuslc, documentation, executable-documentation, awk, trick, help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d6a4b78c-3a93-11e9-88d7-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 27 Feb 2019 13:30:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;work-cycles-https-docs-google-com-document-d-1dkldpcwvzn-z2tokwc80yomidueo6x58dt4debkc84q-edit&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1DKLDpCwvzn_z2tokwC80yOmidueO6x58dt4DEbkc84Q/edit#&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Work cycles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this Work Cycle framework to be more productive with your daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests an alternative to Pomodoro technique, in which you are to write down the contents of the goal, then split in small chunks (periods) of time to complete the individual tasks, then debrief at the end of the period and at the end of the cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An analogy could be a double-loop Pomodoro technique for tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: pomodoro, pomodoro-technique, framework, management, productivity, personal-productivity, gtd, getting-things-done, work-cycle, cycle, time-management, mental-framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f280c496-0df2-11e9-bf65-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 01 Jan 2019 18:27:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;world-cat-https-www-worldcat-org-search&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldcat.org/search&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;World Cat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Site to find books in public libraries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: book, search, library, ebook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 15ca63e4-0df8-11e9-b145-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:04:38 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/01/self-study-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/01/self-study-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-year-nomad-a-review-https-krausefx-com-blog-one-year-nomad&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://krausefx.com/blog/one-year-nomad&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;One year nomad - a review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nomad, felix-krause, digital-nomad, remote, life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7784a1da-fc82-11e8-a2cc-0242ac110002
Read: Mon, 10 Dec 2018 13:49:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-reason-many-ultrarich-people-aren-t-satisfied-with-their-wealth-https-www-theatlantic-com-family-archive-2018-12-rich-people-happy-money-577231&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/family/archive/2018/12/rich-people-happy-money/577231/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Reason Many Ultrarich People Aren’t Satisfied With Their Wealth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the rich are motivated to earn more money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;really rich people are often motivated to acquire more money by the thrill that comes with multiplying one’s fortune by making investments, buying up businesses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those two ways of putting money to use—as a way of covering expenses or as a way of building a bigger fortune—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every billionaire I’ve spoken to, and I’ve spoken to quite a number of them, is extremely excited by each additional increment of money they make&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I have enough to buy this expensive thing I want? but rather Do I have as much or more than these people I’m comparing myself with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;feeling wealthy is about comparison with others in your reference group. So the question is not what individuals want to buy, but what they feel they must buy in order to keep up their status&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rich, wealth, the-atlantic, longform, management, wealth-management, motivation, elite, ultrarich, money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e5650e1c-0081-11e9-a127-0242ac110002
Read: Sat, 15 Dec 2018 15:55:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;etsy-s-experiment-with-immutable-documentation-https-codeascraft-com-2018-10-10-etsys-experiment-with-immutable-documentation&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://codeascraft.com/2018/10/10/etsys-experiment-with-immutable-documentation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Etsy’s experiment with immutable documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading freshness for completeness in documentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: how-doc, what-doc, fyi, documentation, etsy, experiment, immutable-documentation, infobot, bot, slack, slack-integration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6ef4bf24-0082-11e9-a076-0242ac110002
Read: Sat, 15 Dec 2018 15:59:41 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-haskell-pyramid-https-patrickmn-com-software-the-haskell-pyramid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://patrickmn.com/software/the-haskell-pyramid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Haskell Pyramid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-verde-más-verde-https-mailchi-mp-bonillaware-verde-mas-verde-e-68e22b460d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/bonillaware/verde-mas-verde?e=68e22b460d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;El verde más verde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, project-management, slack-time, sabbatical, vertical-slice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ef00176e-7ddc-11e8-a33b-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 09:47:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer-https-dev-to-lewismenelaws-how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer-4opl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/lewismenelaws/how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer--4opl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Fix Burnout as a Developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on burnout and how to fix it:
Stop working so much.
Prioritize your health.
Try something new.
Patience is key.
Talk to your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lewis-menelaws, burnout, burn-out, productivity, listicle, career, psychology, management, time-management, career-management, health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 40d68542-7dff-11e8-89f2-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 13:53:09 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-what-is-the-first-thing-you-implement-at-a-new-company-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-17353854&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17353854&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: What is the first thing you implement at a new company?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the first things that people do when joining a new client.
Mentions the Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence: You don’t want to change something until you understand why it’s there in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chesterton-fence, hacker-news, contractor, client, onboarding, fix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9003a91a-7dff-11e8-a366-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 13:55:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fallacy-of-chesterton-s-fence-https-abovethelaw-com-2014-01-the-fallacy-of-chestertons-fence&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://abovethelaw.com/2014/01/the-fallacy-of-chestertons-fence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Fallacy Of Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Fence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence.
&amp;gt; don’t ever take a fence down until you know the reason why it was put up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author explains that the walls (or contracts, or clauses, or practices) were put in place to cover for a specific need. Do not assume that this need does not exist now, before understanding what the need was in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chesterton-fence, keith-lee, consulting, tip, analogy, discovery, process, people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 736e269e-7e00-11e8-ac4a-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 14:01:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-the-uuid-https-segment-com-blog-a-brief-history-of-the-uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-uuid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A brief history of the UUID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief history of UUID: of how it was developed, why, and a new library in go called ksuid
Explains the origins of networked computers (as opposed to personal computers without any networking) in the 1980s.
Also explains the origins of the UUID, some algorithms for generating them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ksuid, uuid, golang, go, rick-branson, history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c20e6ac4-8fe5-11e8-b54e-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:36:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivering-billions-of-messages-exactly-once-https-segment-com-blog-exactly-once-delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Delivering billions of messages exactly once&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how this company (segment) has solved the problem of delivering the messages once and only once (OAOO), using RocksDB, Kafka, UUIDs. Deployed to AWS, lowers the cost of the previous system (memcached-based).
Impressive numbers: 1.5 TB worth of keys stored on disk in RocksDB
a 4-week window of de-duplication before aging out old keys
approximately 60B keys stored inside our RocksDB instances
200B messages passed through the dedupe system
Also explains in depth how RocksDB works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rocksdb, facebook, database, once-and-only-once, oaoo, message, exactly-once-delivery, delivery, message-delivery, kafka, uuid, client, aws, segment, topic, cloud-scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 962c0c26-8fe6-11e8-bf2c-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:41:55 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;object-collaboration-stereotypes-http-www-mockobjects-com-2006-10-different-kinds-of-collaborators-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mockobjects.com/2006/10/different-kinds-of-collaborators.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Object Collaboration Stereotypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post describes the relationships between two objects:
Dependencies are services that the object needs from its environment so that it can fulfil its responsibilities.
Notifications are other parts of the system that need to know when the object changes state or performs an action.
Policies are objects that tweak or adapt the object&amp;rsquo;s behaviour to the needs of the system.
Parts are components in the implementation that are not controlled from outside the object after being set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dependency, notification, policy, part, collaborator, relationship, steve-freeman, goos, growing-object-oriented-software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f7e738c8-8fe6-11e8-89be-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:44:39 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mocks-fakes-stubs-and-dummies-http-xunitpatterns-com-mocks-20fakes-20stubs-20and-20dummies-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xunitpatterns.com/Mocks,%20Fakes,%20Stubs%20and%20Dummies.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mocks, Fakes, Stubs and Dummies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bibliography for mocks, stubs, fakes, dummies, spies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mock, stub, test-double, dummy, xunit, xunit-pattern, gerard-meszaros, xunitpatterns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea7281ee-9012-11e8-bd95-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 13:59:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-look-don-t-tell&#34;&gt;[Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-vida-de-las-ideas&#34;&gt;[La vida de las ideas]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, idea, startup, execution, value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c72f3522-7958-11e8-935c-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:51:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-re-frame-instead-of-om-next-http-t-dripemail2-com-c-eyjhy2nvdw50x2lkijoimzy1mtcxnyisimrlbgl2zxj5x2lkijoimte1ntgzote5mcisinvybci6imh0dhbzoi8vchvyzwx5znvuy3rpb25hbc50di9hcnrpy2xll3does1yzs1mcmftzs1pbnn0zwfklw9mlw9tlw5lehqvp19fcz1moxa2dmrwc2n0ymluagjxyne2eij9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.dripemail2.com/c/eyJhY2NvdW50X2lkIjoiMzY1MTcxNyIsImRlbGl2ZXJ5X2lkIjoiMTE1NTgzOTE5MCIsInVybCI6Imh0dHBzOi8vcHVyZWx5ZnVuY3Rpb25hbC50di9hcnRpY2xlL3doeS1yZS1mcmFtZS1pbnN0ZWFkLW9mLW9tLW5leHQvP19fcz1mOXA2dmRwc2N0YmluaGJxYnE2eiJ9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why re-frame instead of om next&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Eric Normand on why he chose to write a course on clojure front-end framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-normand, clojure, david-nolen, frontend, framework, reframe, om-next, comparison, course, mooc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea43a380-7959-11e8-bd3b-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:59:32 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lexnet-el-software-que-nunca-debió-existir&#34;&gt;[LexNET: el software que nunca debió existir]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on the software called LexNET and the scandal around it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, lexnet, bonilista, software, scandal, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1aa20256-795a-11e8-9b39-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 16:00:53 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;40&#34;&gt;[40]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read this bonilista by David Bonilla explaining some of the things he has learned from 40 years of experience in life. Explains some of his fears and how he has solved them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, birthday, reflection, fear, money, money-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 296a433e-795a-11e8-981e-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 16:01:18 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-lucha-por-la-red&#34;&gt;[La lucha por la Red]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on the net neutrality in Spain and in the European union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, net-neutrality, internet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 395a8984-795a-11e8-9102-0242ac110002
Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 16:01:45 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-machine-has-figured-out-rubik-s-cube-all-by-itself-https-www-technologyreview-com-s-611281-a-machine-has-figured-out-rubiks-cube-all-by-itself&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/611281/a-machine-has-figured-out-rubiks-cube-all-by-itself/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A machine has figured out Rubik&amp;rsquo;s Cube all by itself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how an AI has solved the rubik cube by itself. The team, including McAleer, has used a technique called &amp;ldquo;autodidactic iteration: a way for the machine to create its own system of rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rubik, rubik-cube, ai, autodidactic-iteration, autodidactic, reward, mcaleer, artificial-intelligence, deep-learning, monte-carlo, monte-carlo-tree-search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0cb8305c-7a1d-11e8-9823-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:16:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-tienda&#34;&gt;[La tienda]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on how more and more investors are deciding to do it only on profitable startups rather than a more global strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, investor, startup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6735c620-7a1d-11e8-a2e9-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:18:53 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-not-a-woman-in-tech-https-communequation-wordpress-com-2017-07-05-im-not-a-woman-in-tech&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://communequation.wordpress.com/2017/07/05/im-not-a-woman-in-tech/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I’m not a woman in tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Maria Scrivener on how she does not consider herself a woman in tech. She prefers to lose the labels and just be considered her, herself. Advocates for being inclusive rather than exclusive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: feminism, women-in-tech, maria-scrivener, women, label, equality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7e2fbffc-7a1d-11e8-bbd2-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:19:32 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;password-security-alert-https-blog-8tracks-com-2017-06-27-password-security-alert&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.8tracks.com/2017/06/27/password-security-alert/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PASSWORD SECURITY ALERT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Porter in which they alert their users that their database has been leaked, therefore some passwords are at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The passwords were hashed and salted, not stored in plain text, but those who share a password across services could be at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack has been successful given that a developer didn&amp;rsquo;t have two-factor authentication (2FA) on their github account and the company was using GitHub LFS (git large file system) to store database backups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-porter, backup, storage, configuration, github, 2fa, plain-text, password, security, security-alert, lfs, git-lfs, github-lfs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 97212f3c-7a1d-11e8-bdcd-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:20:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-green-https-blog-cryptographyengineering-com-2017-07-02-beyond-public-key-encryption&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2017/07/02/beyond-public-key-encryption/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Matthew Green&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Matthew Green on the ideas presented by Shamir in 1984: Identity Based Cryptography (IBE), Attribute Based Cryptography (ABE)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rsa, matthew-green, cryptography, identity-based-cryptography, attribute-based-cryptography, shamir, public-key, encryption, private-key&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a942bf96-7a1d-11e8-b122-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:20:44 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starbucks-should-really-make-their-apis-public-https-blog-tendigi-com-starbucks-should-really-make-their-apis-public-6b64a1c2e923&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.tendigi.com/starbucks-should-really-make-their-apis-public-6b64a1c2e923&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Starbucks should really make their APIs public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Nick Lee in which he explains how he has reverse-engineered the Starbucks API so you can connect to it from another device (not only phones, with the app installed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: certificate-pinning, tendigi, nick-lee, security, man-in-the-middle, proxy, api, attribute-fingerprinting, open-api, starbucks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b3ffb61e-7a1d-11e8-a08c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:21:02 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-toggles-are-one-of-the-worst-kinds-of-technical-debt-https-dzone-com-articles-feature-toggles-are-one-worst&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/feature-toggles-are-one-worst&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feature Toggles are one of the Worst kinds of Technical Debt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the ups and downs of using feature toggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially with long lived branches and feature by abstraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: feature-by-abstraction, feature-toggle, canary-test, jim-bird, technical-debt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dbb1ff46-7a1d-11e8-b40e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:22:09 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testcontainers-making-java-integration-tests-easy-https-zeroturnaround-com-rebellabs-java-integration-testing-with-testcontainers&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/java-integration-testing-with-testcontainers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TestContainers: making Java integration tests easy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to start a new docker container from Java code (using a junit @rule).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the library TestContainers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: testcontainers, rebel-labs, anton-arhipov, test, docker, image, integration-test, testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f13f63bc-7a1d-11e8-a6a2-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:22:45 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-health-to-comment-or-not-to-comment-http-testing-googleblog-com-2017-07-code-health-to-comment-or-not-to-comment-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://testing.googleblog.com/2017/07/code-health-to-comment-or-not-to-comment.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code Health: To Comment or Not to Comment?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about comments in code: where to use them and when not to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dori-reuveni, kevin-bourrillion, comment, clean-code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 15740b0c-7a1e-11e8-9169-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:23:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saints-and-traders-the-john-henry-fable-reconsidered-https-www-ribbonfarm-com-2014-06-04-saints-and-traders-the-john-henry-fable-reconsidered&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2014/06/04/saints-and-traders-the-john-henry-fable-reconsidered/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Saints and Traders: The John Henry Fable Reconsidered&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the guardian syndrome and the Saint syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the story of John Henry, who died right after winning a drilling contest with a machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the finite game and the infinite game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: finite-game, infinite-game, saint-syndrome, guardian-syndrome, comparison, philosophy, venkatesh-rao, john-henry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5228464e-7a1e-11e8-9125-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:25:28 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stacked-pull-requests-keeping-github-diffs-small-https-graysonkoonce-com-stacked-pull-requests-keeping-github-diffs-small&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://graysonkoonce.com/stacked-pull-requests-keeping-github-diffs-small/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stacked Pull Requests: Keeping GitHub Diffs Small&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on using a technique (stacked pull requests) to keep pull requests small and get more feedback, more comments from teammates, therefore reducing the code review fatigue. By Grayson Koonce&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: grayson-koonce, fatigue, code-fatigue, pull-request, pull-request-fatigue, stacked-pull-request, technique, comment, feedback, teammate, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6e3df860-7a1e-11e8-ba6a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:26:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-hate-almost-all-software-http-tinyclouds-org-rant-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyclouds.org/rant.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I hate almost all software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Ryan Dahl on the focus of the software and the inherent complexity of today&amp;rsquo;s software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ryan-dahl, complexity, software, rant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7ab3fcd4-7a1e-11e8-9590-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:26:36 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-reason-for-developers-salaries-stagnation-https-simpleprogrammer-com-developers-salaries-stagnation&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://simpleprogrammer.com/developers-salaries-stagnation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Real Reason for Developers’ Salaries Stagnation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Im this article, the author speaks of developer salaries related to their skills, proficiency, area of interest and role. Also about the real purchasing power stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: salary, skill, role, position, money, career, career-management, fiodar-sazanavets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a4e26bee-7a1e-11e8-ac68-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:27:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-10x-programmer-https-dev-to-nathanepstein-what-is-a-10x-programmer&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/nathanepstein/what-is-a-10x-programmer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;10x&amp;rdquo; Programmer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about makes a good programmer, under the label of the mythical 10x programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different groups of things in the list: things you are/have (skills) and things you do (actitudes). On the former, writing code (good, business code that is correctly organized, architected, designed), to know a lot. On the latter, ownership for the project (implication, care), teaching and learning from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: 10x, author, productivity, skill, attitude, aptitude, attitude-vs-aptitude, nathan-epstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e5d53f46-7a1e-11e8-9097-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:29:35 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-podcasts-have-become-popular-http-www-donnfelker-com-why-podcasts-have-become-popular&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.donnfelker.com/why-podcasts-have-become-popular/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Podcasts Have Become Popular&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Donn Felker on the effect that the Internet is having on consumers: they now decide when to consume the resources, instead of passively waiting for the resources to appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the suggested explanation for on-demand video vs television, podcasts vs radio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: podcast, on-demand, consumer, internet, donn-felker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f7f8a73a-7a1e-11e8-836d-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:30:06 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-know-what-you-want-improve-these-7-universal-skills-self-discipline-get-better-at-ignoring-the-negative-voice-in-your-head-get-out-of-your-bed-go-to-the-gym-don-t-listen-to-i-don-t-want-to&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Self-Discipline: Get better at ignoring the negative voice in your head. Get out of your bed. Go to the gym. Don’t listen to “I don’t want to.”&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Don’t Know What You Want? Improve These 7 Universal Skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal Effectiveness: Learn how to maximize the results you can get during the 16–18 hours you’re awake. Get more done — effectively.
Communication: We think we’re all master communicators. But the truth is that we suck. Communication is both art and science. And our ability to work with others depends on it.
Negotiation: You negotiate all the time. With your spouse, kids, parents, teachers, friends, co-workers, managers, etc. Learn to get the best deal for all parties.
Persuasion: Learn how to get what you want in an ethical way.
Physical Strength &amp;amp; Stamina: Getting stronger is a skill. Pull your own weight. It’s something every human should be able to do.
Flexibility: Sitting all day long behind your computer or in your car turns you into a stiff being. Learn how to stretch your hips, lower back, hamstrings, and calves — the most common weak points of desk workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0862fbca-7a1f-11e8-83fb-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:30:33 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-concentration-training-program-11-exercises-that-will-strengthen-your-attention-https-www-artofmanliness-com-2014-01-30-your-concentration-training-program-11-exercises-that-will-strengthen-your-attention&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artofmanliness.com/2014/01/30/your-concentration-training-program-11-exercises-that-will-strengthen-your-attention/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Your Concentration Training Program: 11 Exercises That Will Strengthen Your Attention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Brett &amp;amp; Kate McKay on exercises for training the attention&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brett-mckay, kate-mckay, training, concentration, exercise, focus, attention&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 14f5e064-7a1f-11e8-be86-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:30:54 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-attention-heist-https-lareviewofbooks-org-article-the-great-attention-heist&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/the-great-attention-heist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Great Attention Heist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Bell, John Zada on the current war for attention, what they call the &amp;lsquo;attention heist&amp;rsquo;: publishers fight for your attention, selling it to third parties. The more they can lure you to spend your (finite) attention with them, the higher the profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They talk about two kinds of attention: short span and long span. Reading news is the first while reading a book or a long article is the second one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They mention unplugging (i.e., a &amp;ldquo;digital sabbath&amp;rdquo;) to help improving the level of concentration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(this was a book review, of &amp;lsquo;The attention merchants&amp;rsquo;, by Tim Wu)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-bell, john-zada, attention-heist, attention, app, smartphone, book-review, tim-wu, book, sabbath, digital-sabbath, long-article&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3f41e6ec-7a1f-11e8-85fc-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:32:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-read-more-books-http-verraes-net-2012-12-2012-12-23-how-to-read-more-books&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://verraes.net/2012/12/2012-12-23-how-to-read-more-books/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to read more books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mathias-verraes, reading, tips-and-tricks, self-study, training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c451a048-7a1f-11e8-82f7-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:35:49 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serving-100-gbps-from-an-open-connect-appliance-https-medium-com-netflix-techblog-serving-100-gbps-from-an-open-connect-appliance-cdb51dda3b99&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/netflix-techblog/serving-100-gbps-from-an-open-connect-appliance-cdb51dda3b99&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Serving 100 Gbps from an Open Connect Appliance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how Netflix has optimized their servers to be able to send TLS content at 100 Gbps, using openbsd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: netflix, openbsd, performance, optimization, drew-gallatin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dc8f92dc-7a1f-11e8-818a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:36:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rebellabs-developer-productivity-report-2017-why-do-you-use-the-java-tools-you-use-https-zeroturnaround-com-rebellabs-developer-productivity-report-2017-why-do-you-use-java-tools-you-use&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/developer-productivity-report-2017-why-do-you-use-java-tools-you-use/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RebelLabs Developer Productivity Report 2017: Why do you use the Java tools you use?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: java-ee, spring, kotlin, java, jvm, scala, clojure, productivity, rebel-labs, oleg-shelajev, zero-turnaround, 2017, report, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1c603222-7a20-11e8-8f75-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:38:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-paper-is-the-real-killer-app-http-www-bbc-com-capital-story-20170120-why-paper-is-the-real-killer-app&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20170120-why-paper-is-the-real-killer-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why paper is the real &amp;lsquo;killer app&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alison Birrane on how working on a low-tech device is different than on a high-tech device (e.g., taking notes on a paper sheet vs on a laptop). On how it stimulates different parts of the brain. The multiple uses of the paper as compared to the narrowness of the apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alison-birrane, killer-app, comparison, media, social-media, gadget, low-tech, technology, smartphone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 2ac58bdc-7a20-11e8-a82d-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:38:40 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-study-guide-to-machine-learning-https-machinelearningmastery-com-self-study-guide-to-machine-learning&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://machinelearningmastery.com/self-study-guide-to-machine-learning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Self-Study Guide to Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: self-study, machine-learning, jason-brownlee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 388125f6-7a20-11e8-aae6-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:39:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-up-the-behemoth&#34;&gt;[Breaking Up the Behemoth]()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Sandi Metz explaining how applications evolve, and what we might do if we&amp;rsquo;re unhappy with the results using:  Design Stamina Hypothesis (Fowler), Procedural vs Object-Oriented Code and X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ood, object-orientation, sandi-metz, martin-fowler, design-stamina, quality, behemoth, monolith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 457003ea-7a20-11e8-a3ff-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:39:25 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-hard-things-to-start-doing-for-yourself-http-www-marcandangel-com-2017-09-24-10-hard-things-to-start-doing-for-yourself&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marcandangel.com/2017/09/24/10-hard-things-to-start-doing-for-yourself/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;10 Hard Things to Start Doing for Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this self-help article on how to help yourself by doing hard things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start letting go of unnecessary ideals
Start putting your heart and soul into the things you do
Start stretching yourself just beyond the edge of comfort
Start taking more deep breaths, so you can mindfully collect more lessons for the long run
Start side-stepping senseless drama
Start staying true to your values and convictions
Start looking for silver linings
Start focusing inward more often
Start embracing your humanness and giving yourself more credit
Start taking the next small, insignificant step (one at a time, every day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Marc Chernoff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: marc-chernoff, self-help, meditation, breathing, comfort-zone, help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 53a89846-7a20-11e8-abd1-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:39:49 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;happiness-is-overrated-finding-deep-meaning-in-life-comes-down-to-4-pillars-http-www-businessinsider-com-emily-esfehani-smith-finding-meaning-life-4-pillars-2017-9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/emily-esfehani-smith-finding-meaning-life-4-pillars-2017-9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Happiness is overrated — finding deep meaning in life comes down to 4 &amp;lsquo;pillars&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about what life is about: not happiness but four pillars: belonging and purpose, transcendence and storytelling
storytelling helps people create meaning because it allows people to create, edit, and transform the story of their lives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: happiness, life, fulfillment, pillar, belonging, purpose, flow, transcendence, storytelling,, chris-weller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9737002a-7a20-11e8-a864-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:41:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-time-to-kill-the-web-https-blog-plan99-net-its-time-to-kill-the-web-974a9fe80c89&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.plan99.net/its-time-to-kill-the-web-974a9fe80c89&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;It’s time to kill the web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains the background of the web and how it wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed to support applications but documents. Explains the downsides and security profile of a webapp as compared to a desktop/native application. By Mike Hearn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, web-app, application, app, desktop-app, native-app, mike-hearn, security, html, html5, javascript, web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a3e1c936-7a20-11e8-8fbe-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:42:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-stay-focused-when-you-re-working-from-home-https-hbr-org-2017-09-how-to-stay-focused-when-youre-working-from-home-formcheck-bc3e82f422e9567c25d37e403ee877e6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/09/how-to-stay-focused-when-youre-working-from-home&amp;amp;formCheck=bc3e82f422e9567c25d37e403ee877e6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Stay Focused When You’re Working from Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on structuring your workday while being at home (remote work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure for success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedule your day: when it&amp;rsquo;s work-related time and when not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set boundaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Elizabeth Grace Saunders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, hbr, harvard-business-review, elizabeth-saunders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b2ddd326-7a20-11e8-9af5-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:42:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cognitive-biases-in-programming-https-hackernoon-com-cognitive-biases-in-programming-5e937707c27b&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/cognitive-biases-in-programming-5e937707c27b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cognitive Biases in Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains some cognitive biases (prejudices of our mind) while programming:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperbolic Discounting: Going for an immediate payoff instead of a delayed larger one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IKEA Effect:Overvaluing your own solutions to a problem, and thus in contrast undervalue other solutions. Also called the &amp;ldquo;Not-Invented-Here (NIH) Syndrome&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premature Optimization: Optimizing before you know that you need to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning Fallacy: Optimistically underestimating the time required to complete a task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recency Bias: Placing higher value on recent events than ones that occurred further in the past&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can never completely eliminate our biases, by being aware of how it is affecting us, we can somewhat mitigate the problems it causes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Yash Ranadive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: yash-ranadive, bias, programming, mind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c8742b18-7a20-11e8-b36f-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:43:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keybase-launches-encrypted-git-https-keybase-io-blog-encrypted-git-for-everyone&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/blog/encrypted-git-for-everyone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keybase launches encrypted git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read how to encrypt git repositories using keybase&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: keybase, git, encryption, security, private-key, public-key, storage, archive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dcd43756-7a20-11e8-b0ee-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:43:39 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-and-surprising-http-paulgraham-com-sun-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/sun.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;General and Surprising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how information can be classified as general vs specific and surprising vs unsurprising. How it&amp;rsquo;s best to find a small surprising general thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: paul-graham, surprising, general, information, classification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f611b626-7a20-11e8-8172-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:44:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-built-a-server-less-telegram-bot-over-a-weekend-and-here-s-what-i-learned-https-medium-com-moses-soh-how-to-build-a-server-less-telegram-bot-227f842f4706&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@moses.soh/how-to-build-a-server-less-telegram-bot-227f842f4706&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I built a server-less Telegram bot over a weekend and here’s what I learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on creating a telegram chatbot for a specific purpose. Connects two people (first one subscribes, then the other asks for help and the first is contacted) so the first helps the second. By Moses Soh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: telegram, chatbot, app, moses-soh, side-project, pet-project, project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 25b1e5d6-7a21-11e8-a838-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:45:41 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reviewing-ethereum-smart-contracts-https-blog-gdssecurity-com-labs-2017-9-27-reviewing-ethereum-smart-contracts-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.gdssecurity.com/labs/2017/9/27/reviewing-ethereum-smart-contracts.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reviewing Ethereum Smart Contracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how to review ethereum contracts and a concrete example of an attack to a smart contract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ethereum, smart-contract, crypto-currency, ico, trustless, security, code-review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5d73322c-7a21-11e8-8e1a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:47:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keep-calm-and-carry-on-scaling-your-org-with-microservices-https-bridgetkromhout-com-speaking-2017-srecon&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bridgetkromhout.com/speaking/2017/srecon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keep Calm and Carry On - Scaling Your Org with Microservices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the slides of this presentation by Bridget Kromhout and Charity Majors about organizations and microservices: the main problem is the communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: charity-majors, bridget-kromhout, microservice, organization, communication, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea81381c-7a21-11e8-b418-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:51:12 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;guía-al-movimiento-noestimates-https-jeronimopalacios-com-2016-09-guia-al-movimiento-noestimates&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jeronimopalacios.com/2016/09/guia-al-movimiento-noestimates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guía al movimiento #NoEstimates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jeronimo Palacios, giving an overview of the no estimates movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: no-estimates, jeronimo-palacios, agile, scrum, estimate, forecast, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f6c70a98-7a21-11e8-a896-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:51:32 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-competence-http-www-economist-com-node-12231124&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/node/12231124&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Core competence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article describing what a core competence is and how can we find out if a competence is considered core or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: economy, definition, core-competence, core-business, management, prahalad, gary-hamel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 01a58660-7a22-11e8-b4f8-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:51:50 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-stopped-procrastinating-learned-to-code-and-launched-my-first-product-https-dev-to-lynnetye-how-i-stopped-procrastinating-learned-to-code-and-launched-my-first-product-2i1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/lynnetye/how-i-stopped-procrastinating-learned-to-code-and-launched-my-first-product-2i1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How I stopped procrastinating, learned to code, and launched my first product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining some tips and tricks to launch a side project. By Lynne Tye&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lynne-tye, tips-and-tricks, product, side-project, launch, business, lean, startup, product-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0e85e3f2-7a22-11e8-b818-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:12 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-are-citi-bikes-faster-than-taxis-in-new-york-city-http-toddwschneider-com-posts-taxi-vs-citi-bike-nyc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://toddwschneider.com/posts/taxi-vs-citi-bike-nyc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;When are Citi Bikes Faster than Taxis in New York City?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Todd Schneider analysing how city bikes compare to taxis in New York city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good analysis, using a Monte Carlo simulation, written in R. Good data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: todd-schneider, data-visualization, map, city-bike, taxi, cab, new-york, new-york-city, comparison, data, data-analytics, monte-carlo, simulation, r&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 18bc20c0-7a22-11e8-9209-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-9-and-intellij-idea-https-blog-jetbrains-com-idea-2017-09-java-9-and-intellij-idea&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/idea/2017/09/java-9-and-intellij-idea/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Java 9 and IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Trisha Gee about upcoming features to IntelliJ Idea 2017.3, centered around java 9 features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: trisha-gee, java-9, jdk-9, java, jdk, intellij-idea, ide, ide-support, jetbrains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 23b8350e-7a22-11e8-a9f3-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:52:48 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-from-your-attackers-ssh-honeypot-https-www-robertputt-co-uk-learn-from-your-attackers-ssh-honeypot-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robertputt.co.uk/learn-from-your-attackers-ssh-honeypot.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learn from your attackers - SSH HoneyPot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to setup a honey pot machine using honssh. By Robert Putt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-putt, honey-pot, security, honeypot, honssh, attacker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 2e36336e-7a22-11e8-9424-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:53:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-type-or-not-to-type-quantifying-detectable-bugs-in-javascript-https-blog-acolyer-org-2017-09-19-to-type-or-not-to-type-quantifying-detectable-bugs-in-javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.acolyer.org/2017/09/19/to-type-or-not-to-type-quantifying-detectable-bugs-in-javascript/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;To type or not to type: quantifying detectable bugs in JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this paper commentary by Adrian Colyer (on a paper by Zheng Gao, Christian Bird, Earl T. Barr) on a study that tries to reproduce fixes for defects based on the dynamic to static typing system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;both Flow and TypeScript are pretty good, and conservatively either of them can prevent about 15% of the bugs that end up in committed code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see these effects quantified:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running the binomial test on the results shows that, at the confidence level of 95%, the true percentage of detectable bugs for Flow and TypeScript falls into [11.5%, 18.5%] with mean 15%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, some recommendations for the future: for typescript and flow to be compatible for more gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original paper: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ttendency.cs.ucl.ac.uk/projects/type_study/documents/type_study.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ttendency.cs.ucl.ac.uk/projects/type_study/documents/type_study.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zheng-gao, christian-bird, earl-barr, typescript, javascript, flow, bug, defect, type-system, dynamic-typing, static-typing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 398cc606-7a22-11e8-b33c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:53:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-artificial-intelligence-can-be-used-for-password-guessing-https-medium-com-heyfebin-how-artificial-intelligence-can-be-used-for-password-guessing-cf4fd4184a46&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@heyfebin/how-artificial-intelligence-can-be-used-for-password-guessing-cf4fd4184a46&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How Artificial Intelligence Can Be Used For Password Guessing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Febin John James on how neural networks can learn from the leaked passwords and try to guess passwords for existing users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: febin-james, ai, artificial-intelligence, generative-adversarial-neural-network, gann, gan, nn, neural-network, guessing, password&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 44fe19ae-7a22-11e8-8e06-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:53:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chrome-to-force-dev-domains-to-https-via-preloaded-hsts-https-ma-ttias-be-chrome-force-dev-domains-https-via-preloaded-hsts&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ma.ttias.be/chrome-force-dev-domains-https-via-preloaded-hsts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chrome to force .dev domains to HTTPS via preloaded HSTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Mattias Geniar explaining the having the new Chrome redirecting .dev domains to https means that people using said .dev for local development will have to either provide a https server on their machines or change to another domain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mattias-geniar, chrome, http, https, server, development, test, machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 509c472c-7a22-11e8-81d7-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:54:03 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;six-ways-to-functional-fizzbuzz-with-vavr-https-www-sitepoint-com-functional-fizzbuzz-with-vavr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/functional-fizzbuzz-with-vavr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Six Ways to Functional FizzBuzz with Vavr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Gregor Trefs about solving the fizzbuzz kata using vavr, importing some concepts from functional programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: functional-programming, gregor-trefs, vavr, case-statement, pattern-matching, functional, kata, fizzbuzz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 6866497a-7a22-11e8-af91-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:54:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-women-take-on-role-of-cfo-at-home-https-paidpost-nytimes-com-northern-trust-more-women-take-on-role-of-cfo-at-home-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paidpost.nytimes.com/northern-trust/more-women-take-on-role-of-cfo-at-home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More Women Take on Role of CFO — at Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how women act as CFO of their houses (managing 30% of the world&amp;rsquo;s wealth), how they teach money and meaning to their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: money-management, cfo, women, gender, home, house&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 74f60720-7a22-11e8-a9a3-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:55:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-internet-of-things-is-sending-us-back-to-the-middle-ages-https-thenextweb-com-lifestyle-2017-09-13-internet-things-sending-us-back-middle-ages&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thenextweb.com/lifestyle/2017/09/13/internet-things-sending-us-back-middle-ages/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Internet of Things is sending us back to the Middle Ages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by JOSHUA A.T. FAIRFIELD on the right-to-own, right-to-repair and property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the difference in the real property of a smartphone vs a car. On the imaginary, they are the same, but in contractual terms, there is a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joshua-fairfield, right-to-repair, bill, law, property, smartphone, eula, license, clause, imaginary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 80c233ee-7a22-11e8-8743-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:55:24 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-in-depth-guide-to-personal-cybersecurity-https-medium-com-nickrosener-an-in-depth-guide-to-personal-cybersecurity-be98ba47c968&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@nickrosener/an-in-depth-guide-to-personal-cybersecurity-be98ba47c968&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;An In-Depth Guide to Personal Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this guide to personal security in the net, by Nick Rosener. Examples include 2fa, password management, app security, phone security, etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nick-rosener, 2fa, mfa, password, security, phone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 92c637d4-7a22-11e8-baba-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:55:54 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;como-generar-fake-data-en-nuestros-tests-de-aceptación-http-programmeratwork-com-2017-09-06-como-generar-fake-data-en-nuestros-tests-de-aceptacion&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://programmeratwork.com/2017/09/06/Como-generar-fake-data-en-nuestros-tests-de-aceptacion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Como generar &amp;ldquo;fake data&amp;rdquo; en nuestros tests de aceptación&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article (in Spanish) by Ricardo Borillo on using and generating fake data for our tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ricardo-borillo, borillo, fake-data, npm, npm-module, acceptance-testing, test, test-data, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a0be3cd8-7a22-11e8-a5aa-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:56:17 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-crash-bandicoot-gool-part-9-http-all-things-andy-gavin-com-2011-03-12-making-crash-bandicoot-gool-part-9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://all-things-andy-gavin.com/2011/03/12/making-crash-bandicoot-gool-part-9/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Making Crash Bandicoot – GOOL – part 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Andy Gavin on making a lisp for games, an embedded language inside another language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOOL prefers the power and maintainability of a lisp rather than the raw power of a lower-level programming language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: andy-gavin, lisp, gool, crash-bandicoot, game, game-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 46ffc936-7a23-11e8-882f-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:00:56 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-symbolics-lisp-machines-rebuttal-to-stallman-s-story-about-the-formation-of-symbolics-and-lmi-https-danluu-com-symbolics-lisp-machines&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://danluu.com/symbolics-lisp-machines/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;History of Symbolics lisp machines - Rebuttal to Stallman’s Story About The Formation of Symbolics and LMI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan Weinreb on the history of lisp machines, the AI winter and the rebuttal of some stories by Richard M. Stallman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-weinreb, lisp, symbolics, rms, richard-stallman, lisp-machine, lmi, dan-luu, ai-winter, ai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5174beda-7a23-11e8-bf1e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:01:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-for-dev-https-github-com-ripienaar-free-for-dev-blob-master-readme-md&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ripienaar/free-for-dev/blob/master/README.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;free-for-dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of (free) resources for programmers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: free-resource, resource, service, amazon, aws, free-tier, free-trial, github&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5bd0ece6-7a23-11e8-8014-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:01:31 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-programmer-should-know-https-github-com-mr-mig-every-programmer-should-know&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mr-mig/every-programmer-should-know&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Every Programmer Should Know&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this page on things a programmer should know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: github, programmer, knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 67c8032c-7a23-11e8-9ab7-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:01:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;haste-makes-waste-when-you-over-staff-to-achieve-schedule-compression-http-www-qsm-com-risk-02-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qsm.com/risk_02.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Haste Makes Waste When You Over-Staff to Achieve Schedule Compression&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Quantitative Software Management (QSM) on how software projects are affected by the size of the team producing it, with charts and based on previous investigation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: research, meta-research, quality, software, software-quality, qsm, quantitative-software-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 72b999a8-7a23-11e8-b831-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:02:10 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacking-back-considered-harmful-https-blog-0day-rocks-hacking-back-considered-harmful-1ea38f882e8f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.0day.rocks/hacking-back-considered-harmful-1ea38f882e8f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hacking back considered harmful?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by x0rz, a security researcher, on hacking back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;active countermeasure that result in limiting the attacker capabilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whether it is ethical to do it, even if it were illegal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethics is knowing the difference between what you have a right to do and what is right to do. — Potter Stewart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: x0rz, security, hacking, hacking-back, ethic, legality, law, quote, potter-stewart, countermeasure, attacker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7d3d216a-7a23-11e8-8d31-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:02:27 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kurt-gödel-separating-truth-from-proof-in-mathematics-http-science-sciencemag-org-content-sci-298-5600-1899-full-pdf-sid-c031062c-8030-4e2c-8716-04409d7abefb&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/sci/298/5600/1899.full.pdf?sid=c031062c-8030-4e2c-8716-04409d7abefb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kurt Gödel—Separating Truth from Proof in Mathematics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Keith Devlin on Goedel&amp;rsquo;s work, especially on the Incompleteness theorem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kurt-godel, kurt-goedel, incompleteness-theorem, bertrand-russell, alfred-north, principia-mathematica, david-hilbert, mathematics, theorem, computability, philosophy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 8bda1c3c-7a23-11e8-b1cb-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:02:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ml-for-the-working-programmer-2nd-edition-chapter-5-https-www-cl-cam-ac-uk-lp15-mlbook-pdf-chapter5-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/~lp15/MLbook/PDF/chapter5.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ML for the working programmer, 2nd edition - chapter 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this chapter, to better understand finite and infinite data structures. Talks about streams (called sequences in ML), HOFs, lambda calculus. The book is by Lawrence Paulson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my examples are in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/haskell-simple-sessions/blob/master/trees/src/Trees.hs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/haskell-simple-sessions/blob/master/trees/src/Trees.hs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/javascript-simple-sessions/tree/master/streams&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/alvarogarcia7/javascript-simple-sessions/tree/master/streams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: book, chapter, lawrence-paulson, ml, sequence, hof, lambda-calculus, combinator, stream, lazy-list, data-structure, infinite-list, higher-order-function, function-composition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 97e67a7a-7a23-11e8-bc72-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:03:12 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-hack-the-uk-tax-system-i-guess-https-medium-com-zemnmez-how-to-hack-the-uk-tax-system-i-guess-3e84b70f8b&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Zemnmez/how-to-hack-the-uk-tax-system-i-guess-3e84b70f8b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;how to hack the uk tax system, i guess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this investigation of how a security investigator found a security defect in the UK tax system page and the process of reporting it and seeing it fixed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zemnmez, open-source, uk, hmrc, responsible-disclosure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a4263c08-7a23-11e8-86c0-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:03:33 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;indirect-sale-value-models-http-www-catb-org-esr-writings-magic-cauldron-magic-cauldron-9-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catb.org/esr/writings/magic-cauldron/magic-cauldron-9.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Indirect Sale-Value Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on models for selling/monetising open source. By Eric S. Raymond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-raymond, open-source, monetization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b0788d3a-7a23-11e8-82df-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:03:53 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ll-never-bring-my-phone-on-an-international-flight-again-neither-should-you-https-medium-freecodecamp-org-ill-never-bring-my-phone-on-an-international-flight-again-neither-should-you-e9289cde0e5f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/ill-never-bring-my-phone-on-an-international-flight-again-neither-should-you-e9289cde0e5f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I’ll never bring my phone on an international flight again. Neither should you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Quincy Larson on what happens when you bring your phone over to the US&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: us, phone, privacy, quincy-larson, international-flight, cross-border-flight, flight, device, laptop, burner-phone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: bc93aaf0-7a23-11e8-8ffe-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:04:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remote-starter-kit-http-www-remotestarterkit-com&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.remotestarterkit.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Remote Starter Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this page detailing some tools for a remote position&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, remote-tool, tool, starter-kit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: cfe1bdfe-7a23-11e8-b024-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:04:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-java-forward-faster-https-mreinhold-org-blog-forward-faster&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mreinhold.org/blog/forward-faster&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Moving Java Forward Faster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Mark Reinhold, explaining his proposal for a faster java release train, changing from every two years to every six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: release, mark-reinhold, release-management, release-train, java, sun, oracle, brian-goetz, jre, jdk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dc842498-7a23-11e8-8b35-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:05:07 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;keeping-a-tidy-life-https-medium-com-ctrlaltjustine-keeping-a-tidy-life-f01bbe2a9b3e&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ctrlaltjustine/keeping-a-tidy-life-f01bbe2a9b3e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keeping a tidy life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Justine Arreche on how she manages her productivity tools: calendar, todo list; for all the activities in her life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: justine-arreche, productivity, management, calendar, todo-list, activity, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e799c860-7a23-11e8-9f75-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:05:26 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-understand-rising-inequality-consider-the-janitors-at-two-top-companies-then-and-now-https-www-nytimes-com-2017-09-03-upshot-to-understand-rising-inequality-consider-the-janitors-at-two-top-companies-then-and-now-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/03/upshot/to-understand-rising-inequality-consider-the-janitors-at-two-top-companies-then-and-now.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;To Understand Rising Inequality, Consider the Janitors at Two Top Companies, Then and Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Neil Irwin on inequality, explaining the professional career of two janitors at two different companies, in a different period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: neil-irwin, inequality, kodak, apple, janitor, mercer, drucker, management, career-management, career, cto, cio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f66efafe-7a23-11e8-ae3d-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:05:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;episode-8-interview-with-ryan-dahl-creator-of-node-js-https-www-mappingthejourney-com-single-post-2017-08-31-episode-8-interview-with-ryan-dahl-creator-of-nodejs&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mappingthejourney.com/single-post/2017/08/31/Episode-8-Interview-with-Ryan-Dahl-Creator-of-Nodejs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Episode 8: Interview with Ryan Dahl, Creator of Node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read [the transcription of] this interview, to Ryan Dahl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, he describes his view of Node.js and how it is not well-suited for building massive web servers, but could be appropriate for web applications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ryan-dahl, go, microservice, web-app, interview, podcast, web-server, go, golang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 03cbbfca-7a24-11e8-927a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:06:13 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-recovering-programmer-http-prog21-dadgum-com-56-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://prog21.dadgum.com/56.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Recovering Programmer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Hague on the user-centric vision and how he faces the problems related to programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: programming, user-centric, vision, game, assembler, james-hague, recovering-programmer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0db84e2c-7a24-11e8-ac3c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:06:30 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-who-value-simplicity-have-built-incomprehensible-machines-http-prog21-dadgum-com-139-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://prog21.dadgum.com/139.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;We Who Value Simplicity Have Built Incomprehensible Machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by  James Hague on examples of libraries that went wrong. How we should have said &amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo; early on instead of accepting it. A blog post about simplicity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: james-hague, simplicity, library, complexity, example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 192eae72-7a24-11e8-bc6c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:06:49 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rapid-release-at-massive-scale-https-code-facebook-com-posts-270314900139291-rapid-release-at-massive-scale&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.facebook.com/posts/270314900139291/rapid-release-at-massive-scale/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rapid release at massive scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 24c02266-7a24-11e8-bddd-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:07:08 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;having-a-work-wife-or-work-husband-is-good-for-your-career-https-www-linkedin-com-pulse-having-work-wife-husband-good-your-career-rebecca-holman&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/having-work-wife-husband-good-your-career-rebecca-holman&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Having a &amp;ldquo;work wife&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;work husband&amp;rdquo; is good for your career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rebecca Holman explaining what is a work spouse (i.e., a trusted equal to bounce off ideas, discuss, advance together). Not a mentor, not a trusted boss, not someone reporting to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some of the benefits of finding that role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rebecca-holman, work-wife, work-husband, work-spouse, team-management, work, job, pairing, mentor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3136db02-7a24-11e8-b84e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:07:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rest-apis-are-rest-in-peace-apis-long-live-graphql-https-medium-freecodecamp-org-rest-apis-are-rest-in-peace-apis-long-live-graphql-d412e559d8e4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/rest-apis-are-rest-in-peace-apis-long-live-graphql-d412e559d8e4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;REST APIs are REST-in-Peace APIs. Long Live GraphQL.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about GraphQL and its comparison to REST APIs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: graphql, rest, api, data, comparison, samer-buna&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3df70628-7a24-11e8-9c3c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:07:51 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-lisp-http-www-formal-stanford-edu-jmc-history-lisp-lisp-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-formal.stanford.edu/jmc/history/lisp/lisp.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;History of Lisp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this paper by John McCarthy explaining the history of lisp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-mccarthy, lisp, invention, language, list-processing, s-expression, m-expression, data, code, lisp-dialect, fortran, ibm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 492eebb4-7a24-11e8-bcec-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:08:10 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-development-450-words-per-minute-https-www-vincit-fi-en-blog-software-development-450-words-per-minute&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vincit.fi/en/blog/software-development-450-words-per-minute/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software development 450 words per minute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article in which Tuukka Ojala explains how his tools for a (blind) software developer: the screen reader, the browser, the braille reader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tuukka-ojala, blindness, accesibility, browser, screen-reader, braille-reader, braille, disability&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 54e4e076-7a24-11e8-abd6-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:08:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;compare-your-efforts-30-vs-3000-loc-for-very-simple-mean-app-http-blog-allcountjs-com-post-128771961651-compare-efforts&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.allcountjs.com/post/128771961651/compare-efforts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Compare your efforts: 30 vs 3000 LOC for very simple MEAN app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains the difference between business value and technical value: a feature for the business could be very valuable but technically costly; also the other way around: they are independent variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains that some value in development can be obtained quicker by using a framework, such as the tool that allcountjs provides: 30 lines to generate the equivalent business features to 3000 lines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: allcountjs, mean, comparison, crud, framework, javascript, frontend, productivity, business-value, technical-value, cost&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5eea69ce-7a24-11e8-8842-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:08:46 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-integration-https-medium-com-leanpub-github-integration-6f6d81847230&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@leanpub/github-integration-6f6d81847230&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how to integrate leanpub with github: write your book (e.g., in markdown) and store it in git, then publish automatically to leanpub&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leanpub, github, integration, self-publishing, publishing, book, tool, toolchain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 699d067e-7a24-11e8-9962-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:09:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wysiwtf-https-alistapart-com-column-wysiwtf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alistapart.com/column/wysiwtf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;WYSIWTF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Karen McGrane explaining the desktop publishing and the difference between writing and formatting for the web. Also, inline editing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: karen-mcgrane, editing, formatting, desktop-publishing, medium, wysiwyg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 7b5f342c-7a24-11e8-b858-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:09:34 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-m-talking-about-when-i-talk-about-tdd-https-medium-com-ramtop-what-im-talking-about-when-i-talk-about-tdd-546a383468be&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ramtop/what-im-talking-about-when-i-talk-about-tdd-546a383468be&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What I’m talking about when I talk about TDD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Uberto Barbini in which he describes his re-discovery of TDD as a tool to design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uberto-barbini, tdd, rediscovery, kent-beck, test-driven-development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 866b41b2-7a24-11e8-9c54-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:09:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;se-radio-episode-273-steve-mcconnell-on-software-estimation-http-www-se-radio-net-2016-11-se-radio-episode-273-steve-mcconnell-on-software-estimation&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.se-radio.net/2016/11/se-radio-episode-273-steve-mcconnell-on-software-estimation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SE-Radio Episode 273: Steve McConnell on Software Estimation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sven Johann interviews Steve McConnell about software estimation and planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks about intrinsic risk management and extrinsic risk management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains that you should manage the risk so the most uncertain is tackled in the beginning. At the retro (following the demo), you get risk identification (as root cause analysis based on not delivering as expected)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Agile was not to be able to change all the time, but to adapt to change&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embrace change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cone-of-uncertainty, agile, project-management, risk, sven-johann, steve-mcconnell, iteration, scrum, risk-identification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9c543506-7a24-11e8-8c9b-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:10:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-psychology-with-bjorn-freeman-benson-https-softwareengineeringdaily-com-2017-03-28-software-psychology-with-bjorn-freeman-benson&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/03/28/software-psychology-with-bjorn-freeman-benson/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software Psychology with Bjorn Freeman Benson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this podcast on psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: software-engineering-daily, bjorn-benson, psychology, walled-garden&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: a90cf1ac-7a24-11e8-a69e-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:10:50 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-cqrs-to-make-controllers-lean-with-derek-comartin-https-softwareengineeringdaily-com-2017-03-10-using-cqrs-to-make-controllers-lean-with-derek-comartin&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwareengineeringdaily.com/2017/03/10/using-cqrs-to-make-controllers-lean-with-derek-comartin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using CQRS to Make Controllers Lean with Derek Comartin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to this podcast on CQRS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cqrs, derek-comartin, command-query-responsibility-segregation, greg-young, udi-dahan, red-book, ddd, domain-driven-design, podcast, software-engineering-daily&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b2056db6-7a24-11e8-97d3-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:05 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;elm-in-production-25-000-lines-later-https-functional-works-hub-com-blog-elm-in-production-25-000-lines-later&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://functional.works-hub.com/blog/Elm-In-Production-25-000-Lines-Later&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elm In Production: 25,000 Lines Later&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Christian Charukiewicz explaining how he started a new project and a new feature in Elm. How he explained this new technology to his teammates and how it is going now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the pros and cons for the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christian-charukiewicz, elm, compiler, experience-report, frontend, functional-language, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: bc6e1190-7a24-11e8-b19a-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:23 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-up-with-alexa-https-www-technologyreview-com-s-608430-growing-up-with-alexa&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/608430/growing-up-with-alexa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Growing Up with Alexa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c2416c52-7a24-11e8-b692-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:33 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jony-s-patience-https-medium-com-mkruz-jony-s-patience-670d5a3dc128&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mkruz/jony-s-patience-670d5a3dc128&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jony’s Patience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Mike Kruzeniski explaining part of John Ive career at Apple and explaining part of the design process the Apple Watch had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ux, design, apple, watch, john-ive, mike-kruzeniski, career, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: cb789e76-7a24-11e8-bdb2-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:11:48 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-four-month-bug-jvm-statistics-cause-garbage-collection-pauses-http-www-evanjones-ca-jvm-mmap-pause-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.evanjones.ca/jvm-mmap-pause.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Four Month Bug: JVM statistics cause garbage collection pauses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this blog post by Evan Jones as an example of unknown unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: evan-jones, unknown-unknown, java, mmap, garbage-collector, pause, unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d4b6a596-7a24-11e8-b245-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:12:04 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pleasure-of-building-big-things-http-rc3-org-2015-03-24-the-pleasure-of-building-big-things&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rc3.org/2015/03/24/the-pleasure-of-building-big-things/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The pleasure of building big things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining that big projects take time to be created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temptation is all around us, to accelerate feedback loops, create products more quickly, release earlier. That has the tension of being &amp;lsquo;half-baked&amp;rsquo; products, that have not achieved the minimum level of loveable feature and, thus, not used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time, focus, rafe-colburn, product, lean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: dddee4c6-7a24-11e8-b11f-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:12:19 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;choose-boring-technology-http-mcfunley-com-choose-boring-technology&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Choose Boring Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan McKinley about how choosing boring (i.e., well-proven) technology can help you focus on your company goals and how &amp;lsquo;the best tool for the job&amp;rsquo; is not always the case, as the job depends on who you ask: developers, ops, business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-mckinley, boring, technology, proven, production-ready, development, operations, focus, business, goal, best-tool-for-the-job&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e91565cc-7a24-11e8-8849-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:12:38 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exclusive-here-s-the-full-10-page-anti-diversity-screed-circulating-internally-at-google-updated-https-gizmodo-com-exclusive-heres-the-full-10-page-anti-diversity-screed-1797564320&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gizmodo.com/exclusive-heres-the-full-10-page-anti-diversity-screed-1797564320&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Exclusive: Here&amp;rsquo;s The Full 10-Page Anti-Diversity Screed Circulating Internally at Google [Updated]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read this document&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: google, scandal, sexism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: fe723d14-7a24-11e8-ab5c-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:13:14 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;check-your-work-https-8thlight-com-blog-connor-mendenhall-2013-10-31-check-your-work-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://8thlight.com/blog/connor-mendenhall/2013/10/31/check-your-work.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check Your Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 172e94e2-7a25-11e8-86cc-0242ac110002
Read: Wed, 27 Jun 2018 16:13:55 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/05/01/self-study-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/05/01/self-study-may-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2018/04/research-shows-a-simple-way-to-increase-your-engagement-at-work&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Research Shows a Simple Way to Increase Your Engagement at Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article By Michael Parke, Justin Weinhardt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found that increasing your engagement and productivity at work could be as simple as making a plan for the day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They talk about two types of planning: time management and contingent planning. The latter is about considering possible disruptions or interruptions they may face and a plan to tackle them (if they happen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They argue that the latter is less frustrating than the former based on the non-accomplished tasks in the former. That the former is less effective when facing a high level of interruptions, as compared to the latter, equally effective no matter how many interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They suggest contingent planning for the days with high expected interruptions, time planning for the rest. But always use planning, for higher output, happiness at work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: engagement, work, productivity, michael-parke, justin-weinhardt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-may-hate-planning-but-you-should-do-it-anyway-https-hbr-org-2016-09-you-may-hate-planning-but-you-should-do-it-anyway&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2016/09/you-may-hate-planning-but-you-should-do-it-anyway&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;You May Hate Planning, But You Should Do It Anyway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Elizabeth Grace Saunders. In it, she points that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning will trigger pain — at least initially&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things tend to go better when you plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planning becomes the canary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She suggests that planning can help you become more productive, even considering the sunk cost of planning itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: elizabeth-saunders, planning, hbr, management, time-management, plan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/04/01/self-study-april-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/04/01/self-study-april-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/01/self-study-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/01/self-study-march-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/02/01/self-study-february-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/02/01/self-study-february-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contract-test-https-martinfowler-com-bliki-contracttest-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/ContractTest.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Contract test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bliki article by Martin Fowler on how to test the integration with external service providers. On how it should be integrated into the building pipeline, but maybe not fail exactly as the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bliki, martin-fowler, contract-test, microservices, pact, integration-test, pipeline, continuous-integration&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/01/01/self-study-january-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/01/01/self-study-january-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/01/self-study-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/01/self-study-december-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/self-study-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/self-study-november-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/10/01/self-study-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/10/01/self-study-october-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/01/self-study-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/01/self-study-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-the-clipboard-works-part-1-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-ntdebugging-2012-03-16-how-the-clipboard-works-part-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ntdebugging/2012/03/16/how-the-clipboard-works-part-1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How the Clipboard Works, Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Matt Burrough, on how the clipboard works on windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how the API works and how the different formats and priorities are organized so the new application can decide which format to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: windows, clipboard, matt-burrough, format, copy-paste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-developers-can-have-a-life-outside-coding-https-belenalbeza-com-top-developers-can-have-a-life-outside-coding&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://belenalbeza.com/top-developers-can-have-a-life-outside-coding/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Top developers can have a life outside coding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Belen Albeza on how top coders don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend all their time programming or with activities related to programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some techniques to make the most of the working hours and some strategies to balance your work-non-work life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: belen-albeza, coding, time-management, energy-management, improvement, opinion, work-life-balance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-phone-is-your-most-vulnerable-gadget-protect-it-now-https-www-wired-com-story-your-phone-is-your-most-vulnerable-gadget-protect-it-now&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/your-phone-is-your-most-vulnerable-gadget-protect-it-now/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Your phone is your most vulnerable gadget. protect it now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Pierce on how the phone device is vulnerable and what options we have available to make it a secure computing device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either switch to a branded-as-secure phone or stick to the main options (Android, iPhone) plus activate some options (updates to the apps and operating system), stay away from public hotspots, don&amp;rsquo;t lend it to strangers and use some apps to monitor what resources apps are using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-pierce, security, phone, mobile-device, hotspot, iphone, android, ios&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-in-switzerland-ruined-me-for-america-and-its-lousy-work-culture-https-getpocket-com-explore-item-living-in-switzerland-ruined-me-for-america-and-its-lousy-work-culture-987981365&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/explore/item/living-in-switzerland-ruined-me-for-america-and-its-lousy-work-culture-987981365&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Living in Switzerland ruined me for America and its lousy work culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Chantal Panozzo comparing the way of living and the economic standards in Switzerland and the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mainly about the topics of the social security network, provided by the state, taxes and owning a car&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chantal-panozzo, comparison, way-of-living, living-standard, car, social-security, usa, us, switzerland, economy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-10-10-10-rule-for-tough-decisions-https-getpocket-com-explore-item-the-10-10-10-rule-for-tough-decisions-327321877&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-10-10-10-rule-for-tough-decisions-327321877&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The 10/10/10 Rule For Tough Decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Chip Heath on a technique to make hard decisions: the 10/10/10 rule; How would you feel 10 minutes, 10 months and 10 years after having applied the actions from that decisions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: decision, decision-making, rule, ten-ten-ten-rule, chip-heath&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-retire-in-your-30s-save-most-of-your-money-and-rethink-your-core-values-https-getpocket-com-explore-item-how-to-retire-in-your-30s-save-most-of-your-money-and-rethink-your-core-values-912524855&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/explore/item/how-to-retire-in-your-30s-save-most-of-your-money-and-rethink-your-core-values-912524855&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to retire in your 30s: save most of your money and rethink your core values&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Danielle Kurtzleben on how to retire early or achieve financial independence early in your career: save a big percentage of your salary, invest wisely and reduce costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: danielle-kurtzleben, investment, frugality, early-retirement, retirement, financial-independence, independence, finance, value, core-value&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>