<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/lessons-learned/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/lessons-learned/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Make, Buy or Rent decision: Stateful vs Stateless components</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/on-the-make-buy-or-rent-decision-stateful-vs-stateless-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 07:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/16/on-the-make-buy-or-rent-decision-stateful-vs-stateless-components/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;From the [Make, Buy or Rent][] article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] [T]he three main system options for organizations seeking to upgrade their systems and the pros and cons of each&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT managers have different criteria for deciding which components to assign in each category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-criteria-for-deciding&#34;&gt;Another criteria for deciding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a client, they have taken the decision to split their core IT systems in to the three options: make, buy, rent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The business logic to handle the core business is &amp;lsquo;make&amp;rsquo;. These systems are completely stateless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The persistance (or storage) for the core business is &amp;lsquo;rent&amp;rsquo;. These systems, by definition, are stateful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other parts of the system are &amp;lsquo;buy&amp;rsquo;. Not important for this article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key concept for this separation is moving the responsibility for uptime and complex data management to a provider. They can take better care of those procedures and use economies of scale to provide high availability, reliability and SLAs. This idea simplifies our components (e.g., services), making them stateless. Even if they cache any internal information, it is a &amp;lsquo;Read Through Cache&amp;rsquo;, meaning that in case the data is not available in the cache, the service will transparently fetch it from the underlying storage system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea for separating components simplifies both development, testing and maintainance, therefore reducing the Total Cost of Ownership (TCO) of our services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/10/01/self-study-in-october-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-engineers-design&#34;&gt;Should Engineers Design?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.capwatkins.com/should-engineers-design&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cap Watkins where he explains the relationship between designers and programmers and how to get the latter involved in the design / UX / UI process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cap-watkins, design, ux, ui, exchange, cross-functional&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sliding-scale-of-giving-a-fuck&#34;&gt;The Sliding Scale of Giving a Fuck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.capwatkins.com/the-sliding-scale-of-giving-a-fuck&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cap Watkins where he explains that different topics have a different importance to each one of us: this topic might be very important for someone else, ergo, it makes mores sense to evaluate their option more carefully. When your importance level is not so high, you can take the other option easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: cap-watkins, sliding-scale, decision-making, discussion, argument, convincing, people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuevos-retos&#34;&gt;Nuevos retos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modestosanjuan.com/nuevos-retos/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Modesto San Juan about him leaving Codesai and joining a new adventure. In Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career-change, modesto-san-juan, codesai, carlos-ble, .net&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;muchas-gracias-modesto&#34;&gt;Muchas gracias Modesto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codesai.com/2016/10/muchas-gracias-modesto/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, by Carlos Blé and the rest of the Codesai team, saying goodbye to Modesto San Juan, commenting on their experiences working with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career-change, modesto-san-juan, codesai, carlos-ble, .net&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-ticket-magpie&#34;&gt;Introducing…Ticket Magpie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thetestdoctor.wordpress.com/2016/10/11/introducing-ticket-magpie/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Billing about the a honeypot application he has to teach about security and attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-hatanian, dan-billing, ticket-magpie, honeypot, security, attack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;destructuring-assignment&#34;&gt;Destructuring assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Operators/Destructuring_assignment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;destructuring assignment page&lt;/a&gt; at MDN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javascript, destructuring, mdn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-lessons-i-learned-from-doing-my-first-real-startup&#34;&gt;10 Lessons I Learned from Doing My First Real Startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://degoes.net/articles/precog-lessons-learned&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, a post-mortem analysis of his company, precog, with 10 items that he learned from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-de-goes, precog, post-mortem, startup, lessons-learned&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-being-nice-and-just-tell-the-fucking-truth-already&#34;&gt;Stop Being &amp;ldquo;Nice&amp;rdquo; and Just Tell the Fucking Truth Already&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://degoes.net/articles/be-nice-not-nice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about giving honest feedback vs being a nice guy. The author concludes that the former is, in fact, the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: feedback, honesty, comparison, john-de-goes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;haskell-s-type-classes-we-can-do-better&#34;&gt;Haskell&amp;rsquo;s Type Classes: We Can Do Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://degoes.net/articles/principled-typeclasses&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the abuse of newtype classes in haskell to overcome some language limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article has helped me understand better inheritance, in the sections orphans and laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also suggests that the compiler could check at compile time that the children impose more restrictive (more specific) laws than the parent, given that any children must comply with the inherited rules (liskov substitution principle)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: inheritance, liskov, lsp, solid, john-de-goes, functional-programming, haskell, type-classes,  newtype-clases, monoid, law&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-the-three-amigos&#34;&gt;Introducing the Three Amigos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrumalliance.org/community/articles/2013/2013-april/introducing-the-three-amigos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Thomas Hewitt about the Three Amigos meeting, to better define a feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ryan-hewitt, three-amigos, agile, meeting, process, scrum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-mac-is-for&#34;&gt;Apple just told the world it has no idea who the Mac is for&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/charged-tech/apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-mac-is-for-722a2438389b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Owen Williams on the latest presentation by Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: owen-williams, mac, apple, strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sigil&#34;&gt;Sigil&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this page for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sigil_(computer_programming)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sigil&lt;/a&gt;, or the symbol attached to the variable. An example is the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; in Perl or the earmuffs in Clojure (&lt;code&gt;*out*&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sigil, wikipedia, example, computer-science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;list-of-languages-that-compile-to-js&#34;&gt;List of languages that compile to JS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jashkenas/coffeescript/wiki/List-of-languages-that-compile-to-JS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of programming languages that compile to JS. By Jeremy Ashkenas and the community&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jeremy-ashkenas, compilation, compiled-language, compiled-to-javascript, compiled-javascript, javascript&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-accountable-for-delivering-value&#34;&gt;Being accountable for delivering value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://niksilver.com/2017/01/17/accountable-for-value/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nik Silver on how the team should be accountable for delivering value, not accountable for delivering artifacts that produce value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: agile, management, nik-silver, accountability, team, value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-partial-value-from-partial-delivery&#34;&gt;Getting partial value from partial delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://niksilver.com/2015/10/20/partial-value-from-partial-delivery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nik Silver on how it is possible to be agile in an environment where the business is not agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, introduces the concept of &amp;lsquo;partial delivery&amp;rsquo;, meaning incomplete delivery from development to business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: delivery, partial-delivery, management, value, partial-value, change, walkawayability, change, nik-silver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hierarchy-of-opinion&#34;&gt;Hierarchy of opinion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://codurance.com/2017/01/16/hierarchy-of-opinion/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mashooq Badar on what are opinions, how important they are and how them impact others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mashooq-badar, opinion, critical-thinking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/08/01/self-study-in-august-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-in-agile-six-months-at-pivotal&#34;&gt;Lessons in Agile: Six Months at Pivotal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/built-to-adapt/lessons-in-agile-six-months-at-pivotal-66b4c57386a4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Maryam Labib where she explains what she has learned in the last 6 months at Pivotal: how to pair program, how to TDD and some good practices to be a better developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: maryam-labib, pivotal, career, professional-career, tdd, pair-programming, team, lessons-learned, experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacking-verbal-communication-systems&#34;&gt;Hacking verbal communication systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/album/4045988/video/173255458&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Alexander on what kind of systems humans use to communicate and how to improve them. Explains the hand signals at Occupy movement (called (Occupy movement hand signals)[&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals]&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_movement_hand_signals]&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: conference, ryan-alexander, lead-dev, conf, hand-signals, occupy-movement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ni-titulitis-ni-cuñadismo-spanish&#34;&gt;Ni titulitis, ni cuñadismo (Spanish)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.koalite.com/2016/06/ni-titulitis-ni-cunadismo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the regulation or no regulation of the programmer trade, by Juan María Hernández&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: regulation, opinion, title, degree, university, juan-hernandez, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-semicolons-necessary-in-javascript&#34;&gt;Are Semicolons Necessary in JavaScript?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gsfbh17Ax9I&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Kyle Robinson Young on whether semicolons are necessary in javascript and why he purposely does not use them, to teach people how to do it. Suggests going for a month with the opposite way (write / don&amp;rsquo;t write) to see how it feels and take an informed decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javascript, semicolon, style, syntax, kyle-young&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;race-conditions-on-the-web&#34;&gt;Race conditions on the web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.josipfranjkovic.com/blog/race-conditions-on-web&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Josip Franjković on the race conditions that can happen using REST APIs, related to eventual consistency matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eventual-consistency, josip-franjkovic, race-condition, rest-api, rest, web&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nist-declares-the-age-of-sms-based-2-factor-authentication-over&#34;&gt;NIST declares the age of SMS-based 2-factor authentication over&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2016/07/25/nist-declares-the-age-of-sms-based-2-factor-authentication-over/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Devin Coldewey, where he explains that the US NIST has published a draft that suggests using SMS for two-factor authentication in a different way: check that they are real phones and not VoIP to reduce the tampering with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  devin-coldewey, 2fa, sms, nist, us-nist, security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-interviews-with-amazon&#34;&gt;My Interviews with Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesocietea.org/2016/07/my-interviews-with-amazon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Aaron Krauss, where he explains his experience interviewing with Amazon at Seattle. Explains the whole process and insights from some phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: aaron-krauss, amazon, interview-process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devops-students-learn-the-value-of-uptime-with-3-a-m-calls&#34;&gt;DevOps Students Learn the Value of Uptime With 3 a.m. Calls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linux.com/news/devops-students-learn-value-uptime-3-am-calls&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the practices related to &amp;ldquo;on call&amp;rdquo; at Holberton School and their students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sylvain-kalache, holberton-school, on-call, full-stack-developer, devops, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;constant-confusion-why-i-still-use-javascript-function-statements&#34;&gt;Constant confusion: why I still use JavaScript function statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/constant-confusion-why-i-still-use-javascript-function-statements-984ece0b72fd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains the comparison of declaring functions in javascript (ES2015 and above), with the short notation for a function. By Bill Sourour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the temporal dead zone (TDZ):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] JavaScript binds the declaration of “sayHelloTo” — reads it first, puts it at the top, and creates a space in memory to hold its value — but it doesn’t set “sayHelloTo” to anything until it reaches it during execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time between “sayHelloTo” being bound and “sayHelloTo” being initialized is called the temporal dead zone (TDZ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tdz, temporal-dead-zone, bill-sourour, javascript, es2015, function, const, var, binding, lifecycle&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>