<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog-rsses on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog-rsses on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 06:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding all pending work in progress (WIP) in your workspace</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/find-all-pending-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 06:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/07/find-all-pending-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a good practice to push your local work at the end of the day. Be it for increasing the bus factor (more people have the code), be it for reducing the lifespan of the branches (less time without integrating) or just enabling visibility (your teammates to see what has been developed). If you&amp;rsquo;re using Continuous Integration (CI) or Continuous Delivery (CD), this is even more often&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can even do it more often: for example before going to lunch, before a meeting, before a demo, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with many repositories (e.g. a microservices environment/architecture), it is often the case where you will have multiple folders with work, possibly work in progress (WIP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we have created a small tool to detect git repositories that have local changes that haven&amp;rsquo;t been pushed yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback is more than welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-ended-up-paying-150-for-a-single-60gb-download-from-amazon-glacier-https-medium-com-karppinen-how-i-ended-up-paying-150-for-a-single-60gb-download-from-amazon-glacier-6cb77b288c3e&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@karppinen/how-i-ended-up-paying-150-for-a-single-60gb-download-from-amazon-glacier-6cb77b288c3e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How I ended up paying $150 for a single 60GB download from Amazon Glacier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Marko Karppinen that explains how a mistake in understanding the pricing model of AWS Glacier cost 150$ instead of the expected 0.86$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When cloud providers use uncommon and/or unpredictable pricing models, even your informed hunch about the cost can be off by several orders of magnitude, like the price differential between an iPad and a Ferrari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to avoid this is by reading, very carefully, through the laughably long passages of meandering technical trivia that constitute the Glacier FAQ or, indeed, this Medium post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: quote, glacier, amazon, aws, amazon-web-service, marko-karppinen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Software Development: Part I</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/nature-software-development-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/nature-software-development-part-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-nature-of-software-development-reading-breadcrumbs-quotes-thoughts&#34;&gt;The Nature of Software development: reading breadcrumbs, quotes, thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Natural Way serves end users well because it delivers value to them sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;serves the business [&amp;hellip;] because it provides important information quickly, and because it provides the ability to adjust direction as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;serves management [&amp;hellip;] see what’s really going on inside the project so that when action is needed, there will be time to act. And it reduces management’s problems by making information visible [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] easier for developers. [&amp;hellip;] clear direction and allows them freedom to use their skills to build what the organization needs, when it’s needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. xv)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-i-the-circle-of-value&#34;&gt;Part I: The Circle of Value&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-search-for-value&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The search for value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value.  &amp;ldquo;what you want.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the building blocks of value or to produce value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding. We produce value by creating teams with responsibility for creating value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value in guiding is not related to creating value in itself, but to help others so they can create value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the value of guiding depends on the value of the value-producing people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing [&amp;hellip;] We organize around features, because features give us the ability to plan and build value most rapidly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning [&amp;hellip;] selecting the features we need, in the order we need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building [&amp;hellip;] product feature by feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slicing [&amp;hellip;] smallest possible value-bearing size&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality [&amp;hellip;] always has a good design and that it is as nearly defect-free as possible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-value-is-what-we-want&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: Value is What we Want&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we generally get value by delivering features. Features that have value. Features that we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;software can save time or money. Software can help us earn money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of value as simply what we want [&amp;hellip;] Each choice gives us something we value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project delivers value only when we ship the software and put it to use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most users don’t use all the features, a smaller set of features can provide real value, and provide it sooner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pieces that make sense to us, and to our users. [&amp;hellip;] minimal marketable features (MMFs)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 12)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-guiding-goes-better-feature-by-feature&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Guiding Goes Better &amp;ldquo;Feature by Feature&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a monolithic project, late in the game we can’t do much to cut costs. We have already written requirements for things we’ll never get&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 22)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We laid out this project with an all-or-nothing mentality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 22)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When our projects grow feature by feature, we can respond to what’s really happening. We can respond to the changing needs and inputs of the business and of management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 24)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-4-organizing-by-feature&#34;&gt;Chapter 4: Organizing by Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the work done, different parts require different skills. The work won’t be done [&amp;hellip;] until it has had the attention of people with each needed skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we organize teams by skill-set, each piece of work will need to be passed around among teams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 26)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;organize into small teams, each of which builds features that the Product Champions can understand. Make sure that each team has all the people and all the skills necessary to build the entire feature, not just part of it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 27)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] we can allocate work across teams easily [&amp;hellip;]  Responsibility and authority are aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 27)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the people belong to the feature teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 30)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You belong to your family; you’re a member of the golf club&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 30)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A highly paid expert shouldn’t be highly paid just because she’s an expert. She should be highly paid because she is helping other people become experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 30)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-5-planning-feature-by-feature&#34;&gt;Chapter 5: Planning Feature by Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vision is about big ideas, not tiny bites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 32)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Eisenhower said, &amp;ldquo;Plans are useless, but planning is indispensable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 33)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do need to plan. We don’t need a detailed list of what will happen and when&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 33)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] software people are terrible at estimating, because humans are terrible at estimating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 34)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;set a time and money budget; produce the most valuable features first; keep the product ready to ship at any time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 34)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not good enough to plan just at the beginning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 36)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t recommend working with larger stories and breaking them down into technical items, often called tasks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 36)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stick with stories&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 36)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] break down stories into smaller stories, each making sense to the business-side people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 36)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the team itself should decide how much work it can accomplish in the next two-week interval&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 37)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point isn’t to make good estimates—the point is to do good work at a consistent pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 37)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some serious risks to estimates: we have an almost irresistible desire to &amp;ldquo;improve&amp;rdquo; them, or to compare them. [&amp;hellip;] business and management get the best results by selecting the work to be done and the work to be deferred&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 38)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is prediction better than steering?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 38)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning with &amp;ldquo;stretch goals&amp;rdquo; is destructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurrying, they’ll inject more defects. Since defects take longer to fix than they do to prevent, hurrying will slow you down. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dirty code slows you down as well [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressure is destructive. Avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 39)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] estimates are likely to be wrong, and they focus our attention on the cost of things rather than on value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 40)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-6-building-the-product-feature-by-feature&#34;&gt;Chapter 6: Building the Product, Feature by Feature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to sharpen our vision of what the product must do—and what’s just &amp;ldquo;nice to have.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 45)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure we’re free of defects, we need to check everything, all the time [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 48)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] grow the design as we go. If we design too much, we won’t get as many features, and that will show up. If we design too little, features will be hard to do, we’ll slow down&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 49)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-7-build-features-and-foundation-in-parallel&#34;&gt;Chapter 7: Build Features and Foundation in Parallel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each feature needs a solid foundation of design, a solid &amp;ldquo;infrastructure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p.52)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to do as little work as possible to deliver the best possible product by our delivery date&amp;hellip;and we need to do that work as soundly as we can afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 53)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers are often trained to try to design a system up front&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 59)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-8-bug-free-and-well-designed&#34;&gt;Chapter 8: Bug-Free and Well Designed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our product is made up of a growing set of correctly working features, built on a growing, evolving foundation of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 61)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defects amount to negative features. Progress is uncertain. Eliminate defects to provide clarity on what’s done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re trying to plan by features, grow by features, and manage by features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot work effectively in a world of defects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 62)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of every iteration, we need to have the software as close to defect-free as possible. The only way to get there is to test it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We test at two levels, with &amp;ldquo;Business&amp;rdquo; tests and &amp;ldquo;Programmer&amp;rdquo; tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 65)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we don’t check something, we don’t know whether it works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 66)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to have a good design at all times. A bad design slows us down, because it is hard to change [&amp;hellip;] We need a high-quality design at every moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 71)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-9-full-circle&#34;&gt;Chapter 9: Full Circle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value is what we want. Features deliver value. Delivering features early gives us value sooner.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Managing by looking at value works better than managing by dates or artifacts that don’t deliver value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Planning features is easy enough to do. Estimate if you must. Selecting the work based on Yesterday’s Weather works better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building by features requires us to build a small, complete product, every couple of weeks. That product must always work correctly, and it must always be well designed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Development must deliver real working features. The product must be well tested. Business-side people and developers contribute to testing. The product must be well designed. Developers keep the design alive all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] A commitment from the top of the business, down to the individual managers and developers [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 77)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search for Value (a quote)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/search-for-value-quote-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/search-for-value-quote-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quote from the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://pragprog.com/book/rjnsd/the-nature-of-software-development&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Nature of Software Development&lt;/a&gt; by Ron Jeffries, talking about value (in software) and the building blocks to achieve it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Value. Value, we’ll see, is “what you want.” [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll tell the story by building up from the bottom of the pyramid, describing how to guide, organize, plan, and build our product, in small slices, with a focus on quality. The value we produce is based on these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guiding. We produce value by creating teams with responsibility for creating value. We make sure they understand what is needed, and understand the time available. We guide them by observing what they actually build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizing. We organize teams with the ability to get the job done. We organize around features, because features give us the ability to plan and build value most rapidly. We apply good people and help them build their skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning. We steer our projects by selecting the features we need, in the order we need them. We produce value in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building. We build up our product feature by feature. This provides frequent delivery of value. We can see how things are progressing early and often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slicing. We slice features down to the smallest possible value-bearing size. We build a capable product as early as possible, and then enhance and grow it as the deadline approaches. We’re always ready to ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality. We apply the necessary practices to ensure that our product always has a good design and that it is as nearly defect-free as possible. We’re able to build value continuously, sustainably, indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 5)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-the-uuid-https-segment-com-blog-a-brief-history-of-the-uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-uuid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Brief History of the UUID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rick Branson on the history of UUID.
Describes the history of uid, uuid, early computing (both networked and not networked) and their own implementation of a uuid library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uuid, uid, flake, snowflake, ksuid, go, golang, rick-branson, library, implementation-history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-data-more-data-https-blog-cloudflare-com-more-data-more-data&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/more-data-more-data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More data, more data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how cloudflare manages its logs. By Hunter Blanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: log, cloudflare, comparison, what-worked, what-did-not-work, kafka, citusdb, sre, site-reliability-engineering, analytics, hunter-blanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no-https-hbr-org-2017-06-help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/06/help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Help Your Team Stop Overcommitting by Empowering Them to Say No&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that describes how important is to say no to some ideas or projects so you can say yes to others.
In other words, how prioritizing is important as time and energy (i.e., resources) are not infinite and must be allocated accordingly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: diana-kander, hbr, harvard-business-review, priority, energy, resources, time, pet-project, yes-people, no-people, yes-culture, no-culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology-http-ben-evans-com-benedictevans-2017-5-24-not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2017/5/24/not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Not even wrong - ways to dismiss technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how technology can be seen as toys before it is developed to the point where it can be expanded and used for other purposes than the one expected / designed for. By Benedict Evans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benedict-evans, technology, prediction, usage, invention, philosophy, wolfgang-pauli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-we-have-a-better-option-here-https-softwaremill-com-do-we-have-better-option-here&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwaremill.com/do-we-have-better-option-here/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Do we have a better Option here?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article comparing &lt;code&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Optional&lt;/code&gt; as types that can contain a value, but maybe not. By Michał Chmielarz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michal-chmielarz, option, optional, vavr, javaslang, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-the-keyboard-faster-than-the-mouse-http-danluu-com-keyboard-v-mouse&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/keyboard-v-mouse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Is the keyboard faster than the mouse?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan Luu comparing the use of the mouse and the use of the keyboard and their speeds.
He groups existing literature on the topic plus some experiments he has done himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentions the amount of myths related to this, based on old and non-accurate research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-luu, keyboard, comparison, mouse, human-interaction-device, hid, interaction, user-experience, interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-crypto-anarchist-manifesto-http-groups-csail-mit-edu-mac-classes-6-805-articles-crypto-cypherpunks-may-crypto-manifesto-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/mac/classes/6.805/articles/crypto/cypherpunks/may-crypto-manifesto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Timothy C. May forecasting the development of a new market based on cryptography and secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same that barbed wire transformed property in the West, is the analogy he uses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: timothy-may, anarchy, encryption, market, forecast, crypto-anarchism, public-key-encryption, zero-knowledge-proof, cryptography&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;ve changed how I organize my books. More, here (TODO))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern; non-technical. A quick introduction to Bertrand Russell, his life and his way of thinking and seeing the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell; non-technical. A first-person view of the events during the Spanish Civil War (1936-1939), seen from the perspective of a British citizen that went there voluntarily. Explains the internal fracture of the left political parties and the fracture of the Spanish society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--
You can delete here and below
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;backlog (partially sorted):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unsorted V&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Machine That Changed the World: The Story of Lean Production&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haskell Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Architecture in Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La lucha por la desigualdad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La psicología del dinero, Hammond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invirtiendo a largo plazo, García Paramés&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Well-Grounded Java Developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quién domina el mundo, Chomsky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;El camino al 18J, Payne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cartas desde la revolución bolchevique, Sadoul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java Performance: The Definitive Guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional Programming Patterns in Scala and Clojure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why programmers work at night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shogun: The Life of Tokugawa Ieyasu, Sadler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrum and XP from the trenches, 2nd edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Els jueus i Catalunya, Villatoro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;El problema de los tres cuerpos, Liu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon Web Services in Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clojure Programming - Practical Lisp for the Java World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mature optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XUnit Test Patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let Over Lambda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Haskell Road to Logic, Math and Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types and Programming Languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamentals of Object-oriented Design in UML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clojure for the brave and true&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Solve It: A New Aspect of Mathematical Method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conceptual Mathematics: A First Introduction to Categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding Computation: From Simple Machines to Impossible Programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming in Haskell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming Languages: Application and Interpretation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing Math with Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect Software: And Other Illusions about Testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computability and Complexity - From a Programming Perspective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking Forth: a language and philosophy for solving problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concepts, Techniques, and Models of Computer Programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging the Communication Gap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specification by Example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Cucumber book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Architecture for Developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Object Design: Roles, Responsibilities, and Collaborations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RESTful Web APIs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RESTful Web Services Cookbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building Maintainable Software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serverless - Patterns of Modern Application Design Using Microservices (Amazon Web Services Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Pattern Language; Alexander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types and Programming Languages, TAPL; Pierce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Speed Reading Book: Read More, Learn More, Achieve More; Buzan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cómo crear mapas mentales (Crecimiento personal); Buzan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First things first ; covey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s best next ; perman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The problems of philosophy; Russell (1998)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rèquiem for the American dream ; chomsky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sun also rises; Hemingway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The travels; Marco polo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;unfinished (unsorted):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release It! - Design and Deploy Production-Ready Software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leprechauns of Software Engineering; Bossavit (*)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Domain-Driven Design: Tackling Complexity in the Heart of Software; Vernon (*)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readings in Database Systems, 5th Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La Sociedad De Coste Marginal Cero (Estado y Sociedad); Rifkin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs (SICP); Abelson, Sussmann, Sussmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next (2):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refactoring (*)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working Effectively with Legacy Code (*)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wip (3):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aprendo Yoga; Van Lysebeth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting things done, &amp;hellip;; Allen (*)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the senior software developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-hey-you-should-stop-using-texts-for-two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/hey-stop-using-texts-two-factor-authentication/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-d-never-work-for-google-twitter-or-facebook&#34;&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://naildrivin5.com/blog/2011/08/01/why-i-wont-work-for-google-twitter-facebook.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-copeland, google, twitter, facebook, job-satisfaction, commitment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-thinking-needs-to-think-bigger&#34;&gt;Design Thinking Needs To Think Bigger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcodesign.com/90112320/design-thinking-needs-to-think-bigger&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by STEVE VASSALLO on systems thinking and design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes a system a system rather than just a collection of parts is that the components are interconnected and interdependent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: steve-vassallo, design-thinking, system-thinking, mental-model, emergence-point, leverage-point, iceberg-model&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cobol-is-everywhere-who-will-maintain-it&#34;&gt;COBOL Is Everywhere. Who Will Maintain It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewstack.io/cobol-everywhere-will-maintain/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel explaining the state of the COBOL systems at some banks and the difficulty of finding young COBOL programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-cassel, cobol, youth, team-management, hiring, bank, java, mainframe, legacy-system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-too-busy-you-need-a-shultz-hour&#34;&gt;You’re Too Busy. You Need a ‘Shultz Hour.’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/18/opinion/youre-too-busy-you-need-a-shultz-hour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Leonhardt, about the Shultz Hour: time set aside to not be busy, so you can set aside the tactical topics and focus on the strategic topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You waste years by not being able to waste hours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amos Tversky  (as Michael Lewis describes in his THE UNDOING PROJECT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-leonhardt, busyness, time-management, shultz-hour, connectedness, social-media, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;avoid-these-35-habits-that-lead-to-unmaintainable-code&#34;&gt;Avoid these 35 habits that lead to unmaintainable code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/avoid-35-habits-lead-unmaintainable-code-christian-maioli-mackeprang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about habits that make writing software more difficult:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saying “I’ll fix it later”, and never doing it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insisting on a one-liner solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making pointless optimizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convincing yourself that styling issues are not that important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweeping things under the rug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using names that don’t add information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring proven best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abandoning plans too early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insisting on a plan that has little chance of working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on your own all the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refusing to write bad code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blaming others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not sharing with your team what you’ve learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being too slow on giving feedback to managers/clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not using Google enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overvaluing your personal style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a personal attachment to your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not knowing how to optimize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the wrong tool for the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not bothering with mastering your tools and IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring error messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Romanticizing your developer toolkit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardcoding values instead of making them configurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinventing the wheel all the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blindly copy/pasting code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not taking the time to learn how things really work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having excessive confidence in your own code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not thinking about the trade-offs of each design, solution, or library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not getting help when you’re stuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing tests to pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disregarding performance testing for critical cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not checking that your build works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing large changes late, or leaving after making a large push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disowning code you wrote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring the nonfunctional requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christian-maioli-mackeprang, maintanability, code, listicle, habit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-a-first-class-language-at-last&#34;&gt;JavaScript — A First-Class Language At Last&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/javascript-first-class-language-atlast-tom-goldenberg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Goldenberg defending javascript, citing sources on why it is a first-class language,
the amount of job offers, and the state of the art in NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-goldenberg, javascript, java, comparison, first-class, language, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-8-hour-workday-doesn-t-work&#34;&gt;Why the 8-Hour Workday Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/why-8-hour-workday-doesnt-work-dr-travis-bradberry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; defending the removal of the 8-hour workday, preferring the division of time in slots.
In the article, 52 minutes of highly focused work then 17 minutes of rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key idea is the work-rest, no matter how big those slots are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives tips on how to separate both, some other tips for improving your performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Travis Bradberry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, pomodoro-technique, travis-bradberry, time, workday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-and-how-to-steer-back-toward-the-light-https-medium-freecodecamp-com-the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-2a31ff7a4cd2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-2a31ff7a4cd2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The dark side of extreme productivity, and how to steer back toward the light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Beau Carnes on how productivity can have a downside, how it can affect your healthy lifestyle.
Explains effective vs efficient, productivity, silent retreat, prayer or meditation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is not to prioritize what’s on your schedule, but to schedule your priorities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Covey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: beau-carnes, productivity, quote, stephen-covey, sustainable-pace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dejé-de-leer&#34;&gt;Dejé de leer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://culto.latercera.com/2017/03/15/deje-de-leer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Catalina Bu on the tsundoku and how to read more. (In Spanish)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: catalina-bu, tsundoku, reading, time-management, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacked-in-translation-from-subtitles-to-complete-takeover&#34;&gt;Hacked in Translation – from Subtitles to Complete Takeover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.checkpoint.com/2017/05/23/hacked-in-translation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about a vector to getting to user&amp;rsquo;s machines through the video player, using subtitle files.
by Check Point Research Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: check-point-research-team, security, vulnerability, vector, attack, subtitle, video-player&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-teamwork-myths-to-tackle-at-your-office&#34;&gt;8 Teamwork Myths To Tackle At Your Office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/8-teamwork-myths-to-tackle-at-your-office&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Leah Ryder on remote work myths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leah-ryder, productivity, myth, remote, remote-work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-elm-is-the-future-of-front-end-development&#34;&gt;Why I think Elm is the Future of Front End Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rgoomar/why-i-think-elm-is-the-future-of-front-end-development-21e9b091fa05&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rishi Goomar comparing reactredux to elm, comparing javascript to elm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rishi-goomar, comparison, elm, javascript, react, redux, javascript-fatigue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;los-viejos-programadores-nunca-mueren-y-silicon-valley-se-está-dando-cuenta-de-ello&#34;&gt;Los viejos programadores nunca mueren, y Silicon Valley se está dando cuenta de ello&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.xataka.com/empresas-y-economia/los-viejos-programadores-nunca-mueren-y-silicon-valley-se-esta-dando-cuenta-de-ello&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Pastor on the age of the programmers in Silicon Valley. In Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, javier-pastor, age, programmer, career-manager, silicon-valley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-tensorflow-powered-ing-api-client&#34;&gt;Creating a TensorFlow-powered ING API client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@donflopez/cracking-the-ing-api-with-tensorflow-9681ae7dc249&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Francisco López on how he has implemented a small bot to click the virtual keyboard and connect to the bank website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ing-direct, francisco-lopez, bot, opencv, tensorflow, machine-learning, python, banking, open-banking-data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&#34;&gt;Be a good mentor, not a dickhead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Edaqa Mortoray about traits of a mentor. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/mortoray/be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://dev.to/mortoray/be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: edaqa-mortoray, mentor, trait, skill, mentorship, apprentice, apprenticeship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-bharry-2017-05-24-the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/bharry/2017/05/24/the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The largest Git repo on the planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by  Brian Harry on how Microsoft manages one of its big repositories. Explains how they have virtualized the git folder and the git workspace at Microsoft using gvfs. Explains how they have performed the improvements necessary to make it useful and usable to programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have support for clients, but what about Linux?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  brian-harry, microsoft, continous-delivery, linux, windows, gvfs, repository, monorepo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 9</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 17:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-9-learn-to-write&#34;&gt;Chapter 9: Learn to Write&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analogy of TDD to writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how to write good email.
Then, good documentation,
then good API documentation&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 8</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-8-bootstrap-a-greenfield-system&#34;&gt;Chapter 8: Bootstrap a Greenfield System&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on a brand new application can be a lot of fun.
There’s no &amp;ldquo;baggage&amp;rdquo; from legacy code, no technical debt,
and there’s a wonderful feeling of freshness when starting
an app from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 101)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decisions you make [&amp;hellip;] can have a lasting impact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 101)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-1-overview&#34;&gt;8.1 Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When given a greenfield project [&amp;hellip;] you have two main goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure everyone involved in the project feels good about the initial direction and decisions being made&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a location for developers to start contributing code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 102)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mention of the iteration Zero, that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] indicates that no direct business value is going
to be delivered initially&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 102)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-2-understand-the-problem&#34;&gt;8.2 Understand the problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do your company a disservice to build an application you don’t think needs to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand why the application should be built, find answers to these questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What business problems will this application solve?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is the proposed application the best solutiont o those problems?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What other solutions were considered?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 104)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentioning the importance of asking why about these problems, also, whether this decided solution is good / the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-3-understand-the-system-s-place-in-the-technical-architecture&#34;&gt;8.3 Understand the System’s Place in the Technical Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mention of the &amp;lsquo;technical architecture&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;existing applications and existing infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 105)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-4-choose-technology&#34;&gt;8.4 Choose Technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;using-the-blessed-stack&#34;&gt;Using the Blessed Stack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to heavily defend your position if you decide to not use
the blessed stack, both to yourself and others. (paraphrased from p. 107)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-a-different-technology&#34;&gt;Using a Different Technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must answer the question “Why shouldn’t I use the blessed stack?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] your first duty is to deliver results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 108).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also consider these factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitness for purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer productivity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer happiness - also called developer experience (DX)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(from p. 108)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-5-outline-the-application-s-architecture&#34;&gt;8.5 Outline the Application’s Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want your application to ooze consistency&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 111)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you want to establish a “culture of consistency”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 113)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each developer should be encouraged to establish a convention when
they first face the need to have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 113)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] considering the political impact [&amp;hellip;] Since it often doesn’t
matter what the decision is, making an unpopular decision can be
little gain for a lot of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 114)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-7-create-a-minimum-deployable-system&#34;&gt;8.7 Create a Minimum Deployable System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think of deployment as the physical act of getting the code up in the production environment and launching as the act of allowing users access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 118)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between deploying and launching. This can be enforced
with some techniques to block/allow access, such as enabling/disabling
these features or controlling access to said features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 7</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/24/senior-software-engineer-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 11:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/24/senior-software-engineer-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-7-make-technical-decisions&#34;&gt;Chapter 7: Make Technical Decisions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opinions like this are often indicators of hidden facts that you have yet to identify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 90)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 6</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 07:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-6-play-well-with-others&#34;&gt;Chapter 6: Play Well With Others&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;challenges you’ll face as a programmer is to explain what you do,
or how you’ve done it, to someone who is not a programmer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Translating your work to non-technical people is a skill that
can be more valuable than any specific technical knowledge you have.
It’s what makes a senior developer in the eyes of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 77)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-1-empathize-with-your-audience&#34;&gt;6.1 Empathize With Your Audience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;these &amp;ldquo;interested parties&amp;rdquo; understand the problem more deeply than
you, but lack the technical knowledge, skill, or time to solve it directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 78)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of thinking of them as &amp;ldquo;pointy-haired bosses&amp;rdquo;, think of
them as partners. They understand the problem and you know how
to solve it. This &amp;ldquo;division of labor&amp;rdquo; is why teams can achieve
greater things than any individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 79)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-2-adapt-and-abstract-information&#34;&gt;6.2 Adapt and Abstract Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to adapt our terms to theirs, and we want to abstract
away irrelevant information as much as we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 80)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When communicating with others, you need to learn how to speak
the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 80)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid technical jargon of your own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen carefully and ask questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t &amp;ldquo;talk down&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;longer descriptive phrases in place of acronyms or other jargon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 81)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;need to distill your message to its absolute minimum without giving out
false information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 82)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to &amp;ldquo;talk the talk&amp;rdquo; with others can make you more effective
and more valuable to your company. Being able to briefly summarize
technical details even more so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p 87)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 5</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 07:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-5-deal-with-technical-debt-and-slop&#34;&gt;Chapter 5: Deal With Technical Debt and Slop&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeing legacy as tech debt that has been acquired&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slop as source for sloppy code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapter about understanding the difference between slop and technical debt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many developers, if they are feeling pressured to complete their work, would call this an acceptable compromise, promise to fix it later, and ship it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 70)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical Debt is [&amp;hellip;] used to explain compromises in implementation that save cost now,
at a larger future cost (just like real debt). [&amp;hellip;] technical debt is code written
under certain assumptions that no longer hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 72)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you’ll likely need to pay it off someday, you might not necessarily have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 73)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses a marker (&lt;code&gt;TECHDEBT&lt;/code&gt;) to explain what and why has been introduced. Also
serves to find this debt later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/13/senior-software-engineer-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 13:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/13/senior-software-engineer-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-3-fix-bugs-efficiently-and-cleanly&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Fix bugs efficiently and cleanly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, you will be given tasks that require no in-depth domain knowledge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A process allows you to focus on the right thing at th right time (p. 14)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will make your productivity and quality more predictable, which, in turn, will help you estimate and keep more of your promises about your work (paraphrased from p. 14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tdd&#34;&gt;TDD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some benefits about TDD:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking before coding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separating the &amp;lsquo;getting it to work&amp;rsquo; from &amp;lsquo;getting it right&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 15)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter can be interpreted as &amp;lsquo;building the thing right&amp;rsquo; vs &amp;lsquo;building the right thing&amp;rsquo;: a red test can be seen as question, a green test as an answer. If the question is defined in business terms, you are building the right thing. When refactoring, you are turning the right thing (no matter how it was built) into the thing right&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] senior software engineers don&amp;rsquo;t ask permission to do their job, they just do it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(p. 20)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- TODO this will turn into a blog post --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Agile Barcelona Open Space</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/notes-agile-open-space-barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 18:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/notes-agile-open-space-barcelona/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended an Agile Barcelona open space at Netmind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arrival, attendees where welcomed by an Agile Coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;es&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Creo que sobrará alguna cosita del café colaborativo... &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/agilebcnOS?src=hash&#34;&gt;#agilebcnOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/compartir?src=hash&#34;&gt;#compartir&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/comunidad?src=hash&#34;&gt;#comunidad&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/gracias?src=hash&#34;&gt;#gracias&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/vvShEZmyfJ&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/vvShEZmyfJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Miquel Rodríguez (@miquelrodriguez) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/miquelrodriguez/status/860792625347137536&#34;&gt;May 6, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10:00, the introduction started: a warm welcome to everyone, including first-time attendees to an open space, explaining what it is, the few rules and laws and making sure everyone had fun. Some time later, the marketplace happened and everyone presented their sessions. A curious thing to see was the effect of a session that everyone wanted to attend (dubbed a &amp;lsquo;black hole&amp;rsquo;). Nobody dared to plan another session in parallel to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the day went by, the sessions were happening. By lunch time, everyone self organized to have lunch. I had the opportunity to catch up with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Jordi_Falguera&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jordi Falguera&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/torinoxx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Victor Fairén&lt;/a&gt;. It was a very enjoyable conversation. It had been a long time since we didn&amp;rsquo;t meet. Hello to both from here :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the evening, two more slots for sessions, followed by a cross-pollination session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, some left and some went for a closing beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sessions&#34;&gt;Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not cover all sessions, including the one I facilitated, but the ones I liked the most&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;la-formula-de-la-cocacola&#34;&gt;La formula de la cocacola&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Full attendance at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/laFormulaDeLaCocacola?src=hash&#34;&gt;#laFormulaDeLaCocacola&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/agileBcnOS?src=hash&#34;&gt;#agileBcnOS&lt;/a&gt;, facilitated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jaumejornet&#34;&gt;@jaumejornet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pavleras&#34;&gt;@pavleras&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/netmindIT&#34;&gt;@netmindIT&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/GFHpqTRJrp&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GFHpqTRJrp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alvaro Garcia (@alvarobiz) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvarobiz/status/860800423787204608&#34;&gt;May 6, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this session, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jaumejornet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jaume Jornet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pavleras&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pablo Domingo&lt;/a&gt; explained flow efficiency and resource efficiency to us, using simple terms and compelling stories, without using any specific jargon. Explaining the efficiencies using games (with volunteers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They mention that this format works very well with C-level employees and other executives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching-from-the-back-of-the-room&#34;&gt;Teaching from the back of the room&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Super graphic recording de &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zigiella&#34;&gt;@zigiella&lt;/a&gt; durante la charla de Training from the BACK of the Room! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/gracias?src=hash&#34;&gt;#gracias&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/agilebcnOS?src=hash&#34;&gt;#agilebcnOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/5NeiWad9hm&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/5NeiWad9hm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Miquel Rodríguez (@miquelrodriguez) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/miquelrodriguez/status/860888995148034048&#34;&gt;May 6, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this session, Miquel Rodríguez explained a few concepts he learnt in a training by Sarah Bowman &amp;ldquo;Training from the back of the room&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He explained the six concepts for training to be effective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movement trumps sitting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images trumps words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talking trumps listening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing trumps reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shorter trumps longer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different trumps same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the four Cs (or phases in a training):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concrete practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few pointers for further reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Training-Back-Room-Aside-Learn/dp/0787996629&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Training from the back of the room&lt;/a&gt;, by Sarah Bowman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Using-Brain-Science-Training-Stick/dp/096568511X/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using brain science to make training stick&lt;/a&gt;, by Sarah Bowman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Neuroci%C3%A8ncia-educadors-David-Bueno-Torrens/dp/8494529013/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Neurociencia per educadors&lt;/a&gt;, by David Bueno (Catalan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked this session, as it helps us deliver more effective trainings, both in formal session as in more ad-hoc / informal ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These open-space events leave me full of energy, after having shared thoughts and happiness with the rest of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to the organizers (the community of Agile Barcelona), the facilitator (Andres Mumenthaler) and Netmind, for hosting the event&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: This post is categorized as &amp;lsquo;We were there&amp;rsquo;, in reference to the awesome &amp;lsquo;Estuvimos allí&amp;rsquo; posts that Carlos Blé (and Codesai) write about events. Also &amp;lsquo;Notes&amp;rsquo; for the ones that Eduardo Ferro writes about events he attends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/agilebcnOS?src=hash&#34;&gt;#agilebcnOS&lt;/a&gt; Session: managing problems with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/agile?src=hash&#34;&gt;#agile&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/yIYzOYnpH6&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/yIYzOYnpH6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Fulgencio Jara (@eltioful) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eltioful/status/860791870938599424&#34;&gt;May 6, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fulgencio Jara as graphic reporter from my session :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-real-reason-why-the-spotify-model-is-broken&#34;&gt;The real reason why the Spotify model is broken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://kernelmag.dailydot.com/issue-sections/staff-editorials/12136/spotify-royalty-payment-model/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-of-7-badass-developer-gets-a-rude-awakening&#34;&gt;[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, they wanted a professional problem solver who could jump in and deliver what the company needed, to meet THEIR customers&amp;rsquo; demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking for ways that I could add value to my employer outside of the code I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed my &amp;ldquo;soft skills&amp;rdquo;—my ability to communicate, learn quickly, and pass my knowledge on to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: john-sonmez, programmer, language-programmer, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-rules-to-live-by-when-you-work-in-an-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34;&gt;6 Rules To Live By When You Work In An Office But Have Remote Team Members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/6-mistakes-when-you-work-in-office-but-have-remote-team-members&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Lauren Moon about how trello works remotely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value Individuals Over Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid Impromptu Meetings At Someone’s Desk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If One Person Is On A Video Call, EVERYONE Is On A Video Call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication Is Asynchronous. Deal With It.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socializing Is Not Around A Watercooler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tools You’re Using Matter. A Lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: remote, remote-work, lauren-moon, listicle, trello, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;princeton-s-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34;&gt;Princeton’s Ad-Blocking Superweapon May Put an End to the Ad-Blocking Arms Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/princetons-ad-blocking-superweapon-may-put-an-end-to-the-ad-blocking-arms-race&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Koebler on the tool a university has written and published, that using computer vision, is able to detect sponsored content in native form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jason-koebler, computer-vision, ad, advertisement, ublock, adblock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hasta-pronto&#34;&gt;Hasta pronto…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javiergarzas.com/2016/07/hasta-pronto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Garzás, where he explains that he&amp;rsquo;ll stop blogging for a while and why&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: javier-garzas, blog, personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-principles-of-clean-architecture&#34;&gt;The principles of Clean Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video about the clean architecture (with a client&amp;rsquo;s lunch and learn initiative). By Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the plugin is vulnerable to the plugged-in system, at the source code level&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate the detail from the general things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clean-architecture, uncle-bob, robert-martin, video, mvp, model-view-presenter, model-view-controller, mvc, quote, plugin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-languages-which-almost-became-css&#34;&gt;The Languages Which Almost Became CSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eager.io/blog/the-languages-which-almost-were-css/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zack Bloom on the origins of CSS and the languages to add representation to HTML pages / markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes the origins of these languages (e.g., RPP, PWP, CHSS, PSL, FOSI, DSSSL) and how the acceptance of CSS came to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was the technology which was easiest for a beginner to pick up which won, rather than those which were most powerful for an expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt; Zack Bloom&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: css, html, history, zack-bloom, mosaic, violawww&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-not-going-to-believe-what-i-m-about-to-tell-you&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not going to believe what I&amp;rsquo;m about to tell you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/believe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Inman about how we process information from outside, especially when it conflicts with our beliefs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-inman, comic, oatmeal, belief&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-perfectly-unhappy&#34;&gt;How to be perfectly unhappy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/unhappy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this comic&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew Inman about the definition of happiness and how it affects the author&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matthew-inman, oatmeal, happiness, comic, definition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spotify-engineering-culture-part-1&#34;&gt;Spotify Engineering Culture - part 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/85490944&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; about the Spotify engineering culture: team organization, the terms they introduce and some general culture about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: team-management, people, spotify, henrik-kniberg, squad, chapter, guild, tribe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speak-like-a-leader&#34;&gt;Speak like a leader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bGBamfWasNQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TEDx Talk&lt;/a&gt; by Simon Lancaster in which he explains the importance of rhetoric in our speech. Explains 6 techniques for achieving better communication:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three breathless sentences: &amp;ldquo;Mangia Bene, Ridi Spesso, ama molto&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Ein Volk, ein Reich, ein Fuhrer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three repetitive sentences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three balancing statements: if we hear the statements as balanced, we imagine that the underlaying thinking is balanced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metaphor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exaggeration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: simon-lancaster, tedx, ted, quote, speech, leadership, communication&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>