<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>randomness on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/randomness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in randomness on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 09:03:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/randomness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Testing a component that includes randomness</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/15/testing-component-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 09:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/15/testing-component-randomness/</guid>
      <description>Context We have been tasked with designing a component to generate secrets for two-factor authentication (2FA), to ensure that the you also own that other &amp;lsquo;channel&amp;rsquo;.
It has to be secure enough to pass to verify a user, meaning no other user should be able to impersonating another one by guessing the secret.
Solution A first solution that he have implemented is to provide a 6-digit pin code.
The solution (in java) is straightforward: get a Random to generate ints for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
