<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 18:17:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Agile Barcelona Open Space</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/notes-agile-open-space-barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 18:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/notes-agile-open-space-barcelona/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended an Agile Barcelona open space at Netmind
Format On arrival, attendees where welcomed by an Agile Coffee.
At 10:00, the introduction started: a warm welcome to everyone, including first-time attendees to an open space, explaining what it is, the few rules and laws and making sure everyone had fun. Some time later, the marketplace happened and everyone presented their sessions. A curious thing to see was the effect of a session that everyone wanted to attend (dubbed a &amp;lsquo;black hole&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Kinesis Zombieland</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/28/aws-kinesis-zombieland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/28/aws-kinesis-zombieland/</guid>
      <description>I attended a workshop on AWS Kinesis, called AWS Kinesis Zombieland by Javi Moreno at capside.
Notes AWS Kinesis Zombieland
 muy importante escoger bien la clave de particionado (id de shard) KPL librería de kinesis que te permite hacer batching, timeout, &amp;hellip;  la otra se llama KCL. KCL permite mantener estado   cuando te pidan una app de big data, pregunta para qué lo quieren, lo mismo que con cualquier proyecto de software latitud = Y, longitud = x el canal se llama stream, la capacidad se llama shard  el shard sólo permite 5 lecturas por segundo, 2MB/s   usar el shard como buffer usar la clave de particionado como algoritmo de agregación cada vez que tienes una tabla en dynamodb, tienes que poner una alerta de throughput nota: lo que no puedes hacer es guardarlos todos y luego procesarlo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Space: Code reviews</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/open-space-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Today we&amp;rsquo;ve discussed about code reviews on this open space
Notes These are my notes, in no particular order:
 reduce information silos all around the company, as everyone [technical] can participate in these events raise the &amp;ldquo;just arrived&amp;rdquo; people&amp;rsquo;s knowledge [Difficult to hit the ground up and running, but these code review sessions can help] invest one person as &amp;lsquo;sheriff&amp;rsquo; for the sprint: they will take care of static analysis tools (such as sonar) and continuous integration (CI; such as jenkins).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: &#39;Is TDD Dead? Of course not! But what´s all the fuzz about then?&#39; by Emily Bache</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/talk-is-tdd-dead-of-course-not-by-emily-bache/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 15:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/talk-is-tdd-dead-of-course-not-by-emily-bache/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just seen this talk: Is TDD dead? Of course not! But what´s all the fuzz about then? by Emily Bache
My notes   deliberate vs accidental learning (around minute 19)
  do not be an evangelist for tdd but rather &amp;ldquo;come learn tdd, come at a dojo with us!&amp;rdquo;
  points to Dan North&amp;rsquo;s talk (at the same foo café)
  points to her book - The Coding Dojo Handbook</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
