<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cate-huston on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/cate-huston/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cate-huston on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/cate-huston/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/11/01/self-study-in-november-2016/</guid>
      <description>Advice for white men I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Cate Huston about how advice affects different people.
 But here are some things to consider:
 Advice on failure is different for people who are judged on performance rather than potential. Advice on saying no is different for people who aren’t appreciated for doing work for the collective… but who are punished if they don’t. Advice on negotiation is different for people who are perceived negatively when they do negotiate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
