<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2021</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Perfect Media Server Hacker News discussion on a media server, half open source (?).
Tags: hacker-news, media-server, perfect, tool, software
Id: c37b0f2a-4dc5-11eb-8048-0242ac110002 Read: Sun, 03 Jan 2021 13:15:34 +0000
How your startup can survive technical debt Mentions the paradox of success: you need debt to start quickly, yet too quickly leaves no time to pay debt. Hence your prototype turns into an MVP, and that is your first piecce of technical debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
