<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>debug on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/debug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in debug on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/debug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</guid>
      <description>Managing projects with GNU Make, Third Edition book about GNU Make, with recipes and going into detail about how to use it
Tags: book, make, gnu-make, project, skeleton, ci, continuous-integration
Id: 028b0e1f-a181-4469-8789-900ce6641d97 Read: Sun, 01 Jul 2024 17:22:52 +0000
Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs a tool to diff pdfs visually
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319
Tags: hackernews, imported, olshansky, testing, test, diff-pdf, pdf, diff, git, e2e-testing, end-to-end-testing, tool
Id: 4fc53bae-d81c-45b4-9f6b-995ec5d4df6a Read: Tue, 02 Jul 2024 07:26:08 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/01/self-study-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>(h0p3&amp;rsquo;s Wiki) This is a highly customized tiddlyWiki, from h0p3.
Tags: wiki, personal-knowledge-base, h0p3
Id: b8b3d973-9611-4180-854a-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Debug bash scripts This article explains how to debug bash scripts using the DEBUG trap.
Declares several log levels for the commands
Tags: debug, bash, trap, help, script
Id: 39f76af4-99ce-48b6-adc1-0242ac110003 Read: Fri, 7 Jun 2019 13:20:26 +0000
Understanding Rust Lifetimes Describes rust lifetimes, lifetime parameters.
Compares them to C++ pointers (in the sense they are difficult to learn, but make things explicit).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/01/self-study-in-december-2016/</guid>
      <description>A Docker Fork: Talk of a Split Is Now on the Table I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Alex Williams and Joab Jackson about the possible split in the Docker environment following Docker&amp;rsquo;s and other providers&#39; product roadmaps. Each own has their policies and priorities and they collide in this case
Tags: docker, alex-williams, joab-jackson, container, oci, kubernetes, devops, tool
An Ode to Boring: Creating Open and Stable Container World I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bob Wise, in which he describes the state of the Docker tool and the Docker Engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
