<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/age/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/age/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-hey-you-should-stop-using-texts-for-two-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/hey-stop-using-texts-two-factor-authentication/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-d-never-work-for-google-twitter-or-facebook&#34;&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://naildrivin5.com/blog/2011/08/01/why-i-wont-work-for-google-twitter-facebook.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-copeland, google, twitter, facebook, job-satisfaction, commitment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-thinking-needs-to-think-bigger&#34;&gt;Design Thinking Needs To Think Bigger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcodesign.com/90112320/design-thinking-needs-to-think-bigger&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by STEVE VASSALLO on systems thinking and design thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes a system a system rather than just a collection of parts is that the components are interconnected and interdependent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: steve-vassallo, design-thinking, system-thinking, mental-model, emergence-point, leverage-point, iceberg-model&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cobol-is-everywhere-who-will-maintain-it&#34;&gt;COBOL Is Everywhere. Who Will Maintain It?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewstack.io/cobol-everywhere-will-maintain/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel explaining the state of the COBOL systems at some banks and the difficulty of finding young COBOL programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-cassel, cobol, youth, team-management, hiring, bank, java, mainframe, legacy-system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-re-too-busy-you-need-a-shultz-hour&#34;&gt;You’re Too Busy. You Need a ‘Shultz Hour.’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/04/18/opinion/youre-too-busy-you-need-a-shultz-hour.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Leonhardt, about the Shultz Hour: time set aside to not be busy, so you can set aside the tactical topics and focus on the strategic topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You waste years by not being able to waste hours.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amos Tversky  (as Michael Lewis describes in his THE UNDOING PROJECT)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-leonhardt, busyness, time-management, shultz-hour, connectedness, social-media, quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;avoid-these-35-habits-that-lead-to-unmaintainable-code&#34;&gt;Avoid these 35 habits that lead to unmaintainable code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/avoid-35-habits-lead-unmaintainable-code-christian-maioli-mackeprang&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about habits that make writing software more difficult:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saying “I’ll fix it later”, and never doing it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insisting on a one-liner solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making pointless optimizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convincing yourself that styling issues are not that important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweeping things under the rug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using names that don’t add information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring proven best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abandoning plans too early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insisting on a plan that has little chance of working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on your own all the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refusing to write bad code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blaming others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not sharing with your team what you’ve learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being too slow on giving feedback to managers/clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not using Google enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overvaluing your personal style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a personal attachment to your code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not knowing how to optimize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the wrong tool for the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not bothering with mastering your tools and IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring error messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Romanticizing your developer toolkit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardcoding values instead of making them configurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinventing the wheel all the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blindly copy/pasting code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not taking the time to learn how things really work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having excessive confidence in your own code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not thinking about the trade-offs of each design, solution, or library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not getting help when you’re stuck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing tests to pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disregarding performance testing for critical cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not checking that your build works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushing large changes late, or leaving after making a large push&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disowning code you wrote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring the nonfunctional requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: christian-maioli-mackeprang, maintanability, code, listicle, habit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-a-first-class-language-at-last&#34;&gt;JavaScript — A First-Class Language At Last&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/javascript-first-class-language-atlast-tom-goldenberg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Goldenberg defending javascript, citing sources on why it is a first-class language,
the amount of job offers, and the state of the art in NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-goldenberg, javascript, java, comparison, first-class, language, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-8-hour-workday-doesn-t-work&#34;&gt;Why the 8-Hour Workday Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/why-8-hour-workday-doesnt-work-dr-travis-bradberry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; defending the removal of the 8-hour workday, preferring the division of time in slots.
In the article, 52 minutes of highly focused work then 17 minutes of rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key idea is the work-rest, no matter how big those slots are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives tips on how to separate both, some other tips for improving your performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Travis Bradberry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, pomodoro-technique, travis-bradberry, time, workday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-and-how-to-steer-back-toward-the-light-https-medium-freecodecamp-com-the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-2a31ff7a4cd2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-dark-side-of-extreme-productivity-2a31ff7a4cd2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The dark side of extreme productivity, and how to steer back toward the light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Beau Carnes on how productivity can have a downside, how it can affect your healthy lifestyle.
Explains effective vs efficient, productivity, silent retreat, prayer or meditation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is not to prioritize what’s on your schedule, but to schedule your priorities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stephen Covey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: beau-carnes, productivity, quote, stephen-covey, sustainable-pace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dejé-de-leer&#34;&gt;Dejé de leer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://culto.latercera.com/2017/03/15/deje-de-leer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Catalina Bu on the tsundoku and how to read more. (In Spanish)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: catalina-bu, tsundoku, reading, time-management, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hacked-in-translation-from-subtitles-to-complete-takeover&#34;&gt;Hacked in Translation – from Subtitles to Complete Takeover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.checkpoint.com/2017/05/23/hacked-in-translation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about a vector to getting to user&amp;rsquo;s machines through the video player, using subtitle files.
by Check Point Research Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: check-point-research-team, security, vulnerability, vector, attack, subtitle, video-player&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-teamwork-myths-to-tackle-at-your-office&#34;&gt;8 Teamwork Myths To Tackle At Your Office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.trello.com/8-teamwork-myths-to-tackle-at-your-office&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Leah Ryder on remote work myths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leah-ryder, productivity, myth, remote, remote-work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-think-elm-is-the-future-of-front-end-development&#34;&gt;Why I think Elm is the Future of Front End Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rgoomar/why-i-think-elm-is-the-future-of-front-end-development-21e9b091fa05&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Rishi Goomar comparing reactredux to elm, comparing javascript to elm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rishi-goomar, comparison, elm, javascript, react, redux, javascript-fatigue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;los-viejos-programadores-nunca-mueren-y-silicon-valley-se-está-dando-cuenta-de-ello&#34;&gt;Los viejos programadores nunca mueren, y Silicon Valley se está dando cuenta de ello&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.xataka.com/empresas-y-economia/los-viejos-programadores-nunca-mueren-y-silicon-valley-se-esta-dando-cuenta-de-ello&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Javier Pastor on the age of the programmers in Silicon Valley. In Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, javier-pastor, age, programmer, career-manager, silicon-valley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-tensorflow-powered-ing-api-client&#34;&gt;Creating a TensorFlow-powered ING API client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@donflopez/cracking-the-ing-api-with-tensorflow-9681ae7dc249&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Francisco López on how he has implemented a small bot to click the virtual keyboard and connect to the bank website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ing-direct, francisco-lopez, bot, opencv, tensorflow, machine-learning, python, banking, open-banking-data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&#34;&gt;Be a good mentor, not a dickhead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Edaqa Mortoray about traits of a mentor. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/mortoray/be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://dev.to/mortoray/be-a-good-mentor-not-a-dickhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: edaqa-mortoray, mentor, trait, skill, mentorship, apprentice, apprenticeship&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet-https-blogs-msdn-microsoft-com-bharry-2017-05-24-the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/bharry/2017/05/24/the-largest-git-repo-on-the-planet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The largest Git repo on the planet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by  Brian Harry on how Microsoft manages one of its big repositories. Explains how they have virtualized the git folder and the git workspace at Microsoft using gvfs. Explains how they have performed the improvements necessary to make it useful and usable to programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have support for clients, but what about Linux?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  brian-harry, microsoft, continous-delivery, linux, windows, gvfs, repository, monorepo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-developer-after-40&#34;&gt;Being A Developer After 40&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/being-a-developer-after-40-3c5dd112210c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forget The Hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose Your Galaxy Wisely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn About Software History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep on Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workplaces Suck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know Your Worth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send The Elevator Down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLVM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take conscious decisions in your life. Be aware of your actions and their effect. Do not blush or be embarrased for changing your opinions. Say “I’m sorry” when required. Listen. Do not be a hotshot. Have integrity and self-respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommends these books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dealers of Lightning by Michael A. Hiltzik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revolution in the Valley by Andy Hertzfeld&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar by Eric S. Raymond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Success of Open Source by Steven Weber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Old New Thing by Raymond Chen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Mythical Man Month by Frederick P. Brooks Jr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peopleware by Tom DeMarco and Tim Lister&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Psychology of Software Programming by Gerald M. Weinberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facts and Fallacies of Software Engineering by Robert L. Glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Design of Everyday Things by Don Norman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly by Bertrand Meyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geekonomics by David Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: adrian-kosmaczewski, career, profession, age, galaxy, long-term, book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;firing-people&#34;&gt;Firing people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://zachholman.com/talk/firing-people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Holman on firing people at your current work, both from the perspective of the employee (fired), employer, coworker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains his personal experience of being fired from Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll know the difference between doing far and away your best work, and doing work that is still good, but just nominally better than what you’ve been doing. Once you catch yourself adjusting to that incremental progression… maybe it’s time to leave, to change things up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: zach-holman, github, team-management, firing, coworker, employee, employer, job, relationship, next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-design-principles-for-developers&#34;&gt;10 design principles — for developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@nirbenita/the-10-design-heuristics-for-developers-1e70a9dc58a7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains what are the 10 design principles for programmers, as outlined by Jakob Nielsen. The article itself is by Nir Benita&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: design-principle, ux, jakob-nielsen, nir-benita, usability, testing, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two&#34;&gt;Design Patterns — Coming Full Circle, Part Two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/design-patterns-coming-full-circle-part-two-ced2c69e4724#.x8ud7eeqm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains how design patterns can be observed and then discovered and shows a list of four patterns dot working with data, by flux.io. Article by Jen Carlile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: design-pattern, data, pattern, flux, flux-io, pattern-catalog, jen-carlile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days&#34;&gt;Why I’m Ending my Github Streak after 844 Days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@karan/why-i-m-ending-my-github-streak-after-844-days-80fd014dc8df&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Karan Goel on the mechanics of following a pattern, of an activity sliced in small parts (1 problem a day or half an hour) and how this can be counterproductive sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discusses ROI of this type of activity at the beginning of your career and later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: karan-goel, github, streak, python, code, everyday, practice, deliberate-practice, career, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs&#34;&gt;Good lessons learned from past jobs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.kartones.net/post/good-lessons-learned-from-past-jobs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Diego &amp;lsquo;Kartones&amp;rsquo; on a synopsis of his work experience, job by job and what he has learned on each job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: diego-kartones, job, professional-career, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;too-much-work-in-progress&#34;&gt;Too Much Work In Progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://monospacedmonologues.com/post/144137568985/too-much-work-in-progress&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Samir Talwar on factors that indicate work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wip, work-in-progress, list, samir-talwar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testdouble&#34;&gt;TestDouble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.martinfowler.com/bliki/TestDouble.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Martin Fowler describing the test doubles that Gerard Meszaros describes in xUnit Test Patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: test-double, martin-fowler, gerard-meszaros, stub, fake, mock, dummy, spy, xunit, junit, pattern, test-pattern&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it&#34;&gt;Scaling to 12 Million Concurrent Connections: How MigratoryData Did It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://mrotaru.wordpress.com/2013/10/10/scaling-to-12-million-concurrent-connections-how-migratorydata-did-it/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mihai Rotaru on how MigratoryData scaled to 12 million concurrent connections in a 1U server. They explain what optimizations they did in order to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: migratorydata, mihai-rotaru, concurrent-connection, 1u-server, scalability, websocket&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-what-you-love&#34;&gt;Do what you love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/do-what-you-love-jorge-diaz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jorge Diaz on doing what takes you out of your comfort zone, changing careers, and life-work in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/scott_dinsmore_how_to_find_work_you_love/transcript?language=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TED talk: How to find work you love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jorge-diaz, work, life, career, comfort-zone, scott-dinsmore, career-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app&#34;&gt;JHipster - The best way to breed a new app&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/olbpetersson/jhipster-the-best-way-to-breed-a-new-app&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by Ola Petersson, where he describes the architecture and contents of the jHipster, its pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jhipster, ola petersson, java, code-generation, code-generator, microservice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-going-to-coding-events-helped-me-get-an-awesome-job&#34;&gt;How going to coding events helped me get an awesome job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/networking-at-meet-ups-getting-hired-f0f7c4f4681a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gwendolyn Faraday on how to kickstart a career in web development, attending events, pairing and networking. That netted her some interviews to start programming for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: networking, gwendolyn-faraday, event, job, learn-to-code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maze-generation-algorithm-recap&#34;&gt;Maze Generation: Algorithm Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2011/2/7/maze-generation-algorithm-recap&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of maze-generation algorithms by Jamis Buck. Including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recursive backtracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eller’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kruskal’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prim’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recursive division algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aldous-Broder algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilson’s algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hunt-and-Kill algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing Tree algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binary Tree algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidewinder algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: recursive-backtracker,eller-algorithm,kruskal-algorithm,prim-algorithm,recursive-division-algorithm,aldous-broder-algorithm,wilson-algorithm,hunt-and-kill-algorithm,growing-tree-algorithm,binary-tree-algorithm,sidewinder-algorithm, jamis-buck, maze, maze-generation, algorithm, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-poverty-of-constraints&#34;&gt;The Poverty of Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2016/3/19/poverty-of-constraints.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jamis Buck on interpreting two Korean proverbs in the world of software:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A dutiful son comes from a poor home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A poor house has many children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: proverb, korea, philosophy, software, constraint, jamis-buck&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>