<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>toolbox on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/toolbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in toolbox on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/toolbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On private but leaked information in a SaaS</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: how to uncorrelate public and private information.
Context Context: there are clients who have sensitive information. Some is just &amp;lsquo;companies being stealth&amp;rsquo; (e.g., don&amp;rsquo;t want to make public until launching), some is just protected by a Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA), some are protected by security clearance. The more sensitive, the greater protection needed. This tool applies to all sensitive information, regardless of where it&amp;rsquo;s stored or how it is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically keeping the intermediate history of your work using git</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/05/29/keeping-intermediate-history-work-git/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: using git to automatically document your development process (special cases only.)
Context When I&amp;rsquo;m spiking a feature, I usually get in the zone (e.g., Csikszentmihalyi&amp;rsquo;s Flow), and I can forget my good engineering practices, searching for that desired answer. After a few of those bouts of coding, you realize you&amp;rsquo;re wandering. You circle around, get lost, get back on track, then get lost again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
