<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/fault/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/fault/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;!--
## Gerald Weinberg on Bugs, Errors, and Software Quality

I&#39;ve listened to [this interview][bug-error-weinberg] with Gerald Weinberg where he first talks about software quality, defining a fault, failure, a boo-boo, a blunder (below). Then, they move on to the cost of quality, experiences in his project &#39;Mercury&#39; (a man in orbit; his contribution was on the software side). Says it&#39;s one of his first projects where a person&#39;s life was directly related to a piece of software.

Fault: wrong operation in code
Failure: user&#39;s experience caused by a fault
Boo-boo: a one-off, small failure. Usually shrugged as a small defect
Blunder: a one-off, big failure. Can kill a career

About the cost of software, he mentions that many managers are not willing to pay the price of almost defect-free software and that this level of quality is not required in every project. This idea is similar to the one &#39;Testing every part is akin to reading every letter on the newspaper: one parts are more important than other&#39;.

This interview talks about similar topics than &#39;Why programs fail&#39;, especially about the definition.

At the end of the interview, he talks about team-based software development (~XP) and an anecdote about a company he was consulting with: follow the process or pay the defects out of your own pocket. One of them, accepted paying for defects, until he made a big mistake. Accepted training the rest of the employees into his very precise methods and became very valuable to the company.

Tags: podcast, gerald-weinberg, quality, interview, manager, software-quality, definition, fault, failure, boo-boo, blunder, project-mercury

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;!--
## Microservice Practitioners with Austin Gunter and Richard Li

I&#39;ve listened to [this podcast][us-practitioners] at Software Engineering Daily with Austin Gunter and Richard Li. In it, they talk about how they have organized the conference &#39;Microservice Practicitioners&#39;: how to find speakers, the vibes of the conference, etc.

Tags: austin-gunter, richard-li, organize-a-conference, conference, microservice, microservice-practitioners, podcast, software-engineering-daily

TODO missing link

--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34;&gt;10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/derickbailey/10-myths-about-docker-that-stop-developers-cold&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this listicle&lt;/a&gt; of docker myths. By Derick Bailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bored-people-quit&#34;&gt;Bored People Quit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://randsinrepose.com/archives/bored-people-quit/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-lopp, boredness, team-management, people, career, tech-lead, quote&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose fault is this?</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/whose-fault-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/whose-fault-is-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the prologue of the book, while thanking everyone that has made the book possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;], none of the people mentioned here would be responsible for any inaccuracy that might exist in the book, as this responsibility is exclusively mine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi (translated)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, prologue of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Flow-The-Psychology-Optimal-Experience/dp/0061339202&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Flow&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(More posts on this same book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/flow
/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This connects with what &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/@tastapod&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dan North&lt;/a&gt; said in the Craft Conf about this idea of the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the only one in the company producing good quality work, the rest are not doing the same&amp;rdquo;. Of course, he was quoting greedy, selfish people who think this instead of attributing the success to the whole team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the whole team, if I recall correctly, it was &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/@svenpet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sven Peters&lt;/a&gt; who explained that &amp;ldquo;[&amp;hellip;] either the team wins or looses. There are no individual wins [&amp;hellip;]&amp;rdquo; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this sense, Csikszentmihalyi assumes all responsibility when quoting and reflecting on other&amp;rsquo;s works. It was his idea to develop on top of others, so any imperfection is his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is similar as when approving a pull request: you make sure that the code works and you stand by it. It is no longer the original owner&amp;rsquo;s cause, but yours too, as you have signed this request. On the pull request, though, the code ownership is already distributed among the whole team, but approvals ensures the presence of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/guardian-of-the-source
/&#34;&gt;guardian of the source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;I had to translate the quote, because I did not borrow the book in English
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;When the talks are available, we will be able the ensure the correct attribution of this idea.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>