<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>octopress on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/octopress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in octopress on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 23:39:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/octopress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Faster site generation with a native Octopress 2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/faster-site-generation-native-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 23:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/faster-site-generation-native-octopress/</guid>
      <description>Note: this article is an answer to a previous one, about the same topic: a tool for a faster site generation while developing / writing articles, using octopress 2.
Introduction Octopress 2 packs, out of the box, some tasks to speed up the site generation while you&amp;rsquo;re writing articles:
Isolate a post:
# usage rake isolate[my-post] desc &amp;#34;Move all other posts than the one currently being worked on to a temporary stash location (stash) so regenerating the site happens much more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.
Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology
BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias I&amp;rsquo;ve read this category of posts by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip: automate the blog publishing</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/tip-automate-the-blog-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 19:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/tip-automate-the-blog-publishing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve automated the generation of the blog using Travis CI. Using this new way, each commit generates a new version of the pages.
These resources have been very useful:
 Prose.io + Octopress + Travis-CI + GitHub Pages = ♥. First post (in this set) that explains how this automation is possible Auto-deploying to My Octopress Blog With Travis-CI. Explains how to generate your key, encript it with travis Octopress + GitHub Pages + Travis: The most useful page, explains step by step what to do for mac and linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster site generation for Octopress 2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/faster-site-generation-for-octopress-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 07:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/faster-site-generation-for-octopress-2/</guid>
      <description>2016-04 update: I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that the original Rakefile does a similar job. See here
After a while, the generation of the static site using Octopress 2 was starting to be slow (around 2 minutes for 85 posts) for the kind of fast feedback cycle I was expecting.
Inspired by their new features in Octopress 3, one of them being faster site generation, I decided to retrofit my installation with the same feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inserting clojure code in octopress</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/14/inserting-clojure-code-in-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 23:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/14/inserting-clojure-code-in-octopress/</guid>
      <description>Inserting this code in the blog:
```clojure (defn all-access[k] (let [{:keys [a b] :as k}] (do a) (do (:b k)))) ```  the octopress processor throws the error:
Error: Pygments can&#39;t parse unknown language: clojure Error: Run jekyll build --trace for more information.  A solution would be to include it as lisp code:
```lisp (defn all-access[k] (let [{:keys [a b] :as k}] (do a) (do (:b k)))) ```  this is an example:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
