<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Typos on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/typos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Typos on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:16:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/typos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of defects</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/14/types-of-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 16:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/14/types-of-defects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, while researching types of defects and the cost of fixing them&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I stumbled upon this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Years ago I worked with a bunch of economists in the US Federal Government - they categorized &amp;lsquo;bugs&amp;rsquo; in their memos into three types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typos: Simple misspellings of words. Infrequent, easy to detect, easy to fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writos: Incoherent sentences. More frequent, hard to detect, harder to fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thinkos: Conceptually bonkers. Very frequent, subtle and hard to detect; almost impossible to fix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most &amp;lsquo;late&amp;rsquo; bugs that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in software projects belong in the last category - a lack of design or the failure to make a working mock-up leads to &amp;lsquo;thinkos&amp;rsquo; which are only obvious when the application is nearly completed. These are expensive to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://developers.slashdot.org/story/03/10/21/0141215/software-defects---do-late-bugs-really-cost-more&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://developers.slashdot.org/story/03/10/21/0141215/software-defects---do-late-bugs-really-cost-more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also add a new category to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethos: Morally wrong, although possibly legal. These may take different forms: vary from a company to the next one,
from society to society, etc. Even harder to fix than &amp;lsquo;thinkos&amp;rsquo;,
as there is a reason (mainly economic) to keep them in place.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a technical note,
  these are not usually well-known artifacts in the company, therefore not everyone
  should know about them. Only a few developers know the correct reasons behind them and
  the rest might be sold a fake reason, so the latter cannot fix these &amp;lsquo;ethos&amp;rsquo;, as they
  assume they are present for a good reason&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;This is also a chapter in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/leprechauns&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Leprechauns of Software Engineering&lt;/a&gt; by Laurent Bossavit: &amp;lsquo;Chapter 10: The cost of defects: an illustrated history&amp;rsquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>