<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2017/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;volver&#34;&gt;¿Volver?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raulavila.com/2017/01/volver/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;donkey-code&#34;&gt;Donkey code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://einarwh.wordpress.com/2017/01/21/donkey-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: einar-host, donkey-code, ddd, domain-driven-development, domain, abstraction, missing-abstraction, business-logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men&#34;&gt;10 Habits That Change Boys Into Men&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/10-habits-that-change-boys-into-men-b103c47d47e0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on why some men are still boys (e.g., expectations from society) and what can boys do to turn into men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, psychology, learning, evolution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-sabbaticals&#34;&gt;On Sabbaticals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://indecorous.com/sabbaticals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about sabbaticals by Ian Malpass. In it, he explains why we need sabbaticals, how to take them, and some details about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you can’t take a sabbatical, you need to take your sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day-to-day work pushes us to think tactically; sabbaticals push us to think strategically. Both are valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work to gain confidence that you can be away, and then trust that that the mechanisms you put in place are good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because your team can function without you, doesn’t mean they want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is rarely a good time to leave work for an extended period of time - don’t let this stop you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow room for serendipity, the unexpected, and exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan for your return before you leave, to avoid worry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sabbatical process doesn’t end after six weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be unhappy or frustrated in your work to go on sabbatical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sabbatical, ian-malpass, team-management, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-favorite-command-line-utilities&#34;&gt;My favorite command-line utilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/macbook-my-command-line-utilities-f8a121c3b019#.3hpq7suhj&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Vitaly Belman in which he explains his curated list of utilities for the terminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: vitaly-belman, terminal, cli, application, utility, tig, git&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-common-mistakes-of-the-first-time-tech-lead&#34;&gt;Three Common Mistakes of the First Time Tech Lead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/three-common-mistakes-first-time-tech-lead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Kua, in which he explains what are the anti-patterns (or mistakes) of a tech lead. They do not only apply to first timers, but more experienced ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially like a comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take all blame and give all credit: I ensure I always take the blame from the stakeholders when something is broken but when they praise, I say its all my teams efforts and I am just guiding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com/by/ravensnowbird/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ravensnowbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: Patrick Kua, tech lead, leadership, team management, mistake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimental-versioning&#34;&gt;Sentimental Versioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://sentimentalversioning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (unknown author) on alternatives to semver (semantic versioning).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: semver, semantic-versioning, sentimental-versioning, humor, parody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;devoxx-2015-how-to-become-a-java-champion&#34;&gt;Devoxx 2015: How to Become a Java Champion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http//www.youtube.com/watch?v=otMc_3Dz3hU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Arun Gupta in which he explains what is a Java champion and how to become one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, arun-gupta, java-champion, devoxx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-i-become-a-champion-programmer&#34;&gt;How Can I Become a Champion Programmer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaspecialists.eu/archive/Issue227.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Heinz M. Kabutz on how to become a java champion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: heinz-kabutz, java-champion&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whatsapp-security-vulnerability&#34;&gt;WhatsApp Security Vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2017/01/whatsapp_securi.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;encrypted-email-service-once-used-by-edward-snowden-relaunches&#34;&gt;Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2017/01/20/encrypted-email-service-once-used-by-edward-snowden-to-relaunch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lavabit, kim-zetter, privacy, encryption, email, mail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-when-you-mix-java-with-a-1960-ibm-mainframe&#34;&gt;What Happens When You Mix Java with a 1960 IBM Mainframe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/happens-use-java-1960-ibm-mainframe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel about the legacy infrastructure of hardware that the U.S. government agencies have. How old mainframes are still useful to web applications and how these mainframes can communicate with more modern systems, through APIs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mainframe, david-cassel, marianne-bellotti, legacy-hardware, legacy-software, legacy-system, legacy, api&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;systems-we-love-how-the-past-informs-our-present&#34;&gt;Systems We Love: How the Past Informs Our Present&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenewstack.io/systems-we-love/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this experience report&lt;/a&gt; by David Cassel about the conference &amp;ldquo;Systems we love&amp;rdquo;: a mix of papers we love and systems that happened at San Francisco in December 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-cassel, systems-we-love, papers-we-love, system, conference, experience-report, joyent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-agonizing-death-of-an-astronaut&#34;&gt;The agonizing death of an astronaut&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.javaslang.io/the-agonizing-death-of-an-astronaut/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Dietrich on why the implementation of the &lt;code&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; in Javaslang seems to be broken but, in fact, follows the rules of the monads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains why &lt;code&gt;map&lt;/code&gt; should be used for non-changing contexts and &lt;code&gt;flatmap&lt;/code&gt; should be used for changing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: daniel-dietrich, monad, option, haskell, optional, maybe, scala, javaslang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-reverse-engineered-16k-apps-here-s-what-we-found&#34;&gt;We reverse engineered 16k apps, here’s what we found&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/we-reverse-engineered-16k-apps-heres-what-we-found-51bdf3b456bb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Fallible team, in which they describe the analysis of apps. They discovered 2500 apps with key and secret on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] whenever you hardcode any API key/token in the app, think hard if you really need to hardcode this, understand the API usage and the read/write scope of the tokens before putting it in the apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: analysis, security, app, key, token, api, fallible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oh-the-emails-you-ll-get&#34;&gt;Oh, the emails you’ll get&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2006/11/09/oh-the-emails-youll-get/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Joel Spolsky, in which he explains how some companies focus on some metrics for measuring performance, how difficult it is to measure performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joel-spolsky, performance, management, consulting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2002-07-15-measurement&#34;&gt;2002/07/15 - Measurement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/07/15/20020715/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Joel Spolsky where he explains how measuring performance is difficult, according to  Robert D. Austin in his book Measuring and Managing Performance in Organizations. He gives some examples of that, mainly about paying out bonuses for performance reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: joel-spolsky, robert-austin, measuring-performance, managing-performance, book, knowledge-worker, bonus, pay, performance, organization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-purpose-of-life-is-not-happiness-it-s-usefulness&#34;&gt;The Purpose Of Life Is Not Happiness: It’s Usefulness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://dariusforoux.com/happiness-usefulness/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Darius Foroux on what the purpose of life is about: making a difference (even if small) in what you leave behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: psychology, purpose-of-life, usefulness, happiness, darius-foroux&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-user-interfaces&#34;&gt;The Future of User Interfaces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://brandur.org/interfaces&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brandur on how interfaces are becoming more and more bloated, slow and ridden with animations. All of that is targeted to the beginner user, rather than the proficient one. He suggests some ideas on finding inspiration from the terminal applications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brandur, interface, interface-design, ux, ui&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-increasing-frustration-with-clojure&#34;&gt;My Increasing Frustration With Clojure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ashtonkemerling.com/blog/2016/06/11/my-increasing-frustration-with-clojure/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ashton Kemerling on the problems he has found working professionally with Clojure and some possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: clojure, language, ashton-kemerling, functional-programming, problem, frustration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-without-if&#34;&gt;Java Without If&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ashtonkemerling.com/blog/2017/01/26/java-without-if/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ashton Kemerling on how he is using a library called &amp;lsquo;lambda&amp;rsquo;, which brings some of the functional programming features to Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lambda, library, ashton-kemerling, functional-programming, java, palatable, john-napier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;top-ten-pull-request-review-mistakes&#34;&gt;Top ten pull request review mistakes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.scottnonnenberg.com/top-ten-pull-request-review-mistakes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Scott Nonnenberg on the most common mistakes while doing a code review in the context of a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scott-nonnenberg, pull-request, code-review, github, diff, listicle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shutting-down-simplicity-itself&#34;&gt;Shutting down Simplicity Itself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://daviddawson.me/blog/2017/02/04/simplicity-itself-shutdown.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Dawson on why he&amp;rsquo;s shutting down his consultancy company, Simplicity Itself, which was mainly focused on microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-dawson, simplicity-itself, shut-down, company, consulting, post-mortem, postmortem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turn-off-your-cellphone&#34;&gt;Turn Off Your Cellphone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://brandur.org/fragments/turn-off-your-cellphone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brandur on how to get more done by unplugging the notifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brandur, time-management, interruption, phone, notification&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dark-standup&#34;&gt;The Dark Standup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://18f.gsa.gov/2017/01/19/the-dark-standup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Brouilette on the steps they took to reduce the amount of hours worked. It started with a few extra questions during the daily standup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What didn’t you do today because you stopped working on time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will the impact be on tomorrow because of it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much more time would you have needed to get everything done today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will you do with those hours tonight instead?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and what they realized after a two-week experiment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The costs of context switching are much higher than we realized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We were spending a lot of time doing things that were urgent but not important, or that didn’t need to have been urgent at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We needed to be a lot more ruthless about saying “No.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some Operations roles are legitimately shorthanded, some of us just needed to impose a little order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOMO WIP (unnecessary work one takes on because one fears missing something) is a real problem, especially as regards to Slack and meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We worked better in the time we had to work, knowing it was finite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work-life balance improves both work and life. People literally slept better when limiting after-hours exposure to Slack and email. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dark-standup, quote, limited-time, overtime, team-management, experiment, question, alan-brouilette&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-means-to-be-a-remote-first-company&#34;&gt;What it Means to be a Remote-First Company&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stackoverflow.blog/code-for-a-living/what-it-means-to-be-a-remote-first-company&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by  Alyssa Mazzina on what Stack Overflow does to keep its remote employees happy, how they are a remote-first company and small practicalities like tools, holiday gifts and stipends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alyssa-mazzina, team-management, remote, remote-work, stack-overflow, team&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;google-s-not-so-secret-new-os&#34;&gt;Google’s not-so-secret new OS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techspecs.blog/blog/2017/2/14/googles-not-so-secret-new-os&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; describing the state of Google&amp;rsquo;s new operating system, Fuchsia or Andromeda (the final name is not final yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: google, os, operating-system, daniel-matte, fuchsia, andromeda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-secrets-of-people-who-finish-their-workweeks-on-thursday&#34;&gt;Four Secrets Of People Who Finish Their Workweeks On Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/3068122/work-smart/four-secrets-of-people-who-finish-their-workweeks-on-thursday&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Kat Boogaard that includes four tips to finish your week early:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Schedule Intentionally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Focus On Priorities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Tune Out Distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They Find Shortcuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kat-boogaard, time-management, eisenhower-productivity-matrix, urgent-vs-important, important-vs-urgent, urgent, important, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflecting-on-one-very-very-strange-year-at-uber&#34;&gt;Reflecting On One Very, Very Strange Year At Uber&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.susanjfowler.com/blog/2017/2/19/reflecting-on-one-very-strange-year-at-uber&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Susan J Fowler on some bad HR practices at Uber and how they are part of the reason their low percentage of women (3%) in the engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sexism, uber, susan-fowler, hr, human-resources, women, work-environment, review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ni-dioses-ni-reyes-sólo-el-hombre&#34;&gt;Ni dioses ni reyes. Sólo el hombre.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive1.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=860ccae5e2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish) by David Bonilla on which he talks about the God Mode and how that is implemented in different applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also liked this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los desarrolladores sólo somos herreros que forjan ceros y unos. Construimos herramientas para satisfacer necesidades de nuestros usuarios, sin que eso nos haga mejores que ellos o nos dé el derecho de supervisar y juzgar sus actos. A la hora de diseñar nuevos sistemas y funcionalidades, lo único que nunca deberíamos olvidar es que no somos dioses ni reyes, sólo hombres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rough translation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, developers, we are only blacksmiths of the digital era. We build tools to satisfy our user&amp;rsquo;s need, without that fact making us better than they are or without the right to overview what they do or to judge their acts. When designing new systems and features, the only thing we must never forget is that we are neither gods nor kings, just humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;las-tres-erres&#34;&gt;Las tres erres&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article (in Spanish) by David Bonilla in which he explains three necessary factors when considering a job offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referentes: es imposible conocer a toda la plantilla de una empresa, pero si conoces a dos o tres empleados clave, podrás hacerte una idea de cómo será el equipo que te vas a encontrar. La gente prefiere trabajar con compañeros que compartan su ética y valores. Yo conocía a casi toda la plantilla de Comalatech tras haber coincidido con unos y otros en distintos eventos… y aún hay gente que se pregunta para qué sirve ir a conferencias técnicas si en Internet “se puede encontrar todo”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referencias: es complicado, pero en el día a día una persona puede ser completamente diferente a la imagen que proyecta públicamente. Me ha pasado. Por eso es importante contar con referencias, terceras personas –antiguos empleados, clientes o proveedores- con las que haya trabajado. Los españoles no solemos pedirlas, pero para los anglosajones son un requisito imprescindible. En el caso de Comala, conseguí las mejores de la mejor fuente posible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retos: los profesionales trabajamos por dinero, pero a partir de cierto nivel de salario, podemos permitirnos el lujo de elegir un trabajo u otro según otros factores. En mi caso, siempre he priorizado por encima de todo el potencial de aprendizaje y, en ese sentido, Comalatech no tenía rival.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: referent, reference, challenge, david-bonilla, bonilista, change-job, job-offer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;translation-from-haskell-to-javascript-of-selected-portions-of-the-best-introduction-to-monads-i-ve-ever-read&#34;&gt;Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jcoglan.com/2011/03/05/translation-from-haskell-to-javascript-of-selected-portions-of-the-best-introduction-to-monads-ive-ever-read/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Coglan, introducing monads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About composability:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;symmetric input and output types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guide to basic monadic functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function
bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form
unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is a monad? Well, it’s a design pattern. It says that whenever you have a class of functions that accept one type of thing and return another type of thing, there are two functions that can be applied across this class to make them composable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt; function that transforms any function so that accepts the same type as it returns, making it composable
There is a &lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; function that wraps a value in the type accepted by the composable functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I]t’s a very useful design pattern to be aware of because it helps you spot accidental complexity: code that isn’t dealing directly with the problem at hand, but which is dealing with glueing data types together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: monad, monad-explanation, haskell, javascript, james-coglan, bind, unit, lift&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-could-have-invented-monads-and-maybe-you-already-have&#34;&gt;You Could Have Invented Monads! (And Maybe You Already Have.)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.sigfpe.com/2006/08/you-could-have-invented-monads-and.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Piponi, in which he slowly introduces monads, using examples from everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-piponi, monad, monad-explanation, haskell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-one&#34;&gt;Monads, part one&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/21/monads-part-one/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes monads as a design pattern that &amp;ldquo;can sneak up on you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-two&#34;&gt;Monads, part two&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/25/monads-part-two/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes monad examples in the C# code. Also describes what an &amp;lsquo;amplifier&amp;rsquo; is. I relate it to composing behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &amp;ldquo;amplifier&amp;rdquo; is something that increases the representational power of their &amp;ldquo;underlying&amp;rdquo; type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, amplifier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-three&#34;&gt;Monads, part three&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/02/28/monads-part-three/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes how to wrap a value in a monadic wrapper (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-four&#34;&gt;Monads, part four&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/04/monads-part-four/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the second function (&lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-five&#34;&gt;Monads, part five&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/07/monads-part-five/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the three laws, which are later compressed into two (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-six&#34;&gt;Monads, part six&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/11/monads-part-six/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains the logical identity of applying the function inside a monad and outside a monad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-seven&#34;&gt;Monads, part seven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/14/monads-part-seven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he states the three laws of monads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying the construction function to a given instance of the monad produces a logically identical instance of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying a function to the result of the construction function on a value, and applying that function to the value directly, produces two logically identical instances of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applying to a value a first function followed by applying to the result a second function, and applying to the original value a third function that is the composition of the first and second functions, produces two logically identical instances of the monad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-eight&#34;&gt;Monads, part eight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/18/monads-part-eight/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes the monad terms he was using other, more common names (&lt;code&gt;unit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-nine&#34;&gt;Monads, part nine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/21/monads-part-nine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he creates a &lt;code&gt;Tainted&lt;/code&gt; monad, which is basically a &lt;code&gt;Nullable&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Maybe&lt;/code&gt; monad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-ten&#34;&gt;Monads, part ten&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/25/monads-part-ten/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes &lt;code&gt;Where&lt;/code&gt; (as the query syntax form) using the &lt;code&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt; signature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-eleven&#34;&gt;Monads, part eleven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/03/28/monads-part-eleven/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he describes the &amp;ldquo;additive monad&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a zero value of every construction of the monadic type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a way to add two monads with the same underlying type together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The zero value is the identity of the add operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bind to apply any function to the zero produces the zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bind to apply the function &lt;code&gt;a=&amp;gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; to any &lt;code&gt;M&amp;lt;A&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; produces the zero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, additive-monad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-twelve&#34;&gt;Monads, part twelve&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/04/02/monads-part-twelve/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he explains how the &lt;code&gt;SelectMany&lt;/code&gt; could be implemented (but it is not implemented in practice)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;monads-part-thirteen&#34;&gt;Monads, part thirteen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericlippert.com/2013/04/03/monads-part-thirteen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Lippert, in which he suggests reading a similar article on the Task comonad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-lippert, monad, monad-explanation, c-sharp, functional-programming, comonad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tasks-monads-and-linq&#34;&gt;Tasks, Monads, and LINQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/pfxteam/2013/04/03/tasks-monads-and-linq/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Toub in which he explains the comonad &lt;code&gt;Task&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A comonad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] dual of a monad, a triple consisting of the type and two operators: &lt;code&gt;Extract&lt;/code&gt; (the flip of &lt;code&gt;Unit&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Return&lt;/code&gt;) and &lt;code&gt;Extend&lt;/code&gt; (the flip of &lt;code&gt;Bind&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comonad, monad, monad-explanation, stephen-toub, c-sharp, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-questions-every-unit-test-must-answer&#34;&gt;5 Questions Every Unit Test Must Answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/what-every-unit-test-needs-f6cd34d9836d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; (titled as a listicle) by Eric Elliot about unit tests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are you testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should it do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the actual output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the expected output?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can the test be reproduced?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-elliott, javascript, unit-test, test&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-should-be-planning-for-2018-not-2017&#34;&gt;Why You Should be Planning for 2018, Not 2017.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/the-mission/why-you-should-be-planning-for-2018-not-2017-7c8fea3e2e52&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin P. Hardy on motivation, planning and designing your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some quotes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] having the power to make choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The responsibility to choose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The results of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] hope reflects your perceptions regarding your capacity to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearly conceptualize goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;develop the specific strategies to reach those goals (i.e., pathways thinking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;initiate and sustain the motivation for using those strategies (i.e., agency thinking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;] motivation involves three components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the value you place on your goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your belief that specific behaviors will actually facilitate the outcomes you desire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your belief in your own ability to successfully execute the behaviors requisite to achieving your goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benjamin-hardy, motivation, life, planning, long-term-plans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-5-better&#34;&gt;Get 5% Better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2016/03/five-percent-better/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, in which the author explains how compound interest does not only apply to investing and saving but also personal improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kaizen, personal-improvement, compound-interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hunter-s-thompson-s-letter-on-finding-your-purpose-and-living-a-meaningful-life&#34;&gt;Hunter S. Thompson’s Letter on Finding Your Purpose and Living a Meaningful Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.farnamstreetblog.com/2014/05/hunter-s-thompson-to-hume-logan/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; from Hunter S. Thompson to his friend Hume Logan, containing advice on living your own life: must find your own way, decide between floating or swimming to your goal and strive to be yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: hunter-thompson, hume-logan, advice, psychology, life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-japanese-philosophy-of-kaizen-offers-an-effective-manageable-way-to-achieve-long-term-goals&#34;&gt;The Japanese philosophy of Kaizen offers an effective, manageable way to achieve long-term goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/867711/the-japanese-philosophy-of-kaizen-offers-an-effective-manageable-way-to-achieve-long-term-goals/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Oppong on kaizen, or continuous improvement, and how it applies like compound interest to your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kaizen, continous-improvement, thomas-oppong, compound-interest, life, psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-a-software-interview&#34;&gt;Preparing for a Software Interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://42hire.com/preparing-for-a-software-interview-6d0392a3d72c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alvaro Videla on interviewing technical people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: recruitement, interviewing, interview, alvaro-videla&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-recursive-data-structures&#34;&gt;Why Recursive Data Structures?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://raganwald.com/2016/12/27/recursive-data-structures.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this essay&lt;/a&gt; by Reginald “Raganwald” Braithwaite, on which he introduces the relationship between data structures and algorithms. Explains how the algorithm can be split into parts, following the data structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses a library containing a function called &lt;code&gt;multirec&lt;/code&gt; for recursion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackage.haskell.org/package/multirec&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a candidate&lt;/a&gt; library, in haskell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lazutkin.com/blog/2008/06/30/using-recursion-combinators-javascript/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;another candidate&lt;/a&gt; library, in javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: reginald-braithwaite, recursive-data-structure, quadtree, javascript, functional-programming, essay, data-structure, isomorphic, tree, multirec, linrec, tailrec, haskell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leading-by-example&#34;&gt;Leading by Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/leading-by-example/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on how the best leadership comes from doing, rather than telling how to do it. From being a leader rather than being a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests further reads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leadership, team-lead, leading-by-example, jeff-atwood, gerald-weinberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discipline-makes-strong-developers&#34;&gt;Discipline Makes Strong Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.codinghorror.com/discipline-makes-strong-developers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Atwood on a project sucess should not be attributed to a language or framework, but to the team&amp;rsquo;s and individuals&amp;rsquo; discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explains how small projects require different levels of discipline than large projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leadership, discipline, nasa, code-complete, coding-horror, jeff-atwood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;effectively-integrating-into-software-development-teams&#34;&gt;Effectively Integrating Into Software Development Teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dennisforbes.ca/index.php/2006/01/29/effectively-integrating-into-software-development-teams/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dennis Forbes about authority and discipline in a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One organization’s Enterprise solution is another organization’s short sighted mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: shiny, dennis-forbes, discipline, authority, psychology, politics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>