<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Lazarillo de Tormes, el; anónimo; non-technical Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s power plays - Politika; Preisler; own-it, non-technical Moon is a harsh mistress, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Old man&amp;rsquo;s war; Scalzi; non-technical, own-it Nightfall; Asimov, Silverberg; own-it, non-technical Interface; Stephenson, George; non-technical, own-it Man who sold the moon, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Agents of innocence; Ignatius; own-it, non-technical Fist of god, the; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical: Synopsis: in a mixture of truth and novel, the author explains the invasion of Kuwait by Iraqi dictator Sadam Hussein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/01/self-study-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/01/self-study-december-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in November 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/self-study-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/11/01/self-study-november-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/10/01/self-study-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/10/01/self-study-october-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 the senior software developer; Copeland, with the aprendices reading club Scandal in Bohemia, a; Doyle: a short novel by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, mentioning Irene Adler and the king of Bohemia Getting things done, &amp;hellip;; Allen (+): A book on productivity, where Allen explains his method of GTD and how to apply it. Explains what has worked and not worked for him in his many years of consulting and coaching clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/01/self-study-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/01/self-study-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>How the Clipboard Works, Part 1 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Matt Burrough, on how the clipboard works on windows.
Explains how the API works and how the different formats and priorities are organized so the new application can decide which format to accept.
Tags: windows, clipboard, matt-burrough, format, copy-paste
Top developers can have a life outside coding I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Belen Albeza on how top coders don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend all their time programming or with activities related to programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>How I ended up paying $150 for a single 60GB download from Amazon Glacier I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Marko Karppinen that explains how a mistake in understanding the pricing model of AWS Glacier cost 150$ instead of the expected 0.86$
 When cloud providers use uncommon and/or unpredictable pricing models, even your informed hunch about the cost can be off by several orders of magnitude, like the price differential between an iPad and a Ferrari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>A Brief History of the UUID I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rick Branson on the history of UUID. Describes the history of uid, uuid, early computing (both networked and not networked) and their own implementation of a uuid library
Tags: uuid, uid, flake, snowflake, ksuid, go, golang, rick-branson, library, implementation-history
More data, more data I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how cloudflare manages its logs. By Hunter Blanks
Tags: log, cloudflare, comparison, what-worked, what-did-not-work, kafka, citusdb, sre, site-reliability-engineering, analytics, hunter-blanks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</guid>
      <description>(I&amp;rsquo;ve changed how I organize my books. More, here (TODO))
Finished:
 Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern; non-technical. A quick introduction to Bertrand Russell, his life and his way of thinking and seeing the world. Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell; non-technical. A first-person view of the events during the Spanish Civil War (1936-1939), seen from the perspective of a British citizen that went there voluntarily. Explains the internal fracture of the left political parties and the fracture of the Spanish society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/01/self-study-june-2017/</guid>
      <description>So Hey You Should Stop Using Texts for Two-Factor Authentication I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining why messages over SMS should not be used for the &amp;lsquo;what you own&amp;rsquo; in 2FA.
Tags: andy-greenberg, 2fa, sms, security, warning
Why I&amp;rsquo;d never work for Google, Twitter, or Facebook I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by David Bryant Copeland on why he would never work for these three companies: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t share the principles and values from these companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>The real reason why the Spotify model is broken I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify
Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty
[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:
 Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/04/01/self-study-in-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>10 Myths About Docker That Stop Developers Cold I&amp;rsquo;ve read this listicle of docker myths. By Derick Bailey
Tags: derick-bailey, docker, myth
Bored People Quit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Michael Lopp on what are some mechanisms why bored people quit.
Some interesting quotes:
 My gig is the care and feeding of engineers, and their productivity is my productivity. If they all leave, I have exactly no job.
  My job isn’t just building product; I also build people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
  The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/01/self-study-in-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>¿Volver? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Raul Avila comparing the options between working in the UK and in Spain (where he&amp;rsquo;s originally from). Inspired by other professionals (e.g., David Bonilla, Jerónimo Palacios).
Tags: spanish, jeronimo-palacios, david-bonilla, expat, comparison, raul-avila, united-kingdom, spain
Donkey code I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Einar W. Høst in which he introduces the concept of a &amp;lsquo;missing domain term&amp;rsquo; with the example of a donkey being &amp;lsquo;closely related to a horse, though not exactly the same&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Coglan, introducing monads.
About composability:
 The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable
 or
 symmetric input and output types
 Guide to basic monadic functions:
 lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
