<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communication on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communication on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/08/01/self-study-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>How I ended up paying $150 for a single 60GB download from Amazon Glacier I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Marko Karppinen that explains how a mistake in understanding the pricing model of AWS Glacier cost 150$ instead of the expected 0.86$
 When cloud providers use uncommon and/or unpredictable pricing models, even your informed hunch about the cost can be off by several orders of magnitude, like the price differential between an iPad and a Ferrari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/01/self-study-in-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>The real reason why the Spotify model is broken I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Sharky Laguana, comparing several royalty models for spotify
Tags: sharky-laguana, spotify, comparison, royalty
[Day 3 of 7] &amp;ldquo;Badass&amp;rdquo; developer gets a RUDE awakening I&amp;rsquo;ve read this email that John Sonmez sends, about being a programmer vs a language programmer. Some quotes:
 Someone who could tear apart complex, confusing puzzles and engineer elegant, reliable solutions&amp;hellip; whether those challenges were software, hardware or &amp;ldquo;wetware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
