<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>antipattern on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/antipattern/</link>
    <description>Recent content in antipattern on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/antipattern/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching on a suite of failing tests</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/13/searching-on-a-suite-of-failing-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 16:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/13/searching-on-a-suite-of-failing-tests/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Today, at a client, in the green phase, we had a test suite which was failing: the whole suite fails but the test cases, individually, succeed.
So my first impression was that something was being shared between tests. Also confirmed because the failing class was an EndToEnd test, in which we load the whole spring context
A quick glance was not revealing anything interesting, so I decided to find which is the minimum suite (as opposed as to the whole suite) that makes the new testcase fail, expecting to narrow the search for possible causes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
