<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/office/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;until-the-end-of-the-internet&#34;&gt;Until the End of the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/until-the-end-of-the-internet-405d55fde60f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-agile-principles-can-fund-your-start-up&#34;&gt;How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/how-agile-principles-can-fund-your-start-up&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one. This works both ways: for buying and for selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests using a base plus the amount of sales in the last year * a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  jurgen-appelo, investment, startup, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-fell-in-love-with-a-programming-language&#34;&gt;How I fell in love with a programming language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.signalvnoise.com/how-i-fell-in-love-with-a-programming-language-8933d5e749ed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Kim on the feelings of love and comfort he feels when he&amp;rsquo;s programming in Kotlin, for Android. Tells the story of DHH and the love of Ruby as a similar one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-kim, dhh, ruby, love-of-language, kotlin, android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-writing-for-the-busy-programmer&#34;&gt;Book writing for the busy programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://gigasquidsoftware.com/blog/2016/06/19/book-writing-for-the-busy-programmer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Carin Meier on what tools she found useful for writing, editing and publishing a science fiction book she was writing for her daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tool, pandoc, carin-meier, book, book-writing, book-editing, book-publishing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-two-and-three-factor-authentication&#34;&gt;one-, two-, and three-factor authentication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://pciguru.wordpress.com/2010/05/01/one-two-and-three-factor-authentication/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jeff Hall, that explains the factors in multi-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jeff-hall, ofa, 2fa, mfa, one-factor-authentication, two-factor-authentication, multi-factor-authentication, pci-guru, security, authentication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scaling-agile-a-law-and-two-paradoxes&#34;&gt;Scaling Agile: A Law And Two Paradoxes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://asprotunity.com/blog/scaling-agile-a-law-and-two-paradoxes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Giovanni Asproni about agile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamental law of scaling: Scaling up amplifies the bad and makes the good more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First paradox of scaling: Most projects are scaled up because they don’t fulfill the prerequisites for scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second paradox of scaling: Projects fulfilling the prerequisites for scaling have a lesser need to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;quote&gt;Giovanni Asproni&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also goes on to explain ten prerequisites for scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: scaled-agile, agile, giovanni-asproni, paradox, law&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carta-abierta-a-ese-empresario-que-no-encuentra-talento&#34;&gt;Carta abierta a ese empresario que no encuentra talento&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/espanol/carta-abierta-a-ese-empresario-que-no-encuentra-talento-669e28e4a89b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ignacio Segura reacting to a previous article about job offer and demand. Ignacio explains how the job market can be modeled and how workers have found ways of selling their time to the best price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ignacio-segura, analogy, job-offer, job, job-market, economy, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;david-dill-why-online-voting-is-a-danger-to-democracy&#34;&gt;David Dill: Why Online Voting Is a Danger to Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.stanford.edu/news/david-dill-why-online-voting-danger-democracy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to David Dill on why the online voting is not a good idea and we should stick to paper as the golden rule for voting processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how difficult is to convince people of the technical limitations and the massive incentive it would be to hack into election systems / services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, david-dill, online-voting, limitation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;clojure-gazette-tdd-in-clojure-on-android&#34;&gt;Clojure Gazette - TDD in Clojure on Android&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us4.campaign-archive2.com/?u=a33b5228d1b5bf2e0c68a83f4&amp;amp;id=7023cf0a33&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; to Alexander Yakushev, about his Google Summer of Code and the project he is currently working on: Clojure-android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: interview, clojure-gazette, alexander-yakushev, google-summer-of-code, gsoc, clojure, tdd, android&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-will-github-be-in-5-years&#34;&gt;What Will GitHub Be in 5 years?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/ben/what-will-github-be-in-5-years&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that describes the current state of Github business and the possible solutions in the upcoming five years. By Ben Halpern&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ben-halpern, github, economy, startup, investment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;serverless-architectures&#34;&gt;Serverless Architectures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/serverless.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this evolving article&lt;/a&gt; by Mike Roberts on what is and is not Serverless: [mobile] backend as a service or function as a service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Converts some n-tier applications into serverless ones, expliciting that this is only a way of doing it, not necessarily the way he would do it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: faas, baas, mbass, function-as-a-service, backend-as-a-service, mobile-backend-as-a-service, serverless, evolving-article, mike-roberts, lambda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;big-co-vs-small-co-job-vs-career-stability&#34;&gt;Big co. vs small co. &amp;amp; job vs. career stability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catehuston.com/blog/2016/06/02/job-vs-career-stability/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Cate Huston on the career and job stability that big companies and small companies can offer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job security means that you know you will keep getting a paycheck from $company. Career security means that you know you can get another job, and develop yourself and your career in the way that is meaningful to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: job-security, cate-huston, big-company, small-company, career-security, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;copy-paste-code&#34;&gt;Copy. Paste. Code?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.devmastery.com/copy-paste-code-6ed9bb841cd4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Sourour on the different point of view of solving questions in coding many years ago compared to nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also explores the concept of copy pasting code without understanding it, explaining that the endgame is writing good code that works and is easy to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: copy-paste, bill-sourour, clean-code, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-so-many-developers-hate-recruiters&#34;&gt;Why so many developers hate recruiters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-tech-recruiter-red-pill-967dd492560c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson on how recruiters for the IT sector work and how to work with them for your best possible outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: career, professional-career, recruitment, recruiter, agent, hiring, quincy-larson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-time-someone-posts-one-of-these-coding-is-over-essays-on-medium-they-undo-a-good-chunk-of&#34;&gt;Every time someone posts one of these “coding is over” essays on Medium, they undo a good chunk of…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@quincylarson/every-time-someone-posts-one-of-these-coding-is-over-essay-on-medium-they-undo-a-good-chunk-of-b7989849390b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Quincy Larson on why we should not tell others about their choosing of learning programming, and every time we do, some doors close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: answer, learn-coding, related-to-article, quincy-larson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;29-behaviors-that-will-make-you-an-unstoppable-programmer&#34;&gt;29 Behaviors That Will Make You An Unstoppable Programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kenmazaika/29-behaviors-that-will-make-you-an-unstoppable-programmer-8778941d80f7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tricks to become a be a better programmer. By Ken Mazaika&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Google very aggressively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain an obnoxious amount of stick-to-itiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that micro-decisions matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that most major decisions don’t matter that much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always use the right tool for the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand that code is cheap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate technologies based on all their merits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say “I don’t know.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always analyze the clues found in error messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the difference between a premature optimization and a show-stopping optimization that NEEDS to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take responsibility for your mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become a power-user of your development tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know how to use Vim (at least a little bit).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never accept freelance work in an unfamiliar technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t count the number of hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absorb massive criticism with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pair program with people with more experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always code review your own work first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize that the hard part of freelancing isn’t writing the code. It’s everything else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and resolve bigger issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into large open source projects to bring your features to life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip a lot of meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know when it’s time to give back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be capable of writing bad code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let other people know that you’re working late without being a jerk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act as a leader, not a boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go play foosball.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn under pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Move fast and break things.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ken-mazaika, list, unbeateable-programmer, unstoppable-programmer, efficiency, 10x, tip-and-trick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;como-melhorar-seus-códigos-usando-object-calisthenics-portuguese&#34;&gt;Como melhorar seus códigos usando Object Calisthenics (Portuguese)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/coderockr-way/como-melhorar-seus-c%C3%B3digos-usando-object-calisthenics-444daf3e2e06&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about object calisthenics, with an example in PHP. By Elton Minetto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: object-calisthenics, elton-minetto, php, portuguese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-this-story-without-distraction-can-you&#34;&gt;Read This Story Without Distraction (Can You?)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/01/fashion/monotasking-drop-everything-and-read-this-story.html?action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=Fashion%20%26%20Style&amp;amp;module=RelatedCoverage&amp;amp;region=Marginalia&amp;amp;pgtype=article&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Verena von Pfetten on the effects on multitasking in our daily lives. Also comments on the movement of monotasking or unitasking, which is the opposite of multitasking: doing one thing at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underlines the benefits of monotasking and how this is related to mindfulness and psychological benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: multitasking, monotasking, unitasking, verena-von-pfetten, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debuggers-are-a-wasteful-timesink&#34;&gt;Debuggers are a wasteful Timesink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artima.com/weblogs/viewpost.jsp?thread=23476&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Robert C. Martin on why we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use debuggers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uncle-bob, robert-martin, debugger, tdd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;taming-the-steamroller-how-to-communicate-compassionately-with-non-native-english-speakers&#34;&gt;Taming the steamroller: how to communicate compassionately with non-native English speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mollyclare/taming-the-steamroller-how-to-communicate-compassionately-with-non-native-english-speakers-d95d8d1845a0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Molly Clare Wilson on tips on how native English speakers can simplify their communication so it is easier for non-native speakers to understand them. Provides guidelines for situations involving &amp;lsquo;speaking and presenting&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;meetings&amp;rsquo;, written form &amp;lsquo;email, text, chat&amp;rsquo; and about correction each others English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: molly-wilson, english, communication, native, non-native, guideline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blue-no-yellow&#34;&gt;Blue. No! Yellow!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/05/21/BlueNoYellow.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; with Robert C. Martin on the productivity increases that different languages provide to the programmer. He says that no language can provide an effect as big as binary to assembler and that we&amp;rsquo;re currently searching the Holy Grail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-martin, uncle-bob, language, comparison, assembler, binary, clojure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-time-development-teams-chose-their-own-working-environments&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Time Development Teams Chose Their Own Working Environments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://codemanship.co.uk/parlezuml/blog/?postid=1383&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Gorman on how takes the decision of working environments and why having other options are financially available. How developers should be in charge of their own working environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: office, working-environment, jason-gorman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-my-1-200-hackintosh&#34;&gt;Building My $1,200 Hackintosh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/building-my-1-200-hackintosh-49a1a186241e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to build a powerful hackintosh. By Mike Rundle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mike-rundle, hackintosh, macintosh, mac, computer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-practical-guide-to-becoming-a-professional-web-developer&#34;&gt;The Practical Guide to Becoming a Professional Web Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-practical-guide-to-becoming-a-professional-web-developer-2f255bc25c90&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Sourour on how to become a web developer. Explains all kind of resources, from learning javascript, deciding on being a frontend of backend developer, which language to choose, how to find a job, getting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bill-sourour, guide, career, beginner, developer, web, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hiring-is-so-hard-in-tech&#34;&gt;Why Hiring is So Hard in Tech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/javascript-scene/why-hiring-is-so-hard-in-tech-c462c3230017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Elliot on how to tackle job interviews, both from the side of the employer and the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: eric-elliot, job-interview, employee, employer, cv, career, professional-career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-node-js-with-brigadier-fluffykins-part-ii-events-eventemitter-and-the-event-loop&#34;&gt;Learn Node.js with Brigadier Fluffykins Part II: Events, EventEmitter and the Event Loop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/learn-node-js-with-brigadier-fluffykins-part-ii-events-eventemitter-the-event-loop-6d4c139694fb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Masha Diminsky on the architecture of javascript and nodejs. Explains the event-driven architecture, the events and the event loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: masha-diminsky, bus, nodejs, javascript, bus, event-loop, event&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-in-6-seconds-how-to-write-a-résumé-that-employers-will-actually-read&#34;&gt;You in 6 seconds: how to write a résumé that employers will actually read&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/you-in-6-seconds-how-to-write-a-r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9-that-employers-will-actually-read-fd7757740802&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that suggests how to customize your cv for maximum engagement from interviewers / head hunters and to make the most of the 6 seconds they (allegedly) spend looking at your cv. Also explains some techniques for preparing the interview, about the cover letter, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: quincy-larson, cv, resume, career, professional-career, ats&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deliberate-practice-what-it-is-and-why-you-need-it&#34;&gt;Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four essential components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailored (practice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetion
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language&#34;&gt;10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jooq.org/2016/03/31/10-features-i-wish-java-would-steal-from-the-kotlin-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list of features&lt;/a&gt; that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language. By Lukas Eder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: list, lukas-eder, kotlin, java, comparison, language, jooq&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-built-uber-engineering-s-highest-query-per-second-service-using-go&#34;&gt;How we built Uber engineering&amp;rsquo;s highest query per second service using Go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.uber.com/go-geofence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; by Kai Wei on a microservice they&amp;rsquo;ve built using Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the reasons for choosing that algorithm for geofencing, the performance they&amp;rsquo;re achieving, and the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uber, go, microservice, performance, geofence, geofencing, rps, go-memory-model, kai-wei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service&#34;&gt;Unwinding Uber&amp;rsquo;s Most Efficient Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@buckhx/unwinding-uber-s-most-efficient-service-406413c5871d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Buck Heroux commenting on the decisions of Uber for building the geofencing microservice (above read).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the different alternatives for algorithms in this problem space and has implemented them in go. Provides a benchmark for comparing those, including a profiling session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: s2, quadtree, rtree, brute-force, geofence, geofencing, uber, comment, buck-heroux, go, read-on-read, meta-read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lawful-hacking-and-continuing-vulnerabilities&#34;&gt;Lawful Hacking and Continuing Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2016/03/lawful_hacking_.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Bruce Schneier on the stance the FBI is taking in regards to vulnerabilities discovered in Apple&amp;rsquo;s devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bruce-schneier, apple, security, fbi, vulnerability, exploit, law, hacking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-life-learning&#34;&gt;A Side Project Helped Jumpstart My Career — Life Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/life-learning/a-side-project-helped-jumpstart-my-career-7cd6f8e9b07f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dave Gerhardt on how making a side project happen affected his life and his skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the reasons for doing it include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It forces you to figure stuff out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only way to learn is by doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gets your brain working on something other than your job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to create your own network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are the CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: long-life-learning, continuous-learning, side-project, dave-gerhardt, drift, professional-development, personal-development, business, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun-jekyll-tricks&#34;&gt;Fun Jekyll Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.madebymarket.com/blog/dev/fun-jekyll-tricks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brian Knapp where he explains some tips and tricks of jekyll (in which octopress is based on): speed, deployment, subcategories inside the blog, _data, _includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brian-knapp, jekyll, octopress, tip-and-trick, improvement, subcategory, meta, automation, deployment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-ola-que-llega&#34;&gt;La ola que llega&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;amp;id=f8a8ee92cc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this bonilista&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla, where he explains (in Spanish) the &amp;lsquo;contractor&amp;rsquo; phenomenon arriving to Spain, 2-3 years after being in other countries and the effects that this could have both for workers and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bonilista, david-bonilla, contractor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-razones-por-las-que-este-sábado-deberías-ir-a-un-code-retreat&#34;&gt;10 razones por las que este sábado deberías ir a un code retreat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://francho.org/2015/11/10/10-razones-para-ir-a-un-coderetreat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of reasons for attending a code retreat, by Francho Joven, who I met in the Global Day Of Code Retreat (GDCR) &amp;lsquo;15 in Zaragoza&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: francho-joven, list, zaragoza, code-retreat, gdcr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meaningful-work-through-passion-not-genius&#34;&gt;Meaningful Work through Passion, not Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pIYUMwxKFzo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; on the importance of hard work and how it can be mistaken as genious. By Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: malcolm-gladwell, passion, genius, work, time-management, productivity, career, mastery-autonomy-purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name&#34;&gt;How to ask your wife for permission to spend $250,000 on a domain name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Stockphoto.com/how-to-ask-your-wife-for-permission-to-spend-250-000-on-a-domain-name-c27a3c2852e1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jon Yau on how they started StockPhoto.com, buying a $250,000 domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: startup, domain, stockphoto, jon-yau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong&#34;&gt;Sorry, developer bootcamps: I was wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@dillonforrest/sorry-developer-bootcamps-i-was-wrong-ea37fcc5572c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Dillon Forrest on the topic of developer bootcamps. Explains why developers should not be threatened by recent graduates of these programs and describes how people pursuing these programs usually are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-investment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth trajectory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: bootcamp, developer-bootcamp, dev-bootcamp, dillon-forrest, intelligence, risk-appetite, resilience, self-investment, entrepreneurship, growth-trajectory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-jvm-and-java-garbage-collection&#34;&gt;The JVM and Java Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoJr5QQYsl8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this webcast&lt;/a&gt; about how the JVM garbage collection works. By Michael W Williams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-williams, oracle, webcast, jvm, garbage-collection, gc,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;files-are-hard&#34;&gt;Files Are Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/file-consistency/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on why software that writes on files is difficult, based on the different filesystems that are below, and the operating system. Written by Dan Luu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses software product to find bugs in filesystems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: filesystem, file, dan-luu, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusión-inquebrantable&#34;&gt;Contrata a un fracasado con ilusión inquebrantable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.contunegocio.es/tecnologia/contrata-a-un-fracasado-con-ilusion-inquebrantable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alberto Mena (in Spanish) on what are the qualities that define a good programmer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;illusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-mena, spanish, team-management, success, developer, quality, developer-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-react&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t react&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.avdi.org/2016/04/14/dont-react/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Avdi Grimm on how the action vs reaction attitude. Why to prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: action, reaction, social-media, avdi-grimm, productivity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34;&gt;FTP is so 90&amp;rsquo;s. Let&amp;rsquo;s deploy via Git instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderwall.com/p/xczkaq/ftp-is-so-90-s-let-s-deploy-via-git-instead&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; on how to deploy using git. By Kerrick Long&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: kerrick-long, git, deployment, webapp, application, devops&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-vs-career-10-key-differences-you-need-to-understand&#34;&gt;Job vs Career: 10 Key Differences You Need To Understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/job-vs-career&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what differentiates a job from a career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, infographic, job-vs-career, comparison, job, career&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-secret-to-employee-motivation&#34;&gt;The Secret To Employee Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.officevibe.com/blog/secret-employee-motivation-infographic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infographic and the article&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Shriar on what motivates employess: mastery, autonomy and purpose. A direct reference to Dan Pink&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The puzzle of motivation&amp;rdquo; TED talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jacob-shriar, motivation, employee, infographic, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-puzzle-of-motivation&#34;&gt;The puzzle of motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; by Dan Pink on what motivates us: intrinsic vs extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about the gap that exists between what science knows and what businesses propose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ted, ted-talk, video, dan-pink, mastery, autonomy, purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count&#34;&gt;Applying a ceiling to the bug count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://techblog.king.com/applying-a-ceiling-to-the-bug-count/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;, written by Susanna Berg, on how King has reduced the amount of bugs in their backlog using an agile technique, measuring and setting a limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: susanna-berg, king, agile, bug, bug-count, defect, defect-count, per-malmen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34;&gt;Coming up in 2016: Spring Framework 4.3 &amp;amp; 5.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://spring.io/blog/2015/08/03/coming-up-in-2016-spring-framework-4-3-5-0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this announcement&lt;/a&gt; of Spring&amp;rsquo;s new release, 5.0, which will require java 8 and will turn most of the features into the reactive programming paradigm. By Juergen Hoeller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: juergen-hoeller, spring, reactive-programming, release, announcement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die&#34;&gt;Why offices are where work goes to die&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swizec.com/blog/why-offices-are-where-work-goes-to-die/swizec/6695&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Swizec Teller explaining the downsides of working in an office as compared to working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: swizec-teller, remote, home-office, office, comparison, time-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Passionate Developer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@bm2yogi/the-myth-of-the-passionate-developer-76a41d457304&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Ibarra on what are the implications of being a passionate developer, how it affects your tasks and what are the factors to a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michael-ibarra, passion, development, job, motivation, myth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mossack-fonseca-breach-wordpress-revolution-slider-plugin-possible-cause&#34;&gt;Mossack Fonseca Breach – WordPress Revolution Slider Plugin Possible Cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wordfence.com/blog/2016/04/mossack-fonseca-breach-vulnerable-slider-revolution/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Maunder, which describes an hypothesis on how the Mossack Fonseca breach could have happened. Also describes and shows how to breach a Wordpress installation with a vulnerable Revolution Slider plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mark-maunder, security, breach, mossack-fonseca-breach, mossack-fonseca, hypothesis, attack, plugin, revolution-slider, wordpress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tim-urban-inside-the-mind-of-a-master-procrastinator&#34;&gt;Tim Urban: Inside the mind of a master procrastinator&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/tim_urban_inside_the_mind_of_a_master_procrastinator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this TED talk&lt;/a&gt; from Tim Urban on how the procrastinator&amp;rsquo;s mind works, exemplified by his own career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: procrastinator, procrastination, mind, time-management, tim-urban&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pep-20-the-zen-of-python&#34;&gt;PEP 20 &amp;ndash; The Zen of Python&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the PEP20&lt;/a&gt;, the zen of python, with special attention to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: pep-20, pep, python, zen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Why I switched from Octopress 2 to Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Franklin Chen on the change he made on the static site generator (SSG) he used. He considered hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo. Was decided between hakyll and hugo for their speed but, finally, decided to use hugo for their bigger community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: franklin-chen, comparison, ssg, static-site-generator, hakyll, octopress, jekyll, hugo, change, speed, statically-typed, dynamically-typed, golang, performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-incremental-regeneration-in-jekyll-3-0-is-such-a-big-deal&#34;&gt;Why incremental regeneration in Jekyll 3.0 is such a big deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://idratherbewriting.com/2015/11/04/jekyll-30-released-incremental-regeneration-rocks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Johnson on one of the new features that jekyll 3.0 brings: incremental generation. How this can speed up the generation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tom-johnson, incremental-generation, speed, performance, octopress-2, octopress-3, jekyll-3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-s3-travis-ci-oh-boy&#34;&gt;Hugo, S3, Travis CI, oh boy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://continuousfailure.com/post/s3_blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Alan Scherger on how to set up a specific stack for developing and deploying a static site blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alan-scherger, static-site-generator, ssg, travis, hugo, s3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deploy-your-blog-to-github-pages-automatically-using-hugo-and-travis&#34;&gt;Deploy your blog to github pages automatically using Hugo and Travis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://rcoedo.com/post/hugo-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Roman Coedo on how to deploy a hugo blog to github pages, using travis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: roman-coedo, travis, hugo, github, github-pages, ssg, static-site-generator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;improve-octopress-with-advanced-tweaks-tips&#34;&gt;Improve Octopress with Advanced Tweaks &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.narga.net/improve-octopress-advanced-tweaks-tips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt; of tips on how to improve the octopress (2) installation. By Nguyễn Đình Quân.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nguyen-dinh-quan, octopress-2, tip, tweak&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;laboratorios&#34;&gt;Laboratorios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2014/11/12/laboratorios/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla, about laboratories to use a percentage of company time to investigate, innovate, learn and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, team-management, time-management, innovation, strategy, improvement, kaizen, laboratory, craftsmanship, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isn-t&#34;&gt;What Refactoring is, and what it isn’t&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://swreflections.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-refactoring-is-and-what-it-isnt.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Jim Bird, where he splits some practices into refactoring and not refactoring. Draws the line between these two different activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also cites scratch refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jim-bird, scratch-refactoring, refactoring, martin-fowler, kent-beck, definition, quote, design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pitfalls-of-unlimited-vacations&#34;&gt;Pitfalls of Unlimited Vacations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://haacked.com/archive/2016/02/18/unlimited-vaction-pitfalls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Phil Haack on the github, travis and netflix policies about unlimited vacations and the effects they have on the employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about minimum vacation periods, (paternity) paid leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: phil-haack, unlimited-vacation, holiday, vacation, team-management, burnout, github, travis, netflix, policy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultura-corporativa&#34;&gt;Cultura Corporativa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.presionblogosferica.com/2011/02/06/cultura-corporativa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Ángel Medinilla about the corporate culture, and how &amp;ldquo;hanging a highly interchangeable sentence on a wall&amp;rdquo; does not represent it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angel-medinilla, corporate culture, spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code&#34;&gt;What It’s Really Like to Learn to Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sandjar/what-it-s-really-like-to-learn-to-code-53f6d9156a32&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains firsthand how it is to learn programming for a novice student,even with a strong financial background and having completed a university degree. By Sandjar Kozubaev&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sandjar-kozubaev, learning, programming, student, firsthand, coding, story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>