<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kaizen on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/kaizen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kaizen on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/kaizen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Coglan, introducing monads.
About composability:
 The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable
 or
 symmetric input and output types
 Guide to basic monadic functions:
 lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/04/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Deliberate Practice: What It Is and Why You Need It I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Corbett Barr on what is deliberate practice and why it is needed to become an expert in a given domain field.
The four essential components:
 Motivation Tailored (practice) Feedback Repetion  Tags: corbett-barr, deliberate-practice, expert, practice, anders-ericsson, talent, professional-development, career
10 Features I Wish Java Would Steal From the Kotlin Language I&amp;rsquo;ve read this list of features that the Kotlin Language has that would be an improvement for the Java language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kata: persistent linked list</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/23/kata-persistent-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 23:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/23/kata-persistent-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just written a new kata, about a persistent linked list.
It is using the same project as for the linked list kata.
For now, only the add, contains and size methods are implemented.
If you have any comments or code review, please let me know</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GMaur code jam 2015: 01 - Mini-Power Swapper</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/gmaur-code-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 04:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/gmaur-code-jam/</guid>
      <description>Last year we started the program 12 months, 12 katas (as inspired by this repository). This year we want to propose something different: an asynchronous code jam
New problem: Mini-Power Swapper This post belongs to a series: code-jam
Each month (or so) we at GMaur will publish a new problem (and announce it on twitter) and post a solution to the last problem.
This month, the Mini-Power Swapper
You can fork the repo, commit there and send a pull request.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
