<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hannah-arendt | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/hannah-arendt/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-02T10:33:36+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Animal Laborans and the Homo Faber]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-animal-laborans-and-the-homo-faber/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-10T01:19:58+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-animal-laborans-and-the-homo-faber</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve found this quote very interesting from the book &ldquo;The Craftsman&rdquo;, by Richard Sennett:</p>

<blockquote><p><em>Animal laborans</em> is, as the name implies, the human being akin to a beast of burden,
a drudge condemned to routine. Arendt enriched this image by imagining him or her absorbed
in a task that shuts out the world, a state well exemplified by Oppenheimer&rsquo;s feeling that the
atomic bomb was a &ldquo;sweet&rdquo; problem, or Eichmann&rsquo;s obsession with making the gas chambers
efficient. In the act of making it work, nothing else matters; Animal laborans takes the work as
end end it itself.</p>

<p>By contrast, <em>Homo faber</em> is her image of men and women doing another kind of work, making
a life in common. Again Arendt enriched an inherited idea. The Lating tag Homo faber
means simple &ldquo;man as maker&rdquo;. [&hellip;] Homo faber is the judge of material labor and practice, not
Animal laborans&rsquo;s colleague but his supertior. Thus, in her view, we human beings live in two
dimensions, In one we make things; in this condition we are amoral, absorbed in a task. We
also harbor another, higher way of life in which we stop producing and start discussion and
judging together. Whereas Animal laborans is fixated in the question &ldquo;How?&rdquo; Homo faber
asks &ldquo;Why?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Richard Sennett, The Craftsman, Prologue, page 7</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
