<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: October | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/october/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-12T17:26:13+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in October 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-01T15:25:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>

<h2>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://elm-lang.org/blog/blazing-fast-html">this article</a> explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.</p>

<p>Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki</p>

<h2>Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://cryto.net/~joepie91/blog/2015/07/19/why-you-should-never-ever-ever-use-mongodb/">this article</a> stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg</p>

<p>Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid</p>

<h2>Do you really get classloaders?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/rebel-labs-tutorial-do-you-really-get-classloaders/">this video</a> by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</p>

<p>My notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>the classloading is lazy: the resources are not loaded until they are mentioned</li>
<li>every classloader has a parent</li>
<li>every class has a classloader associated with it</li>
<li>every object has a class associated with it</li>
<li>classloading delegation: the parent is consulted before loading a class. if it has it, it will load it. If not, I will delegate it</li>
</ul>


<p>There is also <a href="http://www.javaworld.com/article/2074396/core-java/javaone-2011--do-you-really-get-classloaders-.html">this article</a> on the same video</p>

<p>Tags: jevgeny-kabanov, classloader, java,</p>

<h2>Truth table</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truth_table">the wikipedia article</a> about the truth table and the 16 possible binary boolean operators:</p>

<ul>
<li>Contradiction</li>
<li>NOR</li>
<li>Converse nonimplication</li>
<li>Negation (of p)</li>
<li>Material nonimplication</li>
<li>Negation (of q)</li>
<li>XOR (exclusive disjunction)</li>
<li>NAND</li>
<li>AND (conjunction)</li>
<li>XNOR (biconditional)</li>
<li>Projection (of p)</li>
<li>Implication</li>
<li>Projection (of q)</li>
<li>Converse implication</li>
<li>OR (disjunction)</li>
<li>Tautology</li>
</ul>


<h2>7 lines of code, 3 minutes: Implement a programming language from scratch</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/implementing-a-programming-language/">this article</a> by Matt Might about the benefits of implementing a language (from scratch but on top of another existing language used as framework). Chooses lambda calculus as the desired DSL</p>

<p>Tags: matt-might, lambda-calculus, racket, domain-specific-language</p>

<h2>Turing completeness</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness">this wikipedia article</a> (both main and discussion) about this subject.</p>

<p>It has sounded strange to me the reference to S-expressions:</p>

<blockquote><p>Data languages
The notion of Turing-completeness does not apply to languages such as XML, HTML, JSON, YAML and S-expressions because they are typically used to represent structured data, not describe computation [&hellip;]</p></blockquote>

<p>If data (S-expression) is represented as the same format as code (e.g., Lisp&rsquo;s S-expression) and the latter is used to represent a computation, shouldn&rsquo;t be &ldquo;data languages that also are used as computation languages&rdquo; excluded from that list?</p>

<p>As a side note, Lisp is Turing Complete (see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness#Examples">Turing Complete#Examples</a>)</p>

<h2>The Prize Is Won; The Simplest Universal Turing Machine Is Proved</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.wolfram.com/2007/10/24/the-prize-is-won-the-simplest-universal-turing-machine-is-proved/?year=2007&amp;monthnum=10">this article</a> by Stephen Wolfram about the proof of a Turing Machine 2,3 being universal by Alex Smith.</p>

<p>Tags: stephen-wolfram, turing-machine, universal-turing-machine, proof, paper, alex-smith</p>

<h2>No increment operator (++) in Ruby?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3717519/no-increment-operator-in-ruby">this stackoverflow</a> question about the lack of post-increment operator (i++) in Ruby:</p>

<blockquote><p>++ and &ndash; are NOT reserved operator in Ruby.</p>

<p>Mailing list from <a href="http://blade.nagaokaut.ac.jp/cgi-bin/scat.rb/ruby/ruby-talk/2710">Yukihiro Matsumoto aka matz</a></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
