<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gregory-brown on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/gregory-brown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gregory-brown on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/gregory-brown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
