<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Martin-fowler | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/martin-fowler/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-01T07:58:43+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in December 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-02T07:50:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.skorks.com/2009/09/ruby-equality-and-object-comparison/">this article</a>, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:</p>

<ul>
<li>equal? is reference equality</li>
<li>== is value equality</li>
<li>eql? is value and type equality</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin</p>

<h2>Software Folklore</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/software-folklore">this PechaKucha</a> by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</p>

<p>Tags: folklore, chris-ford, analogy, computer-science, pechakucha, software-engineering, software-creation, law</p>

<h2>3 Things Java Programmers Can Steal from Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/3-things-java-can-steal-from-clojure">this article</a> by Eric Normand, where he explains 3 clojure things that can be applied to your day to day java:</p>

<ol>
<li>Persistent Data Structures</li>
<li>Software Transactional Memory</li>
<li>Extensible Data Notation</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: clojure, java, eric-normand, stm, edn</p>

<h2>2 Features of Clojure Editors Professionals Won&rsquo;t Do Without</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/clojure-editors">this article</a> by Eric Normand, where he explains the most necessary features for a clojure editor:</p>

<ol>
<li>REPL Integration</li>
<li>Structural Editing</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: clojure, java, eric-normand, stm, edn</p>

<h2>How to read more books</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://verraes.net/2012/12/how-to-read-more-books/">this article</a> by Mathias Verraes on tips to read more books:</p>

<ul>
<li>Negative things to stop doing</li>
<li>Positive things to start doing</li>
<li>Habits to form</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: mathias-verraes, reading, book</p>

<h2>Effective Learning Strategies for Programmers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://akaptur.com/blog/2015/10/10/effective-learning-strategies-for-programmers/">this article</a> by Allison Kaptur on fixed vs growth mindset and the need for having the latter for being a programmer.</p>

<p>Especially interesting is the provided example of the confusion in the documentation, that can hinder productivity</p>

<p>(Note: this entry is also present in this same month)</p>

<p>Tags: allison-kaptur, fixed-mindset, growth-mindset, research, learning-strategy, recurse-center, carol-dweck, mindset</p>

<h2>Code a fully-functional web app in 14 days… - Challenge Accepted</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@OggimusPrime/code-a-fully-functional-web-app-in-14-days-e247f536772d">this experience report</a> on how Ryan Haase and Benjamin Hoffman built an MVP in 14 days. They describe their stack choices, gotchas and key points.</p>

<p>Tags: ryan-haase, benjamin-hoffman, mvp, angular, firebase, challenge</p>

<h2>Writing-Clear-Code, Not-Clever-Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve-read <a href="https://medium.com/@mikesherov/writing-clear-code-not-clever-code-d6b90353a3c5">this-article</a> by-Mike-Sherov-where-he-explains-the-reflection-he-did-since-his-team-members-were-asking-too-much-about-his-code. His-conclusion-was-to-stop-reducing-the-size-of-the-code-to-improve-readability.</p>

<p>Tags: mike-sherov, clean-code,clear-code, clever-code, reflection, team, code</p>

<h2>En vez de “un Scrum por proyecto” mejor un “Scrum por equipo”</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javiergarzas.com/2015/12/alejate-del-concepto-proyecto-si-quieres-usar-bien-scrum-22-adaptar-scrum-segun-cada-proyecto.html">this article</a> where Javier Garzás explains scrum by teams or by projects and why the former should be preferred (in Spanish).</p>

<p>Tags:  javier-garzas, scrum, project-management, team, agile</p>

<h2>Application gateways: an example in Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.obliquo.eu/post/134421923177/application-gateways-an-example-in-clojure">this example</a> that Cristobal Garcia prepared for me after asking for it at the local Barcelona Software Craftsmanship community (Many thanks!).</p>

<p>He describes what an application gateway is, giving an example in clojure. In this case, the application gateway is used to cache and forward/deny requests to another webservice.</p>

<p>Tags: cristobal-garcia, application-gateway, clojure, example, level-7-firewall, barcelona-software-craftsmanship, scbcn, gift</p>

<h2>Habits For Effective Refactoring</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=THw8t7ePlsc">this video</a> by Jason Gorman about techniques for effective and sustainable refactoring. Among them:</p>

<ul>
<li>check the tests, the coverage to make sure that the refactored code has a good safety net</li>
<li>set a refactoring goal: decide what you want to refactor at this time and when you&rsquo;ll be done</li>
<li>know your code smells</li>
<li>only refactor on green</li>
<li>use automated refactoring steps whenever possible: for the benefits of transactionability and undo are huge and the risk of messing it up decreases</li>
<li>commit after achieving the refactoring goal: allows to create a checkpoint to revert to</li>
<li>bottle the code smells for faster/better learning (in the commit message, he uses a hashtag for searching)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: jason-gorman, refactoring, video, technique, refactor, tutorial, code-smell</p>

<h2>Key to &ldquo;OEIS.org&rdquo; Poster, n. 15</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://oeisf.org/Poster15a_key.pdf">the 15th &ldquo;poster and its key&rdquo;</a> by the OEIS, published by N. J. A. Sloane.</p>

<p>Tags: sloane, oeis, poster-and-key, neil-sloane</p>

<h2>The Clojure Style Guide</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/bbatsov/clojure-style-guide">this style guide</a> to clojure, by Bozhidar Batsov</p>

<p>Tags: bozhidar-batsov, clojure, style-guide</p>

<h2>Marick&rsquo;s Midje information</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Writing-your-own-checkers">Custom checkers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Two-words-you-need-to-know">Domain concepts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Top-down-testing">Top-down testing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/marick/Midje/wiki/Nested-checkers">Nested checkers</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Clusterware 11gR2 – Setting up an Active/Passive failover configuration</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/xpsoluxdb/entry/clusterware_11gr2_setting_up_an_activepassive_failover_configuration">this how-to guide</a> by Gilles Haro on how to create an Active/Passive failover configuration for Oracle.</p>

<p>Tags: failover, high-availability, oracle, gilles-haro, active-passive, database</p>

<h2>Old stuff that rocks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://wincent.com/blog/old-stuff-that-rocks">this list</a> of old technologies that still rock, according to Greg Hurrell.</p>

<p>Tags: list, old-stuff, greg-hurrell</p>

<h2>Do not underestimate credentials leaks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/ChALkeR/notes/blob/master/Do-not-underestimate-credentials-leaks.md">this article</a> that describes how credentials are usually accidentally leaked and a guide on what to do about it. By Сковорода Никита Андреевич.</p>

<p>Tags: credential, leak, guide, how-to</p>

<h2>Clojure for the brave and true: chapter 8 - Writing Macros</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.braveclojure.com/writing-macros">this chapter</a> from Daniel Higginbotham about macros in clojure. In it, he explains common gotchas (e.g., double execution, variable capture), splicing, quoting and unquoting.</p>

<p>Tags: daniel-higginbotham, clojure, macro, chapter, quoting, unquoting, splicing</p>

<h2>The Telescoping Constructor (Anti)Pattern</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.captaindebug.com/2011/05/telescoping-constructor-antipattern.html#.ViF57eztmkp">this article</a> by Roger Hughes on the telescoping constructor, with the example in java. The discussion is whether to apply this or not and whether this is a pattern or an anti-pattern</p>

<p>Tags: roger-hughes, telescoping-constructor, java, pattern, antipattern</p>

<h2>Ruby for Newbies: Testing with Rspec</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://code.tutsplus.com/tutorials/ruby-for-newbies-testing-with-rspec--net-21297">this tutorial</a> on how to make write tests with RSpec in Ruby. Written by Andrew Burgess</p>

<p>Tags: andrew-burgess, ruby, rspec, test, tutorial</p>

<h2>Ruby dynamic method calling</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.khd.me/ruby/ruby-dynamic-method-calling/">this article</a> about dynamically calling methods and a benchmark on three ways of doing it in Ruby:</p>

<ul>
<li>call</li>
<li>send</li>
<li>eval</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: khell, metaprogramming, comparison, benchmark, ruby, evaluation, dynamic</p>

<h2>Becoming a CTO</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article <a href="https://medium.com/@juokaz/becoming-a-cto-337dc1a9c6ae"></a> by Juozas Kaziukėnas about the profile and the abilities of a CTO. Talks about the limiting factors for being one (e.g., stop programming, attend many meetings) and the type of work you are supposed to do (e.g., face business people, communicate the strategy, make yourself respectable).</p>

<p>Tags: juozas-kaziukenas, cto, career-change, technology, career, programmer, title, job</p>

<h2>4 Stages of Team Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=7NouiH2ZT8w">this video</a> by the Glenn Smith &ldquo;Growth Coach Houston&rdquo; about the four stages of team development: forming, norming, storming, performing and how to get through them.</p>

<p>Tags: tuckman, forming, norming, storming, performing, glenn-smith, video, team-management, team</p>

<h2>Time Hacking for College Students</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://goel.io/time-hacking/">this article</a> by Karan Goel about techniques for finding time for important things:</p>

<ul>
<li>prioritizing</li>
<li>waking up early</li>
<li>automate</li>
<li>keep learning</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: karan-goel, time-management, important-vs-urgent, prioritization</p>

<h2>Clojure at a Real Estate Portal</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pitheringabout.com/?p=1069">this article</a> by Jon Pither, where he does a post-mortem analysis of a real-estate project with a fixed deadline (TV ads) with around ten months of development time. They brought in an external company, JUXT, who with 6 seasoned developers were able to finish the project on time and on budget.</p>

<p>Their stack was:  Ring, Compojure, Bidi, and http-kit for our Clojure web-apps, mixing in Friend and Liberator.</p>

<p>Tags: ring, compojure, bidi, http-kit, clojure, fixed-deadline, project, success-story, post-mortem, jon-pither</p>

<h2>Musing on TDD, Impulsive Developers and Aesthetics</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article by Jon Pither on why TDD can be harmful sometimes:</p>

<ul>
<li>limits the amount of lateral thinking</li>
<li>forces a technology</li>
<li>limits the solution space given a fixed problem space</li>
<li>limits creativity and freedom when performing large / aggressive refactorings</li>
<li>sterile place</li>
</ul>


<p>while he agrees that can be useful sometimes:</p>

<ul>
<li>mostly in OOP</li>
<li>to keep you on the rails and focused</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: tdd, jon-pither, senior-developer, junior-developer, aesthetics, lateral-thinking</p>

<h2>Fred George On Programmer Anarchy</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/news/2012/02/programmer-anarchy">this article</a> by Roopesh Shenoy on a talk by Fred George: &ldquo;Programmer Anarchy&rdquo;, where programmers make business decisions based on business metrics set by clients, among other things.</p>

<p>Tags: roopesh-shenoy, fred-george, programmer-anarchy, analogy, anarchy, business-metric, client, agile, methodology</p>

<h2>Programmer Anarchy</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/fredgeorge/programmer-anarchy-chinese">these slides</a> by Fred George about programmer&rsquo;s anarchy. Commented in the article above</p>

<p>Tags: slide, fred-george, programmer-anarchy, analogy, anarchy, business-metric, client, agile, methodology</p>

<h2>What is Programmer Anarchy and does it have a future?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinjeeblog.com/2012/11/20/what-is-programmer-anarchy-and-does-it-have-a-future/">this article</a> by Martin Jee explaining what is programmer anarchy and how it compares to an agile team. Compares the division of labor structure in anarchist and agile teams, using Marxist terms.</p>

<p>He finishes saying that what is a powerful idea in this methodology is the taking of personal responsibilities by the programmers.</p>

<p>Tags: fred-george, programmer-anarchy, analogy, anarchy, martin-jee, agile, methodology</p>

<h2>Agile is the New Black</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/fredgeorge/agile-is-thenewblack">these slides</a> by Fred George where compares xp/agile development in 1999, 2006 and 2011.</p>

<p>Tags: fred-george, agile, methodology, comparison, slide</p>

<h2>Show How, Don&rsquo;t Tell What - A Management Style</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://2ndscale.com/rtomayko/2012/management-style">this article</a> by Ryan Tomayko about the management style they apply at github:</p>

<blockquote><p>instead of telling them what to do, show people how to plan, build, and ship product together.</p>

<p>I’ve never actually told anyone what to do here. In fact, I vehemently refuse to tell people what to do. Here are just a couple reasons why:</p>

<p>I don’t scale. If I tell someone what to do and they do it, then what? Do I have to tell them another thing to do? What happens when I have to decide what to do for 20 people?</p>

<p>Telling people what to do is lazy. Instead, try to convince them with argument. This is how humans interact when there’s no artificial authority structure and it works great. If you can’t convince people through argument then maybe you shouldn’t be doing it.</p></blockquote>

<p>about managers:</p>

<blockquote><p>It’s often cited that GitHub doesn’t have managers. In my opinion, a better way to describe the phenomenon would be to say that everyone at GitHub is a manager</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: ryan-tomayko, management, management-style, team-management, github</p>

<h2>Clojure for the brave and true: chapter 7 - Clojure Alchemy: Reading, Evaluation, and Macros</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.braveclojure.com/read-and-eval/">this chapter</a> from Daniel Higginbotham about the essential concepts for macros: the reader, the evaluator, their relative order and independence. How to use clojure to extend itself and an example: the thread (<code>-&gt;</code>) macro</p>

<p>Tags: daniel-higginbotham, clojure, macro, chapter, reader, evaluator</p>

<h2>Team Bus Factors: How to Reduce Them and How to Prevent Them</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://5whys.com/blog/team-bus-factors-how-to-reduce-them-and-how-to-prevent-them.html">this article</a> by Roy Osherove on the bus factor:</p>

<ul>
<li>what is it</li>
<li>how to reduce them</li>
<li>how to prevent them</li>
</ul>


<p>Also talks about examples of bus-factor people</p>

<p>Tags: bus-factor, roy-osherove, team-management, prevention, reduction, definition</p>

<h2>Hambre de programar</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@xav1uzz/hambre-de-programar-166aeae3b525">this article</a> (in Spanish) by Xavi Gost where he analyses the Barcelona Software Craftsmanship 2015: the events, the relationships and the passion that it has injected to attendees</p>

<p>Tags: xavi-gost, barcelona-software-craftsmanship, 2015, experience-report, scbcn15</p>

<h2>Software Craftsmanship Barcelona 2015</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.idealista.com/labs/blog/idealista/software-craftsmanship-barcelona-2015/">this analysis</a> of the Barcelona Software Craftsmanship 2015 by the Idealista R&amp;D team.</p>

<p>Tags: jaime-perera, barcelona-software-craftsmanship, 2015, idealista, experience-report, scbcn15</p>

<h2>JVMLS 2015 - Compilers are Databases</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48js0H6ooBY">this video</a> by Martin Odersky on why compilers resemble databases and explains how a functional compiler works on the inside.</p>

<p>Explains the notion of a Type, Reference, Symbol, Denotation (and Multi-Denotation) living in the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST)</p>

<p>Also explains the need for a reading compiler (e.g., for quick validation in the IDE), single-pass and multi-pass compiler.</p>

<p>They have built phases to transform the source code into bytecode, but to better use the cache locality, they programmatically mix phases using Java Reflection (metaprogramming) to traverse the tree (AST) once for these selected phases.</p>

<p>Tags: type, reference, symbol, denotation, abstract-syntax-tree, ast, compiler, functional-compiler, scalac, dotty, martin-odersky, analogy, database</p>

<h2>In Functional Programming, what is a functor?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2030863/in-functional-programming-what-is-a-functor/2031421#2031421">this answer</a> of what is a functor</p>

<p>Tags: stack-overflow, functor, answer, functional-programming</p>

<h2>Ten Habits of a Good Programmer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hintjens.com/blog:98">this list</a> of good habits of good programmers by Pieter Hintjens:</p>

<ol>
<li>If it works and is still useful, don&rsquo;t throw it out.</li>
<li>Never solve the same problem twice in parallel.</li>
<li>Solve the same problem often in serial.</li>
<li>Write code, and repeat, until you are fluent in your language.</li>
<li>Learn to use code generators.</li>
<li>Work with others.</li>
<li>Technology is a tool, not a tribal affiliation.</li>
<li>Aim for this cycle: learn, play, work, teach.</li>
<li>Get your edit-compile-run-fail cycles down to seconds.</li>
<li>If you need debuggers, you&rsquo;re doing it wrong.</li>
</ol>


<p>Tags: pieter-hintjens, list, habit, good-programmer</p>

<h2>Beginning Clojure: Cursive</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://potetm.github.io/2015/10/04/beginning-clojure-cursive.html">this tutorial</a> on installing Cursive, IntelliJ Idea&rsquo;s plugin for working with Clojure. Written by Tim Pote</p>

<p>Tags: cursive, clojure, intellij-idea, plugin, tutorial, tim-pote</p>

<h2>#NodeJS : A quick optimization advice</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://top.fse.guru/nodejs-a-quick-optimization-advice-7353b820c92e">this article</a> on the limit for inlining for the NodeJS optimizing compiler (Crankshaft), that includes both source code and comments. Written Julien Crouzet</p>

<p>Tags: nodejs, comment, julien-crouzet, crankshaft, optimizer, inline, function-inline</p>

<h2>Specification Pattern</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Specification_pattern">this wikipedia</a> page on the specification pattern</p>

<p>Tags: eric-evans, martin-fowler, specification-pattern, pattern, design-pattern, dsl, domain-specific-language</p>

<h2>El recruiting está ROTO #Bonilista</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;id=539364dde4">this bonilista</a> where David Bonilla explains why the recruitment sector for technical people in Spain is broken. Article is in Spanish.</p>

<p>Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, recruitment, job, career</p>

<h2>BDDon’t: The practice and the tools</h2>

<p>​I&rsquo;ve  read <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/p2magazine/issue12/bdd-dont/">this article</a> by Kevin Dishman that explains what is BDD and how it I  usually used. Also the common downsides and what to do about it</p>

<p>Suggests using a faster tool, lower on the test pyramid that can bring the same business value at a lower cost</p>

<p>Tags: kevin-dishman, downside, test-pyramid, bdd, test, unit-test, functional-test, acceptance-test</p>

<h2>Cómo usan #Git en GitHub – #scbcn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://codely.tv/screencasts/como-usan-git-en-github/">this screencast</a> on the talk we organized yesterday about github.</p>

<p>Tags: javier-ferrer, codely-tv, codely, event, scbcn, alain-helaili, screencast</p>

<h2>Trying to speed up Binary Search</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://databasearchitects.blogspot.com.es/2015/09/trying-to-speed-up-binary-search.html">this article</a> on how the binary search is implemented and what other algorithms are possible to speed up the search in large datasets, especially common in databases.</p>

<p>Tags: optimization, branch-misprediction, clang, o3, gpp, c, database, binary-search, thomas-neumann</p>

<h2>Scrum 3.0 and Organization 4.0 - impressions from a great evening with Boris Gloger at ImmobilienScout24</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://www.ontheagilepath.net/2015/12/scrum-30-and-organization-40.html">this article</a> by  Sebastian Radics that compares the different ways of doing scrum: 1 2 3, most comments on other strategies or management methodologies like no estimates.</p>

<p>Compares the importance of focusing on the process or on the final product, the role of the scrum master, the role of the product owner, and the team itself.</p>

<p>Tags: management, agile, scrum, team-management, sebastian-radics, scrum30</p>

<h2>Trucos para trabajar con equipos remotos</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://thinkingwithyou.com/2015/11/trucos-para-trabajar-con-equipos-remotos/">this article</a> by Israel Alcázar (Spanish). Explains how this company organized their product development process. explains tools for working with a remote team.</p>

<p>give three pieces of advice for improving it, and further resources to read</p>

<p>Tags: remote, remote-first, isra-alcazar, israel-alcazar, team-management, advice</p>

<h2>Introducing new open-source tools for the Elixir community</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://engineering.pinterest.com/blog/introducing-new-open-source-tools-elixir-community">this article</a> by Steve Cohen that explains what the actor model is and what is the spirit of the elixir language: user friendlier syntax for erlang</p>

<p>They also explain that they have implemented and ad server and access control using elixir. For this matter, they rely on two tools that are now open source</p>

<p>Tags: elixir, microsecond, latency, erlang, actor-model, language-syntax, open-source, steve-cohen</p>

<h2>¿Cuánto pagas por tus herramientas de trabajo?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=374c664073e1a1fa3deca53b4&amp;id=12ed2d6eb0">this bonilista</a> about how much programmers invest in buying their tools (and honing them). By David Bonilla, in Spanish</p>

<p>Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, tool, investment</p>

<h2>Clojure at a Bank – Freeing the Rules</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pitheringabout.com/?p=830">this article</a> by Jon Pither about converting OO business rules into Clojure and using the homoiconicity for increasing the power: when code is data, the rules themselves become searchable (using a search engine), visualizable and analyzable. This wasn&rsquo;t possible before when code was not data.</p>

<p>They have also build further tools to analyze rules with larger sets of data, rather than unit tests, to see if they conflict among each other.</p>

<p>Tags: jon-pither, clojure, homoiconicity, code=data, data=code, rule, rule-engine, bank, business-rule, code-analysis</p>

<h2>Five reasons to learn Clojure and Emacs together</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pitheringabout.com/?p=849">this article</a> by Jon Pither advocating the learning of Clojure and Emacs at the same time. The main reasons are: liberation, change, support, simplicity, mass adoption.</p>

<p>Cites that being hard to learn a new editor is a good idea to separate those who are willing to invest the time in learning (both an editor and a new language) from those who don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Tags: clojure, emacs, jon-pither, learning, liberation, change, support, simplicity, mass-adoption</p>

<h2>Pull Requests Maintainers Won&rsquo;t Hate</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this <a href="https://www.booleanknot.com/blog/2013/09/07/pull-requests.html">list of tips</a> by James Reeves on improving the pull requests
Tags: pull-request, james-reeves, tip, list</p>

<h2>How to get rich in tech, guaranteed.</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://startupljackson.com/post/135800367395/how-to-get-rich-in-tech-guaranteed">this article</a> that describes what is a way to make good money and retire rich why working for a company.</p>

<p>It also explains about entering the startup market, what questions should be asked, what&rsquo;s your real value, what are the benefits of doing it, known limitations and other questions</p>

<p>Tags: startup, career, career-management, work, professional-career, value, money</p>

<h2>Modern Perl 4th edition, a review</h2>

<p>I have read <a href="http://perltricks.com/article/205/2015/12/21/Modern-Perl-4th-edition--a-review">this article</a> that explains how this new book covers the syntax, idioms and the rest of the Perl language.</p>

<p>In this 4th edition, parts of  the text have completely been rewritten, a New formatting applied to ease and improve the reading comprehension</p>

<p>Tags: book-review, review, david-farrell, perl, reedition, modern-perl</p>

<h2>8 Characteristics of Agile Software Developers</h2>

<p>​I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@pm_loop/8-characteristics-of-successful-agile-software-developers-ab2c43abb959">this article</a> that describes what characteristics are common in companies practicing an agile methodology, as revealed by a study (that even though it&rsquo;s not cited, can be tracked back to <a href="http://productdevelopmentsuccess.com/study">here</a>)</p>

<p>Suggests ideas for teams that change in a changing environment and what to do about it.</p>

<p>Written by Keela Robison.</p>

<p>Tags: keela-robison, agile, team-management</p>

<h2>This is why you never end up hiring good developers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://qz.com/258066/this-is-why-you-dont-hire-good-developers/">this article</a> that explains what to look for in a strong, stronger, strongest (software) developer</p>

<p>The main idea is to find a good person that fits the job, without inflicting pain in the team morale and can learn to perform the specific tasks in the future, as (paraprasing) the pool of people that know what you need is much smaller than the people who can learn it.</p>

<p>The article specifies what to look and not look for in a candidate.</p>

<p>Some quotes:</p>

<blockquote><p>grasp of complex topics and the ability to clearly communicate about them, which are the two jobs of the working engineer.</p>

<p>track record of learning new skills and applying them successfully</p>

<p>TL;DR:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Many interview techniques test skills that are at best irrelevant to real working life;</p></li>
<li><p>you want somebody who knows enough to do the job right now;</p></li>
<li><p>or somebody smart and motivated enough that they can learn the job quickly;</p></li>
<li><p>you want somebody who keeps getting better at what they do;</p></li>
<li><p>your interview should be a collaborative conversations, not a combative interrogation;</p></li>
<li><p>you also want somebody who you will enjoy working with;</p></li>
<li><p>it’s important to separate “enjoy working with” from “enjoy hanging out with;”</p></li>
<li><p>don’t hire assholes, no matter how good they are;</p></li>
<li><p>if your team isn’t diverse, your team is worse than it needed to be;</p></li>
<li><p>accept that hiring takes a really long time and is really, really hard.</p></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<h2>Effective Learning Strategies for Programmers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve (re-)read <a href="http://akaptur.com/blog/2015/10/10/effective-learning-strategies-for-programmers/">this article</a> by Allison Kaptur on fixed vs growth mindset and the need for having the latter for being a programmer.</p>

<p>The fixed mindset is present in the 10x-engineer, and the worshipping of heroes.</p>

<p>It also includes a recipe for changing from a fixed-mindset to a growth-mindset.</p>

<p>(Note: this entry is also present in this same month)</p>

<p>Tags: allison-kaptur, fixed-mindset, growth-mindset, research, learning-strategy, recurse-center, carol-dweck, mindset, 10x-engineer, impostor-syndrome</p>

<h2>Doctor! Please fix my agile!</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/59614769/Presentations/Doctor%20please%20fix%20my%20Agile.pdf">these slides</a> by Ville Törmälä on what is agile, organizational problems and the distinction between efficiency and effectiveness. Also talks about the distribution of time and the organization of the environment (what calls)</p>

<p>Tags: slide, agile, efficiency, effectiveness, tip, organization, ville-tormala, project-thinking, team-thinking</p>

<h2>“Wolf” narrative considered harmful (also biologically unlikely)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://laughingmeme.org/2014/09/02/wolf-narrative-considered-harmful-also-biologically-unlikely/">this article</a> that explains what the &ldquo;lone wolf&rdquo; archetype is, among programmers, and possible outcomings for those profiles. Written by Kellan Elliott-McCrea.</p>

<p>Describes some craftsmanship ideas for these roles, based on their proficiency with their tools, that will generate tools for the rest of the team and make the rest more effective. Also discusses the non-management advancement career.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, wolf, lone-wolf, archetype, programmer, programmer-analogy, profile, team-management, kellan-elliott-mccrea</p>

<h2>The Wolf - dictating their own terms</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/the-wolf/">this article</a> by Michael Lopp about the <code>wolf</code> position as a person or in a team. He describes their characteristics and his own experiences working with them.</p>

<p>Tags: management, wolf, team-management, analogy, michael-lopp</p>

<h2>Volkswagen and Cheating Software</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.schneier.com/crypto-gram/archives/2015/1015.html#1">this essay</a> by Bruce Schneier on cheating software, using as an example the Volkswagen case, but especially centered on software that is made do cheat in an undetectable fashion. Or that could be attributed to a programming mistake. The later, says the author, is so common that there could be already intentional or unintentional errors hiding cheating.</p>

<p>The author cites the Internet of Things of new opportunities for companies to use / produce cheating software and about a possible solution: transparency and oversight of the software that more and more reigns our lives.</p>

<p>Other (opinion) articles I&rsquo;ve read on the issue are:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/24/opinion/volkswagen-and-the-era-of-cheating-software.html">Volkswagen and the Era of Cheating Software</a> by Zeynep Tufekci</li>
<li><a href="http://fusion.net/story/202867/volkswagen-software-deception-ai/">Volkswagen isn’t the first company to use software to break the law and it won’t be the last</a> by Daniela Hernandez</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/future_tense/2015/09/volkswagen_s_cheating_emissions_software_and_the_threat_of_black_boxes.html">Harry Potter and the Mysterious Defeat Device</a> by James Grimmelmann</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: cryptogram, bruce Schneier, volkswagen, mistake, quality, transparency, oversight, iot, essay, cheating, cheating software</p>

<h2>Please, Java. Do Finally Support Multiline String Literals</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jooq.org/2015/12/29/please-java-do-finally-support-multiline-strings/">this article</a> explaining the need for multi-line string literal in java.</p>

<p>Tags: java, syntax, string, feature, multi-line string</p>

<h2>The Silver Bullet Syndrome</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wyd6J3yjcs">this talk</a> by Hadi Hariri about chasing the next silver bullet.</p>

<p>He explains this with javascript and nodejs, but it could be exemplified with other technologies / promises as well.</p>

<p>Note: ABC stands for:</p>

<ul>
<li>A = address</li>
<li>B = binding</li>
<li>C = contract</li>
</ul>


<p> Tags: hadi-hariri, silver-bullet, talk, devoxx</p>

<h2>Writing Clean Tests – Small Is Beautiful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.petrikainulainen.net/programming/testing/writing-clean-tests-small-is-beautiful/">this article</a> by Petri Kainulainen on writing BDD style tests with JUnit in java.</p>

<p>There is <a href="https://github.com/NitorCreations/CoreComponents/tree/master/junit-runners">a tool</a>, created by Nitor Creations that allows you to write nested classes in JUnit, allowing for test specialization.</p>

<p>Tags: junit, runner, bdd, test, nitor-creations, petri-kainulainen, tdd</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in September 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-01T13:25:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.growth.supply/the-30-second-habit-with-a-lifelong-impact-2c3f948ead98">this article</a> list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.</p>

<p>Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott</p>

<h2>The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkhLZ7_KZ5w">this video</a> explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson</p>

<p>Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</p>

<h2>Poster de Extreme Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4nN6Gh79Yg8">this video</a> introducing eXtreme Programming. By Martín Salías</p>

<p>Tags: martin-salias, kleer, extreme-programming, xp</p>

<h2>Good Tech Lead, Bad Tech Lead</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.growth.supply/good-tech-lead-bad-tech-lead-948b2b806d86">this comparison</a> of good and bad traits in tech leads. By Jason Liszka.</p>

<p>Explains the differences between good and bad tech leads, even though many of these qualities are shared by plain team members</p>

<p>Tags: jason-liszka, tech-lead, comparison</p>

<h2>Why Procrastinators Procrastinate</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://waitbutwhy.com/2013/10/why-procrastinators-procrastinate.html">this article</a> by Tim Urban on procrastination: this article compares the procrastinator and the non-procrastinator brain with pictures, introducing the Rational part, the Instant Gratification Monkey and the Panic Monster. Shows some reasons why.</p>

<p>There is more on part 2: <a href="http://waitbutwhy.com/2013/11/how-to-beat-procrastination.html">How to beat procrastination</a></p>

<p>Tags: tim-urban, procrastination, rational-part, instant-gratification-monkey, panic-monster, brain, comparison</p>

<h2>Algebraic data type</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebraic_data_type">this wikipedia page</a>, that explains what this is, a few examples and the theory behind it.</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, data-type, algebraic-data-type</p>

<h2>Recursion</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recursion_(computer_science)">this wikipedia page</a>, that explains the recursion basic concepts, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>induction, coinduction</li>
<li>recursion, corecursion</li>
<li>implementation details in iterative vs recursive programs:

<ul>
<li>shortcutting recursion (i.e., arm-length&rsquo;s recursion)</li>
<li>wrapper function</li>
<li>tail-call optimization, related to tail-recursive functions</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>recursion and its relation to data structures</li>
<li>base case / recursive case and removing the need of the base one in corecursion or in non-strict languages</li>
<li>types of recursion:

<ul>
<li>direct, indirect, mutual</li>
<li>generative, structural</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: recursion, corecursion, induction, coinduction, tail-call-optimization, tail-recursion, direct-recursion, indirect-recursion, mutual-recursion, generative-recursion, structural-recursion, arm-length-recursion, iterative-function, recursive-function, base-case, recursive-case, wikipedia, data-structure</p>

<h2>Anonymous function</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_function">this wikipedia page</a>, that describes what is a lambda expression or an anonymous function. How it can be used (e.g., currying, higher-order function, closures) and gives examples in many languages.</p>

<p>Cites its invention (Church, 1936, lambda-calculus) and its first implementation (Lisp, 1958)</p>

<p>Tags: alonzo-church, anonymous-function, lambda-expression, closure, lambda-calculus, lisp, currying, higher-order-function, wikipedia</p>

<h2>Closure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closure_(computer_programming)">this wikipedia page</a>, that explains the concept of closures and the usual confusion between closure and lambda. Also some applications.</p>

<p>Discusses closures as a way of deferring execution and implementing object-oriented (OO) systems</p>

<p>Tags: wikipedia, closure, object-orientation, lambda-expression</p>

<h2>Zen Story: The Master Archer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.thedailyzen.org/2015/06/23/zen-story-the-master-archer/">this story</a> by Charlie Ambler about perfectionism and deep study, exemplified by the general that retires to study archery and the child who draws targets around the arrows.</p>

<p>Tags: charlie-amber, master, student, zen, story</p>

<h2>Loosely Coupled</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.bwhaley.com/loosely-coupled">this article</a> by Ben Whaley about how to loosely couple services introducing a queue and the difference in patterns between push and pull communication.</p>

<p>Tags: ben-whaley, push, pull, coupling, loose-coupling, service, queue, aws</p>

<h2>Being good at programming competitions correlates negatively with being good on the job</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched the small video and the discussion about programmers' talent at <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/programming-competitions-work-performance/">this page</a>. By Peteris Krumins.</p>

<p>The original video explains that being good at a programming contest correlates negatively with skill at a programming job, even if the company hires them.</p>

<p>The discussion explains the analogy with height and the NBA and concludes that this parameter should be preponderated with less importance than others.</p>

<p>Tags: google, peter-norvig, nba, analogy, programming-contest, programming-skill, peteris-krumins</p>

<h2>On Functors</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/on-functors/">this comparison</a> by Peteris Krumins of what the functors are in different languages:</p>

<ul>
<li>C++: function objects</li>
<li>Standard ML: generic implementation of interfaces. They allow to compose structures</li>
<li>Haskell: structure containing zero or more objects that can be converted to another structure containing the other objects. It&rsquo;s an homomorphism between two categories.</li>
<li>Prolog: built-in predicate for self-inspection and the atom at the start of the structure</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: peteris-krumins, comparison, haskell, c-plus-plus, standard-ml, prolog, functor</p>

<h2>Recursive Regular Expressions</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/recursive-regular-expressions/">this article</a> on recursive regular expressions by Peteris Krumins.</p>

<p>In it, he lightly describes how a regular expression relates to a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Context-free_grammar">Context-Free Grammar</a> and the language support for Perl to include recursive regular expressions. Based on the examples (e.g., <code>0^n1^n</code>), it really clicked to me that this could be expressed as a recursive function, with its base case and the recursive one. Also that it &ldquo;depends on solutions to smaller instances of the same problem&rdquo; (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recursion_(computer_science)">wikipedia</a>)</p>

<p>Tags: peteris-krumins, regular-expression, recursion, recursive-regular-expression, perl, context-free-grammar, formal-language-theory</p>

<h2>In Functional Programming, what is a functor?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2030863/in-functional-programming-what-is-a-functor/2031421#2031421">this answer</a>, by Norman Ramsey, on what is a functor.</p>

<p>He explains in simple words what the concept is and how a type can belong to the class functor. Examples in haskell.</p>

<p>Tags: norman-ramsey, functor, stack-overflow, haskell, type-class, class, map, fmap</p>

<h2>Functors</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.clojure.net/2013/01/19/Functors/">this article</a> by Jim Duey explaining functors in Clojure. He introduces a couple of notes of Haskell but all of the examples are in Clojure. Explains functors, a subset of it called applicatives, and the two libraries he has created.</p>

<p>Tags: jim-duey, functor, clojure, haskell</p>

<h2>10 Tips for Proper Application Logging</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javacodegeeks.com/2011/01/10-tips-proper-application-logging.html">this article</a> by Tomasz Nurkiewicz about tips on logging:</p>

<ul>
<li>reduce side effects</li>
<li>use categories and levels</li>
<li>connection with external systems</li>
<li>handling exceptions</li>
<li>automatically / manually reading logging files</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: tomasz-nurkiewicz, logging, sl4j, log4j, tip</p>

<h2>What is &ldquo;duck typing&rdquo;?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ericlippert.com/2014/01/02/what-is-duck-typing/">this article</a> by Eric Lippert about duck typing</p>

<p>Tags: duck-typing, eric-lippert, type-system, c-sharp</p>

<h2>Yagni</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve reread <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/Yagni.html">this article</a> by Martin Fowler on the cost of developing features that are not needed</p>

<p>Tags: martin-fowler, yagni, article, misunderstanding</p>

<h2>Learn Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJlI5FPTbgE">this video</a> by Jordan Medlock on learning haskell, explaining the basics and how to use the REPL</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, repl, jordan-medlock, beginner, video</p>

<h2>Learn Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJlI5FPTbgE">this video</a> by Jordan Medlock on learning haskell, explaining the basics and how to use the REPL</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, repl, jordan-medlock, beginner, video</p>

<h2>TMUX - The Terminal Multiplexer</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read these two parts: (<a href="http://blog.hawkhost.com/2010/06/28/tmux-the-terminal-multiplexer/">one</a>, <a href="http://blog.hawkhost.com/2010/07/02/tmux-%E2%80%93-the-terminal-multiplexer-part-2">two</a>) of an introduction guide to <code>tmux</code> (the unix terminal multiplexer) by Cody from Hawk Host.</p>

<p>In it, he explains the basics of tmux and the main differences with <code>screen</code></p>

<p>Tags: cody, hawk-host, tmux, how-to</p>

<h2>Thermodynamics and Garbage Collection</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.pipeline.com/~hbaker1/ThermoGC.html">this paper</a> by Henry G. Baker that explains the analogy of the garbage collection (&ldquo;a freezer&rdquo;) and thermodynamics, where the state mutator (th program, also an oven) modifies the garbage heap and introduces / extracts entropy into the system.</p>

<p>Comparison between entropy and lack of information, using the theories from Shannon, Maxwell-Boltzmann. There&rsquo;s a reference to the knapsack problem and to simulated annealing.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s also a gentle introduction to thermodynamics in layman terms: heat, temperature, microstates, macrostates, reversability, etc.</p>

<p>In this paper it is also reflected (in macro vs micro states) that the sum all parts is simpler than the single ones (i.e., Information Hiding)</p>

<p>Tags: henry-baker, thermodynamics, microstate, macrostate, analogy, simulated-annealing, garbage-collection, shannon, information, maxwell-boltzmann, freezer, oven, entropy</p>

<h2>How we ended up with microservices</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://philcalcado.com/2015/09/08/how_we_ended_up_with_microservices.html">this article</a>, by Phil Calçado, where he talks about his stay at SoundCloud:</p>

<ul>
<li>the value stream map: from X days to Y</li>
<li>reorganizing teams into service teams</li>
<li>conway&rsquo;s law and teams being responsible for support. Also, being given full authority</li>
</ul>


<p>  Tags: phil-calcado, soundcloud, microservice, team-split, value-stream-mapping, conversion, reorganization</p>

<h2>Lisp is still a secret weapon</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://kep.io/is-lisp-still-a-secret-weapon/">this article</a> by Judd Keppel where he explains it is a good idea that Clojure / ClojureScript continues to be a secret, not known among developers. Cites the article &lsquo;Beating the averages&rsquo; by Paul Graham and the amount of available packages in npm, maven central, etc</p>

<p>Tags: paul-graham, judd-keppel, clojure, clojurescript, weapon, developer</p>

<h2>Perceptron</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perceptron">this wikipedia</a> article that explains the single-layer and multi-layer perceptron. First designed to be a machine (hardware), but later an algorithm for supervised machine learning. Worked by Minsky &amp; Papert and invented by Frank Rosenblatt in 1958.</p>

<p>Tags: peceptron, artificial-intelligence, machine-learning, frank-rosenblatt, 1958, marvin-minsky, seymour-papert</p>

<h2>Is C# a strongly typed or a weakly typed language?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ericlippert.com/2012/10/15/is-c-a-strongly-typed-or-a-weakly-typed-language/">this article</a>, in the form of a dialogue between Eric Lippert and himself about the C# language and its type system.</p>

<p>Tags: type-system, c-sharp, eric-lippert, dialogue, strongly-typed, weakly-typed, language</p>

<h2>Diseño por contratos: construyendo software confiable</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.revista.unam.mx/vol.4/num5/art11/sep_art11.pdf">this paper</a> that explains design by contract, based on the Hoare triplet, pre-post condition, method and class invariant. With examples in Eiffel, Java about a package sender company. Also explains pre/post with inheritance. By Gerardo Rossel and Andrea Manna. In Spanish.</p>

<p>Tags: gerardo-rossel, andrea-manna, design-by-contract, unam-mx, eiffel, java, precondition, postcondition, trust, quality, hoare-triplet, method-invariant, class-invariant</p>

<h2>The Inevitable Return of COBOL</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.hackerrank.com/the-inevitable-return-of-cobol/">this article</a> that explains the current state of COBOL in programming and systems. Written by Ritika Trikha</p>

<p>Tags: ritika-trikha, cobol, programming-language, retirement, median-age</p>

<h2>The Risky Eclipse of Statisticians</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.hackerrank.com/the-risky-eclipse-of-statisticians/">this article</a> where Ritika Trikha explains the current situation regarding Big Data and the statiscian jobs. How Big Data is in demand but the latter are not and what effects this might have.</p>

<p>Tags: ritika-trikha, bootcamp, programming, hiring, big-data, analysis, statistics</p>

<h2>Give it five minutes</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://signalvnoise.com/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes">this article</a> by Jason Fried where he explains why we should give ideas time to sink in and marinate, before dismissing them. Ideas are so fragile that it is better to let them live for a while before dismissing them. This also applies for thoughts (other people&rsquo;s or your own).</p>

<p>Tags: jason-fried, idea, think, startup, blue-hat, thinking-hat,  six-thinking-hats, red-hat</p>

<h2>Reading Clojure Stacktraces</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jayfields.com/2012/06/reading-clojure-stacktraces.html">this article</a> by Jay Fields on reading clojure stacktraces. Very similar to &ldquo;Clojure Stack Traces for the Uninitiated&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: jay-fields, clojure, stacktrace</p>

<h2>Clojure Stack Traces for the Uninitiated</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/connor-mendenhall/2014/09/12/clojure-stacktraces.html">this article</a> on how to interpret clojure stacktraces. Written by Connor Mendenhall</p>

<p>Tags: connor-mendenhall, clojure, stacktrace</p>

<h2>JavaScript type inference</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve found (and played) with <a href="http://www.ccs.neu.edu/home/dimvar/jstypes.html">this JavaScript type inference engine</a>. Written in Javascript (and available online). Written by Dimitrios Vardoulakis.</p>

<p>Tags: javascript-type-inference, type-inference, type-inference-algorithm, dimitrios-vardoulakis, cfa2</p>

<h2>Alternatives to boolean parameters</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/dariusz-pasciak/2015/05/28/alternatives-to-boolean-parameters.html">this article</a> explaining alternatives to sending a boolean parameter to decide on the contents of the function. Written by Dariusz Pasciak</p>

<p>As I heard some time ago, if a function receives a boolean to decide on what to do, it will for sure have more than one responsibility: one for the false value and one for the true value.</p>

<p>Tags: dariusz-pasciak, boolean, srp, boolean-parameter</p>

<h2>Why Are Web Uploads So Painful?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/why-are-web-uploads-so-painful/">this article</a> on web uploads being painful. By Jeff Atwood. The screenshots feel old (2007) and some of the problems have already been solved.</p>

<p>Tags: jeff-atwood, article, upload, browser</p>

<h2>Can Your Team Pass The Elevator Test?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/can-your-team-pass-the-elevator-test/">this article</a> on the elevator test by Jeff Atwood.</p>

<p>Tags: jeff-atwood, article, elevator-test, assumption, microsoft-bob, vision, product, feature</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby: Chapter 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/11/practical-object-oriented-design-in-ruby-chapter-2/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-11T22:07:29+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/11/practical-object-oriented-design-in-ruby-chapter-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve read the second chapter from the Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby, by Sandi Metz.</p>

<p>These are the concepts and links brought up during the discussion:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DataClump.html">Data Clump</a> at the bliki</li>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/117817370205182982732/posts/WaMWtp1Uetp">Refactoring with Loops and Collection Pipelines</a>, indirect link to the article by Martin Fowler</li>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/117817370205182982732/posts/6J9PPQpUjwY">When Worse Is Better: Incrementally Escaping Local Maxima</a>, indirect link to the article by Kent Beck</li>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/117817370205182982732/posts/Sk7DfYFPt5j">Getting It Right by Betting on Wrong</a>, indirect link to an article by Sandi Metz</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in July 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/self-study-in-july-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-30T23:08:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/self-study-in-july-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post</p>

<h2>Clojure made simple</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VSdnJDO-xdg">this talk</a> by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy">Easy made simple</a></p>

<ul>
<li>polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter</li>
</ul>


<h2>Productive pair programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/07/productive-pair-programming/">this article</a> about pair programming, using the driver &amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Building Automated REST APIs with Python</h2>

<p>Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/jeffknupp/building-automated-rest-apis-with-python">these slides</a> about it</p>

<h2>Backwards Compatibility Testing For Your Clojure Project</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.jenkster.com/2014/02/backwards-compatibility-testing-your-clojure-project.html">this article</a> on making leiningen test the application on several clojure versions. Written by Kris Jenkins.</p>

<h2>Succeeding with Automated Integration Tests</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://jeremydmiller.com/2015/06/25/succeeding_with_integration_testing/">this article</a> by Jeremy Miller on integration testing and how to succeed with it. Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Choose the Quickest, Useful Feedback Mechanism, even if that means testing the backend and frontend separately</li>
<li>Prefer white-box than black-box testing</li>
<li>Use quick tests, that can be run locally in an easy fashion</li>
<li>Do not share databases, as they introduce risks of flaky tests</li>
</ul>


<h2>Applied DDD in a Java EE 7 and Open Source World</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9D_-7E7Mrzw">this video</a> by Edson Yanaga in the Java One, about DDD using Java EE 7, JSFs and lambdas on top of glassfish</p>

<h2>Integrated tests are a scam</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read, again, <a href="http://blog.thecodewhisperer.com/2010/10/16/integrated-tests-are-a-scam/">this article</a> by J. B. Rainsberger on integrated tests and why not to use them. From a numerical / combinatorics point of view.</p>

<h2>Functional Programming should be your #1 priority for 2015</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@jugoncalves/functional-programming-should-be-your-1-priority-for-2015-47dd4641d6b9">this introduction</a> to functional programming by Ju Gonçalves. Explains some functional concepts, such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>First-Class Functions</li>
<li>High-Order Functions</li>
<li>Pure Functions</li>
<li>Closures</li>
<li>Immutable State</li>
</ul>


<p>Also recommends a few books on the subject (e.g., SICP, HTDP).</p>

<h2>A Tutorial Introduction to the Lambda Calculus</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.inf.fu-berlin.de/lehre/WS03/alpi/lambda.pdf">this paper</a>, an introduction to the lambda calculus. Haven&rsquo;t done the exercises. Written by Raúl Rojas</p>

<h2>20 common mistakes when doing Test-Driven Development</h2>

<p>I had thought of converting all of <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=svpino%20%23tdd%20mistake&amp;src=typd">his tweets</a> into a blog post, but he has already done this for us: I&rsquo;ve read a <a href="https://blog.svpino.com/2015/05/29/20-common-mistakes-when-doing-test-driven-development">list of common mistakes</a> when doing TDD by <a href="https://twitter.com/svpino">Santiago Pino</a></p>

<h2>Reducing coupling</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the article by Martin Fowler <a href="http://martinfowler.com/ieeeSoftware/coupling.pdf">Reducing Coupling</a> in the IEEE SOFTWARE July/August 2001</p>

<h2>Comparing Java Mock Frameworks – Part 2: Creating Mock Objects</h2>

<p><a href="https://softwareinabottle.wordpress.com/2010/10/06/comparing-java-mock-frameworks-part-2-creating-mock-objects/">List of mock frameworks for java</a>. Have only read the jMock, mockito and jMockit part.</p>

<h2> Software Craftsmanship book review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://meaganwaller.com/software-craftsmanship-book-review/">this review</a> for a book that is already pending in my book list: Software Craftsmanship by Pete McBreen.</p>

<p>The review has been written by Megan Waller, an (ex-)apprentice at 8th Light.</p>

<h2>Fundamental concepts in programming languages</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~crary/819-f09/Strachey67.pdf">this paper</a> containing the contents for lectures in Computer Programming in the year 1967. Written by Christopher Strachey.</p>

<p>Note: I&rsquo;ve also seen this paper recommended in the repo <a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love/tree/master/plt">Papers We Love > plt</a> (Programming Language Theory)</p>

<h2>What is reification?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.angelikalanger.com/GenericsFAQ/FAQSections/TechnicalDetails.html#FAQ101A">this FAQ</a> on reification by Angelika Langer</p>

<h2>Type erasure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wikipedia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_erasure">page on type erasure</a></p>

<h2>How to make an IntelliJ IDEA plugin in less than 30 minutes</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://bjorn.tipling.com/how-to-make-an-intellij-idea-plugin-in-30-minutes">this article</a> on creating new IntelliJ IDEA plugin, by Bjorn Tipling</p>

<h2>How to Write Clean, Testable Code</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched, again, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XcT4yYu_TTs">this video</a> by Miško Hevery. Discusses what are the characteristics of tested and untested code, how to get from one to the other. Discusses techniques for testing code. At the end, there are questions but they cannot be heard (lack of microphone), so it is harder to follow.</p>

<h2>How to Find a Mentor</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/letters-to-my-mother/how-to-find-a-mentor-27fb978a8f1">this opinion</a> on the importance of role models and mentors. The difference between them and a personal experience. Written by Joanne Wilson</p>

<h2>Type theory</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wiki page on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_theory">type theory</a></p>

<p>Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;type systems [&hellip;] language feature used to reduce bugs&rdquo;</li>
<li>two types: Church&rsquo;s typed λ-calculi and Martin-Löf&rsquo;s intuitionistic type theory.</li>
<li>notation:

<ul>
<li>typing judgement: <code>M : A</code>. Term <code>M</code> has type <code>A</code></li>
<li>example: <code>nat</code> may be a type</li>
<li><code>2 : nat</code>, like in Scala</li>
<li>function: &ldquo;arrow&rdquo;</li>
<li>apply function to argument: no parenthesis</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>conversion rule: rule for rewriting terms

<ul>
<li>reduction rule: conversion rule that only works in one direction</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>normal form: a form that cannot be further reduced</li>
<li>element: all closed elements that can be reduced to the same normal form</li>
<li>closed term: a term without parameters. Opposite is an open term</li>
<li>convertibility: property of terms, both open and closed. Said to be convertible if two terms can be reduced to the same term

<ul>
<li>warning: x + 1 and 1 + x are not convertible because they are in normal form and not the same</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Type system</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this wiki page on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_system">type system</a></p>

<p>Some notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;The depth of type constraints and the manner of their evaluation affect the typing of the language&rdquo;</li>
<li>Type polymorphism</li>
<li>{compile time, runtime} x {manually annotated, inferred}</li>
<li>&ldquo;A program associates each value with at least one particular type, but it also can occur that one value is associated with many subtypes.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Classification of types:

<ul>
<li>data type – a type of a value</li>
<li>class – a type of an object</li>
<li>kind – a type of a type, or metatype</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>the type inference might be undecidable (for more complex type inference)</li>
<li>&ldquo;Strong typing offers more safety, but cannot guarantee complete type safety.&rdquo; An example is the division by zero, altough some languages may declare a dependent type &ldquo;non-zero numbers&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h2>The 3 things you should know about hashCode()</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://eclipsesource.com/blogs/2012/09/04/the-3-things-you-should-know-about-hashcode/">this article</a> on the hashCode() method in java, written by Ralf Sternberg.</p>

<h2>Reduce Complexity with Variants</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/reduce-complexity-with-variants">this article</a> on variants in clojure by Eric Normand</p>

<h2>What is new in SQL:2011</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.sigmod.org/publications/sigmod-record/1203/pdfs/10.industry.zemke.pdf">this white paper</a> on the new features in SQL 2011. Written by Fred Zemke</p>

<h2>5 Error Tracking Tools Java Developers Should Know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.javacodegeeks.com/2014/09/5-error-tracking-tools-java-developers-should-know.html">this article</a> about tracking tools for java written by Alex Zhitnitsky, featuring:</p>

<ul>
<li>Raygun</li>
<li>Sentry</li>
<li>Takipi</li>
<li>Airbrake</li>
<li>StackHunter</li>
<li>[Bonus] ABRT</li>
<li>Comments cite <a href="http://squash.io">Squash</a> (server written in ruby, java client available) and <a href="http://rollbar.com">Rollbar</a> (home says supports android but not says anything about java)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Data clump</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DataClump.html">this article</a> on the bliki, by Martin Fowler</p>

<h2>NP-Complete problems</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://webdiis.unizar.es/asignaturas/TC/wp/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/L15_NPcompletos.pdf">these slides</a> by Prof. Elvira Mayordomo about NP-Complete problems, how to reduce them to other problems and practical applications. (In Spanish)</p>

<h2>Removal of sun.misc.Unsafe in Java 9 - A disaster in the making</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.dripstat.com/removal-of-sun-misc-unsafe-a-disaster-in-the-making/">this article</a> about the removal of this Unsafe class in Java 9, by the DripStat team</p>

<h2>How To Write Directly to a Memory Locations In Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://robaustin.wikidot.com/how-to-write-to-direct-memory-locations-in-java">this guide</a> on how to write directly to a memory position in java, by Rob Austin</p>

<h2>Interesting uses of sun.misc.Unsafe</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://bytescrolls.blogspot.com.es/2011/04/interesting-uses-of-sunmiscunsafe.html">this article</a> by Haris A.L.</p>

<h2>Introduction to the theory of np-completeness</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.site.uottawa.ca/~lucia/courses/4105-02/np.pdf">these notes / slides</a> to the introductory course of NP-completeness, by Prof Lucia Moura</p>

<h2>JS Code Kata: Linked List</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/yitznewton/js-code-kata-linked-list">these slides</a> on the kata linked list, by Yitz Schaffer. The slide #13 talks about the transformations:</p>

<ul>
<li>refactor: change form without changing behavior</li>
<li>transform: change behavior while changing form as little as possible</li>
</ul>


<p>Also about the Transformation Priority Premise (TPP) (also in this month)</p>

<h2>The Transformation Priority Premise</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read, again, <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2013/05/27/TheTransformationPriorityPremise.html">this article</a> by Uncle Bob (Robert C. Martin)</p>

<h2>Data structures</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the wiki page for</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SPQR_tree">SPQR tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_search_tree">BSR tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red%E2%80%93black_tree">Red black tree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judy_array">Judy array</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Also, The <a href="http://bigocheatsheet.com/">Big-O notation complexity cheatsheet</a></p>

<h2>On benchmarks: Numbers every programmer should know and their impact on benchmarks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hype-free.blogspot.com/2014/03/on-benchmarks.html">this post</a> on doing back-of-the-envelope calculations on publicly available benchmarks, written by Attila-Mihaly Balazs</p>

<h2>Top Java IDE Keyboard Shortcuts for Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA &amp; NetBeans</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/top-java-ide-keyboard-shortcuts-for-eclipse-intellij-idea-netbeans/">these slides</a> on the topic of keyboard shortcuts for java IDEs, written by Oleg Šelajev</p>

<h2>The hacker’s summer training guide – part 1</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.paymill.com/hackers-training-guide-1">this post</a> by Paymill, that suggests which new languages to learn this summer: rust, go, elixir, ocaml, scala, livescript.</p>

<h2>Applications built extremely right</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://apiumtech.com/blog/applications-build-with-outsourcing/">this post</a> with a list of candidates for building nice products, written by Xavi Hidalgo.</p>

<h2>Agile project seed. Infrastructure by default.</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://apiumtech.com/blog/seed-de-proyecto-agile-infraestructura-por-defecto/">this post</a> on an agile seed project. Reminded me of the 12-factor app</p>

<h2>What an agile developer should know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.apiumtech.com/blog/lo-que-un-desarrollador-agile-deberia-saber/">this post</a> by Xavi Hidalgo</p>

<h2>Bad Apples that can destroy a team</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve listened to <a href="http://www.scrum-master-toolbox.com/2015/03/podcast/dominic-krimmer-describes-the-types-of-bad-apples-that-can-destroy-a-team/">this podcast</a> about the bad apples in a team. Presented by Vasco Duarte and Dominic Krimmer as the main speaker</p>

<h2>How Scala compares with 20 other programming languages according to Reddit analysis</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.typesafe.com/blog/how-scala-compares-20-programming-languages-reddit-analysis">this analysis</a> of the language comparison, written by Oliver White</p>

<h2>Javascript patterns book review</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2047-javascript-patterns-by-stoyan-stefanov.htm">this review</a> by Ben Nadel on the book Javascript Patterns, by Stoyan Stefanov</p>

<h2>Monogamous TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/04/25/MonogamousTDD.html">this article</a> on the fundamentalism of TDD, written by Robert C Martin</p>

<h2>Encapsulating LocalStorage Access In AngularJS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2861-encapsulating-localstorage-access-in-angularjs.htm">this article</a> on why encapsulate the access to the localStorage, written by Ben Nadel</p>

<h2>Anatomy of a zero-knowledge web application</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://clipperz.is/blog/2007/08/24/anatomy_zero_knowledge_web_application/">this article</a> on a zero-knowledge web application, by the clipperz team</p>

<h2>Refactorización de Código Legado Clase Maestra</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VBgCKKevhyI">this video</a> about refactoring a legacy code in C#, by Danijel Arsenovski</p>

<h2>Taming Javaagents</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/shelajev/taming-javaagents-bcn-jug-2015">these slides</a>, again, from a conference I went to a few months ago about java agents. Written by Oleg Šelajev.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/shelajev/ResourceLeakAgent">This</a> is the repository containing the memory leak agent he talks about</p>

<h2>Mathematics for Computer Science, Lecture 1</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched by <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/math_for_comp_science_mit/lessons/Lecture1/">the first recitation</a> in <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/math_for_comp_science_mit/index.php">this course</a>, offered by MIT Open Course Ware (OCW). Recited by Tom Leighton</p>

<h2>Programming Abstractions: Lecture 7</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://xoax.net/comp_sci/crs/programming_abstractions_stanford/lessons/Lecture7/">this lecture</a> by Julie Zelensky about the comparison operator, recursion and a live coding session calculating the most ocurring anagram word in a file.</p>

<p>She uses small outputs to check the correctness of her programs to get short feedback cycles, even if they are manual.</p>

<h2>5 Ways To Launch a JMeter Test without Using the JMeter GUI</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blazemeter.com/blog/5-ways-launch-jmeter-test-without-using-jmeter-gui">this guide</a> on using jmeter without a GUI, by Dmitri Tikhanski</p>

<h2>Clojure unraveled, chapter 5</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the <a href="http://funcool.github.io/clojurescript-unraveled/#language-advanced-topics">fifth chapter</a>, on the topics of Transducers, Transients, Metadata, Macros, Core protocols. Written by Andrey Antukh and Alejandro Gómez</p>

<h2>A guide to the Basics of Data Structures</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/data-structures-basics/">this guide</a> to data structures, covering the stack, the queue, the heap, the tree and the hashmap. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>Government Abandonware</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://techblog.bozho.net/government-abandonware/">this post</a> on abandoned, public software that is not opensource. Dubbed by the author as &ldquo;Government Abandonware&rdquo;. Written by Bozhidar Bozhanov</p>

<h2>The Art of Incremental Stream Processing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mth.io/talks/streams/">these slides</a> on incremental stream processing. The examples are in haskell and scala. Written by Mark Hibberd</p>

<h2>Reader as Link Author</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://hapgood.us/2015/07/22/follow-up-reader-as-link-author/">this insight</a> into federated wikis by Mike Caulfield</p>

<h2>Kafkapocalypse: a postmortem on our service outage</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.parsely.com/post/1738/kafkapocalypse/">this post-mortem analysis</a> of the service outage at parse.ly, by Andrew Montalenti</p>

<h2>Loving a Log-Oriented Architecture</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.parsely.com/post/1550/kreps-logs/">this post</a> on experiences using the log-based architecture, by Andrew Montalenti. Cites the books <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-Logs-Stream-Processing-Integration/dp/1491909382">I Heart Logs</a>,  and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1617290343">Big Data: Principles and best practices of scalable realtime data systems</a> the essay <a href="http://engineering.linkedin.com/distributed-systems/log-what-every-software-engineer-should-know-about-real-time-datas-unifying">The Log</a></p>

<h2>A guide to Algorithmic Complexity</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/algorithmic-complexity">this guide</a> to algorithmic complexity, explaining Big-Oh notation (Big-Oh, Big-Theta, Big-Omega), with examples. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>A guide to Recursion</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://algosaur.us/recursion">this guide</a> to recursion explaining the gist of it. Examples include the Fibonacci sequence and the Hanoi Towers problem. Later, an introduction to the chaos theory and fractals. Written by Radhika Ghosal</p>

<h2>Bootstrapped ClojureScript FAQ</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/clojure/clojurescript/wiki/Bootstrapped-ClojureScript-FAQ">this FAQ</a> related to bootstrapping clojurescript</p>

<h2>Applying property-based testing on my binary search tree implementation</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://garajeando.blogspot.com/2015/07/applying-property-based-testing-on-my.html">this article</a>, written by Manuel Rivero, on applying test-check (a property-based testing framework, similar to quickcheck) to a Binary Search Tree (BST) he did.</p>

<h2>Do Extraterrestrials Use Functional Programming?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://yowconference.com.au/slides/yowlambdajam2013/Chakravarty-Extraterrestrials-Keynote.pdf">these slides</a>, an introduction to lambda calculus, the Turing machine and the Halting Problem. Later, continues to describe ways of solving problems in a functional way. Also performance and optimizations; monads as well. Written by Manuel M T Chakravarty</p>

<h2>WIP Limits</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://theagileist.wordpress.com/2015/06/15/wip-limits/">this post</a> by Tomas Rybing</p>

<h2>Applied capacity planning</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://theagileist.wordpress.com/2015/07/27/applied-capacity-planning/">this post</a> by Tomas Rybing.</p>

<h2>Don’t Get Attached to Programming Languages</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://mikecavaliere.com/dont-get-attached-programming-languages">this post</a> by Mike Cavaliere</p>

<h2>The Top 5 Skills of Rock Star Software Engineers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://softwareplusplus.com/2015/06/24/the-top-5-skills-of-rock-star-software-engineers/">this post</a> by Cory Berg</p>

<h2>5 Reasons to Use Protocol Buffers Instead of JSON For Your Next Service</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codeclimate.com/blog/2014/06/05/choose-protocol-buffers/">this article</a> on Protocol Buffers, written by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Data Serialization Formats</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://gist.github.com/joshsz/11299196">this comparison</a> between MsgPack, JSON, Protocol Buffers, by Josh Szmajda.</p>

<h2>Protocol Buffer Basics: Java</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/javatutorial">this introduction</a> to Protocol Buffers in Java, by Google</p>

<h2>RESTful Considered Harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://dzone.com/articles/restful-considered-harmful?oid=top_title">this article</a>, commenting downsides to using JSON / RESTful APIs, written by Tomasz Nurkiewicz</p>

<h2>“Considered Harmful” Essays Considered Harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://meyerweb.com/eric/comment/chech.html">this post</a>, by Eric Meyer, on why &ldquo;Considered Harmful&rdquo; are harmful as well.</p>

<h2>Keep Lambdas Cohesive</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.agiledeveloper.com/2015/07/keep-lambdas-cohesive.html">this post</a> with recommendations on keeping the java lambdas cohesive. Written by Venkat Subramaniam</p>

<h2>The Joy of Flying Robots with Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty9QDqV-_Ak">this video</a> by Carin Meier at the OSCON 2013 about communicating with robots in Clojure</p>

<h2>How to Learn TDD Without Getting Overwhelmed</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.justinweiss.com/blog/2014/06/02/how-to-learn-tdd-without-getting-overwhelmed/">this article</a> on learning TDD, by Justin Weiss</p>

<h2>Kata - the Only Way to Learn TDD</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.peterprovost.org/blog/2012/05/02/kata-the-only-way-to-learn-tdd/">this article</a> on learning TDD, by Peter Provost</p>

<h2>Koan: Past Perfect</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thecodelesscode.com/case/180">this koan</a>, past perfect, reflecting on the people who prefer the past over the present. Who think that the past was simpler than currently is.</p>

<h2>Koan: Future Imperfect</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thecodelesscode.com/case/181">this koan</a>, continuation from past perfect.</p>

<h2>Why “Agile” and especially Scrum are terrible</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://michaelochurch.wordpress.com/2015/06/06/why-agile-and-especially-scrum-are-terrible/">this article</a> on downsides of Agile and Scrum, written by Michael Church.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
