<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Book | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/book/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-05T01:09:33+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Diseño Ágil Con TDD (Spanish)]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-02T21:32:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve read this book <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/libro-tdd/">Diseño Ágil con TDD</a> (Spanish) by
<a href="https://twitter.com/carlosble">Carlos Blé</a> from cover to cover,
when previously I had only read the theoretical parts (Part I and Chapter 12 in Part II).</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s worth noting that this is the first TDD book in Spanish (I haven&rsquo;t found any book in Spanish predating this one - also backed by the author; published in January 2010) and, as such, there are some translations that could be improved. Not that it makes it more difficult to read. Sometimes it&rsquo;s a good idea to roughly translate concepts into English and then you&rsquo;ll understand the point.</p>

<h2>First part</h2>

<p>The first part is very interesting, a theoretical introduction into TDD, ATDD and Agile methodologies. Points to some good books as a reference (e.g., Growing Object Oriented Software, Guided by Tests; Working Effectively with Legacy Code; Refactoring; etc)</p>

<p>He explains the TDD algorithm (chapter 2) and the ATDD one (chapter 3). These two are maybe the two most important ones on the book. Should you read only a part of this book, I&rsquo;d recommend to read the motivational intro (the fable on the preface) and these two.</p>

<p>He gives excellent pieces of advice who, correctly applied, would set the basis for good software development, such as SOLID, Object Oriented Design (OOD), Inversion of Control (IoC), etc. (See chapter 7, &ldquo;Diseño orientado a objetos&rdquo;).</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a chapter (number 6) on &ldquo;Mocks and other test doubles&rdquo; (translation is mine)</p>

<h2>Second part</h2>

<p>The second part, as many other books where the source code is printed, was dense for me. Other books, such as <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">GOOS</a>, show differences in content with bold typeface, to ease the reader&rsquo;s task.  In my opinion, it would be useful to color the diffs, show them on the left and right, or even show the raw diff (e.g., <code>+++</code> <code>---</code>). I&rsquo;m envisioning a typing program as LaTeX where you could specify a commit with its parent and a range of lines to output.</p>

<p>The second part is written in C# and python, to show a TDD session with him. Warning: it&rsquo;s much better in person than reading his book!</p>

<p>The chapter 12 is a set of antipatterns you might find after starting with TDD. Even after you keep practicing TDD for a while, you will not get rid of these smells. Highly recommended.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s also an appendix on Continuous Integration, although there are better books for this.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Recommend this book if you are starting with TDD, or you are more advanced but it&rsquo;s difficult for you to read in English.</p>

<p>Always good as a refresher to read the theoretical part and the antipatterns</p>

<p>PS: This book is free to read, published under a Creative Commons license (don&rsquo;t know exactly which one)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your First Language]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-02T21:25:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading (in a specific order - below) part of the patterns in <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596518387.do">Apprenticeship Patterns</a>,
I stumbled upon the <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch02.html#your_first_language">&ldquo;Your First Language&rdquo;</a></p>

<p>First of all, the illustration with the baby reading a Java book is priceless.</p>

<p>Having said that, I came to the realization that you might not know a paradigm but just an implementation
(e.g., you don&rsquo;t know about Object-Oriented programming but just about Java), in the same fashion as you could not know about LISPs but only about an implementation, such as clojure.</p>

<p>Also, clicks with the idea of &ldquo;code to interfaces, not implementations&rdquo;. Does it also click with you?</p>

<p>PS: What a great book this is. I&rsquo;m reading it in one of the specified ways: pick a pattern and start navigating
through the book following the &ldquo;see also&rdquo;</p>

<p>PPS: you can read it online for free, <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Listening to the Tests]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/listening-to-the-tests/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T22:05:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/listening-to-the-tests</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Specifically the chapter no. 20 (&ldquo;Listening to the tests&rdquo;) from <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests</a> available <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0321503627/ref=as_sl_pd_tf_lc?tag=httpwwwm3pcou-20&amp;camp=213381&amp;creative=390973&amp;linkCode=as4&amp;creativeASIN=0321503627&amp;adid=12B4KPA3REF515ASAZN8&amp;&amp;ref-refURL=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.growing-object-oriented-software.com%2F">here</a> is so good to learn to hear to your tests.</p>

<p>To hear what they&rsquo;re trying to tell you, the authors (<a href="https://twitter.com/sf105">Steve Freeman</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/natpryce">Nat Pryce</a>) explain this to you:</p>

<ul>
<li>I Need to Mock an Object I Can’t Replace</li>
<li>Logging Is a Feature</li>
<li>Mocking Concrete Classes</li>
<li>Don’t Mock Values</li>
<li>Bloated Constructor</li>
<li>Confused Object</li>
<li>Too Many Dependencies</li>
<li>Too Many Expectations</li>
</ul>


<p>To close, a quote:</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] We’ve found that the qualities that make an object easy to test also make our code responsive to change</p>

<p><a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests</a>, chapter 20, page 229</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Joys of the Craft]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T22:46:50+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Quoting the book,</p>

<blockquote><p>Why is programming fun? What delights may its practitioner expect as his reward?</p>

<p>First is the sheer joy of making things. As the child delights in his mud pie, so the adult enjoys building things, especially things of his own design [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Second is the pleasure of making things that are useful to other people. Deep within, we want other to use our work and to find it helpful. [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Third is the fascination of fashioning complex puzzle-like objects of interlocking moving parts and watching them work in subtle cycles, playing out the consequences of principles built in from the beginning. [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Fourth is the joy of always learning, which springs from the nonrepeating nature of the task. In one way or another the problem is ever new, and its solver learns something: sometimes practical, sometimes theoretical, and sometimes both.</p>

<p>Finally, there is the delight of working in such a tractable medium. The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from the pure thought-stuff. He builds his castles in the air, from air, creating by exertion of the imagination. Few media of creating are so flexible, so easy to polish and rework, so readily capable of realizing grand conceptual structures. (As we shall see later, this very tractability has its own problems.)</p>

<p><cite>Frederick P. Brooks, Jr</cite> in the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Mythical-Man-Month-Engineering-Anniversary/dp/0201835959">&ldquo;The Mythical Man-Month&rdquo;</a></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
