<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-study on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/self-study/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-study on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/self-study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 12 rules for life; Peterson; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  12 rules for life The book contains some rules, some principles to remove doubt and uncertainty from life.
There are plenty of mentions to the Bible, although I consider the book to the secular in its contents.
There are few personal stories on the book (e.g., about his daughter Mikhaila Peterson), which makes it readable and enjoyable. The philosophy behind it is sometimes not-politically-correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Bushido, the soul of Japan; Nitobe; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Skunk Works; Rich; own-it, non-technical  Skunk Works This book describes Ben R. Rich&amp;rsquo;s adventure of creating the F-117A, the stealth plane with a triangular shape.
Describes how he won a bet against legendary plane designer Clarence &amp;lsquo;Kelly&amp;rsquo; Johnson. How he got the 25 cents from his old mentor and friend.
Later, the book reviews Kelly&amp;rsquo;s history as the manager of Skunk Works, how it works, the principles (Kelly&amp;rsquo;s 14 rules), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 3); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy Confidence Hacks: 99 small actions to massively boost your confidence; Davenport; own-it, non-technical Tots estimem l&amp;rsquo;Emma; Burgas; non-technical  Confidence Hacks This is a self help book to boost your confidence.
It covers several areas of your life, that could erode your confidence:
 Relationships Social Life Career Appearance Self-Improvement Body Language Thinking Fun and Adventure Finances  How to read and apply it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 2); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 1); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy My Story, Al Maktoum; non-technical  My Story, Al Maktoum  This important collection of anecdotes and reminiscences from Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum is published to mark the occasion of his fifty years in public service, which began with his appointment as Dubai’s Minister of Defence in 1968.
These stories tell of the vision behind Dubai’s meteoric growth from a small and bustling trading port to an international metropolis at the heart of global business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein; own-it, finance, non-technical Candide; Voltaire; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Simple path to wealth, the; Collins; own-it, non-technical, finance Lagom; Brantmark; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Comment revivre par le jeune; Lützner; own-it, non-technical Educación financiera avanzada desde cero; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance Pensiones públicas, la esclavitud de nuestra época; Hernández; non-technical, own-it, finance On the shortness of life; Séneca; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Código del dinero, el; Samsó; own-it, non-technical, finance Más cosas sobre la bolsa; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance  4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein Candide; Voltaire Came across this book as the source for the term &amp;lsquo;Panglossian&amp;rsquo; or extreme optimist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</guid>
      <description>This quarter I&amp;rsquo;ve focused my efforts on a mix of everything:
 business books: Traction, The Goal philosophy: Stoicism and personal philosophy some finance: classic: Malkiel, personal finance: Robin some classic psychology: Frankl a classic novel: The Metamorphosis (Kafka)  Read this quarter:
 Hombre en busca del sentido, el; Frankl; own-it, non-technical Metamorfosis; Kafka; own-it, non-technical Your money or your life; Dominguez, Robin; non-technical, finance, own-it Traction; Wickman; own-it, non-technical How to Be a Stoic: Using Ancient Philosophy to Live a Modern Life; Pigliucci; own-it, non-technical Guide to the Good Life, The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy, a; Irvine; non-technical, own-it Goal, the; Goldratt (+); own-it Random walk down wall street a; Malkiel [Parts I, II, III]; own-it  Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) Oliver Twist; Dickens Building evolutionary architecture; Ford, Parsons Selfie: How We Became So Self-Obsessed and What It’s Doing To Us; Storr. Just chapter 1: The dying self Sota la cistella; Gasol  Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) I&amp;rsquo;ve re-read this classic book (How to win friends and influence people), by Carnegie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles Book of Transformation; Dalai Lama  Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book on philosophy and ethics. This book contains an analysis of the relationship between the personality, intelligence and happiness.
Tries to describe what &amp;lsquo;virtues&amp;rsquo; are, that they belong in a continuum of acts, aand the good term is always in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Quien se ha llevado mi queso; Johnson; own-it, guillem One minute manager, the; Blanchard; own-it, non-technical, guillem En defensa de los ociosos; Stevenson; non-technical, own-it Ladybird Book of Mindfulness, the (Ladybirds for Grown-Ups); Hazeley, Morris; non-technical Art of the start, the; Kawasaki; own-it, non-technical, guillem Getting started with NoFap; non-technical Emotional intelligence; Goleman; non-technical  Quien se ha llevado mi queso I&amp;rsquo;ve read this fable explaining the little story of two mice and two lilliputians that end up without any cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
Note: the tag &amp;ldquo;guillem&amp;rdquo; is for books suggested by Guillem Fernandez
 Odessa; Forsyth; non-technical, own-it Bogle on mutual funds: new perspectives for the intelligent investor; Bogle; own-it, non-technical, finance Perros de la guerra, los; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical avaro y el oro, el; Esopo; non-technical Aulularia; Plauto; own-it, non-technical Tus zonas erróneas; Dyer; non-technical, own-it Alternativa del Diablo, la; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Guía, el; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Pied piper; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Hunt for the Red October, the; Clancy; own-it, non-technical Peopleware; DeMarco, Lister (+); own-it Time to kill, a; Grisham; own-it, non-technical Ética promiscua; Easton, Hardy; own-it, non-technical Checklist manifesto, the; Gawande; own-it, non-technical, guillem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Lazarillo de Tormes, el; anónimo; non-technical Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s power plays - Politika; Preisler; own-it, non-technical Moon is a harsh mistress, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Old man&amp;rsquo;s war; Scalzi; non-technical, own-it Nightfall; Asimov, Silverberg; own-it, non-technical Interface; Stephenson, George; non-technical, own-it Man who sold the moon, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Agents of innocence; Ignatius; own-it, non-technical Fist of god, the; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical: Synopsis: in a mixture of truth and novel, the author explains the invasion of Kuwait by Iraqi dictator Sadam Hussein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 the senior software developer; Copeland, with the aprendices reading club Scandal in Bohemia, a; Doyle: a short novel by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, mentioning Irene Adler and the king of Bohemia Getting things done, &amp;hellip;; Allen (+): A book on productivity, where Allen explains his method of GTD and how to apply it. Explains what has worked and not worked for him in his many years of consulting and coaching clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</guid>
      <description>(I&amp;rsquo;ve changed how I organize my books. More, here (TODO))
Finished:
 Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern; non-technical. A quick introduction to Bertrand Russell, his life and his way of thinking and seeing the world. Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell; non-technical. A first-person view of the events during the Spanish Civil War (1936-1939), seen from the perspective of a British citizen that went there voluntarily. Explains the internal fracture of the left political parties and the fracture of the Spanish society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
  The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/books-read-in-2016q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/books-read-in-2016q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
 La psicología del dinero, Hammond Invirtiendo a largo plazo, García Paramés Quién domina el mundo, Chomsky Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell El camino al 18J, Payne Cartas desde la revolución bolchevique, Sadoul Shogun: The Life of Tokugawa Ieyasu, Sadler Els jueus i Catalunya, Villatoro Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern El problema de los tres cuerpos, Liu    The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/books-read-in-2016q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/books-read-in-2016q3/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Pocket Guide by Chromatic Notes to a Software Team Leader (1st Edition), by Roy Osherove  Non-technical:
 The Zero Marginal Cost Society: The Internet of Things, the Collaborative Commons, and the Eclipse of Capitalism, by Jeremy Rifkin Snow Crash, by Neal Stephenson La guerra no tiene rostro de mujer, by Svetlana Aleksiévich  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Talking with Tech Leads: From Novices to Practitioners by Patrick Kua  Books I want to finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change, 2nd Edition by Kent Beck and Cynthia Andres, again. Building Microservices, Designing Fine-Grained Systems, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Reinventing Organizations by Frederic Laloux. Blog posts under the tag reinventing-organizations  Non-technical:
 L&amp;rsquo;acabadora, by Michela Murgia Disrupted: My Misadventure in the Start-Up Bubble by Dan Lyons  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/books-read-in-2016q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/books-read-in-2016q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 101 cosas que ya sabes, pero siempre olvidas by Ernie J. Zelinski; in Spanish Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs by Abelson, Sussman, and Sussman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag sicp. Only chapters 1 and 2.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Building microservices, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Why programmers work at night by Swizec Teller Readings in Database Systems, 5th Edition by Peter Bailis, Joseph M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/books-read-in-2015q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/books-read-in-2015q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby, An Agile Primer (POODR) by Sandi Metz, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag poodr.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Haskell Programming, By Chris Allen and Julie Moronuki. This book is still in progress and I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing it Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs by Abelson, Sussman, and Sussman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/books-read-in-2015q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/books-read-in-2015q3/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 The Craftsman by Richard Sennett. Posts under the tag the-craftsman Software Craftsmanship: The New Imperative by Pete McBreen. Posts under the tag software-craftsmanship-book Lisp Hackers by Vsevolod Dyomkin The Passionate Programmer: Creating a Remarkable Career in Software Development by Chad Fowler.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Haskell Programming, By Chris Allen and Julie Moronuki. This book is still in progress and I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing it Functional Programming Patterns in Scala and Clojure by Michael Bevilacqua-Linn Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt  Books I want to finish:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in July 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post
Clojure made simple I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk Easy made simple
 polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter  Productive pair programming I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about pair programming, using the driver &amp;amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé
Building Automated REST APIs with Python Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/books-read-in-2015q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/books-read-in-2015q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q2 on 2015:
 Flow by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi. Blog posts under the tag flow Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce. Blog posts under the tag goos. Read in the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. TDD in Java, by Viktor Farcic and Alex García. I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed this book.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 The Well-Grounded Java Developer by Benjamin J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in May 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015 into a single post
Programmer passion considered harmful I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.
Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by Ken Auer
Improve your development environments with virtualization I have seen this video: Improve your development environments with virtualization by Luke Sneeringer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/books-read-in-2015q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 12:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/books-read-in-2015q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q1 on 2015, as inspired by Manuel, on this post:
 Fifty Quick Ideas to Improve your User Stories, by Gojko Adzic and David Evans Fun retrospectives by Taina Caetano and Paulo Caroli Implementation patterns by Kent Beck Clean code by Robert C. Martin; again  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 The Well-Grounded Java Developer, by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg Refactoring, by Martin Fowler, (with Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, and Don Roberts) Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests, by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce Flow, by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi  (Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve written this list a posteriori, in May 2015)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2014Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/31/books-read-in-2014q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/31/books-read-in-2014q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q4 on 2014, as inspired by Manuel, on this post:
 ATDD by Example: A Practical Guide to Acceptance Test-Driven Development by Markus Gärtner Head First Design Patterns by Eric Freeman, Elisabeth Robson, Bert Bates, Kathy Sierra Apprenticeship Patterns, Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman by Dave Hoover, Adewale Oshineye Diseño ágil con TDD, by Carlos Blé Jurado; again The Mythical Man-Month, Anniversary Edition: Essays On Software Engineering by Frederick P.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
