<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/creativity/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-create-reality-https-www-mrmoneymustache-com-2019-02-27-how-to-create-reality&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2019/02/27/how-to-create-reality/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Create Reality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, it is explained how to create a (different) reality in the mind of your target (users).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin with the End in Mind – and Start by Painting a Beautiful Picture of that end  destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the technique at the core of the world’s best marketing and negotiation strategies, and it works so well because it short circuits the human brain into making everyone – including you – see things in the desired way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a simple picture of a very clear end destination that automatically got people’s imagination running and filling in their own details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some examples as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: communication, people-management, leadership, marketing, pete-adeney, mr-money-mustache, paint-the-picture, technique&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: add12910-3b3f-11e9-8a1b-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:00:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;red-flags-in-software-developer-job-descriptions-https-joecmarshall-com-posts-job-description-red-flags&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joecmarshall.com/posts/job-description-red-flags/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Red Flags in Software Developer Job Descriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that explains some red flags the author has detected while reading job offers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress Developer - Degree + 10 years experience required: refers to the exageration of needed qualifications for jobs that do not require it, apparently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP Contractor - 2 Months: refers to the short-term mentality of jobs, and the environment that it creates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early Stage Emmployee / Technical Co-founder / Person to Make My Thing: refers to how cheap ideas are and how important (to developers) execution is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technologies: Coldfusion + jQuery: refers to old/out of fashion technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: job-offer, pattern, joe-marshall, old-technology, fashionable, short-term, long-term, mentality, hiring, recruiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 3841f764-3b40-11e9-9d75-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:04:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-be-productive-with-big-existing-code-base-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19254008&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19254008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to be productive with big existing code base&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this HN discussion, there are some pearls regarding working with big, legacy codebases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done it the way they did doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they did it wrong. A reference to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Chesterton%27s_fence&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reference to Working Effectively With Legacy Code, by Feathers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 1. Assess how much of the code is actually understood. Is there any record of the &amp;gt; design decisions, the edge cases, the debugging process, the paths that weren&amp;rsquo;t taken? Who knows the most about the codebase and how it got to be how it is?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 2. What&amp;rsquo;s the current specification? Don&amp;rsquo;t look at the stack, look at input and output cases. How well does the code meet the spec? Where is it failing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 3. Before you change anything you need to know what the change process is. You &amp;gt; probably do already know this, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t need to find out whether there are &amp;gt; any demarcations of responsibility, even if they&amp;rsquo;re only informal and unstated areas of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 4. When you have all that, you can start working on the code with some knowledge of the context you - and the code - are operating in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 5. If code works, don&amp;rsquo;t rewrite or refactor for style without a very very good &amp;gt; reason. And don&amp;rsquo;t do it unless you can change all the &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; code at once. Otherwise &amp;gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a mess of incompatible idioms that make future changes hard to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; 6. Write your own docs as you go. Best case is other people will benefit from reading them, worst case is you&amp;rsquo;ll remind yourself what you were doing six months from now - because you&amp;rsquo;ll have forgotten by then.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reference to flamegraphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; The problem with the after-the-fact abstraction layer is that if the original team members are not available, you are likely not in possession of the whole theory of the software. Hence it is not likely you can in the beginning choose the right abstractions. Endquote. This is a reference to &amp;ldquo;Programming as theory building&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;gt; Get it into a state that will support current business goals and roadmap while protecting current business value and users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: the quotes are copied directly from the discussion page and are property of the original commentators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: wewlc, michael-feathers, hackernews, yc, legacy-code, theory-building, quote, chesterton-fence, working-effectively-with-legacy-code, programming-as-theory-building&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 0eb0ef62-3b41-11e9-863a-0242ac110003
Read: Thu, 28 Feb 2019 8:10:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nodejs-logging-made-right-https-itnext-io-nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itnext.io/nodejs-logging-made-right-117a19e8b4ce&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NodeJS logging made right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters-https-nicepage-com-doc-article-20348-web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nicepage.com/doc/article/20348/web-design-3-0-when-your-web-design-really-matters&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 2, we will talk about website builders that are lagging behind the trends and slowing down the Web Design evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 3, you will learn how to create modern web designs quickly and easily in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has walk through the different design phases, techniques; both in press (printed) design as in web design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains some web builders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the concept of the web 3.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Element overlapping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking the limitations of Bootstrap-like Grids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;States the different needs for webmasters and designers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Designers need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free positioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removing table constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Property Panel for elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Windows and Mac OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Webmasters need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean HTML and CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile device support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WordPress and Joomla support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building websites online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website builders are lagging behind the rapidly changing Web Design world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of web design tools has involved several transitions. However, progress has stopped. There are numerous signs that the new transition must happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are separate markets for web designers and webmasters. Popular website builders do not support the main features of Web Design 3.0: free positioning, modern grids, and layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: comparison, web-design, print-design, web-builder, creativity, metaphor, grid-layout, bootstrap, flexibility, design, web-3.0, web-design-3.0, web-2.0, progression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 5101ce2e-3f5e-11e9-83d9-0242ac110005
Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:49:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gotify-a-self-hosted-push-notifications-service-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19347848&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19347848&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gotify – a self-hosted push-notifications service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gotify, self-hosted, notification, notification-service, android, open-source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: e839c82a-4367-11e9-b34d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:08:36 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-how-to-speak-like-a-leader-not-like-an-engineer-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19349676&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19349676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: How to speak like a leader, not like an engineer?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links and resources for speaking like a leader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leader, engineer, comparison, change, public-speaking, speak, speaking, career-management, career-change, professional-growth, resource:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 1a478fc8-4368-11e9-b657-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:10:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;archivebox-open-source-self-hosted-web-archive-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19346985&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19346985&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ArchiveBox: Open-source self-hosted web archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools for archiving purposes. Has links to other sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/machawk1/warcreate&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://getpolarized.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://getpolarized.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: burtonator, web-archive, polarized, warch, warc, personal-knowledge-base&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4168161c-436e-11e9-aa0d-0242ac110007
Read: Sun, 10 Mar 2019 19:54:03 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-as-a-freelancer-what-s-the-best-app-to-track-finances-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-19450331&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19450331&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: As a freelancer, what&amp;rsquo;s the best app to track finances?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes tools for finance for freelancers. Stresses the importance of time wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: time-management, money-management, freelance, tool, ask-hn, hackernews, finance, time-wealth, money-wealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: b74a6696-4c83-11e9-99bd-0242ac110005
Read: Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:20:21 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-learned-in-my-first-year-as-a-solo-founder-https-tik-dev-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tik.dev/lessons-learned&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What I Learned in My First Year as a Solo Founder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learnings by a solo founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benefits of having a side project or side hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: side-hustle, side-business, learning, reflection, solo-founder, founder, revenue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f0dee42c-5142-11e9-9444-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:19:16 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-tests-not-too-many-mostly-integration-https-kentcdodds-com-blog-write-tests&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kentcdodds.com/blog/write-tests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Write tests. Not too many. Mostly integration.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paraphrasing of some advice for healthy eating: &amp;lsquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rsquo; (Pollan)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I find myself saving time when I put time in to write tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too many: you get diminishing returns on your tests as the coverage increases [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly integration: as you move up the pyramid, the confidence quotient of each form of testing increases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests strike a great balance on the trade-offs between confidence and speed/expense&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: unit-test, testing, test-pyramid, healthy-testing, advice, integration-test, quote, kent-c-dodds, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: d148d774-5144-11e9-94d8-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:32:42 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-rules-for-eating-https-www-webmd-com-food-recipes-news-20090323-7-rules-for-eating&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/food-recipes/news/20090323/7-rules-for-eating&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;7 Rules for Eating&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this reference article, Michael Pollan explains his seven rules for eating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything your great grandmother wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recognize as food. &amp;ldquo;When you pick up that box of portable yogurt tubes, or eat something with 15 ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce, ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;What are those things doing there?&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t eat anything with more than five ingredients, or ingredients you can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay out of the middle of the supermarket; shop on the perimeter of the store. Real food tends to be on the outer edge of the store near the loading docks, where it can be replaced with fresh foods when it goes bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that won&amp;rsquo;t eventually rot. &amp;ldquo;There are exceptions &amp;ndash; honey &amp;ndash; but as a rule, things like Twinkies that never go bad aren&amp;rsquo;t food,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not just what you eat but how you eat. &amp;ldquo;Always leave the table a little hungry,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Many cultures have rules that you stop eating before you are full. In Japan, they say eat until you are four-fifths full. Islamic culture has a similar rule, and in German culture they say, &amp;lsquo;Tie off the sack before it&amp;rsquo;s full.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Families traditionally ate together, around a table and not a TV, at regular meal times. It&amp;rsquo;s a good tradition. Enjoy meals with the people you love. &amp;ldquo;Remember when eating between meals felt wrong?&amp;rdquo; Pollan asks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t buy food where you buy your gasoline. In the U.S., 20% of food is eaten in the car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, four myths:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food is a delivery vehicle for nutrients. What really matters isn&amp;rsquo;t broccoli but its fiber and antioxidants. If we get that right, we get our diet right. Foods kind of get in the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need experts to tell us how to eat. Nutrients are invisible and mysterious. &amp;ldquo;It is a little like religion,&amp;rdquo; Pollan said. &amp;ldquo;If a powerful entity is invisible, you need a priesthood to mediate your relation with food.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole point of eating is to maintain and promote bodily health. &amp;ldquo;You are either improving or ruining your health when you eat &amp;ndash; that is a very American idea,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;But there are many other reasons to eat food: pleasure, social community, identity, and ritual. Health is not the only thing going on on our plates.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are evil foods and good foods. &amp;ldquo;At any given time there is an evil nutrient we try to drive like Satan from the food supply &amp;ndash; first it was saturated fats, then it was trans fat,&amp;rdquo; Pollan says. &amp;ldquo;Then there is the evil nutrient&amp;rsquo;s doppelganger, the blessed nutrient. If we get enough of that we, will be healthy and maybe live forever. It&amp;rsquo;s funny through history how the good and bad guys keep changing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can all be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: healthy-eating, michael-pollan, rule, advice, myth, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 30ece1fc-5145-11e9-87de-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:35:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-https-blog-usejournal-com-lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.usejournal.com/lean-testing-or-why-unit-tests-are-worse-than-you-think-b6500139a009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lean Testing or Why Unit Tests are Worse than You Think&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article puts testing in an economic perspective. Calls it lean testing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also references/paraphrases Michael Pollan&amp;rsquo;s Rules for eating ().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creates a testing trophy, a figure to explain the best testing pattern, replacing the testing pyramid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains return on investment (ROI) on tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;integration tests provide the best balance of cost, speed and confidence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integration tests lie somewhere between unit tests and end-to-end tests so they provide the best balance. Therefore, they have the highest ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea is to just not mock so much&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: economic-perspective, lean-testing, testing-trophy, testing-pyramid, return-on-investment, roi, critical-path, testing, unit-test, anti-architecture, architecture, maintenance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: efe85d00-5147-11e9-87ce-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 10:55:02 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-user-programming-https-www-inkandswitch-com-end-user-programming-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inkandswitch.com/end-user-programming.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;End-user programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the writer explains some of the end-user modifications to programs. Examples include: adding download capabilities to instagram, generating backups for files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, applications (especially mobile) are tightly sealed, not allowing modification or extension. Even FOSS (free, open source software), modification implies the learning curve / entry barrier of having to setup, compile, debug the original program and modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives the example of the UNIX command line, as a programming environment. One that provides (one of) the best REPL examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Characterizes spreadsheets as ad-hoc databases, programs; mostly created by domain experts (aka subject matter experts), than professional software engineers. Take into account that these hats are non-exclusive: a domain expert can also be a professional software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author tries to coin the term &amp;ldquo;end-user programming&amp;rdquo; to differentiate it from programming by professional software developers, who try to build general-purpose apps, to be used by thousands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means, that a professional software developer can be an &amp;ldquo;end-user programmer&amp;rdquo;, when creating solutions for themselves (limited user group), rather than for the general public. Maybe those one-off scripts that we create, are some kind of end-user programs. This is described in the article as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks of the chasm the user has to cross in order to customize the behaviour of their software. This is related to working in a framework or a library, in the sense of &amp;lsquo;who keeps the control&amp;rsquo;. In an UNIX, filesystem environment, you keep the control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References &amp;ldquo;citizen developers&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.gartner.com/it-glossary/citizen-developer/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three qualities for end-user programming: embodiment, living systems, and in-place toolchains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment: it requires the programmer hold many abstractions in their mind. Related to abstract reasoning. Mentions that many end-users don&amp;rsquo;t have these abstractions in their mind, but are capable of abstract reasoning in their own domains of expertise. Mentions that via visual representations onscreen, we can help the end-user. An example: preview formula results in a spreadsheet; highlight the cells in a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embodiment means, broadly, making elements of the programming experience more concrete and visual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living systems: interaction with them. Refers to shortening the feedback cycle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Live programming gives the programmer immediate feedback on the behavior of a program as it is edited, replacing the edit compile-debug cycle with a fluid programming experience.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But only short feedback loops, but also to change the system behaviour from within, such as the LISP compiler reading and compiling the source code from inside a program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-place tool chains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user should be able to edit their programs without installing additional tools or programs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a Unix shell script is just a series of commands saved into a text file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning that the user is already accustomed to issuing those commands. A script is just grouping those commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gives examples of end-user programming success stories: spreadsheets, SQL, browser dev tools,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: end-user-programming, programming, extensibility, open-closed-principle, ocp, mofication, user, extension, unix, repl, spreadsheet, reflection, theory, history, review, sql, dev-tools, chasm, abstraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 4490792a-514b-11e9-9861-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:18:52 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-https-medium-com-web-development-why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@web.development/why-developers-consider-agile-development-to-be-nonsense-1eaf28715e66&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why developers consider Agile development to be nonsense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article explains how Agile development is apt and indicated for short-term software development, especially for contracting or consulting companies, where the client is external to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why it does not make as much sense in products/services where there is a leapfrog solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t give the customer what they ask for; understand them, and revolutionize their world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: leapfrog-solution, google, agile, agile-development, comparison, project-management, client, consulting, management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9035ea3c-514f-11e9-9676-0242ac110006
Read: Thu, 28 Mar 2019 11:49:37 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-bother-with-what-three-words-https-shkspr-mobi-blog-2019-03-why-bother-with-what-three-words&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2019/03/why-bother-with-what-three-words/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why bother with What Three Words?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, the author questions why using a closed protocol for translating geo-coordinates to words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author complains that it is masquerading a for-profit, closed algorithm as an open standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, that the GPS locations are drifting very quickly in some places, therefore the translated address changes, but the local address (e.g., 1 Wall Street), does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gps-drift, australia, open-standard, closed-standard, for-profit, protocol, open, closed, what-three-words, w3w, i18n, startup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 960e6750-5202-11e9-bb40-0242ac110008
Read: Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:11:07 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-and-all-that-comes-with-it&#34;&gt;Software and all that comes with it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyrd.com/2011/fromthefront/sgfgw/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;driving-your-dba-crazy-in-3-easy-steps&#34;&gt;Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyrd.com/2011/ddd-day-it/shzym&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ddd, model, entity, aggregate, team-management, dba, agile, ubiquitous-language, alberto-brandolini, bus-factor, slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shorter-feedback-is-not-always-bett&#34;&gt;Shorter Feedback is not Always Bett&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.com/notes/kent-beck/shorter-feedback-is-not-always-bett/1097086386990891&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this note&lt;/a&gt; from Kent Beck on why shorter feedback loops might not always be better. I.e., why some processes take time to set in and results are not observable until that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  kent-beck, feedback-loops, open-question, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;la-regla-del-triple-check-para-ir-a-eventos&#34;&gt;La Regla del Triple Check para ir a eventos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bonillaware.com/regla-triple-check-para-ir-a-eventos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by David Bonilla about a rule to help you decide attendance to events, in Spanish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rule, time-management, david-bonilla, event, spanish, triple-check&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-interview-with-charles-wetherell&#34;&gt;An interview with Charles Wetherell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://demin.ws/blog/english/2012/08/25/interview-with-charles-wetherell/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; by Alexander Demin about the interviewee&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;Etudes for Programmers&amp;rdquo;. In it, they talk about the origin of the études, the author&amp;rsquo;s research interests and activities. Also about the book (written in 1978) and how computer science has changed since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about three things a programmer should know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ability to do formal mathematics. The level necessary to understand Hopcroft and Ullman combined with a little graph theory is enough. Discrete mathematics is essential; calculus is only necessary for folks working in special application areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ability to write clearly in their native language. Dijkstra said that if a person couldn’t write their own language, they couldn’t write a correct program. (Well, that’s what I hope Dijkstra said!). Writing programs is essentially the same as writing a non-fiction essay. If you can’t make the step-by-step connections clearly in your own language, why would we think you could in C, for example?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that a program is primarily for communication with humans, not computers. When you write a program, the computer will do whatever you say. You must convince the humans who read the program that what you have asked the computer to do is the correct thing to do. Remember, the computer doesn’t care about correctness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to the last question means that programs should always have the form of paragraphs of comments that describe the intention of the program followed by paragraphs of code that implement that intention. All of the formatting should be designed to make readers as able as possible to read the code easily; the compiler doesn’t care. In particular, follow conventions of mathematics and your native language, not those you found in some random language manual. Write the comments first and then write the code, not the other way around. If you don’t know what you want to achieve and why, any code you write is, by definition, incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: charles-wetherell, alexander-demin, interview, book, etude, etudes-for-programmers, practice, ability, skill, list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-javascript-maybe&#34;&gt;How to fix Javascript… maybe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@wob/how-to-fix-javascript-maybe-8857819bfa16&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Drew Hamlett about the lack of style guide for javascript and how this affects the adoption of the language and the sprout of similar libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggests the creation of a standard style guide for javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: drew-hamlett, javascript, style-guide, analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;isomorphic-javascript-devbeat-master-class&#34;&gt;Isomorphic JavaScript: #DevBeat Master Class&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/spikebrehm/a-28174727&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; by Spike Brehm on Isomorphic JavaScript and why it&amp;rsquo;s important: initial pageload and speed, reducing effort and duplication, SEO (crawlability).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: isomorphic-javascript, isomorphism, javascript, seo, crawler, frontend, app, application, fat-client, fat-server, thin-client, thin-server, ria-spike-brehm, slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-sourcing-our-docker-images&#34;&gt;Open-sourcing our docker images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.modulus.io/open-sourcing-our-docker-images&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Brandon Cannaday about the Docker images that they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: docker, brandon-annaday, open-ource, image, container, modulus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growing-up-in-an-open-source-world&#34;&gt;growing up in an open source world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://fiveisprime.me/2015/02/18/growing-up-in-open-source/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Hernandez where he explains that fixing the style guide can limit your creativity and how the software is written in enterprise and open-source environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also about how developers grow when exposed to different style guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: style-guide, matt-hernandez, creativity, dreyfus-model, enterprise, open-source, programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanlon-s-razor-and-working-with-young-engineers&#34;&gt;Hanlon&amp;rsquo;s Razor and working with young engineers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://fiveisprime.me/2013/07/27/young-engineers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Hernandez on the importance of understanding (and empathising) towards others&amp;rsquo; positions and worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the Hanlon Razor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never attribute to malice that which is adequately explained by ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags:  hanlon-razor, empathy, team-management, ignorance, malice, matt-hernandez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro-to-sails-js&#34;&gt;Intro to sails.js&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GK-tFvpIR7c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;, an introduction to the sails.js framework: a realtime nodejs server for creating REST APIs, inspired by Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: sailsjs, ruby-on-rails, ror, framework, video, introduction, mvc, rest-api, realtime, nodejs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;node-js-and-hapi-creating-a-rest-api&#34;&gt;Node.js and hapi - creating a rest api&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.modulus.io/nodejs-and-hapi-create-rest-api&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about creating a REST API using &lt;a href=&#34;http://hapijs.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hapi&lt;/a&gt;, a nodejs framework. Written by Matt Hernandez&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matt-hernandez, rest-api, nodejs, hapi, framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-pokedex-org-a-progressive-webapp-for-pokémon-fans&#34;&gt;Introducing Pokedex.org: a progressive webapp for Pokémon fans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pocketjavascript.com/blog/2015/11/23/introducing-pokedex-org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nolan Lawson about the challenge of having a 60 fps application on a mobile device, making it offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uses Angular 2, javascript 7, PouchDB as well as LocalForage for storage. All processing on WebWorkers, except for DOM manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: angular-2, javascript-7, angular, javascript, pouchdb, localforage, cloudant, 60fps, mobile, app, offline-first, offline, pokemon, api, nolan-lawson, web-worker, flip-technique, css, progressive, pokedex, svgomg, frontend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lambdaconf-2015-how-to-learn-haskell-in-less-than-5-years-chris-allen&#34;&gt;LambdaConf 2015 - How to Learn Haskell in Less Than 5 Years Chris Allen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bg9ccYzMbxc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Allen on how to learn haskell, what are some common pitfalls while learning it and how learning and teaching (it) are different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talks about his (with a coauthor) book, focused on not reducing the readers that make it to the end and, finally, increasing the amount of haskell users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References &lt;a href=&#34;https://yow.eventer.com/yow-2014-1222/stop-treading-water-learning-to-learn-by-edward-kmett-1750&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; by Kmett.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chris-allen, haskell, learning-to-learn, meta-learning, lambda-conf, talk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extreme-continuous-delivery-at-unruly&#34;&gt;Extreme Continuous Delivery - at Unruly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xpdays.de/2014/downloads/002-extreme-continuous-delivery-at-unruly/cd_javaone.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt; about how the company Unruly does continuous delivery (CD), maximizing business value, minimizing time to market (TTM). Also describes how they do deployments and how to organize teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References: Extreme Programming Explained (Beck), Continuous Delivery (Humble &amp;amp; Farley)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: silo, team-management, culture, continuous-delivery, tdd, nagdd, shared-infrastructure, acceptance-testing, module-testing, conway-law, cross-pollination, continuous-investment, slide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-chat-applications-and-robots-for-skype&#34;&gt;Building chat applications and robots for Skype&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensourcehacker.com/2013/03/28/building-chat-applications-and-robots-for-skype/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on building robots for skype. By Mikko Ohtamaa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: skype, robot, bot, mikko-ohtamaa, slack, integration, api&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-never-wrote-down-our-company-values&#34;&gt;Why I never wrote down our company values&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/why-i-never-wrote-down-our-company-values-8143520497e8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Mikael Cho on the subject of having company values, preaching or writing them down. Also, what happens when hard times come, regarding your values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mikael-cho, value, company-value, analogy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-protocol-design&#34;&gt;Interview with Jesper Louis Andersen about Erlang, Haskell, OCaml, Go, Idris, the JVM, software and protocol design &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this interview (&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial/interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-b0de06440fbd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/this-is-not-a-monad-tutorial/interview-with-jesper-louis-andersen-about-erlang-haskell-ocaml-go-idris-the-jvm-software-and-5628fe591295&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;) to Jesper Louis Andersen, interviewed by Federico Carrone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part is about a comparison of languages, what/why he uses them, and protocol design. The second is more about the Erlang language, the BEAM VM, and some experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: federico-carrone, erlang, interview, jesper-andersen, jesper-louis-andersen, haskell, ocaml, go, idris, the-jvm, protocol-design, software-design, language, functional-programming, protocol, land-of-lisp, northern-war&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress&#34;&gt;Migrating to Hugo From Octopress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://nathanleclaire.com/blog/2014/12/22/migrating-to-hugo-from-octopress/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; by Nathan LeClaire on migrating the blog from Octopress to Hugo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: static-site-generator, hugo, go, octopress, ruby, jekyll, nathan-leclaire, migration, blog, meta&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dynamic-static-site-generators-strategies&#34;&gt;Dynamic Static Site Generators strategies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://timnash.co.uk/dynamic-static-site-generators-strategies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining what are static site generators, and an example with Jekyll. By Tim Nash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tim-nash, static-site-generator, jekyll, strategy, explanation, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog-like-a-confused-hacker&#34;&gt;Blog like a confused hacker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://timnash.co.uk/using-wordpress-static-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Nash on what tools he recomends for static site generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: tim-nash, static-site-generator, jekyll, hide, strategy, explanation, comparison, sublime, wordpress, amazon-s3, cdn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resolving-the-frontend-backend-api-design-conflict&#34;&gt;Resolving the Frontend/Backend API Design Conflict&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://launchany.com/resolving-the-frontendbackend-api-design-conflict/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that explains the &amp;ldquo;Backend for Frontend&amp;rdquo; (BFF) pattern, for solving the different needs of data depending on each device / client. By James Higginbotham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: james-higginbotham, bff, pattern, backend-for-frontend, api, soa, microservice, frontend, backend, architecture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-if-we-forget-to-write-the-tests&#34;&gt;What If We Forget To Write The Tests?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;amp;id=f70f14b644&amp;amp;e=4a925444f9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by J. B. Rainsberger on the trust issues related to starting to use a new methodology (TDD in this case) and how to see what impacts it might have in your day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, tdd, motivation, team-management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-microservices-the-unix-philosophy-and-the-richardson-maturity-model-a-practical-perspective&#34;&gt;API microservices, the Unix philosophy, and the Richardson Maturity Model - a practical perspective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@chrstphrhrt/microservices-the-unix-philosophy-and-the-richardson-maturity-model-425abed44826&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Hart on why startups and companies alike should be careful when choosing th latest technology and how this applies to microservices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: microservice, chris-hart, startup, analysis, company, technical-debt, bounded-context, ddd, rest-api&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;effective-programming&#34;&gt;Effective programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sebas5384/effective-programming-d7e5bb2f3b80&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Sebastian Ferrari on the importance of clean code, systems thinking and functional programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifies the important difference between effectiveness and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links to this talk by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/OqEeIG8aPPk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Russ Ackoff&lt;/a&gt;. States the difference between &amp;ldquo;the right thing&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the thing right&amp;rdquo;, by Drucker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: drucker, thing-right, right-thing, sebastian-ferrari, system-thinking, russ-ackoff, video, ted, difference, clean-code, functional-programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-how-to-learn&#34;&gt;Learning how to learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@thejameskyle/learning-how-to-learn-7f04d6f42c1e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Kyle about the &amp;ldquo;how to learn&amp;rdquo; as one important skill for programmers and how having the solution at a few keystrokes limits / handicaps this ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: programmer, learn-to-learn, james-kyle, stack-overflow, skill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-some-functional-programmers-criticize-design-patterns-in-oop-languages-as-a-sign-of-language-deficiency-while-monad-is-also-a-design-pattern&#34;&gt;Why do some functional programmers criticize design patterns in OOP languages as a sign of language deficiency, while Monad is also a design pattern?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Why-do-some-functional-programmers-criticize-design-patterns-in-OOP-languages-as-a-sign-of-language-deficiency-while-Monad-is-also-a-design-pattern/answer/Edward-Kmett?srid=hVnO&amp;amp;share=12410d1e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this answer&lt;/a&gt; by Edward Kmett comparing the design patterns in OOP to the design patterns in functional languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: functional-language, object-oriented-language, edward-kmett, oop, pattern, monad, interface, quora, answer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;should-we-even-debate-refactoring-with-stakeholders&#34;&gt;Should We Even Debate Refactoring With Stakeholders?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://us2.campaign-archive2.com/?u=80ca60ec48ef77dfaa1f38943&amp;amp;id=215f7f649b&amp;amp;e=4a925444f9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by J. B. Rainsberger on the power balance between stakeholders and programmers and how it can be inclined to a &amp;lsquo;more trust&amp;rsquo; / &amp;lsquo;less trust&amp;rsquo; by following some actions. The analogy is to a trade you cannot understand, therefore you have to hope that the taken decisions are in your best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, refactor, business-need, communication, stakeholder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-eternal-struggle-between-business-and-programmers&#34;&gt;The Eternal Struggle Between Business and Programmers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.thecodewhisperer.com/permalink/the-eternal-struggle-between-business-and-programmers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by J. B. Rainsberger on the discussion between business (&amp;lsquo;we want more features, now&amp;rsquo;) and the programmers (&amp;lsquo;we want more refactoring, now&amp;rsquo;). Concludes that both players need each other, in a symbiotic fashion, to keep their jobs at the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He suggests that Scrum cannot work without the XP practices and that we need to refactor aggressively after having finished our initial design, to keep the costs down. In fact, agreeing with both parts in this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References one of his own videos, at Oredev&amp;rsquo;13, &amp;ldquo;Fundamental Theorem of Agile Software Development&amp;rdquo;, where he describes the relationship between accidental / essential complexity in the cost of a feature, attributing most of it to accidental (&amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;re not good at our jobs&amp;rsquo;) and describing the need for more design / refactor after the initial design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: j-b-rainsberger, j-brains, rainsberger, refactor, business-need, design, oredev, talk, agile, xp, scrum, software-development, accidental-complexity, essential-complexity, mythical-man-month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turning-code-to-cash-how-to-make-money-as-a-web-developer-and-live-to-tell-the-tale&#34;&gt;Turning code to cash — How to make money as a Web Developer and live to tell the tale.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kurtrohlandt/turning-code-to-cash-how-to-make-money-as-a-web-developer-and-live-to-tell-the-tale-f5eedc557b3e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Kurt Rohlandt with a list of items to check while dealing with clients as a freelancer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing is simple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your skill set — and let your client know it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be clear about what they are buying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to use the best tool for the job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To your client you’re more than just a developer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign off your jobs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: freelancer, kurt-rohlandt, list, tip, client&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>