<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Talk | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/talk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-07T10:36:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in August 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-02T19:45:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Humble Object</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the <a href="http://xunitpatterns.com/Humble%20Object.html">Humble Object</a> list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>humble dialog</li>
<li>humble executable</li>
<li>humble transaction controller</li>
<li>humble container adapter</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros</p>

<h2>How you know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve reread <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/know.html">this small essay</a> by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.</p>

<p>Tags: paul-graham, reread, read</p>

<h2>Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.martinfowler.com/ieeeSoftware/protectedVariation.pdf">this article</a> by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software > Design.</p>

<p>Discusses Information Hiding, Protected Variation and the Open-Closed Principle.</p>

<p>Tags: craig-larman, ocp, open-closed principle, design, information-hiding, ih, protected-variation, pv,</p>

<h2>Lambda, Javascript Micro-Services on AWS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.jayway.com/2014/12/18/lambda-javascript-micro-services-aws/">this post</a> explaining how to deploy a microservice on AWS on top of Lambda. Written by Anders Janmyr</p>

<p>The cool thing is that you get billed by milliseconds!</p>

<p>Tags: anders-janmyr, devops, microservice, lambda, aws</p>

<h2>Migrating To Clojure. So Much Fn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hv4slaRydRM">this talk</a> by Jan Stępień where he talks about his experience on migrating part of an application to clojure from ruby on rails</p>

<p>Tags: jan-stepien, clojure, migration, ruby-on-rails, talk, wrocloverb</p>

<h2>Te recomiendo escribir en un blog</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/07/te-recomiendo-escribir-en-un-blog/">this article</a> from Carlos Blé in which he recommends writing a blog, on things we discover along the way. (Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, meta, blog, long-way</p>

<h2>We need enough technical debt</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.svpino.com/2015/08/05/we-need-enough-technical-debt">this article</a> on why we need to accumulate a bit of technical debt, as a way of being less perfectionist and deliver more features / value to our stakeholders. Written by Santiago L. Valdarrama.</p>

<p>Tags: santiago-valdarrama, technical-debt, perfectionism</p>

<h2>Escribe mejores tests en Javascript</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://carlosvillu.com/escribe-mejores-tests-en-javascript/">this list</a> of tips to write better javascript tests (Spanish). By Carlos Villuendas</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-villuendas, javascript, test</p>

<h2>Down the Rabbit Hole</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/brettwooldridge/HikariCP/wiki/Down-the-Rabbit-Hole">this wiki</a> page on how to tune some aspects of the server hotspot JVM, by Brett Wooldridge</p>

<p>Tags: performance, jvm, hotspot, inline, bytecode, brett-wooldridge</p>

<h2>XP Manchester Lightning Talks 2015 Live broadcast</h2>

<p>I have watched the first two <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VD4UEW2i7hU">lightning talks</a> from XP Manchester, edition number 61.</p>

<p>Tags: lightning-talk, broadcast, simplicity, manchester, 2015</p>

<h2>Counting hash collisions with the birthday paradox</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/counting-hash-collisions/">this article</a> on the birthday paradox, or the percentage of chance of people sharing the same birthday. This could be applied to hash function, as the title says, but is not included in the article. Written by Matt Might</p>

<h2>Why I&rsquo;m The Best Programmer In The World*</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/why-im-the-best-programmer-in-the-world/">this ironically-titled article</a> by Jeff Atwood on humility and how to improve as a programmer.</p>

<p>Tags: jeff-atwood</p>

<h2>The Key to Giving and Receiving Negative Feedback</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hbr.org/2015/08/the-key-to-giving-and-receiving-negative-feedback?">this article</a> by Joseph Grenny about how to give and receive negative feedback. It is exemplified by the plant manager who was expecting another kind of feedback from his subordinates and was surprised by their negative feedback.</p>

<p>Tags: joseph-grenny, negative-feedback, feedback, by-example</p>

<h2>Testing Clojure web applications with Kerodon</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://semaphoreci.com/community/tutorials/testing-clojure-web-applications-with-kerodon">this guide</a> on how to test compojure-based applications with kerodon. Written by Nebojša Stričević</p>

<p>Tags: nebojsa-stricevic, compojure, kerodon, clojure, testing, guide</p>

<h2>Using The Option Type Effectively</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uku-taht/2015/04/29/using-the-option-type-effectively.html">this article</a> on how to use the <code>Option</code> type (in rust), similar to <code>Optional</code> in java or <code>Maybe</code> in haskell. Written by Uku Taht.</p>

<p>Tags: uku-taht, option, maybe, optional, rust</p>

<h2>When Should You Think?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/03/11/when-to-think.html">this post</a> by Robert C Martin on when to think and the hypothesis that TDD does not allow you to think before coding.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, robert-c-martin, design, hypothesis</p>

<h2>Orthogonal latin squares: an application of experiment design to compiler testing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://barbie.uta.edu/~mehra/20_an%20application%20of%20experiment%20design%20to%20compiler%20testing.pdf">this paper</a> by Robert Mandl on techniques that can be applied to reduce the burden of exhaustive testing to compilers. Preferring &ldquo;surely all relevant distinct combinations&rdquo; we can reduce the amount of testing. This paper tries to formalize the concept of &ldquo;near-exhaustive testing&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: latin-square, robert-mandl, compiler, testing, near-exhaustive-testing, optimization, exhaustive-testing</p>

<h2>  Practical Type System Benefits</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://themonadreader.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/nccb.pdf">this article</a> by Neil Brown on benefits of the type system, with examples in haskell. He goes on to explore the benefits of involving the type-checker at compile time to remove type errors and ease the programming effort:</p>

<blockquote><p>I find that several problems in Haskell can be solved by involving the type system
further: The trick is to involve the type system in ways that provide a big benefit
for the cost, but not going so far that the type system gets in the way of code
that you know &ndash;but can’t easily prove to the compiler&ndash; is safe</p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also learned the concept of the quasi-quoter: similar to a preprocessor, executed at compile time and type-checked</p>

<p>Tags: neil-brown, quote, quasi-quoter, preprocessor, haskell, monad-reader</p>

<h2>ClojureScript and the Blub Paradox</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read this article comparing javascript and clojurescript using the fizzbuzz kata. There is a nice example of the pattern matching for the cases (i.e. &ldquo;switch&rdquo;) of the fizz, buzz. Written by Nate Wildermuth</p>

<p>Tags: clojurescript, javascript, fizzbuzz, kata, nate-wildermuth</p>

<h2>No malinterpretes tu carrera</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2011/02/no-malinterpretes-tu-carrera/">this article</a> on (not) changing careers from programmer to designer, analyst, team manager. About the programmer&rsquo;s passion and why not to misinterpret your career. Written by Carlos Blé. In Spanish.</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, career, programming, management, career-change</p>

<h2>Just Haskell or Nothing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://cheecheeo.github.io/just_haskell_or_nothing.html">these slides</a> on packaging values in (Just a) or Nothing for possibly failed computations in haskell. Written by John Chee</p>

<p>Tags: john-chee, haskell, just, nothing, maybe, functor</p>

<h2>Tracking Joy at Work</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://begriffs.com/posts/2015-03-15-tracking-joy-at-work.html">this article</a> about quantifying happiness at the office (or at work). Joe Nelson, the author of the article, uses the quantifying method described int the book <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Experience-Sampling-Method-Measuring-Everyday/dp/1412925576/">Experience Sampling Method</a> (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experience_sampling_method">wikipedia page</a>) by Hektner, Schmidt, Csikszentmihalyi.</p>

<p>The last one, not coincidentally is the author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Flow-The-Psychology-Optimal-Experience/dp/0061339202">Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience</a>.</p>

<p>Tags: mihaly-csikszentmihalyi, flow, quantification, data, experience-sampling, article, joe-nelson</p>

<h2>Going &ldquo;Write-Only&rdquo;</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://begriffs.com/posts/2015-04-20-going-write-only.html">this article</a> by Joe Nelson on going &ldquo;write-only&rdquo; on social media, blogs, news, etc, as opposed to read-only (only consuming media) or read-write (consuming and producing). He cites another programmer, <a href="http://joey.hess.usesthis.com/">Joey Hess</a> and about the quality and durability of your work.</p>

<p>Tags: article, joe-nelson, write-only, social-media, reading, philosophy, thoreau, nietzsche, joey-hess</p>

<h2>Create a static site with Hakyll, Github and Travis CI</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://begriffs.com/posts/2014-08-12-create-static-site-with-hakyll-github.html">this article</a> on how to create your blog with hakyll and travis ci. Written by Joe Nelson</p>

<p>Travis ci is used to do continuous integration and automatically deploy each commit to production (github pages).</p>

<p>Tags: hakyll, haskell, joe-nelson, meta, blog, continuous-deployment, github, github-pages, travis-ci</p>

<h2>Falling in Love with Computer Science</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=haxusGuUyt4">this video</a> by Kathy Pham, an American that discovered her passion, her love to computer science a few years ago. She tells the events around computer science from the beginning of college to the current moment.</p>

<p>Tags: kathy-pham, passion, love, computer-science, autobiography, time-lapse, google-developers</p>

<h2>Duck Typing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h0rTF__RNo4">this video</a> by Dan Grossman, part of the <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/proglang">&ldquo;Programming Languages&rdquo; MOOC</a>, in which he explains what is a Duck Type and how to use (and abuse) them in ruby.</p>

<p>Tags: ruby, dan-grossman, mooc, mooc-programming-languages</p>

<h2>Not-So-Private Clojure Functions</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://christophermaier.name/blog/2011/04/30/not-so-private-clojure-functions">this article</a> explaining how to bypass private functions in clojure: either create a lambda or create a different namespace. Written by Christopher Maier</p>

<p>Tags: private-variable, clojure, testing, joy-of-clojure, christopher-maier, private-function, namespace</p>

<h2>Frege (and Clojure)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://seancorfield.github.io/blog/2015/02/13/frege-and-clojure/">this article</a> that tells the Pragmatic Programmer&rsquo;s advice to learn a new language every year and the author (Sean Corfield) explains his trajectory learning them. He also cites the Lein plugin he&rsquo;s built: <code>lein-fregec</code> and how to connect clojure and frege (a.k.a JVM&rsquo;s haskell).</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, frege, jvm, clojure, ffi, pragmatic-programmer, advice, lein-fregec,  sean-corfield, comparison</p>

<h2>Two months early. 300k under budget</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://thoughtworks.github.io/p2/issue09/two-months-early/">the tale</a> of a Thoughtworks Project Manager who convinced his client to start using clojure to deliver a custom-made CMS. Written by Dave Elliman.</p>

<p>Tags: dave-elliman, thoughtworks, project-manager, clojure, cms, microservice</p>

<h2>Convince your boss to use Clojure</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.lispcast.com/convince-your-boss-to-use-clojure">this guide</a> by Eric Normand on how to convince your boss or your company to start using clojure.</p>

<p>Tags: company, clojure, eric-normand, how-to, guide</p>

<h2>A brief introduction to Prolog</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1NAUo8nWLfNvvW3Wb7HJMunljjDJbzu7mo-5twKeGDvc/edit#slide=id.g63daf4745_0_56">these slides</a> about a brief introduction to prolog and how to do web development in it. By Jaelle Scheuerman</p>

<p>Tags: jaelle-scheuerman, prolog, web-development, rest, slide</p>

<h2>Arrayzing - The JavaScript array cheatsheet</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://gist.github.com/ourmaninamsterdam/1be9a5590c9cf4a0ab42">this cheatsheet</a> for javascript arrays. Written by Justin Perry</p>

<p>Tags: cheatsheet, array, javascript, gist, justin-perry</p>

<h2>Some words on lazy evaluation and sharing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://pseudo.fixme.fi/~opqdonut/blog/Some_words_on_lazy_evaluation_and_sharing.html">this article</a> comparing the <code>fix</code> definition with a hand-made one and its &ldquo;sharing&rdquo; problems. Written by Joel E. Kaasinen</p>

<p>Tags: joel-kaasinen, haskell, fix, sharing, non-strictness, lazy-evaluation</p>

<h2>Hammock Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f84n5oFoZBc">this video</a> by Rich Hickey. A few notes:</p>

<p>A: identifying a problem that we&rsquo;re trying to solve</p>

<p>D: assessing if the proposed solution solves the problem</p>

<p>the union of the features is not the purpose of the product / is not the product</p>

<p>proramming is not completing features</p>

<p>avoiding problems /= solving problems</p>

<p>book: how to solve it - G. Polya. Practices &amp; techniques for solving mathematic problems</p>

<p>How to solve the problem</p>

<ul>
<li>state the problem</li>
<li>understand the problem:

<ul>
<li>what do you know: facts, context, constraints.</li>
<li>what do you don&rsquo;t know</li>
<li>are there related problems? solutions to related problems. find an analogy: starting from scratch vs incremental step</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>be discerning</li>
<li>more input, better output:

<ul>
<li>read about your domain problem, research papers (maybe ACM)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>tradeoffs:

<ul>
<li>find at least two options (ups and downs) to compare before taking a decision</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Focus time for programmers like alone time for kids. Hammock time is important mind&rsquo;s eye time</p>

<p>Waking mind:</p>

<ul>
<li>critical thinking</li>
<li>analysis</li>
<li>tactics</li>
<li>prone to local maxima</li>
<li>feed work to background mind</li>
<li>analyze its products</li>
</ul>


<p>Background mind:</p>

<ul>
<li>making connections</li>
<li>synthesis</li>
<li>strategy</li>
<li>abstracts, analogies</li>
<li>solves most non-trivial problems</li>
</ul>


<p>loading it: work it hard in the waking mind to be included in the background mind</p>

<p>abstraction = software strategy</p>

<p>tip: small answer is better than big answer (occam&rsquo;s razor?)​</p>

<p>Tags: rich-hickey, hammock-driven-development, background-mind, waking-mind, solve-problem, george-polya, book, analysis, design, talk</p>

<h2>Parallelism /= Concurrency</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://ghcmutterings.wordpress.com/2009/10/06/parallelism-concurrency/">this article</a> on the differences between parallelism and concurrency, with examples in the haskell compiler GHC. Written by <a href="https://ghcmutterings.wordpress.com/author/simonmar/">simonmar</a></p>

<p>Tags: haskell, concurrency, parallelism, ghc, simonmar, comparison</p>

<h2>Parallelism vs. Concurrency</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://wiki.haskell.org/Parallelism_vs._Concurrency">this page</a> from the haskell wiki.</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, concurrency, parallelism, ghc, comparison</p>

<h2>Writing code that writes code — with Hack Codegen</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://code.facebook.com/posts/1624644147776541/writing-code-that-writes-code-with-hack-codegen/">this article</a> about metaprogramming (code that generates code) in PHP. Written by Alejandro Marcu.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve arrived to this from this tweet:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-cards="hidden" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is what happens when your programming language doesn&#39;t have macros <a href="https://t.co/ZfsEe2EJIj">https://t.co/ZfsEe2EJIj</a>. Yuck.</p>&mdash; David Nolen (@swannodette) <a href="https://twitter.com/swannodette/status/634495099607613440">August 20, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Tags: alejandro-marcu, metaprogramming, php, macro, lisp, clojure</p>

<h2>How katas can help you learn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://codurance.com/2015/08/18/How-katas-can-help-you-learn/">this article</a> on learning from katas, with the example of the Roman Numerals kata in Objective-C. Written by Sandro Mancuso.</p>

<p>Tags: sandro-mancuso, kata, learning, roman-numeral, objective-c</p>

<h2>Java 8: Definitive guide to CompletableFuture</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.nurkiewicz.com/2013/05/java-8-definitive-guide-to.html">this article</a> about Java 8&rsquo;s feature, the <code>CompletableFeature</code>. Written by Tomasz Nurkiewicz</p>

<p>Tags: tomasz-nurkiewicz, java-8, completable-future, future, non-blocking, reactive-programming</p>

<h2>Are You Making These 10 DDD Mistakes?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://danielwhittaker.me/2015/07/05/are-you-making-these-10-ddd-mistakes/#">this infographic</a> on 10 DDD common mistakes, by Daniel Whittaker.</p>

<p>Tags: ddd, daniel-whittaker, bounded-context, ubiquitous-language, infographic</p>

<h2>Haste: Full-Stack Haskell for Non-PhD Candidates</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3v03NFcyvzc">this talk</a> at the Strange Loop Conference 2014 about Haste language, a haskell version that compiles to javascript, therefore letting you write haskell in the browser. By Erin Swenson-Healey and James Cooper</p>

<p>In this talk they recommend the <a href="http://www.seas.upenn.edu/~cis194/lectures.html">CIS194 course</a></p>

<p>Tags: haste, haskell, james-cooper, erin-swenson-healey, strange-loop, 2014, talk</p>

<h2>A Year of Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wZ0RQG3mFPw">this talk</a> about experiences using haskell professionally, by the American Justin Leitgeb in a Equatorian company in Quito, Stack Builders. He goes on to explain the haskell language in comparison to ruby on rails, what he mostly used with his clients.</p>

<p>Also explains what sells and doesn&rsquo;t (mostly productivity, not security) and gives pointer for applying it to a company</p>

<p>Tags: justin-leitgeb, ecuador, haskell, stack-builders, lambda-days, 2015, client, professional, consulting, consultancy</p>

<h2>A Taste of Haskell</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched a lesson by Simon Peyton-Jones, that introduces haskell to experienced programmers, not in the language but in programming in general. At the conference OSCON 2007</p>

<p>Links: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jLj1QV11o9g">part 1</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IqXTUbdLig0">part 2</a>, <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/oscon2007/os-peytonjones">slides</a></p>

<p>Tags: oscon, 2007, haskell, introduction, lesson, simon-peyton-jones</p>

<h2>Programming - Why Haskell is Great</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RqvCNb7fKsg">this video</a> introducing some features of haskell. The most basic features, the REPL,  function composition. By FrungyKing</p>

<p>Tags: haskell, introduction, video, screencast, repl, frungyking</p>

<h2>History of Haskell: being lazy with class</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3bjXGrycMhQ">this video</a> by Simon Peyton-Jones at the &ldquo;History of Programming Languages Conference III&rdquo; which explains how the language was designed and written, a language timeline, what options they took, how they decided about monadic IO, etc.</p>

<p>Tags: simon-peyton-jones, 2007, history-of-programming-languages-conference, haskell, talk</p>

<h2>The Humble Programmer</h2>

<p>​I&rsquo;ve read [this EWD][ewd-340]​ about the necessary humbleness for being a programmer and the slow expansion of the trade, as compared to hardware engineers.</p>

<p>He cites six reasons for preferring to be a humble programmer:</p>

<ul>
<li>the programmer only needs to manage simple programs</li>
<li>simple programs imply reducing the search space</li>
<li>construct a program from a mathematical proof instead of test its properties after building the software. see quote below</li>
<li>a good abstraction can hide much complexity and difficulty</li>
<li>the importance of the used tool in the final product</li>
<li>&ldquo;the only problems we can satisfactory solve are the ones that admit a factored solution&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>In this essay I&rsquo;ve found the idea of</p>

<blockquote><p>Testing shows the presence, not the absence of bugs</p></blockquote>

<p>That <a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Edsger_W._Dijkstra">Wikiquote</a> attributes to an earlier paper (in 1969). In this paper, the verbatim quote is:</p>

<blockquote><p>program testing can be a very effective way to show the presence of bugs, but is hopelessly inadequate for showing their absence.</p></blockquote>

<p>This idea also connects to the &ldquo;lower bounds&rdquo; and &ldquo;upper bounds&rdquo; of program correctness expressed in the article <a href="https://cdsmith.wordpress.com/2011/01/09/an-old-article-i-wrote/">An Old Article I Wrote</a> which is about static types, by Cdsmith. Admittedly, much later, in 2008, so this idea could be inspired by the Dijkstra&rsquo;s article.</p>

<p>Tags: edsger-dijkstra, ewd, dijkstra, humble-programmer, essay, comparison, absence-of-bugs, quote</p>

<h2>Building a Link Shortener with Snaplets</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve seen <a href="https://vimeo.com/59109358">this video</a> of how to build a link shortener webapp in haskell with the framework snap. By Ryan Trinkle. Found it in the <a href="http://snapframework.com/docs">snap docs</a> page.</p>

<p>Tags: snap, haskell, link-shortener, talk, webapp, framework, ryan-trinkle</p>

<h2>Comparing Haskell Web Frameworks</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.edofic.com/posts/2014-02-23-haskell-web.html">this comparison</a> of haskell web frameworks, by Andraz Bajt (a.k.a, edofic)</p>

<p>Tags: andraz-bajt, edofic, haskell, web-framework, framework, comparison</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talk: Software Is Eating the World]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-10T19:00:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="http://reaktor.com/blog/erik-meijer-software-eating-world/">this talk</a> by Erik Meijer</p>

<h2>My notes</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Agile-The-Good-Hype-Ugly/dp/3319051547">Agile!: The Good, the Hype and the Ugly</a></p></li>
<li><p>The hacker way</p>

<ul>
<li>code always wins vs manager always wins</li>
<li>source: <a href="http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter/">http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter/</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>we&rsquo;re doing maths => we&rsquo;re building a proof</li>
<li>reinforcement learning

<ul>
<li>agent is the company</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>related to &ldquo;build, measure, learn&rdquo; by Eric Ries (<a href="http://theleanstartup.com/book">the lean startup</a>)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Feedback systems</h3>

<ul>
<li>Open (no) feedback system, such as timed sprinklers</li>
<li>Closed feedback system</li>
<li>Output only system</li>
</ul>


<h3>Why everything is software</h3>

<ul>
<li>Examples of everything is software</li>
<li>Software is eating the world</li>
<li>Even hardware is modeled as software</li>
</ul>


<h3>Modeling as a Finite State Machine (FSM)</h3>

<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s memory in the feedback loop. See the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finite-state_machine">finite state machine</a></li>
<li>A lesson from &ldquo;World War Z&rdquo;: &ldquo;When nine people agree on something, it&rsquo;s the tenth man&rsquo;s responsibility to disagree no matter how improbable the idea&rdquo;. &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t believe your own [ideas]&rdquo;. There&rsquo;s an article <a href="http://lifehacker.com/plan-more-effectively-with-the-tenth-man-rule-1689738373">here</a> and <a href="http://evidencemag.com/world-war-z/">here</a>, but they don&rsquo;t cite any official source related to this. The second one cites World War Z again, so it might be <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias">confirmation bias</a>.</li>
<li>Test in production (e.g., <a href="https://github.com/Netflix/SimianArmy/wiki/Chaos-Monkey">chaos monkey</a> from Netflix) rather than doing TDD</li>
<li>No evidence of TDD as effective, he sees it as waste</li>
<li>Move fast and break things</li>
</ul>


<h3>About layered organizations</h3>

<ul>
<li>Layered architecture. Examples: OSI, Catholic Church, Army</li>
<li>Analogy: Software development as a professional team structure (also cited from Netflix)</li>
<li>Book: Creativity from Constraints: the psychology of breakthrough. Focus, constraint, creativity</li>
<li>Presentation: <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Developing-Expertise-Dave-Thomas">Developing Expertise: Herding Racehorses, Racing Sheep</a></li>
<li>Analogy: Developers are like junkies, we want to be high all the time</li>
<li>Answering a new proposal: instead of &ldquo;no, but&rdquo; (black hat), &ldquo;yes and&rdquo; (blue hat). Reference to <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bossypants-Tina-Fey-ebook/dp/B0047Y0FGY">Bossypants</a> by Tina Fey</li>
<li>Your knives, your tools. &ldquo;How can we make millions if we don&rsquo;t value our tools?&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>About software:</p>

<blockquote><p>software will take over the world, and developers are the ones who make it happen.</p></blockquote>

<p>About methodologies:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Programming, motherfucker. Do you speak it?&rdquo; (<a href="http://programming-motherfucker.com/">Source</a>)</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-study in May 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-09T14:41:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update: I&rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015
into a single post</p>

<h2>Programmer passion considered harmful</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/on-coding/programmer-passion-considered-harmful-5c5d4e3a9b28">this article</a> on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.</p>

<h2>Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.coursereport.com/blog/software-craftsmanship-are-bootcamps-enough">this article</a> on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by <a href="https://twitter.com/kauerrolemodel">Ken Auer</a></p>

<h2>Improve your development environments with virtualization</h2>

<p>I have seen this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg_vPMnC7_k&amp;feature=youtu.be">Improve your development environments with virtualization</a> by Luke Sneeringer.</p>

<p>My notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>development should be exactly like production.</li>
<li>except where it is too painful. there it should be different</li>
</ul>


<h2>Buffer&rsquo;s take on values</h2>

<p>I have found these <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Bufferapp/buffer-culture-04">values</a>, written by Buffer, very interesting.</p>

<h2>Public static void</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kj5ApnhPAE">&ldquo;Public, static void&rdquo;</a> by Rob Pike. The slides can be found <a href="http://www.oscon.com/oscon2010/public/schedule/detail/13423">here</a></p>

<h3>My notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>too much bureaucracy</li>
<li>fighting the compiler</li>
<li>dynamic vs static typing</li>
<li>language too verbose</li>
<li><p>do not mix the two of them</p></li>
<li><p>a language niche:</p>

<ul>
<li>comprehensible</li>
<li>statically typed</li>
<li>light on the page</li>
<li>fast to work in</li>
<li>scales well</li>
<li>doesn&rsquo;t require tools but supports them well</li>
<li>good at networking and multiprocessing</li>
</ul>


<p>(minute 10:09)​</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://golang.org">Go</a> was born to fill this niche</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Nothing is something</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Software is eating the world</h2>

<p>This video has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/10/talk-software-is-eating-the-world/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>The Cost of Test Driven Development</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.typemock.com/2009/03/the-cost-of-test-driven-development.html">this article</a>, on the cost of doing TDD, which refers to <a href="http://www.msr-waypoint.net/en-us/groups/ese/nagappan_tdd.pdf">this paper</a>: Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams (below)</p>

<h2>Realizing quality improvement through test driven development: results and experiences of four industrial teams</h2>

<p>This paper has been extracted to a <a href="../../../../2015/05/12/paper-tdd-in-industrial-teams/">post</a> of its own.</p>

<h2>Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched the video <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3T00X_sNg4Q">Learn You Some Lisp for Great Good</a>, by Howard Abrams.</p>

<p>I guess this is a reference to the popular <a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/">Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!</a>.</p>

<p>He suggests many interesting resources for learning Lisp dialects. The live coding is in Clojure:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://landoflisp.com/">The land of Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/">Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs</a>. See also <a href="https://twitter.com/SICPQuotes">SICPQuotes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mitpress.mit.edu/books/little-schemer">The Little Schemer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/pdf/eintr.pdf">An Introduction to Programming in Emacs Lisp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.4clojure.com/">4clojure Questions</a></li>
<li><a href="http://clojurekoans.com/">Clojure Koans</a></li>
</ul>


<p>On another topic, in the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClojureBCN/events/222418104/">Bank accounts exercise from Exercism</a> meetup, we discussed the book <a href="https://pragprog.com/book/shcloj2/programming-clojure">Programming Clojure (2nd edition)</a> by Stuart Halloway</p>

<h2>Professor Frisby&rsquo;s Mostly Adequate Guide to Functional Programming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/DrBoolean/mostly-adequate-guide">this guide</a> to functional programming. It is still work in progress (WIP) but still interesting. Written in javascript, so you can REPL in the browser.</p>

<h2>Learning Code Good</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video, by Saron Yitbarek: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-nsnAYRqYLA">Learn Code Good</a>.</p>

<h2>Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R9FOchgTtLM">Why You Don&rsquo;t Get Mock Objects</a>, by Gregory Moeck.</p>

<p>In it, they point to the <a href="http://www.growing-object-oriented-software.com/">Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests</a> book (<a href="/blog/categories/goos">category here</a>), the paper <a href="www.jmock.org/oopsla2004.pdf">Mock Roles, not Objects</a> (also present in the GOOS book).</p>

<h2>Technical Debt: A Repayment Plan</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/tech-debt-repayment">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jeremyjarrell">Jeremy Jarrell</a> on technical debt how to repay it: schedule, taxes, default, etc</p>

<p>This has made me think of the <a href="http://scbcn.ideascale.com/a/dtd/Deuda-t%C3%A9cnica-origen-y-consecuencias/69782-25568">&ldquo;Deuda técnica, origen y consecuencias&rdquo; talk</a> (Technical debt: origin and consequences) (Spanish), that was delivered by <a href="https://twitter.com/@jgomezz">Javier Gómez</a> at the Software Craftsmanship 2014.</p>

<h2>Revisiting XP: be a thoughtful programmer by exercising more collective ownership</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/revisit-p-collective">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tiagooo_romero">Tiago Garcia</a> on the collective code ownership, as stated by Xtreme Programming (XP), with some example and guidelines.</p>

<h2>Where&rsquo;s the Real Bottleneck in Scientific Computing?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.americanscientist.org/issues/pub/wheres-the-real-bottleneck-in-scientific-computing/99999">this article</a> by Greg Wilson on the tools and procedures investigators use to produce software.</p>

<h2>Testing inside the Sprint</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://ronjeffries.com/articles/2015-03-01-testing-in-sprints/">this article</a> by Ron Jeffries.</p>

<p>Discusses the need for testing and why this hasn&rsquo;t been communicated enough, as there still are people who have not understood it.</p>

<p>Also about why people equal something failing when using scrum with scrum failing.</p>

<h2>DTO vs Domain Models</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/05/dto-vs-domain-models/">this article</a> by Carlos Blé</p>

<h2>Homoiconicity isn’t the point</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://calculist.org/blog/2012/04/17/homoiconicity-isnt-the-point/">this article</a> by David Herman about homoiconicity, comparing Lisp dialects (have it) to others that don&rsquo;t. The main point is at the end, where it says:</p>

<blockquote><p>[&hellip;] homoiconicity isn’t the point, read is</p></blockquote>

<h2>So You Don&rsquo;t Want to be a Programmer After All</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/so-you-dont-want-to-be-a-programmer-after-all/">this article</a> by Jeff Atwood. Cites the golden handcuffs (also known as golden shackles), reasons to be and not to be a programmer, and how to be an average and outstanding programmer</p>

<h2>The Nature of Lisp</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.defmacro.org/ramblings/lisp.html">this article / introduction</a> to Lisp by Slava Akhmechet</p>

<h2>[David Pollak&rsquo;s] My Thoughts on Go</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://blog.goodstuff.im/golang">these comments</a> on Go Lang from David Pollak</p>

<h2>The Well-Rounded Technologist</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/02/the-well-rounded-technologist.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Should I read papers?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/21/should-i-read-papers.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp-1 vs Lisp-2</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hornbeck.wordpress.com/2009/07/05/lisp-1-vs-lisp-2/">this article</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/hornbeck">@Hornbeck</a> about the lisp 1 and lisp 2.</p>

<h2>Science Corps</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dkQkafxFoIQ">TEDx talk</a> by Aza Raskin, featuring Data Banks and Science corps</p>

<h2>Healthy Codebase and Preparatory Refactoring</h2>

<p> I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://brewhouse.io/blog/2014/11/10/healthy-codebase-and-preparatory-refactoring.html">this article</a> by Philippe Creux about preparatory refactoring</p>

<h2>You Are Learning Haskell Right Now (Or Anything You Want Really)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/12/11/you-are-learning-haskell-right-now.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Lisp is Abstract Syntax</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/04/16/lisp-is-abstract-syntax.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Two Things Types Have Taught Me</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2014/10/30/two-things-types-have-taught-me.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t Bet Against Yourself</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Learning Math: A Blank Is A Blank With A Blank</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/04/15/dont-bet-against-yourself.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>The False Economy Of Metaprogramming</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://michaelrbernste.in/2015/03/06/the-false-economy-of-generated-methods.html">this article</a> by Michael Bernstein</p>

<h2>Management and Engineering, overlapping</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.quora.com/Does-Adam-DAngelo-feel-comfortable-with-the-transition-from-an-engineer-to-a-management-position?srid=3OC&amp;share=1">this Quora answer</a> by Adam D'Angelo. The original title is: Does Adam D'Angelo feel comfortable with the transition from an engineer to a management position?</p>

<h2>Evolution of The Twitter Stack</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/ly83zQkBjCxnIX">these slides</a> about changing the technology stack in Twitter: from Rails to JVM-based</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: Nothing Is Something]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-04T05:43:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/04/video-nothing-is-something</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have seen this video: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;v=9lv2lBq6x4A">Nothing is something</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/@sandimetz">Sandi Metz</a>, as I saw it recommended <a href="http://garajeando.blogspot.com.es/2015/04/interesting-talk-nothing-is-something.html">here</a></p>

<p>In the video, she talks programming in this fashion: (it is a stack, not an unordered list)</p>

<ul>
<li>Abstraction seeking</li>
<li>Message centric</li>
<li>Condition Averse</li>
<li>Smalltalk Infected</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>Not here to change the language but change you</p></blockquote>

<p>This is a pattern I&rsquo;ve also heard from <a href="https://twitter.com/@old_sound">Alvaro Videla</a>, where he said that other, more powerful languages can change your mind and help you bring some of those concepts to your own language. He was talking about Haskell, she, about Smalltalk.</p>

<p>She shows how to smell the <code>null object pattern</code> (that she independently discovered herself too - can be improved studying the classics<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>), also called <code>active nothing</code>. Decorates the <code>Animal</code> with a wrapper, to call it <code>GuaranteedAnimal</code></p>

<p>Later on, shows how to code an example on a &lsquo;tail&rsquo;, extending behaviour with inheritance and how to get rid of it: prefer composition versus inheritance. The importance of roles.</p>

<blockquote><p>Inheritance is for specialization, not for sharing code</p></blockquote>

<p>Steps to convert inheritance into composition:</p>

<ol>
<li>Isolate the difference</li>
<li>Name the concept</li>
<li>Define the role</li>
<li>Inject the players</li>
</ol>


<p>This is a trick I discovered here: when you don&rsquo;t know what name put here, create a spreadsheet and ask yourself what name the row should have. There is an example <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_detailpage&amp;v=9lv2lBq6x4A#t=1959">at this minute</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>a reference to a pattern by the same name at <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Apprenticeship-Patterns-Guidance-Aspiring-Craftsman/dp/0596518382">Apprenticeship Patterns</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talk: Simplicity Matters]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/18/talk-simplicity-matters/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-18T12:44:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/18/talk-simplicity-matters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve seen this video by <a href="http://twitter.com/@richhickey">Rich Hickey</a>: &ldquo;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rI8tNMsozo0">Simplicity matters</a>&rdquo;, taken from <a href="http://twitter.com/@trikitrok">Manuel Rivero</a>&rsquo;s google plus' <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/117817370205182982732/posts/W6Gd9v67BgS?cfem=1">site</a></p>

<p>here are my notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>the software is the elephant</li>
<li>do more, do it differently, do it better</li>
<li>complexity of the elephant is going to dominate what you can do</li>
<li>your ability to reason about your program is critical</li>
<li>design is about pulling things apart</li>
<li>become familiar by learning, trying</li>
<li>&ldquo;We can be creating the exact same programs out of significantly simpler components&rdquo;. Rich Hickey</li>
</ul>


<p>Complexity vs simplicity:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Complexity     </th>
<th> Simplicity</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>state, objects </td>
<td> values</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>methods </td>
<td> functions, namespaces</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>variables </td>
<td> managed refs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>inheritance, switch, matching  </td>
<td> polymorphism à la carte</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>syntax </td>
<td> data</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>imperative loops, fold </td>
<td> set functions</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>actors </td>
<td> queues</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>ORM </td>
<td> declarative data manipulation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>conditionals </td>
<td> rules</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>inconsistency </td>
<td> consistency </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<ul>
<li>he does not agree on &ldquo;simplicity&rdquo; on the agile manifesto</li>
<li>simplicity is not about you. simplicity is a lot of hard work

<ul>
<li>clicked with paul graham&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/avg.html">LISP startup</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>simplicity is not an objective</li>
</ul>


<p>Order is all over the place:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Complex  </th>
<th> Simple</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>positional arguments </td>
<td> named arguments or map</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>syntax </td>
<td> data</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>product types  </td>
<td> associate records</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>imperative programs </td>
<td> declarative programs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>prolog </td>
<td> datalog</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>call chains </td>
<td> queues</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>XML </td>
<td> JSON, Clojure literals</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
