<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backlog on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/backlog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backlog on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/backlog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blazing-fast-html-virtual-dom-in-elm&#34;&gt;Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://elm-lang.org/blog/blazing-fast-html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-should-never-ever-ever-use-mongodb&#34;&gt;Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://cryto.net/~joepie91/blog/2015/07/19/why-you-should-never-ever-ever-use-mongodb/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-really-get-classloaders&#34;&gt;Do you really get classloaders?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/rebel-labs-tutorial-do-you-really-get-classloaders/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the classloading is lazy: the resources are not loaded until they are mentioned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every classloader has a parent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every class has a classloader associated with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;every object has a class associated with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;classloading delegation: the parent is consulted before loading a class. if it has it, it will load it. If not, I will delegate it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.javaworld.com/article/2074396/core-java/javaone-2011--do-you-really-get-classloaders-.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; on the same video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jevgeny-kabanov, classloader, java,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth-table&#34;&gt;Truth table&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Truth_table&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; about the truth table and the 16 possible binary boolean operators:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contradiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NOR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converse nonimplication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negation (of p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Material nonimplication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negation (of q)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XOR (exclusive disjunction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAND&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AND (conjunction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XNOR (biconditional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projection (of p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projection (of q)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converse implication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR (disjunction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tautology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-lines-of-code-3-minutes-implement-a-programming-language-from-scratch&#34;&gt;7 lines of code, 3 minutes: Implement a programming language from scratch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://matt.might.net/articles/implementing-a-programming-language/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Matt Might about the benefits of implementing a language (from scratch but on top of another existing language used as framework). Chooses lambda calculus as the desired DSL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: matt-might, lambda-calculus, racket, domain-specific-language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turing-completeness&#34;&gt;Turing completeness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; (both main and discussion) about this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has sounded strange to me the reference to S-expressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data languages
The notion of Turing-completeness does not apply to languages such as XML, HTML, JSON, YAML and S-expressions because they are typically used to represent structured data, not describe computation [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If data (S-expression) is represented as the same format as code (e.g., Lisp&amp;rsquo;s S-expression) and the latter is used to represent a computation, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be &amp;ldquo;data languages that also are used as computation languages&amp;rdquo; excluded from that list?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, Lisp is Turing Complete (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness#Examples&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Turing Complete#Examples&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prize-is-won-the-simplest-universal-turing-machine-is-proved&#34;&gt;The Prize Is Won; The Simplest Universal Turing Machine Is Proved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wolfram.com/2007/10/24/the-prize-is-won-the-simplest-universal-turing-machine-is-proved/?year=2007&amp;amp;monthnum=10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Stephen Wolfram about the proof of a Turing Machine 2,3 being universal by Alex Smith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: stephen-wolfram, turing-machine, universal-turing-machine, proof, paper, alex-smith&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-a-successful-commitment-in-each-sprint&#34;&gt;Making a successful commitment in each Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://succeeding-with-agile.blogspot.com/2015/07/making-successful-commitment-in-each.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Nikolaos Raptis on committing to work in each sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: nikolaos-raptis, sprint, agile, commitment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-increment-operator-in-ruby&#34;&gt;No increment operator (++) in Ruby?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3717519/no-increment-operator-in-ruby&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; question about the lack of post-increment operator (i++) in Ruby:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;++ and &amp;ndash; are NOT reserved operator in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mailing list from &lt;a href=&#34;http://blade.nagaokaut.ac.jp/cgi-bin/scat.rb/ruby/ruby-talk/2710&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yukihiro Matsumoto aka matz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-is-data-data-is-code&#34;&gt;Code is Data, Data is Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.mulesoft.com/dev/news-dev/code-is-data-data-is-code/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by James Donelan on the equivalence of code and data in homoiconic languages, including Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article talks about homoiconicity, manually creating Abstract Syntax Trees (AST) out of data and the macro environment. Also, compares the difference between macros and functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: code=data, data=code, james-donelan, clojure, homoiconicity, abstract-syntax-tree, ast, macro, function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-in-practice-test-driven-development&#34;&gt;Agile in Practice: Test Driven Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uGaNkTahrIw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; introducing TDD by the Agile Academy. Explains its motivations and the basic cyclical fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: agile-academy, video, tdd, introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-in-practice-pair-programming&#34;&gt;Agile in Practice: Pair Programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ET3Q6zNK3Io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by Agile Academy on practicing pair programming. Explains the destination and how to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: agile-academy, pair-programming, video, introduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-low-cost-approach-to-working-on-side-projects&#34;&gt;A low cost approach to working on side projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://practicingruby.com/articles/low-cost-approach-to-side-projects&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Gregory Brown on how to apply the MVP and Lean Startup principles to side projects (a.k.a. pet projects). Try to start with a brainstorming session of all the features you want your product to have, then prioritise, picking the most important ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most projects&amp;rsquo; needs can be solved with a minimal version, in the form of a script that took half an hour to develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: gregory-brown, mvp, lean-startup, script, proof-of-concept, priority, backlog, side-project, pet-project, low-cost, cost-reduction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extreme-programming&#34;&gt;Extreme Programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kFM2Vcu-BRo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; by STAR Videos on the basic principles behind Extreme Programming and how to use it to improve software quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: star-videos, extreme-programming, xp, software-quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disruptor-high-performance-alternative-to-bounded-queues-for-exchanging-data-between-concurrent-threads&#34;&gt;Disruptor: High performance alternative to bounded queues for exchanging data between concurrent threads&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://lmax-exchange.github.io/disruptor/files/Disruptor-1.0.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this white paper&lt;/a&gt; describing the disruptor framework: a way of exchanging data between concurrent threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses a ring buffer and other techniques to eliminate write contention, reduce read contention and produces good results. It was developed for a financial exchange environment but it&amp;rsquo;s general purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: martin-thompson, dave-farley, michael-barker, patricia-gee, andrew-stewart, trisha-gee, disruptor, contention, framework, concurrency, parallelism, white-paper, comparison, arrayblockingqueue, concurrentlinkedqueue, doug-lea, benchmark, lmax, low-level-optimization, optimization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dissecting-the-disruptor-what-s-so-special-about-a-ring-buffer&#34;&gt;Dissecting the Disruptor: What&amp;rsquo;s so special about a ring buffer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://mechanitis.blogspot.com.es/2011/06/dissecting-disruptor-whats-so-special.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the ring buffer data structure. A FIFO data structure where elements get overwritten to reduce pressure on the garbage collector. Every message gets sent to every consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: patricia-gee, trisha-gee, disruptor, ring-buffer, data-structure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dependency-inversion-principle&#34;&gt;The Dependency Inversion Principle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.objectmentor.com/resources/articles/dip.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about the Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) written Robert C. Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It explains the theory, philosophy behind it. Also, creates an example with a copy buffer and different output locations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: robert-martin, dependency-inversion-principle, dip, example, comparison, object-oriented, principle, solid, design-principle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dip-in-the-wild&#34;&gt;DIP in the Wild&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/articles/dipInTheWild.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; about the Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) written by Brett L. Schuchert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is explained non-canonical representations of this principle, how in other cases he has solved it and conclusions of using it day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: brett-l.-schuchert, dependency-inversion-principle, dip, example, object-oriented, solid, design-principle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-new-product-development-game&#34;&gt;The New New Product Development Game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/1986/01/the-new-new-product-development-game&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about the holistic approach to product development, considered seminal for Scrum and other Agile methodologies. Written by Hirotaka Takeuchi and Ikujiro Nonaka&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In it, they describe how teams are distributed, the responsibilities for each one, and the degrees of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cites the six basic characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built-in instability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-organizing project teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overlapping development phases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multilearning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;subtle control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organizational transfer of learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: hirotaka-takeuchi, ikujiro-nonaka, scrum, agile, product-development, management, 1986&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>