<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Craftsman on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/the-craftsman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Craftsman on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 01:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/the-craftsman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Animal Laborans and the Homo Faber</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-animal-laborans-and-the-homo-faber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 01:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/10/the-animal-laborans-and-the-homo-faber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve found this quote very interesting from the book &amp;ldquo;The Craftsman&amp;rdquo;, by Richard Sennett:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal laborans&lt;/em&gt; is, as the name implies, the human being akin to a beast of burden,
a drudge condemned to routine. Arendt enriched this image by imagining him or her absorbed
in a task that shuts out the world, a state well exemplified by Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s feeling that the
atomic bomb was a &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; problem, or Eichmann&amp;rsquo;s obsession with making the gas chambers
efficient. In the act of making it work, nothing else matters; Animal laborans takes the work as
end end it itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By contrast, &lt;em&gt;Homo faber&lt;/em&gt; is her image of men and women doing another kind of work, making
a life in common. Again Arendt enriched an inherited idea. The Lating tag Homo faber
means simple &amp;ldquo;man as maker&amp;rdquo;. [&amp;hellip;] Homo faber is the judge of material labor and practice, not
Animal laborans&amp;rsquo;s colleague but his supertior. Thus, in her view, we human beings live in two
dimensions, In one we make things; in this condition we are amoral, absorbed in a task. We
also harbor another, higher way of life in which we stop producing and start discussion and
judging together. Whereas Animal laborans is fixated in the question &amp;ldquo;How?&amp;rdquo; Homo faber
asks &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Sennett, The Craftsman, Prologue, page 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>