<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Q1 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Q1 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 3); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy Confidence Hacks: 99 small actions to massively boost your confidence; Davenport; own-it, non-technical Tots estimem l&amp;rsquo;Emma; Burgas; non-technical  Confidence Hacks This is a self help book to boost your confidence.
It covers several areas of your life, that could erode your confidence:
 Relationships Social Life Career Appearance Self-Improvement Body Language Thinking Fun and Adventure Finances  How to read and apply it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</guid>
      <description>This quarter I&amp;rsquo;ve focused my efforts on a mix of everything:
 business books: Traction, The Goal philosophy: Stoicism and personal philosophy some finance: classic: Malkiel, personal finance: Robin some classic psychology: Frankl a classic novel: The Metamorphosis (Kafka)  Read this quarter:
 Hombre en busca del sentido, el; Frankl; own-it, non-technical Metamorfosis; Kafka; own-it, non-technical Your money or your life; Dominguez, Robin; non-technical, finance, own-it Traction; Wickman; own-it, non-technical How to Be a Stoic: Using Ancient Philosophy to Live a Modern Life; Pigliucci; own-it, non-technical Guide to the Good Life, The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy, a; Irvine; non-technical, own-it Goal, the; Goldratt (+); own-it Random walk down wall street a; Malkiel [Parts I, II, III]; own-it  Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
Note: the tag &amp;ldquo;guillem&amp;rdquo; is for books suggested by Guillem Fernandez
 Odessa; Forsyth; non-technical, own-it Bogle on mutual funds: new perspectives for the intelligent investor; Bogle; own-it, non-technical, finance Perros de la guerra, los; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical avaro y el oro, el; Esopo; non-technical Aulularia; Plauto; own-it, non-technical Tus zonas erróneas; Dyer; non-technical, own-it Alternativa del Diablo, la; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Guía, el; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Pied piper; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Hunt for the Red October, the; Clancy; own-it, non-technical Peopleware; DeMarco, Lister (+); own-it Time to kill, a; Grisham; own-it, non-technical Ética promiscua; Easton, Hardy; own-it, non-technical Checklist manifesto, the; Gawande; own-it, non-technical, guillem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
  The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/books-read-in-2016q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/books-read-in-2016q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 101 cosas que ya sabes, pero siempre olvidas by Ernie J. Zelinski; in Spanish Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs by Abelson, Sussman, and Sussman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag sicp. Only chapters 1 and 2.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Building microservices, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Why programmers work at night by Swizec Teller Readings in Database Systems, 5th Edition by Peter Bailis, Joseph M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/books-read-in-2015q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 12:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/books-read-in-2015q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q1 on 2015, as inspired by Manuel, on this post:
 Fifty Quick Ideas to Improve your User Stories, by Gojko Adzic and David Evans Fun retrospectives by Taina Caetano and Paulo Caroli Implementation patterns by Kent Beck Clean code by Robert C. Martin; again  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 The Well-Grounded Java Developer, by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg Refactoring, by Martin Fowler, (with Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, and Don Roberts) Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests, by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce Flow, by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi  (Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve written this list a posteriori, in May 2015)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
