<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/08/01/self-study-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Breakthrough a step toward revealing hidden structure of prime numbers https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41126944
Tags: hackernews, imported, igitur, mathematics, math, prime-number, prime
Id: 88d89b5c-5d23-4d59-84aa-1d612b111e6d Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:34:30 +0000
How I got my laser eye injury https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41127706
Tags: hackernews, imported, omnibrain, laser, injury, quanta-ray, eye-protection, eye-hazard
Id: ab6cba10-aede-4ce1-9673-2481d4684c22 Read: Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:25:34 +0000
JVM/Java: Null-Restricted and Nullable Types the markers ?, !, (default) for nullability in Java
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41136974
Tags: hackernews, imported, lichtenberger, java, programming, null, nullability, language, syntax, jep, java-enhancement-proposal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</guid>
      <description>Managing projects with GNU Make, Third Edition book about GNU Make, with recipes and going into detail about how to use it
Tags: book, make, gnu-make, project, skeleton, ci, continuous-integration
Id: 028b0e1f-a181-4469-8789-900ce6641d97 Read: Sun, 01 Jul 2024 17:22:52 +0000
Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs a tool to diff pdfs visually
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319
Tags: hackernews, imported, olshansky, testing, test, diff-pdf, pdf, diff, git, e2e-testing, end-to-end-testing, tool
Id: 4fc53bae-d81c-45b4-9f6b-995ec5d4df6a Read: Tue, 02 Jul 2024 07:26:08 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/12/01/self-study-december-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/12/01/self-study-december-2022/</guid>
      <description>CCache: a fast c/c++ compiler cache Related to 027d6f8a-714e-11ed-869a-0242ac110003
Tags: tool, cache, compilation-cache, optimization, speedup, c, cpp, c++, gcc, clang
Id: f2423a38-714d-11ed-92b4-0242ac110003 Read: Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:58:30 +0000
CATS: OpenAPI fuzzing and test generation tool Tags: cats, tool, openapi, fuzz-testing, test-tool, java, endava, eoin-woods
Id: 08b0cdb0-714f-11ed-a45c-0242ac110003 Read: Thu, 01 Dec 2022 08:06:18 +0000
I&amp;rsquo;ve fuzzed a small part of the GitHub API. Here are my findings. Using CATS to fuzz part of the Github API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2021</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2021/01/01/self-study-january-2021/</guid>
      <description>Perfect Media Server Hacker News discussion on a media server, half open source (?).
Tags: hacker-news, media-server, perfect, tool, software
Id: c37b0f2a-4dc5-11eb-8048-0242ac110002 Read: Sun, 03 Jan 2021 13:15:34 +0000
How your startup can survive technical debt Mentions the paradox of success: you need debt to start quickly, yet too quickly leaves no time to pay debt. Hence your prototype turns into an MVP, and that is your first piecce of technical debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 12 rules for life; Peterson; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  12 rules for life The book contains some rules, some principles to remove doubt and uncertainty from life.
There are plenty of mentions to the Bible, although I consider the book to the secular in its contents.
There are few personal stories on the book (e.g., about his daughter Mikhaila Peterson), which makes it readable and enjoyable. The philosophy behind it is sometimes not-politically-correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/09/30/books-read-2020q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Bushido, the soul of Japan; Nitobe; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/06/30/books-read-2020q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Skunk Works; Rich; own-it, non-technical  Skunk Works This book describes Ben R. Rich&amp;rsquo;s adventure of creating the F-117A, the stealth plane with a triangular shape.
Describes how he won a bet against legendary plane designer Clarence &amp;lsquo;Kelly&amp;rsquo; Johnson. How he got the 25 cents from his old mentor and friend.
Later, the book reviews Kelly&amp;rsquo;s history as the manager of Skunk Works, how it works, the principles (Kelly&amp;rsquo;s 14 rules), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/03/31/books-read-2020q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 3); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy Confidence Hacks: 99 small actions to massively boost your confidence; Davenport; own-it, non-technical Tots estimem l&amp;rsquo;Emma; Burgas; non-technical  Confidence Hacks This is a self help book to boost your confidence.
It covers several areas of your life, that could erode your confidence:
 Relationships Social Life Career Appearance Self-Improvement Body Language Thinking Fun and Adventure Finances  How to read and apply it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 2); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/09/30/books-read-2019q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 1); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy My Story, Al Maktoum; non-technical  My Story, Al Maktoum  This important collection of anecdotes and reminiscences from Sheikh Mohammed bin Rashid Al Maktoum is published to mark the occasion of his fifty years in public service, which began with his appointment as Dubai’s Minister of Defence in 1968.
These stories tell of the vision behind Dubai’s meteoric growth from a small and bustling trading port to an international metropolis at the heart of global business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/06/30/books-read-2019q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein; own-it, finance, non-technical Candide; Voltaire; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Simple path to wealth, the; Collins; own-it, non-technical, finance Lagom; Brantmark; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Comment revivre par le jeune; Lützner; own-it, non-technical Educación financiera avanzada desde cero; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance Pensiones públicas, la esclavitud de nuestra época; Hernández; non-technical, own-it, finance On the shortness of life; Séneca; own-it, non-technical, philosophy Código del dinero, el; Samsó; own-it, non-technical, finance Más cosas sobre la bolsa; Hernández; own-it, non-technical, finance  4 pillars of investment, the; Bernstein Candide; Voltaire Came across this book as the source for the term &amp;lsquo;Panglossian&amp;rsquo; or extreme optimist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in April 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/04/01/self-study-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>How to validate password with regular expression Explains the &amp;lsquo;?=&amp;rsquo; character in a regex, to validate conditions. Make it &amp;lsquo;.*&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;contain&amp;rsquo;, rather than &amp;lsquo;startWith&amp;rsquo;
Tags: password, validation, look-ahead, regex, regular-expression
Id: 2ed5999a-555f-11e9-8bf8-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 02 Apr 2019 15:51:30 +0000
Unlock honest feedback from your employees with this one word I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about asking for advice instead of asking for feedback and how that helped.
Tags: comparison, advice, feedback</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/31/books-read-2019q1/</guid>
      <description>This quarter I&amp;rsquo;ve focused my efforts on a mix of everything:
 business books: Traction, The Goal philosophy: Stoicism and personal philosophy some finance: classic: Malkiel, personal finance: Robin some classic psychology: Frankl a classic novel: The Metamorphosis (Kafka)  Read this quarter:
 Hombre en busca del sentido, el; Frankl; own-it, non-technical Metamorfosis; Kafka; own-it, non-technical Your money or your life; Dominguez, Robin; non-technical, finance, own-it Traction; Wickman; own-it, non-technical How to Be a Stoic: Using Ancient Philosophy to Live a Modern Life; Pigliucci; own-it, non-technical Guide to the Good Life, The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy, a; Irvine; non-technical, own-it Goal, the; Goldratt (+); own-it Random walk down wall street a; Malkiel [Parts I, II, III]; own-it  Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/01/01/self-study-january-2019/</guid>
      <description>Work cycles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this Work Cycle framework to be more productive with your daily routine.
Suggests an alternative to Pomodoro technique, in which you are to write down the contents of the goal, then split in small chunks (periods) of time to complete the individual tasks, then debrief at the end of the period and at the end of the cycle.
An analogy could be a double-loop Pomodoro technique for tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) Oliver Twist; Dickens Building evolutionary architecture; Ford, Parsons Selfie: How We Became So Self-Obsessed and What It’s Doing To Us; Storr. Just chapter 1: The dying self Sota la cistella; Gasol  Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) I&amp;rsquo;ve re-read this classic book (How to win friends and influence people), by Carnegie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/09/30/books-read-2018q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles Book of Transformation; Dalai Lama  Ética a Nicómaco; Aristóteles I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book on philosophy and ethics. This book contains an analysis of the relationship between the personality, intelligence and happiness.
Tries to describe what &amp;lsquo;virtues&amp;rsquo; are, that they belong in a continuum of acts, aand the good term is always in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/30/books-read-2018q2/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Quien se ha llevado mi queso; Johnson; own-it, guillem One minute manager, the; Blanchard; own-it, non-technical, guillem En defensa de los ociosos; Stevenson; non-technical, own-it Ladybird Book of Mindfulness, the (Ladybirds for Grown-Ups); Hazeley, Morris; non-technical Art of the start, the; Kawasaki; own-it, non-technical, guillem Getting started with NoFap; non-technical Emotional intelligence; Goleman; non-technical  Quien se ha llevado mi queso I&amp;rsquo;ve read this fable explaining the little story of two mice and two lilliputians that end up without any cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/03/31/books-read-2018q1/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
Note: the tag &amp;ldquo;guillem&amp;rdquo; is for books suggested by Guillem Fernandez
 Odessa; Forsyth; non-technical, own-it Bogle on mutual funds: new perspectives for the intelligent investor; Bogle; own-it, non-technical, finance Perros de la guerra, los; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical avaro y el oro, el; Esopo; non-technical Aulularia; Plauto; own-it, non-technical Tus zonas erróneas; Dyer; non-technical, own-it Alternativa del Diablo, la; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Guía, el; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Pied piper; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical Hunt for the Red October, the; Clancy; own-it, non-technical Peopleware; DeMarco, Lister (+); own-it Time to kill, a; Grisham; own-it, non-technical Ética promiscua; Easton, Hardy; own-it, non-technical Checklist manifesto, the; Gawande; own-it, non-technical, guillem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Lazarillo de Tormes, el; anónimo; non-technical Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s power plays - Politika; Preisler; own-it, non-technical Moon is a harsh mistress, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Old man&amp;rsquo;s war; Scalzi; non-technical, own-it Nightfall; Asimov, Silverberg; own-it, non-technical Interface; Stephenson, George; non-technical, own-it Man who sold the moon, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Agents of innocence; Ignatius; own-it, non-technical Fist of god, the; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical: Synopsis: in a mixture of truth and novel, the author explains the invasion of Kuwait by Iraqi dictator Sadam Hussein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/09/30/books-read-2017q3/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 the senior software developer; Copeland, with the aprendices reading club Scandal in Bohemia, a; Doyle: a short novel by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, mentioning Irene Adler and the king of Bohemia Getting things done, &amp;hellip;; Allen (+): A book on productivity, where Allen explains his method of GTD and how to apply it. Explains what has worked and not worked for him in his many years of consulting and coaching clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Software Development: Part I</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/nature-software-development-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/nature-software-development-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The Nature of Software development: reading breadcrumbs, quotes, thoughts Preface  The Natural Way serves end users well because it delivers value to them sooner.
serves the business [&amp;hellip;] because it provides important information quickly, and because it provides the ability to adjust direction as needed.
serves management [&amp;hellip;] see what’s really going on inside the project so that when action is needed, there will be time to act. And it reduces management’s problems by making information visible [&amp;hellip;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search for Value (a quote)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/search-for-value-quote-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/search-for-value-quote-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>A quote from the book The Nature of Software Development by Ron Jeffries, talking about value (in software) and the building blocks to achieve it:
 Value. Value, we’ll see, is “what you want.” [&amp;hellip;]
We’ll tell the story by building up from the bottom of the pyramid, describing how to guide, organize, plan, and build our product, in small slices, with a focus on quality. The value we produce is based on these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/06/30/books-read-2017q2/</guid>
      <description>(I&amp;rsquo;ve changed how I organize my books. More, here (TODO))
Finished:
 Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern; non-technical. A quick introduction to Bertrand Russell, his life and his way of thinking and seeing the world. Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell; non-technical. A first-person view of the events during the Spanish Civil War (1936-1939), seen from the perspective of a British citizen that went there voluntarily. Explains the internal fracture of the left political parties and the fracture of the Spanish society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 9</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 17:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 9: Learn to Write Analogy of TDD to writing.
Explains how to write good email. Then, good documentation, then good API documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 8</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/28/senior-software-engineer-chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 8: Bootstrap a Greenfield System  Working on a brand new application can be a lot of fun. There’s no &amp;ldquo;baggage&amp;rdquo; from legacy code, no technical debt, and there’s a wonderful feeling of freshness when starting an app from scratch.
(p. 101)
  The decisions you make [&amp;hellip;] can have a lasting impact
(p. 101)
 8.1 Overview  When given a greenfield project [&amp;hellip;] you have two main goals:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 7</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/24/senior-software-engineer-chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 11:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/24/senior-software-engineer-chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7: Make Technical Decisions  Opinions like this are often indicators of hidden facts that you have yet to identify
(p. 90)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 6</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 07:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6: Play Well With Others  challenges you’ll face as a programmer is to explain what you do, or how you’ve done it, to someone who is not a programmer
Translating your work to non-technical people is a skill that can be more valuable than any specific technical knowledge you have. It’s what makes a senior developer in the eyes of others.
(p 77)
 6.1 Empathize With Your Audience  these &amp;ldquo;interested parties&amp;rdquo; understand the problem more deeply than you, but lack the technical knowledge, skill, or time to solve it directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 5</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 07:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/23/senior-software-engineer-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5: Deal With Technical Debt and Slop  Seeing legacy as tech debt that has been acquired Slop as source for sloppy code Chapter about understanding the difference between slop and technical debt.   Many developers, if they are feeling pressured to complete their work, would call this an acceptable compromise, promise to fix it later, and ship it
(p. 70)
  Technical Debt is [&amp;hellip;] used to explain compromises in implementation that save cost now, at a larger future cost (just like real debt).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senior Software Engineer, Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/13/senior-software-engineer-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 13:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/13/senior-software-engineer-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3: Fix bugs efficiently and cleanly In the beginning, you will be given tasks that require no in-depth domain knowledge
Process  A process allows you to focus on the right thing at th right time (p. 14)
It will make your productivity and quality more predictable, which, in turn, will help you estimate and keep more of your promises about your work (paraphrased from p. 14)
 TDD Explains some benefits about TDD:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/03/31/books-read-in-2017q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
  The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/books-read-in-2016q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/books-read-in-2016q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
 La psicología del dinero, Hammond Invirtiendo a largo plazo, García Paramés Quién domina el mundo, Chomsky Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell El camino al 18J, Payne Cartas desde la revolución bolchevique, Sadoul Shogun: The Life of Tokugawa Ieyasu, Sadler Els jueus i Catalunya, Villatoro Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern El problema de los tres cuerpos, Liu    The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/books-read-in-2016q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/09/30/books-read-in-2016q3/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Pocket Guide by Chromatic Notes to a Software Team Leader (1st Edition), by Roy Osherove  Non-technical:
 The Zero Marginal Cost Society: The Internet of Things, the Collaborative Commons, and the Eclipse of Capitalism, by Jeremy Rifkin Snow Crash, by Neal Stephenson La guerra no tiene rostro de mujer, by Svetlana Aleksiévich  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Talking with Tech Leads: From Novices to Practitioners by Patrick Kua  Books I want to finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 10:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/07/04/self-study-in-july-2016/</guid>
      <description>Until the End of the Internet I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jason Zimdars explaining the &amp;ldquo;end of the internet&amp;rdquo; policy at Basecamp: they will make everything possible to keep the services running for existing customer until the end or until the last customer uses it.
Tags: policy, end-of-the-internet, jason-zimdars, basecamp, product
How Agile Principles Can Fund Your Start-Up I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Jurgen Appelo explaining how the agile values can help you negotiate funding for your startup: instead of negotiating with each investor, agree on a formula and invest in many small rounds, instead of a big one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/books-read-in-2016q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Extreme Programming Explained: Embrace Change, 2nd Edition by Kent Beck and Cynthia Andres, again. Building Microservices, Designing Fine-Grained Systems, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Reinventing Organizations by Frederic Laloux. Blog posts under the tag reinventing-organizations  Non-technical:
 L&amp;rsquo;acabadora, by Michela Murgia Disrupted: My Misadventure in the Start-Up Bubble by Dan Lyons  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stability terms from &#34;Release it!&#34;, a quote</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/26/stability-terms-from-release-it-a-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 22:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/26/stability-terms-from-release-it-a-quote/</guid>
      <description>In Release It!, terms related to stability:
 transaction: is an abstract unit of work processed by the system mixed workload: is a combination of different transaction types processed by a system. system: the complete, interdependent set of hardware, applications, and services required to process transactions for users stability: resilient system keeps processing transactions, even when there are transient impulses, persistent stresses, or component failures disrupting normal processing stress (to the system): is a force applied to the system over an extended period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of a software consultant</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/10/role-software-consultant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 10:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/10/role-software-consultant/</guid>
      <description>A quote from Reinventing Organizations, about roles, job descriptions and job titles in Chapter 2.2: Self-management (structures), page 90:
 [In] Teal Organizations [&amp;hellip;] people are not made to fit pre-defined jobs; their job emerge from a multitude of roles and responsibilities they pick up based on their interests, talents, and the needs of the organization.
 Frederic Laloux, Reinventing Organizations   In my opinion, this is the role of the software consultant when working with a client: even if the customer has asked for help in some parts of their activity, a senior-enough consultant can discover other areas where they can add value, even if that new work doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much in common with the initial request (this change should be approved by the people that will be affected).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwritten principles for coaching, a quote</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/10/unwritten-principles-coaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 10:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/06/10/unwritten-principles-coaching/</guid>
      <description>A quote from Reinventing Organizations, about a few unwritten principles for coaching, in Chapter 2.2: Self-management (structures), page 70:
  It’s okay for teams to struggle. From struggle comes learning. And teams that have gone through difficult moments build resilience and a deep sense of community. The coach’s role therefore is not to prevent foreseeable problems, but to support teams in solving them (and later help them reflect on how they’ve grown in the process).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in May 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/self-study/</guid>
      <description>Being A Developer After 40 I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Adrian Kosmaczewski on the required topics to be a developer at age 40 and keep enjoying it:
 Forget The Hype Choose Your Galaxy Wisely Learn About Software History Keep on Learning Teach Workplaces Suck Know Your Worth Send The Elevator Down LLVM  He references galaxy, the big stack you are positioned (JVM, .net, PHP, etc). He makes a special mention of the LLVM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/books-read-in-2016q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/books-read-in-2016q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 101 cosas que ya sabes, pero siempre olvidas by Ernie J. Zelinski; in Spanish Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs by Abelson, Sussman, and Sussman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag sicp. Only chapters 1 and 2.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Building microservices, by Sam Newman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag building-microservices Why programmers work at night by Swizec Teller Readings in Database Systems, 5th Edition by Peter Bailis, Joseph M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/books-read-in-2015q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/books-read-in-2015q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby, An Agile Primer (POODR) by Sandi Metz, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag poodr.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Haskell Programming, By Chris Allen and Julie Moronuki. This book is still in progress and I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing it Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs by Abelson, Sussman, and Sussman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q3</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/books-read-in-2015q3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/books-read-in-2015q3/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 The Craftsman by Richard Sennett. Posts under the tag the-craftsman Software Craftsmanship: The New Imperative by Pete McBreen. Posts under the tag software-craftsmanship-book Lisp Hackers by Vsevolod Dyomkin The Passionate Programmer: Creating a Remarkable Career in Software Development by Chad Fowler.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Haskell Programming, By Chris Allen and Julie Moronuki. This book is still in progress and I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing it Functional Programming Patterns in Scala and Clojure by Michael Bevilacqua-Linn Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt  Books I want to finish:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q2</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/books-read-in-2015q2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/30/books-read-in-2015q2/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q2 on 2015:
 Flow by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi. Blog posts under the tag flow Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce. Blog posts under the tag goos. Read in the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. TDD in Java, by Viktor Farcic and Alex García. I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed this book.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 The Well-Grounded Java Developer by Benjamin J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category: Poodr</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/01/category-poodr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 07:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/01/category-poodr/</guid>
      <description>This category is mainly dedicated to anything related or included in the book &amp;lsquo;Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby&amp;rsquo;, by Sandi Metz
Note: This has been created a posteriori with a previous date</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What versus How</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/06/what-versus-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 07:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/06/what-versus-how/</guid>
      <description>After reading the GOOS1, the more and more I get this feeling of what vs how:
 Information hiding The total simpler than the sum of the parts Extracting a concept so you can think about this. Makes you find better names:  test name variable name method name interface / protocol name    I also got this feeling when reading Clean Code. But with this other book the smell is much harder, stronger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose fault is this?</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/whose-fault-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 14:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/whose-fault-is-this/</guid>
      <description>In the prologue of the book, while thanking everyone that has made the book possible:
 [&amp;hellip;], none of the people mentioned here would be responsible for any inaccuracy that might exist in the book, as this responsibility is exclusively mine
Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi (translated)1, prologue of &amp;ldquo;Flow&amp;rdquo;
 (More posts on this same book, here)
This connects with what Dan North said in the Craft Conf about this idea of the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the only one in the company producing good quality work, the rest are not doing the same&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I read Apprenticeship Patterns</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/how-i-read-apprenticeship-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 13:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/how-i-read-apprenticeship-patterns/</guid>
      <description>At the Craft Conf 2015 I saw someone with the book Apprenticeship Patterns by Dave Hoover and Adewale Oshineye and asked them about the book. After praising the contents, they asked me how to approach the book.
I recalled reading it non-sequentially, and explained it to them:
 Read the introduction, preface, etc first When you get to the patterns, pick one at random 10: Read it and navigate through the see also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category: Flow</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/01/category-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 07:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/01/category-flow/</guid>
      <description>This category is mainly dedicated to anything related or included in the book &amp;lsquo;Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience&amp;rsquo;, written by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi
Note: This has been created a posteriori with a previous date</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q1</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/books-read-in-2015q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 12:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/31/books-read-in-2015q1/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q1 on 2015, as inspired by Manuel, on this post:
 Fifty Quick Ideas to Improve your User Stories, by Gojko Adzic and David Evans Fun retrospectives by Taina Caetano and Paulo Caroli Implementation patterns by Kent Beck Clean code by Robert C. Martin; again  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 The Well-Grounded Java Developer, by Benjamin J. Evans and Martijn Verburg Refactoring, by Martin Fowler, (with Kent Beck, John Brant, William Opdyke, and Don Roberts) Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests, by Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce Flow, by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi  (Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve written this list a posteriori, in May 2015)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: Diseño Ágil con TDD (Spanish)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/book-diseno-agil-con-tdd-spanish/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book Diseño Ágil con TDD (Spanish) by Carlos Blé from cover to cover, when previously I had only read the theoretical parts (Part I and Chapter 12 in Part II).
It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that this is the first TDD book in Spanish (I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any book in Spanish predating this one - also backed by the author; published in January 2010) and, as such, there are some translations that could be improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your First Language</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language/</guid>
      <description>After reading (in a specific order - below) part of the patterns in Apprenticeship Patterns, I stumbled upon the &amp;ldquo;Your First Language&amp;rdquo;
First of all, the illustration with the baby reading a Java book is priceless.
Having said that, I came to the realization that you might not know a paradigm but just an implementation (e.g., you don&amp;rsquo;t know about Object-Oriented programming but just about Java), in the same fashion as you could not know about LISPs but only about an implementation, such as clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listening to the tests</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/listening-to-the-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 22:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/listening-to-the-tests/</guid>
      <description>Specifically the chapter no. 20 (&amp;ldquo;Listening to the tests&amp;rdquo;) from Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests available here is so good to learn to hear to your tests.
To hear what they&amp;rsquo;re trying to tell you, the authors (Steve Freeman and Nat Pryce) explain this to you:
 I Need to Mock an Object I Can’t Replace Logging Is a Feature Mocking Concrete Classes Don’t Mock Values Bloated Constructor Confused Object Too Many Dependencies Too Many Expectations  To close, a quote:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Category: Goos</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/01/category-goos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 07:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/01/01/category-goos/</guid>
      <description>This category is mainly dedicated to anything related or included in the book &amp;lsquo;Growing Object-Oriented Software Guided by Tests&amp;rsquo;, by Nat Pryce and Steve Freeman
Note: This has been created a posteriori with a previous date</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2014Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/31/books-read-in-2014q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/31/books-read-in-2014q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q4 on 2014, as inspired by Manuel, on this post:
 ATDD by Example: A Practical Guide to Acceptance Test-Driven Development by Markus Gärtner Head First Design Patterns by Eric Freeman, Elisabeth Robson, Bert Bates, Kathy Sierra Apprenticeship Patterns, Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman by Dave Hoover, Adewale Oshineye Diseño ágil con TDD, by Carlos Blé Jurado; again The Mythical Man-Month, Anniversary Edition: Essays On Software Engineering by Frederick P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joys of the Craft</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 22:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft/</guid>
      <description>Quoting the book,
 Why is programming fun? What delights may its practitioner expect as his reward?
First is the sheer joy of making things. As the child delights in his mud pie, so the adult enjoys building things, especially things of his own design [&amp;hellip;]
Second is the pleasure of making things that are useful to other people. Deep within, we want other to use our work and to find it helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joys of the Craft as Article</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft-as-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 22:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft-as-article/</guid>
      <description>Quoting the book,
 Why is programming fun? What delights may its practitioner expect as his reward?
First is the sheer joy of making things. As the child delights in his mud pie, so the adult enjoys building things, especially things of his own design [&amp;hellip;]
Second is the pleasure of making things that are useful to other people. Deep within, we want other to use our work and to find it helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
