<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>February on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/february/</link>
    <description>Recent content in February on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/february/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2020</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/02/01/self-study-february-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/02/01/self-study-february-2020/</guid>
      <description>localdots — HTTPS domains for localhost localdots combines Caddy and smallstep/certificates with automated configuration and hot reload.
Generates SSL/TLS certificates automatically Reloads Caddy automatically with every change
Tags: https, tls, ssl, caddy, certificate, ssl-certificate, development, dev, environment, local, localhost
Id: 851bde02-2e14-11ea-9ec6-0242ac11000d Read: Fri, 03 Jan 2020 10:33:45 +0000
Write Your Own Compiler Link to create a new compiler, for the T3X language.
 less than 150 pages of comprehensible code and straight-forward prose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/02/01/self-study-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Amazon DynamoDB Transactions: How it Works Explains how transactions work in DynamoDB
Tags: dynamodb, aws, help, transaction, serializable
Id: 7fb09cd4-2639-11e9-9377-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:53:20 +0000
Jepsen: Aerospike I&amp;rsquo;ve read this analysis of Aerospike, that explains what kind of database it is, what CAP properties satisfies
Tags: cap, cap-theorem, jepsen, aphyr, aerospike, database, acid, ap, cp, consistency, availability, partitioning, paxos
Id: bd7151c6-2639-11e9-a38e-0242ac110002 Read: Fri, 01 Feb 2019 15:55:04 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/02/01/self-study-february-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/02/01/self-study-february-2018/</guid>
      <description>Contract test I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bliki article by Martin Fowler on how to test the integration with external service providers. On how it should be integrated into the building pipeline, but maybe not fail exactly as the rest.
Tags: bliki, martin-fowler, contract-test, microservices, pact, integration-test, pipeline, continuous-integration</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/01/self-study-in-february-2016/</guid>
      <description>Software and all that comes with it I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about creating software and asking questions to deliver value, by Alberto Brandolini
Tags: alberto-brandolini, software, slide, team-management, agile
Driving your DBA crazy in 3 easy steps I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about dealing with the knowledge that is present in the database, not expressed in ubiquitous language and cause of the low bus factor, by Alberto Brandolini
Analogy between the movie The Shining and a model / entities / aggregates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
