<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>how-to on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in how-to on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:41:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tip: using tortoise credentials in git CLI</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/using-tortoise-credentials-from-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 12:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/using-tortoise-credentials-from-cli/</guid>
      <description>TortoiseGit part  Go to a repo right button, Settings Git -&amp;gt; Credential Add a creadential Config type: global Helper: wincred  Sync once using your HTTPS password
CLI part Open the $REPO/.git/config and add
[credential] helper = wincred Remote git operations should not ask for credentials anymore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two persons involved in a git commit, in github</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/14/two-persons-involved-in-a-git-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 17:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/02/14/two-persons-involved-in-a-git-commit/</guid>
      <description>On git You can have multiple persons involved in a single git commit: an author and a committer.
The difference is explained by Manuel Doninger 1:
 The author is the one who did the code change. The committer is the person who committed that change to a repository.
 an example, by the same author:
 Example: I&amp;rsquo;m not a committer in the EGit project, so i have no rights to push directly to the EGit repository at Eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 21:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/</guid>
      <description>Humble Object I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Humble Object list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:
 humble dialog humble executable humble transaction controller humble container adapter  Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros
How you know I&amp;rsquo;ve reread this small essay by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.
Tags: paul-graham, reread, read
Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software &amp;gt; Design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
