<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hypothesis | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/hypothesis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-09T16:55:55+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logging Is a Feature]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/19/logging-is-a-feature/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-19T23:43:10+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/04/19/logging-is-a-feature</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At a client, we&rsquo;re facing this challenge: we cannot access production logs, as we don&rsquo;t have access to production environments. The solution we&rsquo;ve chose is to implement the logging component as a layer on top of <a href="http://www.splunk.com/">Splunk</a>.</p>

<p>This formatter layer &ndash;per component&ndash; accesses a generic layer &ndash;for the whole company&ndash; that accesses splunk. In this manner, it is very easy to reuse the splunk connection and configuration and inject mocks. Also helps with the local environment: you always log to console (even if in production you don&rsquo;t have access to it) and can disable this in local, not needing a local splunk installation.</p>

<p>Strategies for dealing with this:</p>

<ul>
<li>functional logger: no shared state

<ul>
<li>can only log information available in this scope: parameters, attributes, static information</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>stateful logger: information is added to the threadContext and logged whenever necessary

<ul>
<li>can log information in this scope plus any of the previous invokings.</li>
<li>the problem is precisely sharing state: you have to control all the possible parents to know where this data comes from. A piece of information may come from any source.</li>
<li>Lose the reference of who is invoking you, as there is no customization for this. (only using implementation)</li>
<li>Speak two different languages: one for logging and one for business logic</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>mixed: mix and match the best of both worlds.

<ul>
<li>The problem with the shared state can be solved if no data is overwritten and any information is stored in a map where the key is the fully qualified (FQ) method name (or FQ class name + FQ method name)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>The GOOS book explains this very well on the 20th chapter, first half &ldquo;logging is a feature&rdquo;. If we log as described in chapters 19 and 20, some of the problems are reduced:</p>

<ul>
<li>multiple levels of abstraction</li>
<li>indirect control over logging. decide in a single place whether to log exceptions of each kind or not</li>
<li>remove &ldquo;implementation details&rdquo; such as &ldquo;log.isDebugEnabled&rdquo;</li>
<li>remove performance issues: no need to build strings for logging every time, only need to pass objects. inside the logging layer, if the logger is enabled for that level, then spend the time building strings and print them</li>
</ul>


<p>We should remember that:</p>

<ul>
<li>Whenever logging becomes useful data (for the stakeholders) it no longer is a debug information and needs to be tested (automatically). In my opinion, it is not enough to test it daily when debugging, as these stakeholders rely on the data. Also, humans are not good detecting small differences, while machines excel at it.</li>
<li>Why treat the logging feature different from any other? It is an investment, like any other, and as such should work properly</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Legacy Code Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/21/a-legacy-code-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-21T20:05:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/21/a-legacy-code-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the best legacy code introductions I&rsquo;ve seen:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Grand Redesign in the Sky</p>

<p>Eventually the team rebels. They inform management that they cannot continue to develop in this odious code base. They demand a redesign. Management does not want to expend the resources on a whole new redesign of the project, but they cannot deny that productivity is terrible. Eventually they bend to the demands of the developers and authorize the grand redesign in the sky.</p>

<p>A new tiger team is selected. Everyone wants to be on this team because it&rsquo;s a greenfield project. They get to start over and create something truly beautiful. But only the best and brightest are chosen for the tiger team. Everyone else must continue to maintain the current system.</p>

<p>Now the two teams are in a race. The tiger team must build a new system that does everything that the old system does. Not only that, they have to keep up with the changes that are continuously being made to the old system. Management will not replace the old system until the new system can do everything that the old system does.</p>

<p>This race can go on for a very long time. I&rsquo;ve seen it take 10 years. And by the time it&rsquo;s done, the original members of the tiger team are long gone, and the current members are demanding that the new system be redesigned because it&rsquo;s such a mess.</p>

<p><cite> Robert C. Martin </cite> in the chapter 1: Clean Code from the book by <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Clean-Code-Handbook-Software-Craftsmanship/dp/0132350882/">the same name</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Also, why should you estimate the new tiger team abilities better than the old tiger team? Is it because the language, tools, or just because they are &ldquo;plain better&rdquo;?</p>

<p>What guarantees that the resulting software is going to be better than the old one?</p>

<p>Another interesting definition of legacy code is Michael Feather&rsquo;s one (code without tests).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your First Language]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-02T21:25:37+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/your-first-language</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading (in a specific order - below) part of the patterns in <a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9780596518387.do">Apprenticeship Patterns</a>,
I stumbled upon the <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/ch02.html#your_first_language">&ldquo;Your First Language&rdquo;</a></p>

<p>First of all, the illustration with the baby reading a Java book is priceless.</p>

<p>Having said that, I came to the realization that you might not know a paradigm but just an implementation
(e.g., you don&rsquo;t know about Object-Oriented programming but just about Java), in the same fashion as you could not know about LISPs but only about an implementation, such as clojure.</p>

<p>Also, clicks with the idea of &ldquo;code to interfaces, not implementations&rdquo;. Does it also click with you?</p>

<p>PS: What a great book this is. I&rsquo;m reading it as explained <a href="../../../../2015/04/25/how-i-read-apprenticeship-patterns/">here</a> <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>PPS: you can read it online for free, <a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000001813/">here</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>This post was extracted on 2015-04-25. The refactor techniques are very useful, not only for programming<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Should We Start the TDD Cycle on Refactor?]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/should-we-start-the-tdd-cycle-on-refactor/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-29T20:30:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/29/should-we-start-the-tdd-cycle-on-refactor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this lexical scope, TDD by example is referring to this book<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, available <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">on Amazon</a></p>

<h3>The TDD cycle</h3>

<p>Altough <a href="https://twitter.com/KentBeck">Kent Beck</a> in his book Test-Driven Development by example explains in &ldquo;Part I: the money example&rdquo;<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> that one should</p>

<blockquote><p>quickly add a test;</p>

<p>run all the tests and see the new one fail [&hellip;]</p>

<p><cite>Kent Beck </cite></p></blockquote>

<p>Implying that the TDD cycle starts with the red. Later on he explains that the cycle continues with green and refactor and back to red.</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;ve been hearing for a while that there&rsquo;re some useful refactors to be done before introducing new code. Rings in my head but the only example I have is Xavi Gost&rsquo;s &ldquo;La economía del refactoring<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>&rdquo;</p>

<h3>Refactoring</h3>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the definition of refactor (found <a href="http://www.refactoring.com/">here</a>):</p>

<blockquote><p>[Refactoring] is a disciplined technique for restructuring an existing body of code, altering its internal structure without changing its external behavior.</p>

<p> <cite>Martin Fowler</cite></p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;ve found some info on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1355101/test-code-refactor-when-should-we-start-a-refactoring">stackoverflow</a> about the subject. The currently <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/1355782">accepted answer</a> points out some interesting comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do not refactor on red. Always a good reminder</li>
<li>If you are refactoring for introducing a feature, how much refactor is enough? This is speculative development, possibly taking much time from needed development</li>
</ul>


<p>The last point is the one that interests me the most:</p>

<ul>
<li>Your refactoring might not be where you&rsquo;re going to introduce new production code<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> (spatial caché)</li>
<li>You might end up introducing features after a few hours/days of refactoring, therefore losing focus on the refactor you did and why (local caché)</li>
<li>Given that I&rsquo;ve already &ldquo;cleaned up&rdquo; this, I could also go somewhere else (slippery slope). Heard from <a href="https://twitter.com/xav1uzz">Xavi Gost</a> at the CAS2014 at his talk <a href="http://cas2014.agile-spain.org/sessions/sesion-1h-la-economia-del-refactoring-una-vision-desde-la-gestion-economica-del-proyecto-xavier-gost/">La economía del refactoring</a></li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>No está justificado hacer cambios fuera de la rebanada.</p></blockquote>

<p>Roughly translated to &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not justified to change outside the bread slice&rdquo;, as Xavi was referring to software as sliced bread instead of layers, vertical rather than horizontal</p>

<h3>Should you do it?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Doing it would be a good thing, as long as you know in advance what will be affected by the next feature.</li>
<li>It can allow for less refactoring at the end of the cycle. This is not about duplication but refactoring to patterns. There might be a gain in refactoring to a pattern before introducing another feature. An example might be adding a new strategy when it&rsquo;s currently coded as if-then-else</li>
<li>The last responsible moment might be before or after introducing the feature. You decide.</li>
<li>Work less as there&rsquo;s no need for adding new cases to old structures and then simplifying</li>
</ul>


<h3>Should you not do it?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Foreseeing the future is difficult, therefore you might end with unused development, as it is speculating</li>
<li>Related to the last point, you might end refactoring in the wrong places. There&rsquo;s no current business value to it.</li>
<li>Not useful on first round of a new feature, you can use a lambda transition to the red again. But then, this is not a general pattern, only applicable to a big percent of cases.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>Short answer: it mainly depends on your environment:</p>

<ul>
<li>You: experience, common sense (sadly) &mdash;another post coming&mdash;, benefit/time-wasted ratio</li>
<li>Your project: how tight are deadlines, how critical that code is, the team&rsquo;s pressure</li>
</ul>


<p>Long answer: Yes, as long as:
 1. You realize there is a fine line between fixing code and rewriting code (Egoless programming #4). Don&rsquo;t be a lone enforcer
 2. Strictly follow the boy scout rule but only around your campfire, not outside of it.
 1. You know your domain, pitfalls and team well
 1. You want to test this hypothesis and post an answer</p>

<h3>Sources</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://cas2014.agile-spain.org/sessions/sesion-1h-la-economia-del-refactoring-una-vision-desde-la-gestion-economica-del-proyecto-xavier-gost/">La economía del refactoring</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/xav1uzz">Xavi Gost</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Test-Driven-Development-By-Example/dp/0321146530">Test-Driven Development by example</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/KentBeck">Kent Beck</a></li>
<li><a href="http://refactoring.com">Refactoring.com</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/martinfowler">Martin Fowler</a></li>
</ul>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Test-Driven Development by example; Beck, K. (ISBN-13: 078-5342146530)<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>from the book, description of part I, before chapter I<a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>That talk is not yet available (AFAIK), but there&rsquo;s a <a href="http://ocana.github.io/articles/Conferencia-Agile-Spain-2014-primer-dia/">post</a> about it (Spanish)<a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>The &ldquo;pains&rdquo; you might feel before introducing new features might not be real<a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
