<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notification on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/notification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notification on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/notification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in March 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/03/01/self-study-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS logging made right Explains logging and tracing in nodejs.
Usage of thread-local storage, trace id, continuation local storage.
Tags: nodejs, logging, tracing, thread-local, thread-local-storage, trace-id, continuation-local-storage, cls, tls, proxy, hook
Id: 5bed4596-3f5b-11e9-83e1-0242ac110005 Read: Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:28:42 +0000
Web Design 3.0: When Your Web Design Really Matters In Chapter 1, we will find out how Web Design is changing. Also, you will learn about the birth of the new generation of web designers, who are designing web pages in Web Design 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in February 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/02/01/self-study-in-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>WhatsApp Security Vulnerability I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Bruce Schneier on a security defect in whatsapp, where an &amp;lsquo;unconfirmed&amp;rsquo; message can be re-encrypted (with a new key) and resent. This is a vector for some attacks.
Tags: bruce-schneier, security, whatsapp, encryption, attack-vector
Encrypted email service once used by Edward Snowden relaunches I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, by Kim Zetter, on Lavabit restablishing its service. Explains the company&amp;rsquo;s past and the new services they are offering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tool: Building a local pipeline</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 11:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/tool_building_local_pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Motivation At a client, one of the projects has a long building process and the tests are mostly slow, so I use a local building pipeline, an example of the Pipes and Filters pattern.
This allows for executing manually only the fast unit tests, then automatically (no user intervention, no time spent) executing the rest of them before pushing. In case the latter fails, it is possible to do git push -f to the pipeline without corrupting the central repository (origin) history, possibly disturbing others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What defines a dependency</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/what-defines-a-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 07:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/what-defines-a-dependency/</guid>
      <description>A friend and I were arguing about this code (fragment):
public void register (final String userName) { try { registeredUsers.add(new User(userName)); } catch (AlreadyRegisteredUserException e) { resultListener.alreadyRegistered(userName); } } I would have said that resultListener is a dependency as, first, it was injected by the constructor, second, it is necessary for the execution (negative case).
He suggested that:
 being injected through the constructor is usually what happens with dependencies, but does not make it one (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Peer Stereotypes</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/object-peer-stereotypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 07:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/13/object-peer-stereotypes/</guid>
      <description>We categorize an object&amp;rsquo;s peers (loosely) into three types of relationship. An object might have:
 Dependencies: Services that the object requires from its peers so it can perform its responsibilities. The object cannot function without these services. It should not be possible to create the object without them. For example, a graphics package will need something like a screen or canvas to draw on&amp;ndash;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense without one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
