<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data-structure on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/data-structure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data-structure on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/data-structure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2024</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2024/07/01/self-study-july-2024/</guid>
      <description>Managing projects with GNU Make, Third Edition book about GNU Make, with recipes and going into detail about how to use it
Tags: book, make, gnu-make, project, skeleton, ci, continuous-integration
Id: 028b0e1f-a181-4469-8789-900ce6641d97 Read: Sun, 01 Jul 2024 17:22:52 +0000
Diff-pdf: tool to visually compare two PDFs a tool to diff pdfs visually
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40854319
Tags: hackernews, imported, olshansky, testing, test, diff-pdf, pdf, diff, git, e2e-testing, end-to-end-testing, tool
Id: 4fc53bae-d81c-45b4-9f6b-995ec5d4df6a Read: Tue, 02 Jul 2024 07:26:08 +0000</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2022</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/08/01/self-study-august-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2022/08/01/self-study-august-2022/</guid>
      <description>A Tutorial on Portable Makefiles (2017) https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32303193
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a4860376-c1a0-11ed-ae57-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 07:43:01 2022
Software engineering books https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32305997
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a23a4924-c1a0-11ed-a585-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 13:57:25 2022
Show HN: Emery – Personal productivity workspace https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32312413
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a6dab644-c1a0-11ed-b024-0242ac110004 Read: Mon Aug 1 21:42:53 2022
Minify your container https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32334741
Tags: imported, hacker-news
Id: a94d30aa-c1a0-11ed-bb01-0242ac110004 Read: Wed Aug 3 17:42:44 2022
Against Discipline https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32340703</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in June 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/06/01/self-study-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t look, don&amp;rsquo;t tell I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla on what strategies companies use to deal with security and defects.
Explains full disclosure, responsible disclosure and bug bounties.
Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, security, full-disclosure, responsible-disclosure, bug-bounty, reporting, hacker, cracker
Id: a1a6925a-7958-11e8-a87f-0242ac110002 Read: Tue, 26 Jun 2018 15:50:21 +0000
La vida de las ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve read this bonilista by David Bonilla about the value of the ideas and what differentiates a good idea from a good execution from a good outcome</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/01/01/self-study-in-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>Translation from Haskell to JavaScript of selected portions of the best introduction to monads I’ve ever read I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by James Coglan, introducing monads.
About composability:
 The symmetry of the argument and return types is what makes these functions composable
 or
 symmetric input and output types
 Guide to basic monadic functions:
 lift, which converts a &amp;lsquo;simple’ function into a debuggable function bind, which converts a debuggable function into a composable form unit, which converts a simple value into the format required for debugging, by placing it in a container</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in October 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/10/01/self-study-in-october-2015/</guid>
      <description>Blazing Fast HTML: Virtual DOM in Elm I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article explaining how Elm works in relation to the virtual DOM. By Evan Czaplicki.
Tags: elm, dom, virtual-dom, comparison, speed, haskell, evan-czaplicki
Why you should never, ever, ever use MongoDB I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article stating the downsides of using MongoDB. Written by Sven Slootweg
Tags: mongodb, downside, sven-slootweg, json, document-store, postgresql, acid
Do you really get classloaders? I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video by Jevgeny Kabanov on classloaders: what they are, how they work nad some tips to solve common issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in September 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/self-study-in-september-2015/</guid>
      <description>The 30 second habit with a lifelong impact I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article list of patterns, by Robyn Scott, in which it is explained why to compress information in a few ideas, investing 30 seconds to condense the article.
Tags: 30-second, habit, robyn-scott
The Strengths and Weaknesses of Extreme Programming I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this video explaining the strengths and weaknesses of extreme programming. By William Matheson
Tags: extreme-programming, xp, william-matheson, video, strength, weakness</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in July 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/07/01/self-study-in-july-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from July 2015 into a single post
Clojure made simple I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this talk by Rich Hickey at the Java One. It references the talk Easy made simple
 polymorphism without inheritance; single dispatch on the first parameter  Productive pair programming I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about pair programming, using the driver &amp;amp; copilot technique, written by Carlos Blé
Building Automated REST APIs with Python Investigating QA automation for REST APIs, I&amp;rsquo;ve read these slides about it</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
