<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Q4 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Q4 on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/q4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2020Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2020/12/30/books-read-2020q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 12 rules for life; Peterson; own-it, non-technical, philosophy  12 rules for life The book contains some rules, some principles to remove doubt and uncertainty from life.
There are plenty of mentions to the Bible, although I consider the book to the secular in its contents.
There are few personal stories on the book (e.g., about his daughter Mikhaila Peterson), which makes it readable and enjoyable. The philosophy behind it is sometimes not-politically-correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2019Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/12/30/books-read-2019q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
 Tao of Séneca (vol 2); edited by Ferriss; own-it, non-technical, philoshopy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2018Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/12/31/books-read-2018q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) Oliver Twist; Dickens Building evolutionary architecture; Ford, Parsons Selfie: How We Became So Self-Obsessed and What It’s Doing To Us; Storr. Just chapter 1: The dying self Sota la cistella; Gasol  Como ganar amigos e influir sobre las personas; Carnegie (+) I&amp;rsquo;ve re-read this classic book (How to win friends and influence people), by Carnegie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2017Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/12/31/books-read-2017q4/</guid>
      <description>Read this quarter:
Note: re+read means I&amp;rsquo;m re-reading this book. The (+) stands for one-or-more times, as in the regexes.
 Lazarillo de Tormes, el; anónimo; non-technical Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s power plays - Politika; Preisler; own-it, non-technical Moon is a harsh mistress, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Old man&amp;rsquo;s war; Scalzi; non-technical, own-it Nightfall; Asimov, Silverberg; own-it, non-technical Interface; Stephenson, George; non-technical, own-it Man who sold the moon, the; Heinlein; own-it, non-technical Agents of innocence; Ignatius; own-it, non-technical Fist of god, the; Forsyth; own-it, non-technical: Synopsis: in a mixture of truth and novel, the author explains the invasion of Kuwait by Iraqi dictator Sadam Hussein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2016Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/books-read-in-2016q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/books-read-in-2016q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Functional Programming in Scala, by Chiusano and Bjarnason. Doing the exercises with the codurance team Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, Hofstadter  Books I want to finish. Usually come from another quarter:
Books that have entered the queue:
Non-technical that have entered the queue:
 La psicología del dinero, Hammond Invirtiendo a largo plazo, García Paramés Quién domina el mundo, Chomsky Homenaje a Cataluña, Orwell El camino al 18J, Payne Cartas desde la revolución bolchevique, Sadoul Shogun: The Life of Tokugawa Ieyasu, Sadler Els jueus i Catalunya, Villatoro Russell en 90 minutos, Strathern El problema de los tres cuerpos, Liu    The ending date of the quarter is the same as the publication date &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2015Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/books-read-in-2015q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/31/books-read-in-2015q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter1:
 Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby, An Agile Primer (POODR) by Sandi Metz, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;. Blog posts under the tag poodr.  Books started, not yet finished (WIP):
 Haskell Programming, By Chris Allen and Julie Moronuki. This book is still in progress and I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing it Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware by Andy Hunt Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs by Abelson, Sussman, and Sussman, with the &amp;lsquo;@deAprendices&amp;rsquo;s reading club&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2014Q4</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/31/books-read-in-2014q4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 12:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2014/12/31/books-read-in-2014q4/</guid>
      <description>Books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this quarter Q4 on 2014, as inspired by Manuel, on this post:
 ATDD by Example: A Practical Guide to Acceptance Test-Driven Development by Markus Gärtner Head First Design Patterns by Eric Freeman, Elisabeth Robson, Bert Bates, Kathy Sierra Apprenticeship Patterns, Guidance for the Aspiring Software Craftsman by Dave Hoover, Adewale Oshineye Diseño ágil con TDD, by Carlos Blé Jurado; again The Mythical Man-Month, Anniversary Edition: Essays On Software Engineering by Frederick P.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
