<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles-rsses on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles-rsses on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 17:58:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Support for out of hours on-call support</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2016/10/05/support-for-out-of-hours-on-call-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 17:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2016/10/05/support-for-out-of-hours-on-call-support/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As the preface for the guide for on-call support, a positive note:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;readme&#34;&gt;README&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re cool. I know it. Do not trust yourself, trust me that I trust you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might be sleepy. It’s OK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is going to be fine. Take 5 minutes to think about anything, anytime. Especially before any rash decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With great power comes great responsibility. Use it wisely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restoring the services comes first, investigation comes second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the very minimum of investigation after the incident (collect things that might disappear), leave the rest for the next day on office hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever everything is done, go to sleep but keep an eye on your phone. Someone will contact if necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dhatanian&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;David Hatanian&lt;/a&gt; and another colleague for the feedback on this draft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring functional code</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2016/09/28/refactoring-functional-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 20:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2016/09/28/refactoring-functional-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With my pairing mate we have refactored this piece of functional code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original code:&lt;/p&gt;
function filterTokens (rawTokens) {
  const cleanedTokens = rawTokens.map(token =&gt; (token.length &amp;&amp; token[0] === &#39;-&#39;) ? token.substring(1) : token)
  return cleanedTokens.filter(token =&gt; token !== &#39;&#39; &amp;&amp; stopWordsArray.indexOf(token) === -1)
}

&lt;p&gt;Refactored code:&lt;/p&gt;
function filterTokens (rawTokens) {
  const cleanedTokens = rawTokens.map(token =&gt; startsWithADash(token) ? removeDashFrom(token) : token)
  const processedTokens = cleanedTokens.filter(token =&gt; isNotEmpty(token) &amp;&amp; isNotAStopWord(token))
  return processedTokens

  function startsWithADash (token) {
    return (token.length &amp;&amp; token[ 0 ] === &#39;-&#39;)
  }

  function removeDashFrom (token) {
    return token.substring(1)
  }

  function isNotAStopWord (token) {
    return stopWordsArray.indexOf(token) === -1
  }

  function isNotEmpty (token) {
    return token !== &#39;&#39;
  }
 }

&lt;p&gt;These two codes do the same, but the second reads better, given that each small concept (e.g., &lt;code&gt;cleanedTokens&lt;/code&gt;) or operation (e.g., &lt;code&gt;removeDashFrom&lt;/code&gt;) has a name. Even the returned value, usually &lt;code&gt;result&lt;/code&gt;, has an appropiate name. The machine will optimize that variable assignment to a variable but the human reader will dig deeper only if required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing functional code should not be an excuse to forget about clean code. The two are independent variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have found that the second reads better than the first one, but we have reached this conclusion because we have similar values and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Joys of the Craft as Article</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft-as-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 22:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/articles/2014/12/15/the-joys-of-the-craft-as-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quoting the book,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is programming fun? What delights may its practitioner expect as his reward?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First is the sheer joy of making things. As the child delights in his mud pie, so the adult enjoys building things, especially things of his own design [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second is the pleasure of making things that are useful to other people. Deep within, we want other to use our work and to find it helpful. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third is the fascination of fashioning complex puzzle-like objects of interlocking moving parts and watching them work in subtle cycles, playing out the consequences of principles built in from the beginning. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth is the joy of always learning, which springs from the nonrepeating nature of the task. In one way or another the problem is ever new, and its solver learns something: sometimes practical, sometimes theoretical, and sometimes both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is the delight of working in such a tractable medium. The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from the pure thought-stuff. He builds his castles in the air, from air, creating by exertion of the imagination. Few media of creating are so flexible, so easy to polish and rework, so readily capable of realizing grand conceptual structures. (As we shall see later, this very tractability has its own problems.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Frederick P. Brooks, Jr&lt;/cite&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Mythical-Man-Month-Engineering-Anniversary/dp/0201835959&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Mythical Man-Month&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jmbeas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;J.M. Beas&lt;/a&gt; did an awesome take on this subject on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jmbeas.es/2010/11/01/por-que-programar-es-divertido/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;his blog&lt;/a&gt; (Spanish)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>