<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: March | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/march/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-16T10:57:15+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in March 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-02T10:58:19+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/self-study-in-march-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Learning Programming Isn’t That Hard, Deep Work Is Hard</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@benedictfritz/learning-programming-isn-t-that-hard-deep-work-is-hard-40a4cf3104f4">this article</a> by Benedict Fritz on two types of work (i.e., deep and shallow) and how programming is of the deep type. He links the difficulty of learning to program to the difficulty of practicing deep work.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, benedict-fritz, deep-work, shallow-work, learn-to-program, psychology</p>

<h2>BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing">this category of posts</a> by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</p>

<p>Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc</p>

<p>Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis</p>

<h2>BeCodeWeek by Yeray Darias</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://developerscookbook.blogspot.com.es/search/label/desk-surfing">this category of posts</a> by Yeray Darias about his BeCodeWeek, a desk-surfing experience at BeCode.</p>

<p>Publishes one entry per day detailing his activities: working for an open-source library, discussions, etc</p>

<p>Tags: becodeweek, yeray-darias, desk-surfing, experience, experience-report, analysis</p>

<h2>Tracer Bullets</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?TracerBullets">this page</a> about tracer bullets, an analogy from the military warfare to a software project.</p>

<p>Serves the purpose of adjusting the aim of the cannon to better reach the target.</p>

<p>Tags: analogy, metaphor, warfare, management</p>

<h2>Cohesion - the cornerstone of software design</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://codurance.com/2016/03/03/cohesion-cornerstone-software-design/">this article</a> by Sandro Mancuso on the topic of cohesion. Describes the 7 types of cohesion, as described in Structured Design<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup>, from worst to best:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coincidental cohesion</li>
<li>Logical cohesion</li>
<li>Temporal cohesion</li>
<li>Procedural cohesion</li>
<li>Communicational/informational cohesion</li>
<li>Sequential cohesion</li>
<li>Functional cohesion</li>
</ul>


<p>and about Design-Level Cohesion:</p>

<ul>
<li>Coincidental relation (R1)</li>
<li>Conditional relation (R2)</li>
<li>Iterative relation (R3)</li>
<li>Communication relation (R4)</li>
<li>Sequential relation (R5)</li>
<li>Functional (R6)</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: cohesion, codurance, edward-yourdon, larry-constantine, list, sandro-mancuso, software-design, design-level-cohesion, smc-cohesion, dlc-cohesion</p>

<h2>Etsy CTO Q&amp;A: We Need Software Engineers, Not Developers</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://thenewstack.io/etsy-cto-qa-need-software-engineers-not-developers/">this interview</a> with John Allspaw, where they explain the onboarding experience for new hires at Etsy, the DevOps philosophy and the need for engineering skills, more than developer skills. This can be exemplified in the need to know more, defining the boundaries of your job and finding the right tool for the job.</p>

<p>Tags: devops, interview, q-and-a, john-allspaw, etsy, onboarding, hire, team-management, deploy</p>

<h2>Frequency Reduces Difficulty</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/FrequencyReducesDifficulty.html">this article</a> by Martin Fowler on why we should repeat things that are difficult for us:</p>

<ul>
<li>Perfectioning the technique</li>
<li>Internalizing the details</li>
<li>Easing its automation</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: martin-fowler, automation, process, perfection, internalizing, technique, detail, process-theory, agile</p>

<h2>Lambdas are confusing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched this video where Coman Hamilton from JAXenter interviews Dr. Heinz Kabutz about Java&rsquo;s lambda syntax. Cites the problem with exceptions, generics, method overloading.</p>

<p>Tags: java, lambda, coman-hamilton, jaxenter, heinz-kabutz, problem</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;feature=youtu.be">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcHom1eVhi4&amp;feature=youtu.be</a></p>

<h2>El full-stack developer en 2016</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.developerdepueblo.com/development/full-stack-developer-2016/">this article</a> by Jose Ignacio Andrés about the job descriptions of 2016.</p>

<blockquote><p>El principal valor de un full-stack es poder simplificar el trabajo a los demás miembros del equipo.</p></blockquote>

<p>My translation:</p>

<blockquote><p>The main value of a full-stack developer is to be able to simplify other teammates' work</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: teamwork, teammate, fullstack, simplification, work, team-management, jose andres</p>

<h2>I am a software craftsman</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.dirv.me/i-am-a-software-craftsman/index.html">this article</a> by Daniel Irvine about calling yourself a craftsman or not. He says that if you adhere to their values, you should.</p>

<p>Tags: craftsmanship, label, daniel-irvine, craftsman, group-belonging</p>

<h2>Teaching Programming Languages in a Post-Linnaean Age</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://cs.brown.edu/~sk/Publications/Papers/Published/sk-teach-pl-post-linnaean/paper.pdf">this paper</a> by Shriram Krishnamurthi where he explains the need for books like <a href="http://www.plai.org/">PLAI</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>lack of paradigms in new languages, and its separation (or lack of)</li>
<li>design of languages cheaper and cheaper these days</li>
<li>rigor level in publications</li>
<li>inductive and deductive learning</li>
</ul>


<h2>Notes</h2>

<p><code>post-Linnaean</code> refers to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Linnaeus">Carl Linnaeus</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>He is known as the father of modern taxonomy</p></blockquote>

<p>Tags: inductive-learning, deductive-learning, dsl, domain-specific-language, type-soundness, continuation-style, garbage-collection, reactive-programming, scheme, plai, teaching, programming-language, shriram-krishnamurthi</p>

<h2>Lazy Ruby</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://sonnym.github.io/2014/04/05/lazy-ruby/">this article</a> by sonnym about using ruby&rsquo;s lazy (non-strict) features, detailing an example with Fibonacci&rsquo;s sequence.</p>

<p>Tags: laziness, strictness, non-strictness, ruby, fibonacci, comparison</p>

<h2>Jessica Livingston</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://paulgraham.com/jessica.html">this essay</a> by Paul Graham about his co-founder at the Y-combinator: Jessica Livingston. She was considered the Social Radar at YC</p>

<p>The essay also talks about the non-existent separation between working hours and not and about her implication and personality.</p>

<p>Tags: jessica-livingston, paul-graham, y-combinator, feminism, yc, essay</p>

<h2>Four Laws Of Software Economics (Part 1)</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://medium.com/@RichMironov/four-laws-of-software-economics-part-1-e162aa0ea9e5">this article</a> by Rich Mironov on why the development team will never be big enough (because of economics, because there are more things to be done than time to do them, so we have to prioritize them) and about the communication problems between the dev team and the client(s).</p>

<p>Also talks about the general personality of clients and devs and task prioritization</p>

<p>Tags: exclusive-or, magical-thinking, tnstaafl, management, agile, team, capacity, death-march, estj, intp, software-economics, product-strategy, law-of-ruthless-prioritization, law, rich-mironov, slack, myers-briggs-type</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Structured Design: Fundamentals of a Discipline of Computer Program and Systems Design by Yourdon and Constantine.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
