<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/uuid/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/uuid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-haskell-pyramid-https-patrickmn-com-software-the-haskell-pyramid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://patrickmn.com/software/the-haskell-pyramid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Haskell Pyramid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;el-verde-más-verde-https-mailchi-mp-bonillaware-verde-mas-verde-e-68e22b460d&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/bonillaware/verde-mas-verde?e=68e22b460d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;El verde más verde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: david-bonilla, bonilista, project-management, slack-time, sabbatical, vertical-slice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ef00176e-7ddc-11e8-a33b-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 09:47:29 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer-https-dev-to-lewismenelaws-how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer-4opl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/lewismenelaws/how-to-fix-burnout-as-a-developer--4opl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Fix Burnout as a Developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on burnout and how to fix it:
Stop working so much.
Prioritize your health.
Try something new.
Patience is key.
Talk to your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: lewis-menelaws, burnout, burn-out, productivity, listicle, career, psychology, management, time-management, career-management, health&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 40d68542-7dff-11e8-89f2-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 13:53:09 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-hn-what-is-the-first-thing-you-implement-at-a-new-company-https-news-ycombinator-com-item-id-17353854&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17353854&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask HN: What is the first thing you implement at a new company?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the first things that people do when joining a new client.
Mentions the Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence: You don’t want to change something until you understand why it’s there in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chesterton-fence, hacker-news, contractor, client, onboarding, fix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 9003a91a-7dff-11e8-a366-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 13:55:22 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fallacy-of-chesterton-s-fence-https-abovethelaw-com-2014-01-the-fallacy-of-chestertons-fence&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://abovethelaw.com/2014/01/the-fallacy-of-chestertons-fence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Fallacy Of Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s Fence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on the Chesterton&amp;rsquo;s fence.
&amp;gt; don’t ever take a fence down until you know the reason why it was put up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author explains that the walls (or contracts, or clauses, or practices) were put in place to cover for a specific need. Do not assume that this need does not exist now, before understanding what the need was in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: chesterton-fence, keith-lee, consulting, tip, analogy, discovery, process, people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 736e269e-7e00-11e8-ac4a-0242ac110003
Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 14:01:43 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-the-uuid-https-segment-com-blog-a-brief-history-of-the-uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-uuid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A brief history of the UUID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief history of UUID: of how it was developed, why, and a new library in go called ksuid
Explains the origins of networked computers (as opposed to personal computers without any networking) in the 1980s.
Also explains the origins of the UUID, some algorithms for generating them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: ksuid, uuid, golang, go, rick-branson, history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: c20e6ac4-8fe5-11e8-b54e-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:36:00 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivering-billions-of-messages-exactly-once-https-segment-com-blog-exactly-once-delivery&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/exactly-once-delivery/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Delivering billions of messages exactly once&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains how this company (segment) has solved the problem of delivering the messages once and only once (OAOO), using RocksDB, Kafka, UUIDs. Deployed to AWS, lowers the cost of the previous system (memcached-based).
Impressive numbers: 1.5 TB worth of keys stored on disk in RocksDB
a 4-week window of de-duplication before aging out old keys
approximately 60B keys stored inside our RocksDB instances
200B messages passed through the dedupe system
Also explains in depth how RocksDB works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: rocksdb, facebook, database, once-and-only-once, oaoo, message, exactly-once-delivery, delivery, message-delivery, kafka, uuid, client, aws, segment, topic, cloud-scale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: 962c0c26-8fe6-11e8-bf2c-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:41:55 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;object-collaboration-stereotypes-http-www-mockobjects-com-2006-10-different-kinds-of-collaborators-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mockobjects.com/2006/10/different-kinds-of-collaborators.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Object Collaboration Stereotypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post describes the relationships between two objects:
Dependencies are services that the object needs from its environment so that it can fulfil its responsibilities.
Notifications are other parts of the system that need to know when the object changes state or performs an action.
Policies are objects that tweak or adapt the object&amp;rsquo;s behaviour to the needs of the system.
Parts are components in the implementation that are not controlled from outside the object after being set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dependency, notification, policy, part, collaborator, relationship, steve-freeman, goos, growing-object-oriented-software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: f7e738c8-8fe6-11e8-89be-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 08:44:39 +0000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mocks-fakes-stubs-and-dummies-http-xunitpatterns-com-mocks-20fakes-20stubs-20and-20dummies-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xunitpatterns.com/Mocks,%20Fakes,%20Stubs%20and%20Dummies.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mocks, Fakes, Stubs and Dummies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bibliography for mocks, stubs, fakes, dummies, spies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: mock, stub, test-double, dummy, xunit, xunit-pattern, gerard-meszaros, xunitpatterns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Id: ea7281ee-9012-11e8-bd95-0242ac110003
Read: Wed, 25 Jul 2018 13:59:15 +0000&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-the-uuid-https-segment-com-blog-a-brief-history-of-the-uuid&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://segment.com/blog/a-brief-history-of-the-uuid/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Brief History of the UUID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rick Branson on the history of UUID.
Describes the history of uid, uuid, early computing (both networked and not networked) and their own implementation of a uuid library&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: uuid, uid, flake, snowflake, ksuid, go, golang, rick-branson, library, implementation-history&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-data-more-data-https-blog-cloudflare-com-more-data-more-data&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cloudflare.com/more-data-more-data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More data, more data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how cloudflare manages its logs. By Hunter Blanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: log, cloudflare, comparison, what-worked, what-did-not-work, kafka, citusdb, sre, site-reliability-engineering, analytics, hunter-blanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no-https-hbr-org-2017-06-help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2017/06/help-your-team-stop-overcommitting-by-empowering-them-to-say-no&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Help Your Team Stop Overcommitting by Empowering Them to Say No&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article that describes how important is to say no to some ideas or projects so you can say yes to others.
In other words, how prioritizing is important as time and energy (i.e., resources) are not infinite and must be allocated accordingly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: diana-kander, hbr, harvard-business-review, priority, energy, resources, time, pet-project, yes-people, no-people, yes-culture, no-culture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology-http-ben-evans-com-benedictevans-2017-5-24-not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2017/5/24/not-even-wrong-ways-to-dismiss-technology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Not even wrong - ways to dismiss technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how technology can be seen as toys before it is developed to the point where it can be expanded and used for other purposes than the one expected / designed for. By Benedict Evans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: benedict-evans, technology, prediction, usage, invention, philosophy, wolfgang-pauli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-we-have-a-better-option-here-https-softwaremill-com-do-we-have-better-option-here&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwaremill.com/do-we-have-better-option-here/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Do we have a better Option here?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article comparing &lt;code&gt;Option&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Optional&lt;/code&gt; as types that can contain a value, but maybe not. By Michał Chmielarz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: michal-chmielarz, option, optional, vavr, javaslang, comparison&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-the-keyboard-faster-than-the-mouse-http-danluu-com-keyboard-v-mouse&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://danluu.com/keyboard-v-mouse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Is the keyboard faster than the mouse?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Dan Luu comparing the use of the mouse and the use of the keyboard and their speeds.
He groups existing literature on the topic plus some experiments he has done himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentions the amount of myths related to this, based on old and non-accurate research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: dan-luu, keyboard, comparison, mouse, human-interaction-device, hid, interaction, user-experience, interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-crypto-anarchist-manifesto-http-groups-csail-mit-edu-mac-classes-6-805-articles-crypto-cypherpunks-may-crypto-manifesto-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/mac/classes/6.805/articles/crypto/cypherpunks/may-crypto-manifesto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Crypto Anarchist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Timothy C. May forecasting the development of a new market based on cryptography and secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same that barbed wire transformed property in the West, is the analogy he uses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: timothy-may, anarchy, encryption, market, forecast, crypto-anarchism, public-key-encryption, zero-knowledge-proof, cryptography&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>