<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uuid on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/uuid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in uuid on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/uuid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On private but leaked information in a SaaS</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/11/04/private-leaked-information-saas/</guid>
      <description>This is another tool for your toolbox: how to uncorrelate public and private information.
Context Context: there are clients who have sensitive information. Some is just &amp;lsquo;companies being stealth&amp;rsquo; (e.g., don&amp;rsquo;t want to make public until launching), some is just protected by a Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA), some are protected by security clearance. The more sensitive, the greater protection needed. This tool applies to all sensitive information, regardless of where it&amp;rsquo;s stored or how it is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2018</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2018/07/01/self-study-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The Haskell Pyramid I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how the productivity for Haskell is achieved: not using the topics discussed on social networks (monads, functors, laws, lenses, etc) but using more basic tools
Tags: haskell, productivity, lucas-di-cioccio, learning, development, tool, monad, hype, pyramid, productive-haskell-bar, bar
Id: 454f53fc-7dd6-11e8-8208-0242ac110003 Read: Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:59:47 +0000
El verde más verde I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on how to structure creative projects (e.g., UX, programming) by professionals, as told by David Bonilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in July 2017</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/01/self-study-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>A Brief History of the UUID I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by Rick Branson on the history of UUID. Describes the history of uid, uuid, early computing (both networked and not networked) and their own implementation of a uuid library
Tags: uuid, uid, flake, snowflake, ksuid, go, golang, rick-branson, library, implementation-history
More data, more data I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about how cloudflare manages its logs. By Hunter Blanks
Tags: log, cloudflare, comparison, what-worked, what-did-not-work, kafka, citusdb, sre, site-reliability-engineering, analytics, hunter-blanks</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
