<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meetup on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meetup on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in August 2019</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 10:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2019/08/01/self-study-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>List the local NPM link packages npm ls -g &amp;ndash;depth=0 &amp;ndash;link=true
Tags: npm, npm-link, node, link, global-dependency
Id: c01a0efa-b832-11e9-87be-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:12:52 +0000
Mutation testing tool for java / jvm This is a mutation testing tool for the JVM / java
Tags: pitest, pit, mutation-testing, testing, test, tool, jvm, java, mutation
Id: 02d29d3e-b833-11e9-b785-0242ac110003 Read: Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:14:44 +0000
Ugly trivia kata, using mutation testing This is a kata I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced, then shown at the Software Crafters meetup (at Softonic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Agile Barcelona Open Space</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/notes-agile-open-space-barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 18:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/05/07/notes-agile-open-space-barcelona/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I attended an Agile Barcelona open space at Netmind
Format On arrival, attendees where welcomed by an Agile Coffee.
At 10:00, the introduction started: a warm welcome to everyone, including first-time attendees to an open space, explaining what it is, the few rules and laws and making sure everyone had fun. Some time later, the marketplace happened and everyone presented their sessions. A curious thing to see was the effect of a session that everyone wanted to attend (dubbed a &amp;lsquo;black hole&amp;rsquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup cross-pollination</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/25/meetup-cross-pollination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 23:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/25/meetup-cross-pollination/</guid>
      <description>Adrian Bolboaca has written a very interesting post on being a community bumble-bee. (Source can be found here)
He goes on to explain how he has visited many meetups all over Europe and the big chunk of information and experience he has learned from them.
He tells us about a selfish approach to organizing meetups:
 When one teaches two learn
(apparently attributed to) Robert Heinlein, source
 I share this feeling of learning while teaching, as long as you reflect and analyze (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TDD Meetup Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 05:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/16/tdd-meetup-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we organized a TDD meetup at the FIB - Barcelona School of Informatics UPC, within Barcelona Software Craftsmanship sponsored by the Junior Empresa d&amp;rsquo;Informàtica. The meetup started at 9:00 until 18:00, with a one-hour pause in the middle.
Where  Please make sure the meetup space (e.g., classroom, meeting room) is available and ready to be used at least 15 minutes before the meetup starts The organizer and the event host should be there in advance to prepare the physical environment (chairs, wifi, beamer, etc) as well as mentally: getting comfortable with the space, loading the presentation, prepare the speaker notes, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven module Base for cucumber in java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 07:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve built a small maven module, to be used directly with cucumber. You can fork the repository here
This is the setup I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed for the meetup &amp;ldquo;BDD Cucumber kata (gherkin + code)&amp;quot;. Will see if this code is successfully used by the ~40 participants in a couple of weeks
(Quote from the README.md):
This maven project has been possible due to Thomas Sundberg and this post
Should you want to, there&amp;rsquo;s a tweet to thank him the effort: [tweet intent here](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
