<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Read | The long way through Software Craftsmanship]]></title>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/categories/read/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-10T01:18:11+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[alvaro garcia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Study in August 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-02T21:45:19+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/08/02/self-study-in-august-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>

<h2>Humble Object</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read the <a href="http://xunitpatterns.com/Humble%20Object.html">Humble Object</a> list of patterns, by Gerard Meszaros, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>humble dialog</li>
<li>humble executable</li>
<li>humble transaction controller</li>
<li>humble container adapter</li>
</ul>


<p>Tags: pattern, gerard-meszaros</p>

<h2>How you know</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve reread <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/know.html">this small essay</a> by Paul Graham on storing information in our heads, based on the context. On the importance of rereading, to add more contexts to the initial one.</p>

<p>Tags: paul-graham, reread, read</p>

<h2>Protected Variation: The Importance of Being Closed</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.martinfowler.com/ieeeSoftware/protectedVariation.pdf">this article</a> by Craig Larman in the magazine IEEE Software > Design.</p>

<p>Discusses Information Hiding, Protected Variation and the Open-Closed Principle.</p>

<p>Tags: craig-larman, ocp, open-closed principle, design, information-hiding, ih, protected-variation, pv,</p>

<h2>Lambda, Javascript Micro-Services on AWS</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.jayway.com/2014/12/18/lambda-javascript-micro-services-aws/">this post</a> explaining how to deploy a microservice on AWS on top of Lambda. Written by Anders Janmyr</p>

<p>The cool thing is that you get billed by milliseconds!</p>

<p>Tags: anders-janmyr, devops, microservice, lambda, aws</p>

<h2>Migrating To Clojure. So Much Fn</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hv4slaRydRM">this talk</a> by Jan Stępień where he talks about his experience on migrating part of an application to clojure from ruby on rails</p>

<p>Tags: jan-stepien, clojure, migration, ruby-on-rails, talk, wrocloverb</p>

<h2>Te recomiendo escribir en un blog</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.carlosble.com/2015/07/te-recomiendo-escribir-en-un-blog/">this article</a> from Carlos Blé in which he recommends writing a blog, on things we discover along the way. (Spanish)</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-ble, meta, blog, long-way</p>

<h2>We need enough technical debt</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.svpino.com/2015/08/05/we-need-enough-technical-debt">this article</a> on why we need to accumulate a bit of technical debt, as a way of being less perfectionist and deliver more features / value to our stakeholders. Written by Santiago L. Valdarrama.</p>

<p>Tags: santiago-valdarrama, technical-debt, perfectionism</p>

<h2>Escribe mejores tests en Javascript</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://carlosvillu.com/escribe-mejores-tests-en-javascript/">this list</a> of tips to write better javascript tests (Spanish). By Carlos Villuendas</p>

<p>Tags: carlos-villuendas, javascript, test</p>

<h2>Down the Rabbit Hole</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://github.com/brettwooldridge/HikariCP/wiki/Down-the-Rabbit-Hole">this wiki</a> page on how to tune some aspects of the server hotspot JVM, by Brett Wooldridge</p>

<p>Tags: performance, jvm, hotspot, inline, bytecode, brett-wooldridge</p>

<h2>XP Manchester Lightning Talks 2015 Live broadcast</h2>

<p>I have watched the first two <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VD4UEW2i7hU">lightning talks</a> from XP Manchester, edition number 61.</p>

<p>Tags: lightning-talk, broadcast, simplicity, manchester, 2015</p>

<h2>Counting hash collisions with the birthday paradox</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/counting-hash-collisions/">this article</a> on the birthday paradox, or the percentage of chance of people sharing the same birthday. This could be applied to hash function, as the title says, but is not included in the article. Written by Matt Might</p>

<h2>The Key to Giving and Receiving Negative Feedback</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://hbr.org/2015/08/the-key-to-giving-and-receiving-negative-feedback?">this article</a> by Joseph Grenny about how to give and receive negative feedback. It is exemplified by the plant manager who was expecting another kind of feedback from his subordinates and was surprised by their negative feedback.</p>

<p>Tags: joseph-grenny, negative-feedback, feedback, by-example</p>

<h2>Testing Clojure web applications with Kerodon</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://semaphoreci.com/community/tutorials/testing-clojure-web-applications-with-kerodon">this guide</a> on how to test compojure-based applications with kerodon. Written by Nebojša Stričević</p>

<p>Tags: nebojsa-stricevic, compojure, kerodon, clojure, testing, guide</p>

<h2>Using The Option Type Effectively</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uku-taht/2015/04/29/using-the-option-type-effectively.html">this article</a> on how to use the <code>Option</code> type (in rust), similar to <code>Optional</code> in java or <code>Maybe</code> in haskell. Written by Uku Taht.</p>

<p>Tags: uku-taht, option, maybe, optional, rust</p>

<h2>When Should You Think?</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://blog.8thlight.com/uncle-bob/2014/03/11/when-to-think.html">this post</a> by Robert C Martin on when to think and the hypothesis that TDD does not allow you to think before coding.</p>

<p>Tags: tdd, robert-c-martin, design, hypothesis</p>

<h2>Orthogonal latin squares: an application of experiment design to compiler testing</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://barbie.uta.edu/~mehra/20_an%20application%20of%20experiment%20design%20to%20compiler%20testing.pdf">this paper</a> by Robert Mandl on techniques that can be applied to reduce the burden of exhaustive testing to compilers. Preferring &ldquo;surely all relevant distinct combinations&rdquo; we can reduce the amount of testing. This paper tries to formalize the concept of &ldquo;near-exhaustive testing&rdquo;</p>

<p>Tags: latin-square, robert-mandl, compiler, testing, near-exhaustive-testing, optimization, exhaustive-testing</p>

<h2>  Practical Type System Benefits</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="https://themonadreader.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/nccb.pdf">this article</a> by Neil Brown on benefits of the type system, with examples in haskell. He goes on to explore the benefits of involving the type-checker at compile time to remove type errors and ease the programming effort:</p>

<blockquote><p>I find that several problems in Haskell can be solved by involving the type system
further: The trick is to involve the type system in ways that provide a big benefit
for the cost, but not going so far that the type system gets in the way of code
that you know &ndash;but can’t easily prove to the compiler&ndash; is safe</p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also learned the concept of the quasi-quoter: similar to a preprocessor, executed at compile time and type-checked</p>

<p>Tags: neil-brown, quote, quasi-quoter, preprocessor, haskell, monad-reader</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
