<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ron-jeffries on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/ron-jeffries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ron-jeffries on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/ron-jeffries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Software Development: Part I</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/nature-software-development-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/nature-software-development-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The Nature of Software development: reading breadcrumbs, quotes, thoughts Preface  The Natural Way serves end users well because it delivers value to them sooner.
serves the business [&amp;hellip;] because it provides important information quickly, and because it provides the ability to adjust direction as needed.
serves management [&amp;hellip;] see what’s really going on inside the project so that when action is needed, there will be time to act. And it reduces management’s problems by making information visible [&amp;hellip;]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Search for Value (a quote)</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/search-for-value-quote-chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2017/07/09/search-for-value-quote-chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>A quote from the book The Nature of Software Development by Ron Jeffries, talking about value (in software) and the building blocks to achieve it:
 Value. Value, we’ll see, is “what you want.” [&amp;hellip;]
We’ll tell the story by building up from the bottom of the pyramid, describing how to guide, organize, plan, and build our product, in small slices, with a focus on quality. The value we produce is based on these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in May 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/05/09/self-study-in-may-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from May 2015 into a single post
Programmer passion considered harmful I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on why programmer passion could be negative. The title is similar to a paper by Dijkstra.
Software Craftsmanship: Are Bootcamps Enough? I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article on software craftsmanship, development bootcamps and passion by Ken Auer
Improve your development environments with virtualization I have seen this video: Improve your development environments with virtualization by Luke Sneeringer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
