<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bdd on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</title>
    <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/bdd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bdd on The long way through Software Craftsmanship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/categories/bdd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in January 2016</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2016/01/01/self-study-in-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>Test cases in inner classes with JUnit I&amp;rsquo;ve read this answer in stackoverflow about nested test runners in JUnit
Tags: junit, stackoverflow, answer, nested-runner
Recording a Great Coding Screencast I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article by John Lindquist where he explains how he sets up the recording environment for egghead.
Tags: john-lindquist, record, screencast, egghead, code-screencast, record-video, video
React Testing Course I&amp;rsquo;ve watched the full course by Trevor D. Miller on how to test react components and the libraries to make it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Study in December 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/12/02/self-study-in-december-2015/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Equality And Object Comparison I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article, written by Alan Skorkin, that explains equality comparisons in ruby:
 equal? is reference equality == is value equality eql? is value and type equality  Tags: ruby, comparison, equality, object, reference, alan-skorkin
Software Folklore I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this PechaKucha by Chris Ford on what are laws and how they relate to creating software. Also talks on what could be an analogy to software creation (says not science, not engineering)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-study in June 2015</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/06/03/self-study-in-june-2015/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve grouped all small posts related to the self-study from June 2015 into a single post
Le monitoring de flux par l’exemple I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about monitoring, in the way of &amp;ldquo;by example&amp;rdquo;, by Cédrick Lunven and Julien Kirch (French)
The First Micro-service Architecture I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about microservices and how they were implemented many years ago by Robert C. Martin
How I Learned to Balance My Life With Remote Work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this article about balancing life and work, either physical or remote by Michael Erasmus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven module Base for cucumber in java</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 07:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/03/10/maven-module-base-for-cucumber-in-java/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve built a small maven module, to be used directly with cucumber. You can fork the repository here
This is the setup I&amp;rsquo;ve proposed for the meetup &amp;ldquo;BDD Cucumber kata (gherkin + code)&amp;quot;. Will see if this code is successfully used by the ~40 participants in a couple of weeks
(Quote from the README.md):
This maven project has been possible due to Thomas Sundberg and this post
Should you want to, there&amp;rsquo;s a tweet to thank him the effort: [tweet intent here](https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open discussion: Behaviour-Driven Development</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/15/open-discussion-behaviour-driven-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 02:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/15/open-discussion-behaviour-driven-development/</guid>
      <description>This week we had a great discussion about Behavior Driven Development (BDD). We have explained it as a way of developing software based on requirements, via automatically tested specifications. For more information, see the wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s article on the subject
I forgot to mention that this is the perfect start to TDD, as this is usually called the double-loop TDD. See a post on it on coding is like cooking
In this double-loop TDD, the first thing is to create a BDD scenario, run it (red-1), create a unit test that reflects this red (red-2), pass it, refactor; go to red-1 as many times as you need, doing TDD cycles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing BDD at a client</title>
      <link>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/09/implementing-bdd-at-a-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 22:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alvarogarcia7.github.io/blog/2015/02/09/implementing-bdd-at-a-client/</guid>
      <description>This was a low-hanging fruit as a team member who specialises in QA complained about testing in the last moment during the last sprint&amp;rsquo;s retrospective.
Did the grunt job of connecting the dots and configuring the maven project (using jbehave). Also, got the inspiration from a tutorial.
Announced it only as it was in place and QA approved of it
This grunt job clicked with Sweep the floor
Let&amp;rsquo;s see how the sprint goes and what are the pain points during this sprint</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
